okay
it is now co-stars turn it's my turn and
what do I have
what's my equipment oh Jesus you guys
are really putting me through the loops
today go okay so you don't have a shirt
you do have a little fanny pack inside
the fanny pack you have lots and lots of
cutlery you're the type of person who
when you're at a restaurant you kind of
like to swipe a little bit of cutlery
you have like a little hoarder mentality
with cutlery but that's not to say you
know you wouldn't just Chuck a four kind
of dude you don't care about it that
much you just like the act of taking and
holding cutlery so it's not letting you
collect them you just like taking them
and have yeah you're a klepto also in
your pockets you have a dead rat you
were planning to eat it later
that was you found it on the hike up
here you're planning to eat it later
so you've done this originally that was
your original plan but then you were
like I care more about Randall than this
right I found on the roadkill on the way
so okay all right so yeah I'm not gonna
use the rat and saving that for later I
have a bunch of silver all right well
then I'm gonna move up to the battle
how many men came up to the battle five
spaces so you can't move that far unless
you're gonna sprint up mmm and unless
you roll 20 you're not be able to attack
where was I right right here okay so
I'll just move up and oh I'll use an
ability then okay see then do a spirit
rush right there okay yep right there
yet okay so spirit rush you are now you
won't be able to do anything and that
includes using your Nimbus okay until it
comes around to two rounds of pass
okay so you're gonna have to skip two
turns and then you can do three turns at
once
okay cool all right so Co moves up
forward gets on the ground crosses its
legs and starts dictating so shirtless
dead rats no no the rats still in his
pocket
oh yeah that's deep in my pocket just
starts meditating of the battle buzz it
is your turn
ah let's see
wait pause no I'm sorry bones your turn
my apologies dip bones yeah yeah all
right so slinks just probably not really
good meat in melee right
no but you view your wants your blonde
honestly dead bones it's more like a
club it's actually made of a pretty big
it's yeah it's actually someone you used
to know not really a friend not really a
foe he died and you happened to fashion
it into a bone wand so you can use it
like a club - it's the dead bone it's
the dead bone all right got it so I'm
gonna use this club I'm gonna take the
skeleton oh it's peanut butter jelly
time trying to impress new data right
for regardless dead bones you have to
say peanut butter jelly time when you
were rolling the dice I'm still a little
fella fail however does not matter you
missed anyway okay so okay you go to
swing at you go to swing your club you
swing at the skeleton and you just
completely bollocks it up and just you
basically just swift and he's like a
foot in front of you it's not even close
you kind of thought you were wielding a
sword or something you're like oh yeah
he's blinking oh it's like a billy hard
too you know yeah it's you know you're
not you're not a combat oriented I'm
established it yeah you're kind of out
of your element being there that's
understandable
okay now pause it is your turn
can I search for hidden walls yeah sure
man awesome okay I really care about the
discount ends you guys are gonna take
care of them you don't care about your
dad no not as much as you guys do 9 all
right you take a minute to search for
hidden walls to over search the room
in it you're able you're now your eyes
are able to kind
to focus a little bit down the hallway
you can reveal part of this area over
here me what about this sign huh as a 9
is he's just searching he's just doing a
search 14 14 okay this really not
effective there's two dice well which
one rolled a die well then he rolled the
nine I want him anyway this is positive
fucking hit him walls man leave me alone
pause it pause it searching around he
don't see any inner walls except for the
one the one that these skeletons are
were looking at and he can see the
skeletons are by the wall but even
though the skeletons are looking back
and like pause makes eye contact with
them right they actually look at it they
don't react in any way they are clearly
defending that wall and have no
intention of reacting the pause did you
move up pause I'm guessing yeah well
yeah because we made eye contact right
when yeah and when you when you start to
move up the skeleton just draw their
weapon they don't move towards you they
just don't want you coming any closer
they start talking and there's they
don't really talk they just kind of like
clap their jaws together like they like
talk like and cliques basically because
that's all they can do trying to sound
very threatening toward you in fact you
are mildly terrified of these bone
clacking skills my jaws back at them yes
but this will be the end of your turn
okay can I roll yeah you are clucking
your jaws back at the skeletons in
return kind of kind of like a feared
look right yeah
fear look you do kind of it you you
can't really tell but you can tell that
the skeleton stopped clacking when you
start clacking so you know I think you
got the last words gonna be the number
of teeth that he chips all right now the
skeletons turn the skeletons are moving
in on dad this skeleton goes to grab
ahold of dad from behind so he's gonna
try and get him in like a chokehold
that's dads move dad resists and pushes
him back how do you like it now fucker
dad resists the move nobody uses dads
on him the other skeleton immediately
goes try to do the exact same thing 13
again dad resists pushing this skeleton
away he's not being he's not being taken
back during this dad involuntarily yells
you won't stop me from my mission I will
see John dark dead I tell you and pushes
both the skeletons away after he pushes
it away Cormac pulls out an axe at his
pocket throws it at the skeleton he's
facing and hits him dealing three damage
the axe is lodged in side of his the
skeletons ribcage I would never cheat my
axe like that
Justin is now your turn wasting a
perfectly good axe all right I can't I
can only move five right yeah all right
can I try this bad as you try to sprint
yeah if you wanna try Sprint's up okay
ooh
four you're not gonna be able to sprint
you start running forward but you forget
about the bag and you actually do the
stop right in front of it you're not
gonna be able to move any more than this
but you can still take your turn mm you
lose the ability to move anymore cuz you
just started running you're like oh that
big some fire and then now you can still
do something if you want you're standing
right next Roman bag of skeletons and
the flaming bag alright ah can I toss
the flaming bag yeah sure grates on fire
mind you the teamwork pass here I go
ahead and roll alright so I you didn't
so you you're gonna throw the bag so you
pick up the bag you're gonna throw like
a football you're really confident in
this throw you're gonna be able to hit
whatever you want but you didn't
actually tell me what you want to throw
so I have to just assume so you chuck
that you chuck it hitting at the one
that was just recently hit dad and you
hit this skeleton in the head with the
bag
it doesn't necessarily do any damage but
the bag lands right on the skeletons
head and now he's blinded on fire so his
head's on fire he's got a shattered like
right ribcage with an accident
terrifying he's pretty terrifying he's
still alive and moving too it's like
yeah but the skeleton is clearly blinded
so all right Jake all right just do this
all right I'm gonna go for disguise okay
all right so Jake you have to change
your voice if you ever break this voice
okay when you were doing something in
character like if you're ever talking at
the table and you're trying to talk in
character you will immediately break
this the skies but but I can talk I can
talk normally out of character yes you
can talk normally out of injury okay so
Jake is now going to look just like a
skeleton a high-ranking skeleton you
thrown in yeah please yeah I just want
to do it you say so fun I'm sorry it's
fun to say I know all right can you roll
Jake how well this disguise is rolling
right now keep your pants on it's a
pretty good disguise the skeletons
probably will buy it mind you they're
kind of far you can still do your move
though if you want to move and try and
talk to the skeletons
I will walk and talk at the same time
two three four five that's as close as
you can get come to me pretties do we
know that you still get to be just as
weird skeleton dude pop oh um Justin
Roman and paws do everybody does except
for probably dad because you guys have
seen Jake do this all the time and it's
ADA yeah you guys can like tell codes
not even yet cause not even paying
attention he's just in full meditation
stance
well can I can I say that I'm summoning
the power of Grayskull no you can't
you're in full meditation you can't you
don't even know this is happening but it
wouldn't surprise you anyway Jake's
always pulling this and
down because if you know you guys have
been around Jake so long you typically
still know like even though he's like
put onto the skies Jake rarely can fool
you guys it has to be like the perfect
disguise this is not the perfect
disguise all Jake did was pick up some
bones next to him and kind of just like
he's just holding them just walking
around jingling the skull but it is a
good enough disguise that it will
probably trick these skeletons also my
fair brethren my name is dick Lord the
two skeletons seeing seeing Jake
actually turned to face him but we don't
know what reaction they have other than
that greatings
Roman is your turn okay I am gonna move
one two three four so I'm gonna move
next to Coe okay and oh wait Coe is the
one and goes the one meditating push
Jake into the skeleton what I mean Boyce
just alright give it I want to get up in
their grill I want to fight him Jake
does not know this is happening he's
trying to maintain his bone disguise go
ahead and push him oh wow it's barely
it's a good push you pushed Jake into
the skeleton the skeleton by the way on
fire covered in axe Jake kind of tumbles
into him the skeleton was so weak that
he's the the bones just shatter some of
the parts of the skeleton actually land
on Jake mostly the burning bag and
laying on his on his arm and now this
skeleton lowers his weapon as jake has
now somewhat fused with the older
skeleton combat is still going but at
the same time the skeleton at this point
is completely non-threatening towards
Jake
Jake is there anything you want to save
the skeleton boardgames right Co is
still chanting as channel usability
which isn't gonna do anything dead bones
it is your turn alright I want to
enlarge dad again okay I want to make
that big yeah it's gotta get swole Big
Daddy you heard that before
- alright you go to cast enlarge on dad
but miss enlarging the skeleton the
skeleton is about four times larger
maybe a little bit bigger enough to
block the doorway at the very least see
spell in a non-hostile position he's
still not hostile geez wait a second he
does have any flesh we could just walk
between his legs
sure you could yeah pause now your turn
okay well I want to try and be friendly
skeletons like so far their attention by
chattering my teeth they haven't shot at
me after chattering with teeth so like
can I move I want to move forward one
okay just to see whether or not they
they see from Aslan okay
roll to dodge arrows they're gonna roll
the dodge I'm gonna tell you in a second
okay you're gonna dodge the first one
you are gonna be dodging to roll the
second one Wow alright you dodged both
in fact the second one pause you catch
you now have an arrow nice yeah really
really good you you move up as you move
up two more skeletons come out of the
doorway behind you you can see the two
archers that were on the wall so let me
in fact you can see many skeletons as
you approach
you can move on the wall and again the
skeletons aren't really being
threatening towards you they just really
started clacking their bones man can I
can I channel my teeth back you get I
can you can you thought you liked me
when you needed it
while clacking your teeth you kind of
make your jaw sore you really don't want
to collect your teeth anymore it's
current it's kind of starting to hurt
knocks is there anything else you really
want to do you've dodged narrow you but
that was only really your walk your fuck
can I can I toss their arrow back like
yeah sure that's a sign of peace you're
gonna throw an arrow at them guys I
would befriend these skeletons
all right you throw the arrow it lands
just right in front
yeah it just lands right on the ground
that is a really weird swastika Jesus
pause okay what you see Jesus Christ
pause I didn't bring up a swastika it's
fine
all right is now the skeletons turn this
skeleton walk and see no no okay no see
Millie totally ceiling okay
is that me it's that better oh you're
shrunk there you go
so this skeleton walks up and starts to
really look at Jake because Jake has
given off that he's some sort of leader
of the skeletons the skeletons aren't
that smart but I mean he's very
perplexed by Jake and doesn't really
want to attack anymore
he's confused he takes a good look at
Jake and he sees past the disguise now
he's gonna swing his sword to break
Jake's disguise permanently oh shit
sorry scale to her that's the big story
he swings his weapon Jake is able to
jump back out of the way of the weapon
but in the process he starts that his
disguise starts to fall apart
oh and now there's an a large skeleton
that is a very large skillet
the other two two more skeletons shoot
two more arrows at pause pause new role
to dodge two more arrows build you
captain alright big money big money no
whammy no whammy stop Oh
alright the first arrow pause hit you
it's a tranquilizer you fall to the
ground you're asleep the skeleton
started to move this one skeleton starts
to move towards pause and grabs a hold
of him and is now carrying pause back
the only person who knows this is
happening currently is Justin Cormac
turns to fight the giant skeleton swings
his weapon and misses somehow it went
right through his legs they were just
all bones he's not used to fighting
giant skeleton tries to stab and clearly
Justin is now your turn it's my turn
alright I want to try to help pause okay
what are you doing oh you're just gonna
walk up in attack what are you trying to
do that to help specifics specifics I'm
gonna walk up and toss pause to safety
okay awesome I'm gonna toss some you
know towards the cloud and CO and like
up towards his friends can I have your
toss records your so we can see it oh
yeah yeah thanks it's gonna cut the
corner on okay if you'll find a family
that loves them Wow Wow
six so you grab you grab pause and you
throw him in the wrong direction
no it's fine he just lands over here
behind the wall it still accomplishes
your goal but you're like that's not
what I meant to do alright is now Jake's
turn well seeing that my disguise is no
longer active can I go up in
I want to punch the skeleton in the junk
yeah man
Jake walks up he's gonna punch him right
in the pelvic way I can't roll the dice
I'm drawing on them hit f1 yeah I got
this you swing at the skeleton you don't
do a ton of damage you only get to hit
him for about one or two we'll say two
just because we're nice um
but clearly but you doesn't even do
anything the skeletons in large state he
barely even feels this so you can now
you see that after you punch you can see
that and you still have your move so you
can either back off or or take a more
defensive stance for if he returns your
attack I want to punch him in the nuts
again can I do that you can but you'll
have to use quite a bit of your stamina
you'll have to be really focused on a
chain of punches with document like core
not good enough I've if you want to do
it yeah you can punch your dad but it
again you've already swung once for your
turn you're gonna have to really focus
if you want to do this again
alright let's sprint out peace out
Cormac which direction you're gonna be
running here 20 all right you can roll
out you can Jake you are so scared after
hitting this skeleton of doing nothing
that you just get a sudden burst of
speed that even though you normally are
worried about you know all those action
figures of five figures falling out of
your fanny pack doesn't matter you can
move the full seven steps in any
direction
Jake is one of the dungeon I'm gonna
move behind the cloud cuz he'll protect
me cuz Randall savvy Randall will so
save me all right it is now Roma's turn
panthan staying a long time to kill this
one skeleton guys he's really big he's
really big now like really come on it's
okay cuz almost cosel's done charging
it's gonna be amazing
Roman okay so we have a giant I was
actually thinking about that yeah
just feel so terrible but okay so we
have giant skeleton do I I don't know
what's going on behind me you just
you've probably at this point seen that
there's something going on but you're
not you so you probably looked saw like
there's another skeleton Justin's
apparently dealing with it pause is
currently down out you've seen pause get
thrown over to the corner your call on
how you would react
it's basically there's one skeleton over
there giant skeleton in front of dad
okay
yeah we're saving dad so I'm gonna pick
up CO and put him in front of the
skeleton well he also know he gets the
moves too in his turns look that's the
thing is he can just feel good with that
okay yep roll I'm gonna come out of my
meditation like you have to kind of drag
him and you actually kind of interrupt
his meditative state it's gonna
interrupt this turn code is now your
turn but you only get two turns not
three roaming trying to help you out has
weight awaken you from your meditative
state also because you've been awakened
you're slightly disoriented you're not
where you were you're not where you were
you were expecting more time for your
power so your moves aren't gonna be as
good as you want but you still have two
full turns to do what you want right now
okay goddamn shit that's big skeleton
I'm gonna pull out my my whatever force
pillar geomancer okay yep yep and I'm
gonna try to smash him up against the
ceiling I assume there's a ceiling here
yep mm-hmm okay I'm gonna go I'm gonna
go for the coast mash the thanks smash
thanks smash thank you okay
you start to sex successful you start to
say the Minnesota sex now remember this
is only this is only one pillar so
you're gonna be doing it correctly
you're gonna be directly doing it under
one of his feet because his feet you
would think are across tuturro things so
do you want to raise this left or right
there's AB you care
can we lower the ceiling a huge we could
lower the ceiling but he's already he's
already committed to raising things
underneath him damn it yeah either way
there's right but either way it's not
gonna matter the skeletons going to try
and just step step beside it step to the
side but he can't so the skeleton gets
smashed up against the ceiling takes
five damage comes back down fallen on
the ground so the skeleton is now on the
ground he lands back on that there's now
a dirt pillar do I have something for
that I should but I closed my thing
what's that ability called Co it is
called for circular I'll get something
in a second so there's now a pillar in
in play here but at the same time you
don't actually hit him or are you you
actually you hit him and he lands down
he's now down on the ground okay
and you now have one more turn to do
something all right
so now that he's laying down on the
ground right down on the ground yep
right so now I'm gonna bring a pillar
down from the ceiling and to finish him
off okay question this is your fatality
yep
14 okay you bring the ceiling down
completely encasing the skeleton but on
the bad news this is now completely
covered in dirt you just basically
caused an avalanche walling off the
mushroom room combat has now ended
because the last skeleton that was
fighting is now moving away unless
Justin you would like to do something
the skeleton as he walks away he's not
he's clearly not engaged in a battle he
came to grab pause but now that you've
thrown him by the way he's just backing
off do you want to continue or do you
just want to let him go eyes want to
give him the finger as he walked good
roll to see if he even sees it look what
your luck yeah double bird you pull up
the bird you yell double bird the
skeleton sees it and it's just like it
actually kind of makes him feel bad so
you dude you've made his day worse and
he walks away it goes
back inside behind the wall sook on
that's over combat is now over I wanna
go over here and I want to just kick
tall's in the head today wakes up okay
Bozz try waking up for me will do
captain and don't be a one again please
nobody one that's that you roll it into
the pause wakes up pause you take a
minor amount of damage from waking up
but your all-around good dad happened
dad turns to co-star says good work but
unfortunately you've now walled us in
we're gonna have to start digging this
out and it's gonna take a while yeah
that's unfortunate what did you say you
say something about jontron earlier what
I'm questioning dad about what he
shouted that well oh yeah something John
dar dar he's corn maque dude he's dead
the Apple 3 reference I'm sorry no he's
he's yelling about John dar he says it's
nothing he has a little side mission he
wants to take care of and actually now
that you've encased us in he's actually
gonna go see if he can do that he wants
you kids to stay here dig this out he's
gonna go towards the skeleton me where
you going dad you know he's gonna go he
has something he needs to deal with that
has nothing to do with this and he's
gonna try and walk off does anyone want
a same way today there's still only two
of us that know about that right who
knows about what John dar the side path
over here with the skeletons there is no
side path over here no no no there I'm
saying only Justin and positive there's
no only Justin pause no there if you
want you guys can kind of talk about it
dad is slowly starting to make his way
over there to investigate it himself you
say anything dad know that look ease the
skeletons can be reasoned with
some of them can't he's pretty confident
that he's going to be able to get past
these skeletons though but at the same
time he's not sure that you guys could
come with him at this point so he's kind
of saying you kids wait here dig that
out I'll be back in a bit
oh all right dad it's everyone sounds
okay dad
fine dad all right dude