welcome to for unrolls live today we're
going to be playing essentially what is
tabletop role play you call it dungeon
dragons path 1 or whatever we have the
rule set dumbed down very very very much
so that the game is much more about the
discussion and interaction the comedy
the drama then rolling dice
we will only really be rolling a d20
everything's really really simple it
should be really fun if you saw our
holiday stream you already know what to
expect if you saw the trailer video you
can kind of see how these some of these
guys would already talk so what I'm
going to do here is I'm gonna get my
microphone unmuted and then we're gonna
get a little introduction of everybody
who's gonna be involved today mr. Jake
hello yo what's happening so mr. Jake uh
today is all about you man
congratulations on successfully funding
your Kickstarter yeah man what I thought
we were gonna have you know to do a lot
of work today you know trying to like
sell it but you were done that for us so
we don't think the Shelf must be a Hail
Mary holy crap we're gonna fail please
help us out and now it's like well some
stretch goals would be nice but no we do
justice you're funded so that's the show
everybody pack up gentlemen don't thanks
for coming all right uh I know everybody
uh Rob's line was awesome no but so so
here's the story for why we're doing
this for Jake honestly KO's been a
massive fan of stuff I was like one of
those fans who just didn't really know
you Jake but I was like oh shovelknight
yeah that guy that guy um a jerk and we
did it we did a stream with Jake two
weeks ago it was a ton of fun we offered
to set this up he wanted to do it and he
got to bring Aaron here with us who's
going to be joining us who that's you
mr. ego ooh
that's that's that's you the guy who
writes naughty words on my board and I
have to try and erase them what you're
saying like all these people are gonna
reference this stuff but they did
earlier you're the only one who's done
it
yes I know I know I know the irony of
the statement yeah I know
I set the precedent for how these
monkeys act sometimes so I'm sorry
thanks for joining us both you guys uh
the reason why we're all here together
again is for Jake's Kickstarter nuran
it's super cool basically it's a music
album that you also get a crazy
interactive experience even if you don't
have a VR headset an oculus um it's
still gonna be awesome
regardless it works with oculus but
oculus is not required at all yeah so
we're actually later in the day we're
going to take a look at that but uh
we're gonna get everybody started here
and start to get some classes so today
from the Buffalo wizard side we have
Roman joining us hello Rome hello mr.
co-star okay dead bums eight it's still
not officially above the wizard
we have pause and pause and we have
Justin hi so how this is going to work
is we are playing a very very basic
tabletop these guys are going to make
some classes we're going to go over some
really basic store and we're gonna get
right into the game on the stream you
guys can see everybody's what you would
Sassoon is health don't think of it as
health think of it as more like stamina
and health if you do damage if you take
damage if you do actions you're going to
use your stamina and when you use your
stamina and it gets low you have the
potential to die you also have the
potential to die if you just don't get
out of the way like seriously but if
there's a dragon don't attack his mouth
I'll just kill you and we have to either
no you can
I would I would suggest it but you know
you can means we have to maybe says
we've suggested you know we have it's
the sea devil just learning very quick
devils learning very quick how I also
made to lie it's well I mean I can't
just tell you everything I have to only
you know tell you enough and then hope
that you figure out the rest on your own
my love works does this game have RPG
elements well what do you mean by you
may like strengths and all that type of
stuff no I mean like is it like a
role-playing game yes yeah you're gonna
be role-playing Jake today you're gonna
be man you're all going to be
a group of family you don't have to be
brothers some of members of the table
have already expressed being a sister
and you don't all have to you're going
to be all dwarves but if you would like
to pretend you are adopted and don't
realize you're not a dwarf
that is completely okay mr. Jake as it
is your day today you get the decide
which class you want to be of all these
matters we have six classes as well as
the seventh class which gets to just
pick any of the skills and they get to
pick last and then you get to make up
whatever the name of your classes do bad
but though it is one of these I colored
cards yeah is a different class it says
so green over here this is a lumberjack
if you would like to be the lumberjack
class you can be a paladin a warrior I
think that's a sorcerer a monk or uh a
bard
and I think this one's pretty obvious it
is a clearing up sweetheart
yes this shiites your choice really
confused all of them a card I'm pretty
much honor bound to be the bard aren't I
well which three abilities are gonna go
with today then I can low you to sleep
with a lullaby mm-hmm you'll have to
actually sing to use this ability though
I hope you well that good artists borrow
great ones steel so I'm not gonna take
borrowing okay I definitely want to
double down okay you like to double down
okay and and I think I think we're
definitely going to uh we're definitely
going to disguise you get a name for
your dwarf
you got any anything else you want to go
with your little backstory what type of
character gonna be today Jake all right
my Dorf is going to be named hmm that's
a weird name yeah I asked my door
comment to be named dick Lord dick Lord
great great precedent we're starting
with today Jake thanks all right dick
Lord what might as young I wanted to be
penis warlock well you can't now Aaron
you're just gonna have to come up with a
different name also you said you wanted
to be a boy you are gonna be penis
warlock the girl to Worf I mean P you
know that makes more sense
normal tall
why it's the discarnate worth you don't
have to be a dwarf area you can be the
board you can be any creature you like I
want to be this red one cuz it has a
cute girl
wait gonna be a warrior do you want to
actually be the cute girl uh yeah okay
what does he like holding a salad in
front of early Buddhist it's a leaf you
know she doesn't have the most the best
wait man you trying to make it fun of
her man
oh look it's like one of those bruises
uh they are clearly fairy marks or
potentially bruises whatever way Erin
wants the role play them maybe he's
being beat by the other faith folks at
home what if Erin is beating her oh my
god we got to get him out of this girl
Erin is the girl he's not well I guess
he could be beating up himself but guys
are very presumptuous sorry she's just a
strong independent woman with with
leaves on her titties
yeah strong independent woman with
things on her titties so let's that's a
totally fine character to go with is the
Centaurs wiener like between the front
legs or between the back one or both i
would assume would be the back legs
right the lower half source so he's
gonna have the the horse Tony suggesting
that he has like a horse stick and
Amanda no no I mean he can't even look
down and see himself go or anything uh
okay and if he gets up on his hind legs
you know this is like really tall it's
got like an aerial view then it's like
it's so then a centaur is just a
centipede okay yeah yeah sure
I'm glad we're working this out there
Erin you need to pick three abilities
for your warrior what the fuck I got a
want this responsibility you have to
pick three free I you know the reason
why we got you and I even told eels like
here's the ability to look at them ahead
of time if you want I don't know there's
too many words unleashed a series of
punches great that's good you just did
you just said you wanted to be a warrior
dude you don't kick cherry-pick class
abilities yeah all right Aaron so this
here's how it works kay
what taste magic what's the magic this
is a sorcerer over here right oh man I
don't want fucking rolling fog what the
fuck is this shit
ah it gets a little dreary it's
flammable
so I mean there's there's potential
there for you to let things on fire with
it alright I'm done I'm going for okay
good good you got rolling fug yep let's
heat blink I want that one that's
already scented it great
flares that's not good that sounds
fantastic hearing that it's very good
for someone who didn't read the
abilities you made the excellent choices
so what we're going to do next is we're
gonna have a Roman you're up pick some
classes man okay see um kind of kind of
won't go yellow here okay you're gonna
go with a paladin yeah yeah I want to
mix it up you know okay yeah great
fantastic okay uh I got to pick my three
abilities now or just class yes you pick
your three abilities okay if you're
gonna provide intervention okay
blessing a strength okay
and no no you should be reading your
class abilities okay buddy you need to
be reading your class abilities instead
of drawing on the table I thought I took
that away from you guys
well you can never felt you absolutely
did not you can't stop an artist uh plan
let's plan right
what's that I made you a breast what's
your third ability Rovin ah all right
let's do unholy water okay all right
we're gonna have mr. kuester coaster go
next I think I'm gonna go with the
Romans name though I'm confused
Oh what's Roma's character oh yeah I
guess I guess promo you know okay
I just ski picked paladin so I assumed
he was going with room in the paladin
playing himself I know I'm this is
completely different kind of paladin
robb
okay yeah well yeah what's appellant
right here only ah glad you respected my
book oh that's why I just thought I just
noticed the change there was me yeah I
like that
ah okay so my is that
okay right ah my name is going to be
inky mm-hmm I love books and now I tend
to get ink on my fingers and that's just
sort of a name that stuck okay good
that's good I like it mr. Koester you're
gonna go with the monk here and I'm
gonna go with these abilities it's okay
if the viewers don't know what all the
abilities do just yet I'm sure they will
get to see them time and time again here
media you guys don't actually to drag
your abilities to your hand but it feels
right dead bones it makes a tray makes
hands that it makes sense is it my it
does make sense Devils is your turn
does anybody else want to be the seventh
class pick
if not I'll do it yeah hybrid class yeah
dead bones it's the hybrid class yeah I
wanna die first
which will explain it when we're done so
pause you're up two classes
oh well Justin already expressed
interest in being this so I'm only gonna
be him I'm just joking ah I'm gonna be
I'll be the lumberjack again yeah I like
mounting people anyways it's a lot of
fun you know ah that's not a lie
I feel like earthquake would be awesome
and uh oh god I can't make up my mind
anymore Rob what do I do what would you
suggest it's up to you man it's
completely up to you do you want to
throw up this I don't like pink pigs
suck get out here
nothing don't throw them away we're
gonna Devils I need to pick someone hold
on I need to put on the men and I will
be sir Spanky mokey
really wow wow very excellent
showmanship the applause are you wait
are you a monkey or you just named sir
Spanky I'm just I'm just named him bad
you look like a monkey
that's why why do you was that give self
giving did you get it as a nickname in
school did you where'd you come across
this name pause thank you thank you
thank you good answer for me pay thanks
answer you Justin you're up I'll be I
guess I'll pick the warrior
spanky is special in the head alright so
your three abilities there Justin
alright my three abilities I'm gonna
take chivalry okay it's like a lot of
Honor it's a role-playing game
role-playing game long it's gonna take
blockade yeah bottom honor okay yep and
it would take tosser because I I'm at
all sir okay thank you all right
fantastic and uh you know else about
yourself just oh my name uh oh you got
the cute girl damage it I did you didn't
pick that class you were going to it in
your move I gave you second pick yeah
but you know what I got a better class
cuz I got fucking Kamehameha blasts yeah
guy teleport to a Instant Transmission
and I got bog you you do realize that we
actually made the Goku class and you
could have just been Goku but you picked
another class and I are trying to be go
boo what the fuck you talking about good
there's no there's not the monk class
was Goku who's the monk man he's got
like punching and he's got like that
spear bomb skill look all the Goku shit
me took all the Goku shit man you're
gonna be Goku imposter now Aaron like
you're like the wanna be your krill
whatever I'll be just I'll be Santa Roku
know your Crillon man you just crayon
yourself nice Christmas huh
you Cox oculus the mighty cock stop
alright or dick or whatever it is yeah
but okay just call dick I like that yeah
yeah let's just show you this gig yeah
I'll fit for dicks ai ai ai ai doll dick
dick I yeah alright justice dick what
fuck up yep alright
Thank You dick ah alright dead bones you
were the last class you have to come up
with a name for your class and I think
it's really remaining abilities like to
come name first and the abilities of the
Buddha you can do the abilities first
alright I want enlarge okay cuz that's a
very useful skill mm-hmm in all walks of
life
you can't pick two of the same class
keep that um oh oh whoa oh that's a
wrinkle yeah that's a wrinkle
yeah I'm sorry oh that's a shit not
something that would've been fine yeah
ring Keeler uh you know I want to
spirits I do I just I wanted the punch
was great but I want see spirits and uh
spirits like as it's spooky ghosts
spirits let's go with honor chains all
right so I am a don't you get to pick
more abilities than that no I guess the
three
I am a seer a seer yeah very good and
your name - Aldo you my name is my name
is blinky that's cuz I just I blink a
lot it's like a tick I hate books so
yeah yeah very good
all right so we're going to do is I need
to get all your cards over here because
I need to drag them into the first board
and we're gonna go to the first town so
you're all you're all family pauses the
oldest so he's in charge it's just it's
it's very custom very uh I'd be the
youngest sure you can be the youngest I
get to beat wait how young is it I don't
want to be like too young I want to be
like reasonably young um I don't think I
don't think the world were in actually
has laws of legality I'm pretty sure
it's you know yeah well you know what
the world that we're playing it in right
now and the people who are watching at
home who live in that world are very
judgmental so but you're also not a
human so like I mean hey man if you want
all right I'm three come fuck me baby
yeah don't dwarves live to be like 400
years you'll they lived like hundreds of
years so amazing eighteen still you know
I don't I don't know if it'd be like 50
but the age of 100 80 yeah I don't even
think you you know you get an erection
until you're 30 most likely not three so
yeah probably not three like five but
they're girly though they're gonna news
you talk like you have experience with
dwarf dong uh no comment good it's the
music industry man it's crazy yeah I you
can happen man it was the beard
vestibule one of the cards no that's
okay
I'm taking them to our first world here
oh hey Ron I think we're like the the
most mature here since we're not you
know writing our fucking names in front
of her you know yeah about that
maybe we're loading the first map man
we're loading the first map you feel a
chance oh yeah and a backstory only one
type of story means me and Roman came
over the back story I'm gonna just be
trippin balls all day at there's more
eye effect on here on this board you
know if you get it like close to
horizontal all right if you want to take
your cards into your hands all you can
Hey oh it's me look at them I wouldn't I
wouldn't put them into the kittens own
your hand just so other people can mouse
over and altum for when you start to
reference them okay so who we so who is
a pause you're gonna be the oldest
oldest hands gonna be the youngest so
he's probably straggling at the back
here I'll guess pause who is who's going
to be your see my bud you know they
can't see your butt cuz you're at the
back margin my party why would I wanted
why would I want to hang in bang with
all the friends when I barely read
literally family business
yo I'm sorry right sort of habit incest
you as you realms live stream going on
this weird dude
gotcha weird if you make it weird mom
making it weird dude he's three universe
wait yet is what up I still got lovely
lady lumps bra okay can you actually
walk at three like are you yeah he's so
you know I can I can fucking shoot
command manager well what am i feeding
innocent okay good uh so pause you're
the second oldest who's like your death
in here is gonna be Jake though okay so
fine
is that fine with everyone we're all
good here what's the age difference like
how much older my than him um well how
old are you
first aha remember your dwarf you live
to at least 400 so you can be at 169 269
yeah that is a huge gap from oldest the
youngest man
yeah that's why it's super fucking weird
okay okay good uh so I just threw my
card and I lost it what did you do with
your card oh did you lose it into one of
these gamezone's
until we find your card you only hit two
abilities that's just no good yours
you're resourceful oh dude you're dude
you you're a sorcerer man you have to
like keep these like notes and stuff to
do your spell's you're three so you
clearly haven't memorized them I mean
get back we're well Dell Blair no don't
now we gotta go adventuring for it
you'll find it in the town I'm sure
you'll be able to recover your long-lost
spell here oh fuck I can't just lose I
can't throw a spell bail no you yeah you
you left it you were here earlier in the
day - you were scouting out this little
town - tell all your brothers and
sisters and you left one of your books
behind oh my god fucking books
that's bullshit you don't see fucking
Vegeta going like oh I'm a big bang
attack in my locker all you did when
Fujita was like three I mean he had to
like learn net he probably practiced a
lot you know he'd get big bag until
Excel soggy yeah yeah he didn't get big
bang for a while so - yeah just go come
no like thank you for that tip ass ass
DBZ knowledge yeah all right so we are
in the first town you have all come here
seeking glory and money you've come here
to meet up with a fellow wizard that is
a long time friend of pazzo was your
name again
Oskar Spanky Spanky the monk no sir
spank you go bug - Thank You buzz sir
Spanky the monkey to meet up and
basically just go on an adventure
you're all you're all just here to make
a bunch of cash today that's that is
your goal that's not what I'm here what
are you here for urine then okay what
are you what it what it all this bluff
okay that's true aaron is here for
revenge
he's really hoping to get back at sir
Spanky the monkey ring he really hates
his older brother Wow
what did I ever do to you middle child
you haven't done much he's only been
alive for three years no so I barely
know him yeah you killed my father did
you that X is that actually family fact
you guys all have to agree on this did
that actually happen did pause sure as
good as all of our fault so it's not
just like an errant mind this is
actually this HAP I'm the most beat up
about it because I was dad's favorite is
this really your dad's favorite that's
totally different
I mean hey fine I thought I was dad's
favorite okay we know what happened on
those camping trips okay well how many
camping trips he's three what is he
biforn is just like time to go camping
so well how old are you then I don't
know 20 27 K there we go there we go
there's still reason one says okay now
it's legal it's fine okay yeah okay so
uh you guys may now move up into the
town as you move closer to the town the
first thing you see is a stack of cards
wow those are just extras found them
apparel a stack of cars and a tavern for
now you may you're going to move as a
group you're gonna be falling pause
unless one of you decides to break off
from pause so pause can I break off from
the group like what are you eating um
you can just tell him to wait here
you're gonna go check things out sure I
don't want to do that though hey it is a
seven person TNT group so telling six
other people
hey wait here i'ma go do stuff pretty
much he's kind of a dick move but you
are Spanky the leader where's the
entrance the entrance is right over here
oh man or is there like a limited space
like amount of space we know this is
this is see this orange orange box this
is like a table food for drinks this is
a saloon that I drew it's not looking
funny as it tables thank you that's
impressive
thanks oh we're you guys feeling up for
some drinks yeah there are people NPCs
in there
oh yeah this
definitely Simoes yeah definitely you
know why don't we go to the bar and
check it out first okay let's do that
it was amazing one space out of time
okay
yeah you just all go ahead and move for
yourselves that's totally yep and then
one night you go to go turn you got a
turn did was carrying oh I I grabbed
just didn't forget down we're kissing
it's supposed to get all right you guys
are all going to lose the ability to
move your things around
oh hi guys no don't leave don't leave
your younger brother behind
get on the bar get to this table Oh Oh
God I think we're drum and go I did well
it looks like our way to the tavern we
lost Jake I guess CJ oh thank god
I will fix it unfortunately hey I think
my adventure has ended here's your
rolling fog by the way you left it in
the tavern you left in the tavern weird
I'm just oh man I'll just spawn a new
Roman
I found Roman I found Roman he's over
here there you spawn the Romans right
you entered that you enter the tavern
you all stiff to come to drink a bar
wench comes up and towards costar asks
anything I can get you uh yeah let's get
some what you guys want ale can you get
me another father
the woman the with my woman gives a
really weird look - uh mr. Aaron in the
corner there but says sure I'll get you
some drinks ales anything else you guys
want that is not a fighter one father
yeah they have that type of night or two
I'll take a side as well the father is
actually a house beverage if you wanted
that Aaron I don't know is it
non-alcoholic I don't want to get drunk
before I kill my brother
no it is actually it's very it's like
50% right here oh if we bring another
father and I'm just gonna kill him right
front of you no it's not actually father
it's it's an alcoholic it's no I would
that's what you said that it's an
alcoholic beverage it's not actually a
person you can order it but give us a
figure speech like I will pound it back
in once it well do you want to order a
father itself yeah
you're gonna order a father in front of
your yogurt brother who thinks you know
what made double action made awful
that's really passive-aggressive little
capable dad okay you know having it can
I have an apple juice uh she says we
don't have apple juice man fuck you all
right I'm out of here okay fuck this
place I'm burning with rage here and all
I want to fuckin apple juice to remind
me of the good times with my daddy and
motherfuckin I have to stare this
asshole in the face all day yeah point
you spanking the monkey monkey yeah okay
bro okay I did in a shoulder rub for did
you want to leave the bar and just get a
brush over me I don't want to be not
striking out you know you want to move
into the corner maybe yes I move to the
corner roll for me sure yeah we can roll
go ahead and roll the dice just this
over here you get to do your roll funny
no that was me grooving the dice you're
going to roll it ego I can't do your
roll for you you have to pick up the
dice oh there you go you hit the peep no
you're already gonna fog in sorry it's
okay okay this is why I killed dad there
you go you got a 13 you successfully
move into the corner and begin to pout
sulk
sure okay very good so the bar wench
goes off comes back brings a bunch of
drinks and s co-star what would y'all
here for today what what are y'all doing
here today you guys hungry you want some
calzones this is anything with natural
this is now this is just they don't
serve food at this bar uh-uh at business
some riddle as a young it's just it's
just British the pharmaceuticals that's
all I got
let's get weird man yes we're good then
Oh nobody you to you what can I can I go
see my younger brother I want to talk
with him okay yeah you're gonna move
into the corner which is gonna come back
bring you guys some drinks I'll be look
so much alike
pause no what do you want look do you
can see that the resemblance what do you
want to say this well mister you go here
I'm a girl my brother mrs. ego you're
okay
mrs. ego she's married Missy you go
Missy go I'm sorry
I know are you are you air are you uh
married in this errand uh it's
complicated okay okay that's good
does your family know it's complicated
or if you like kept it on the bed dad
Oh your brothers are still alive I
assume your mother is your mother alive
guys no idea no often we were young yeah
I'm the only enough the cell phone so
wait on me I'll wait what do you mean
what do you mean your mother's off Aaron
was born I guess 20 years ago okay
yes 27 years ago in a while okay all
right that smokes never came back
pause please talk you can talk to Aaron
about anything you like you know I don't
want to like make you matter a thing but
just just quit being so salty man we're
in front of our family here
just quit bring our father up okay don't
worry I just I just have a lot of issues
that I have to deal with man I watched
him die
and I watched him get murdered which are
the same thing you have to say to that
Jack uh first and foremost my name is
our Jack so please don't call me that
time sir spank the monkey you know that
oh look look who's getting offended now
I'm not I'm not you just called me Jack
that's fucked up
you're fucked up you have a reason why
killed dad I want both era P gimme
therapy uh I don't prepare a role for
therapy okay Aaron is having a
psychological breakdown right now he's
really we're gonna see if he can get it
under control
or if he's going to continue down a
downward spiral of hating his family
because of his father's death Aaron is
starting to get it under control here
huh the talks with your brother is
helping you know that you know that deep
down even though pause did kill your
father it was for a good reason because
I don't want to fuck him I love my
father
yeah but you knew you know deep down it
was a good reason that you know your
older brother had to kill your father
because your father was
a pedophile okay
I'm really glad you got three years old
anymore but alright
that's I would have got him help for
that instead of killing him pause but
that's well I'm the oldest brother I saw
touch Justin I saw him touch co and what
you were bored I just I would have
Twitter it anymore
mad fucking get rid of him no he was a
menace to society if he's gonna touch
children he look at us there's eight of
us here I asked him to some baby never
did