dead bones is now your turn so what
party tricks than I exactly do with my
little wand um I would say you were
allowed to move small things on the
ground no more than a pound and you
could only move them maybe like two or
three spaces you're not going to be able
you're not really gonna be able to throw
them it's just a little tiny telekinesis
party trick it's just until I can eat a
party trick wand yeah that's all it's
really for your main weapon is your
slingshot which you've had since a boy
you got not the best of aim but you do
packed a decent punch with it you know
the blinking it kind of gets me all
right I want to enlarge dad okay yep
this it doesn't obviously I know I said
yeah I'm a new dad yeah you know you you
you will know that that's obviously your
character knows that the nimbus did not
the nimbus just hear the nimbus looked
at Roman and cormac and assumed Roman
was dad right 10-4 new dad okay all
around bigger not on us was that three
stamina okay uh you enlarge dad he
becomes a four times the size whoa yeah
yeah hey Dad Daggett's big uh the actual
size says I hope he doesn't mess with us
anymore like you did in the past the
actual size causes these bones that are
lying on the ground to go flying not in
a way that they would like hurt Roman or
anything but just just you know it moves
by the way and it pushes back this
skeleton right here who dad nice flip da
man he's doing flip kicks and stuff good
job um I need to get a role to see if
dad will thank dead bones hmm dad's
approval uh dad says nothing oh maybe
worse he could be mad I'm gonna make you
pass are you blinky oh thanks inky
alright we've come to is that it dead
bones you know do you want to move or
anything good yeah I'll move up and
start looking at this cloud and being
you know like what the fuck is this okay
uh pause is that your turn okay well
while while dead bones is like wandering
to himself with the fuck is this ah can
I go up and try to inhale it
um it's my only that's too far okay you
can move my loser up but or you can
screw into it but you wouldn't be able
to do anything to it okay how many
spaces going to move up so you can move
one two three four five wow this is not
as easy as I thought you can move to
around one two three four five if you
use your whole turn you could walk right
up to the cloud but you want to be able
to do anything other than say a couple
sentences to either Roman dead bones of
the cloud and you'd have to sprint to do
it I'll just sprint I don't care okay go
ahead and roll I need you to roll to see
if you fall or something retarded oh god
no you're fine you just named you don't
make it all the way though you're just
right in front but you're close enough
that you can at least see and be next to
dead bones and see the cloud anything
else was and I don't know what it is
screaming okay I came in to touch
trumpet co do you want to respond to
anything tell them like cuz there do you
hear a little conversation something
like what is this thing it's touching
Roman oh yeah yeah yeah I gotta explain
them it's Randall know what it's real
guys ran those around I don't know what
okay pause and just pause and dead bulls
are now left in suspense that what do
you mean is Thranduil that's where they
are on the story alright Justin it's now
your turn you did not get eat any of the
mushrooms I believe right I did not so
you're completely fine okay yeah I want
to run up as well ok I want to get close
are you gonna try and sprint or just
kind of walk yeah yeah no miss me okay
oh alright uh this is not even a sprint
for you just then you actually ran a lot
of track when you were younger you run
so fast now that you have no problem
moving six spaces that's just no problem
to you you can doubt you can also take
another turn now oh sweet i want to i
want to try to inhale the cloud before
pauses secret is gonna run in front of
pods cut them off yeah it's nice in the
cloud paws should run I should have run
more buddy I know I'm a little bit
disappointed alright well it's fine I
gotta roll for this yep
oh okay unfortunately it is a 17 Wow
yeah that's actually good so uh you
inhale Randall Randall is inside of you
he does it how's that random dude it's
uh it does it does not actually you
don't feel anything but I mean you'd
like to think you did because you just
smoked into a cloud being into your body
weight so now is Jill Justin arendal no
rental just inside of him that's why I'm
k r angel is gonna burst rimadyl Egan
can you blow him out of people I mean
it's inside Justin do Billy he far
Randall out later on he probably will
yeah i know i expect me to tell justin
that a yes they're like this
invulnerable need to fart just okay
voluntary i'll do that what's it like a
fucking strange rattle OG like come on
alright Jake is your turn all right um I
want to try to serenade Randall out of
there can I can I roll too first let me
move so you're gonna move up a little
closer one two three four five and then
you're to play your music right from
here I mean we could do this from from
afar yeah you did from afar you're gonna
try and sing a song you're due wait
you're just you're just gonna try and
what sing Randall out here I'm gonna try
to get him to his his new dad because
what you know I think that he's
imprinted strongly enough that i think
it's it's possible that he might
actually just come out and want to be
with his desk do you mean Roman army I
mean it's new dad Roman all right let's
do this um what type of song are you
gonna play what do you what are you
doing to look all right we got this like
Les Paul Sorrento there were a fine
cloud um-hmm I'd sure like to hug you
but it's not allowed
when's your dad now and he's very proud
thank you how do you the ass chat
they're gonna be greatly impressed I had
Randall in it yeah yeah I think I can
get him out of there the pan con Randall
does just come like Justin's can't help
but open his mouth and just grow as
Randle comes right out and flies to you
it captivated by your song jinkies new
dad ok she's a dancer I always wanted a
cloud son all right I lost my son I was
a dad for 30 seconds the joys of
fatherhood yeah well you know everything
now Jana be at least an Italian descent
I don't him so many spirals of sadness
gonna send him off to cloud college ok
so this skeleton is going to make a
break for it he's gonna run he's scared
shitless of Cormac he's going to run
right into this fog of war Cormac is not
even going to bother chasing he doesn't
even care he turns around and says good
work guys and just as he's doing at the
enlarged starts to wear on normal size
normal dead I wanted to get a hug on his
leg or something at this big dad uh
combat has now empty ended so you can
all regroup hey Carm act it dad can only
get so enlarged yeah dad what whispers
receps where's the my room's where's
Erin I said there's mushrooms I don't
care about air right now uh uh keys
Cormac says now you do know that some of
the mushrooms are very very poison and
the poison of these mushrooms it can
only be cured by another form of
mushroom so we have to be very very
careful but these mushrooms are insanely
powerful because by taking them it'll
based on replies Randall again uh yeah
sure yeah hold to inhale Randall can i
enlarge Randall one is done my boss goes
to inhale Randall but you can interrupt
this Co if you really want regardless of
his role because it's not a 20 by just
making Randall move
oh yeah that's a good idea where do you
want Randall to go that's right children
let's let's put Randall I don't even
know how to Helen you Randall just goes
where you want him to go through a
heavily he'll listen a new dad no
Randall Randall doesn't have an
ownership Randall's kind of like just
he's a few he's part of part of co is a
way to think of it like Randall &amp; Co are
of one mind okay that's so the reason
exists know the reason why he thought
Roman was dad is because deep down co is
always seen Roman as a fatherly figure
because his dad wasn't a really good dad
that's that's all it was and co was also
captivated by jakes music because he
just loves his go with older brothers
music and you know that's why Randall
was able to come out and neither of them
ever touched me when pause goes to make
it pause goes to handle it in co has the
immediate reaction of no and looks
towards his real dad in which case the
cloud moves and co gets that Coco
suddenly realizes the bond he has with
Randall now like whoa I mind control you
cool yay mess with this fire over here
you can however dad says dad again we
like he was still talking about the
mushrooms it's like so we need to be
really careful when picking these
mushrooms the poison mushrooms are
terrible and the other mushrooms will be
very very helpful in letting us defeat
bo boppin also keep in mind that even
touching those poisonous mushrooms can
inherently infect you so when we're
picking them we have to be very very
careful in the middle of this discussion
Jake walks over to start touching the
fire what do you want to do with fire
chick I just want to touch it okay go
ahead and roll okay cool per year all
right Jake burns his hand slightly nice
i'm glad you too Jake Jake you should
touch my shoulder yo check out this fire
can I wrote the touch of shoulder hip
touch his shoulder go ahead alright cool
you go to touch a shoulder but
accidentally touches nuts that's a
common problem with worse apparently it
was definitely an accident and mistakes
were made and I do flee regret this
occurrence corpsman corpsman explains
that the best way to go through this
dungeon is going to be the long way
around so going all the way around is
going to be the safest way to getting to
boken who is in this big room by the
lake he explains that while they could
probably get in via the lake it would be
really really hard to swim and he
doesn't think we're gonna be able to
find the type of things to build a boat
pause maybe we were so short cuts yet
this is the but this is the best
shortcut is to go around and ignore
these middle judge is the long cut yeah
the shortcut is to go the long way and
avoid it do you see these orange walls
then that is like the skeleton space by
going on the outskirts they can avoid
avoid much of the the inner skeleton
tribes and not have to try to fight past
the gates that can just go around and go
through the secret passage core Matic
explains that if you guys can solve the
riddles of the lion king you'll be able
to take the secret passage to get right
into bogans layer I want to solve I want
to smell the roses office for medical or
tells the answer Hakuna Matata cormac
explains that the riddle is given by the
lion king he doesn't actually know the
riddles wait dad are you liking no no
he's it's no he's not actually sure if
the lion king is even a lion it's
personal in the dungeon apparently can
let them get past so does everything is
everything I'm not just ours no I'm not
the lion king no you kids are not
understanding and I just Durvasa win
yeah yeah okay son please at this point
by the way open his scarred at this
point Cormac is fully into the dad thing
he now refers to you as sons just
because he's realized that's a great
way to control you monkeys into doing
things no pause you can't just Cormac
tells pause and Roman they're both
grounded for one week after this could
we just get large Cormac descended like
this is it does anything grow outside in
this long shortcut that he pointed out
anything grow didn't grow is there
vegetation out there yeah the mushrooms
which he was talking about are located
in the very next room yeah inside the
wall this is the hole oh no no so so if
you go if you go I'm sorry I'm sorry
know that that was just me pointing
which way you're supposed to go know if
you go towards the arrow you will go to
where Cormac was talking about where the
mushrooms are where we can pick them for
the battle if you go down this hallway
we're going to come up against a
skeleton resistance obviously one way
shorter and one way is very easier but
it's he suggest you go this way I don't
like no scars beard scratches when he
kisses us a core mock is gonna try and
intimidate you guys by demanding you
listen to dad now does anyone want to
try and resist a core maxell speech
about listening to dad no I put him to
sleep one way down oh okay are you gonna
start try to put dad to sleep no no no
go ahead let him I'll let him do his
spiel uh it was a three but I know that
the dad does not really impress you guys
he says a bunch of stuff a lot he uses a
lot of metaphors that don't really work
uh what most of you guys think a little
bit less of dad after that and the suit
each but dad now starts walking towards
the next room it wants to know if you
guys are gonna come with him what is the
left side mushrooms right no no forwards
mushrooms fortunately I really do you
want to go a little shit what's what
buckets have to do with banana peels
dude maybe we could make daddy to
mushroom oh my god you catch it I'll be
the coolest dad ever you know what uh uh
Lisa the game was such utter shit maybe
you know him eating some mushrooms
it actually open up his mind what if he
already ate some mushrooms and that's
why it was so shit oh my goddess Kali
the bird watchings in right which
question should eat we don't know what
we're watching him the red ones are what
you want to eat yeah Jake at the purple
it is fucking sweet he saw what it's
really awesome all right we need to
think this through okay there's
different mushrooms half of us need to
try one the other happy to try the other
I don't really want any measures so
you're having mushrooms I really don't
want to eat any mushrooms it's happening
as cormac moves into the other room
while you guys discuss who's gonna eat
the mushrooms two more skeletons come
out of the shadows and begin battle you
guys are again in combat Cormac and the
skeletons well the first turn the scale
concerns were walking in Cormac is going
to get the surprise by ducking around
the corner just before the skeletons can
see him the skeletons can't see you guys
yet as it's a pretty big distance and
while this room is lit skeletons don't
really have the best of eyes but combat
has now started the skeletons have a
Nagra to anyone or anything like that
where's Randall Randall is wherever co
wants him to be so yeah right now please
wherever he's just in the sky somewhere
hanging out um first turn initiative
we're gonna give two dead bones who
noticed this happening first dead bones
you have the first turn the first thing
I do you just saw the skeletons you were
the first person of all your brother's
to see the skeletons they haven't even
noticed it yet can i alert these guys
the skeletons yeah hey dad's fight
skeletons yeah are you gonna do it
loudly quietly like whoa i think i think
i'll let the role decide how loud it is
ok they might just be model he might
just make you blink you might just
mumble it notice ligo that's what's cool
ah dead bones goes to warn his brothers
about the dead bones goes to warn the
brothers very good our first one that
bones goes to warn the brothers but this
goes haha shut the fuck up you're gonna
have some mushrooms okay dead bones
screams k which alert the skeletons of
something in the room but none of none
of the rest of you even though the
skeletons are coming there's an audible
shut up from dad uh being being heard
here
cause it is now your turn you don't know
the skeletons are coming all you know is
dad's mad and dead buzz is having
trouble talking it's a pauses turn oh
gotcha now yeah combat is started but
you don't actually know what you're in
contact you just see dead phones
freaking out and something's wrong with
dad hmm I do a weapon chat like what do
I have for weapons uh you have almost at
tomahawk wow you have a large spear
pause large Spears a spear and you have
your trusty acts but pause you hate to
use your acts on anything but trees like
you're a very very proud lumberjack and
you absolutely hate it your axe however
sharp as all hell like we're talking
five damage base like everybody else is
doing like three damage with their melee
weapons but this axe is just pristine
sharpness but you really really do not
like using it on anything but a tree
alright so I'm kind of like a dire
situation bring it out even in a dire
situation you're the type of person
would you would rather die your your axe
is more like your waifu okay you care
more about your axes then your cell okay
I respect it and respect that acts like
if you decided to use your acts on
anything but basically a tree would be
you kind of just you'd have to be out of
control or in a near death situation to
ever do anything like that so see it as
dead bones is still acting like a bitch
all I want to do is I want to bring out
my spear and intimidate him and tell him
that he's gonna eat the mushrooms okay
that's that's all I want to do is all
about the mushrooms because we don't
know about the skeletons dude you know
just I'm just sitting here you pull it
on my fucking spear be like dude we're
fucking force meeting you mushrooms
whether you like it or not see how
intimidating it is ok right after dead
bones screams pause tells them it's
really not effective but he says
basically to shut up pause you say to
dead bones do fucking eat much no no no
you can't say that you're can't be angry
all right now I'd be angry man
nice about it nothing there yeah yeah
that's why I did it haha gold playing
asshole well I put up my spear and I
forget what I'm about to say okay you
said nothing all right just nicely try
and have meet the mushrooms because
suggested it nicely tell me they're
really nice I don't know doesn't need to
be angry all right the two skeletons
walk forward dad tries to as the
skeleton turns around the corner dad
swings his goddamn Mase trying to just
knock the skeletons head clean off he
whiffs though is he this is just like a
blind turn he whiffs swinging at the
skeleton the skeleton just just a
natural miss he wasn't sure if he was
going to hit anything the skeleton backs
off just a little bit kind of dazed from
the swing the other skeleton charges at
dad dagger in Han and but but Dad it's
quickly able to dodge away from the the
skeletons thrust and is now facing
towards him that badass at this point
though you were all alerted that dad is
now in combat Justin it is now your turn
all right ah see let's look at the old
bilities real quick all right are you
going to just a heads up when you guys
use an ability do me a favor and bring
the card at least in front of us that
way I can just show chat what actually
you're trying to do i would like to toss
okay yep uh-huh I've had bones at the
skeleton dead bones are you okay with
this or would your character not be okay
with this is this something that you and
Justin do all the time or is this just
like what the fuck justin i feel like
this is you know even though i don't
have as tie the bond with justin was
your character's name even again crocs
populous the mighty confident no i don't
really like pop up as much i feel like
we go it's dick remember yeah it stick
your short
I feel like me and jakey dick tosses me
around a lot pig tosser all right let's
start it throw them with info so i'm
going I'm going I'm rolling with it it's
how we end up with assigned names okay
um go ahead and throw Justin needs
you're just trying to throw him we're
here directly at the skeleton right this
skeleton that's next one two three four
five Devils doesn't make it he's through
he's flying through the air dead ones i
need to see if you can stick the landing
wait KidCo you can make the Nimbus save
me oh no you may actually use the Nimbus
to catch him ok I will try to do that ok
instead of rolling I need co2 role for
the Nimba night ok yeah use that name is
power baby uh 15 girl uh the Nimbus
cloud actually catches dead bones and
pushes him up right in front of the
skeletons yeah I love you knew you were
all right it is now Jake string ok what
is in my inventory what kind of
materials do I have um you have a sack
of gold you for a weapon of choice you
don't actually like weapons Jake I just
like to use your fists ok your fists do
not feel pain at this point you have
like no feeling in your hands yeah I'm
still tripping balls um and well no
you're coming off the trip but again
with no feeling in your hands you really
have a lot of pent-up sexual
frustrations as you find it really hard
sometimes to pleasure yourself talk
about it give himself to strangers at
once yeah never mind your sexual your
sexual tension is out there you have a
very good personal sex life because of
your no feelings in your hands um
besides I'm a bard I'm just a
natural-born panty dropper you have here
once my loot you have your loot for
Monica you have a burlap sack inside
your sack you have your marble
collection and you also collect
collectible elven figurines and I mean
because you're traveling guy you kind of
just carry your whole collection with
you are the kind of figurines that you
you know on no no they are not those
type of figurines at all but next
question is Nimbus flammable Nimbus is
not flammable No Deal well there goes my
plan all right well anyway I'm you're
allowed my burlap sack into the fire
with your collectible action figures
that would be very against your
character your character cares about
these action figures yeah jumping down
my shirt for a while so you're just
gonna you don't have it way yeah you
have a shirt okay and you're just going
to what cult like this is really aim to
your character Drake remember you really
care about these action figures you
really want to take them out of their
their bag too right right right I take
them out of the sack and put them in my
pocket for safekeeping okay that's fine
yep and you're gonna like the second
fire I want to light the sack on fire
and just lob it towards the skeletons
okay okay let go ahead and roll we need
it we need to talk about what not
throwing things when there's allies in
the way all right uh Jake goes to Jake
goes to throw his sack uh it lands about
here and there's just a bag on fire nice
look at that takes backpacks on fire
Jake you're now a little bit encumbered
but shake the sprinter with just in the
Sprinter just investment Jake so you can
only move four steps right now because
you now have to like waddle a little bit
with your action figures in gold and
everything you keep kind of in your
pockets you're actually hold you
actually there was one action figure
it's your it's the doll of your it's
your it's your precious one it resembles
your dad well it resembles Michael
Jackson who you think is your dad and
it's your most prized collection and you
don't want to put that in your pocket so
you're actually holding it in your hands
right now okay okay excellent what's it
made out of it's made out of plastic
okay good okay all right let me move
forward you can maybe like one or two
spaces forward after you've done that
all right let's move two spaces forward
here okay and I'm just trying to scope
out these skeletons to see if I can
fashion one into a weapon somehow
if I touch them you your come to life no
well you know maybe but anyway you
you're the type of person where you
don't actually prefer weapons you would
rather just truck people in the face
mind you when I'm saying you can punch
people the face you punch them for the
same amount of damage Roman does with
his hammer you are really big into
fisting so that yes that's a given um
maybe I could could I make brass
knuckles out of this gelding named sure
maybe you make me make so you're
probably pretty skilled and making
little things to power up your punches
yeah I think you could do that nice all
right I'd like to roll to try to make
you hand you are a child throwing your
sack Roman is your turn ok so in front
of me I have a flaming sack yeah cloud
and dead bones yeah yes so her twins
Roman hahaha which way you also have the
crazies you also have the Jews skeleton
bodies that are leg in front of you the
flaming sack maybe some rocks on the
ground there's these little fire pits in
the four corners of the room it's a
really wait wait what's that swastika
doing there that's the flaming sack oh
thank you so much for I just treat you
to it do I was just drawing an ex uh-huh
oh good there you go there's the sack oh
nice I see a sack races is that you for
deutschland oh they are you boat
blessing a strength okay yes the cast is
on dead bones okay sorry I'm gonna move
for wait one two three alright move
forward a little bit I'll be behind the
flaming sky to the side of the sack yeah
don't you just wanna be well you know
now you need to pick the phrase once the
guys Roman the phrase is peanut butter
jelly time so yeah butter jelly time
when you are attacking but so basically
when you roll when you have to roll the
dice you have to say peanut butter jelly
time if you do your damage will be done
the families okay if you forget to wrote
if you forget to say this you will miss
and he'll be like this this lasts until
we get out of combat yeah okay