all right let's get to digging all right
you guys one of the skulls and I'm gonna
break it in half so I can use it as like
a scoop I'm nice
can I pick up my flaming bag it's on
your head oh so it is so you guys you
guys are okay does anybody wanna watch
dad as he walks out or are you guys just
gonna you don't even care to see what I
would probably follow him
every two steps he takes I take one
because like I'm still waking up yeah I
need you to roll to see if you're
actually being sneaky or you trying to
be sneaky no no I'm not trying to be
sneaky I'm just following because I'm
tired okay just really just roll to make
sure that you're able to do it for me
I want to make sure that you're able to
to walk right now you're fine you can
walk after a couple steps here dad
notices and he turns around he says no
no you can't come with me right now I
need you to stay here dig out the tunnel
let me deal with these skeletons
I just chatted my teeth back at him sure
roll the chatter teeth you you roll you
were warned of this do you start
chattering your teeth and you like kind
of chip your front tooth it was actually
a veneer you had done and what I wasn't
really done well it wasn't done with
very good porcelain oh so you've now
chipped it that's gonna be quite
expensive dad walks up to you okay dad
walks up to you and gives you a hug that
is tender it's it's it's an okay it's an
okay hug but it also feels kind of
awkward because he's not really your dad
call dad and a man hug and he just so
well yeah and he whispers wait here for
me son he then turns to the skeletons
kay does some of those jaw clacking and
the fire goes out and it makes it
completely dark in the cave and he
starts walking to work
- dad what are you reading right now
wholly possible the rest the rest of you
besides dead bones is apparently doing
something should be looking at this dirt
wall and I'm resting bones no I mean
blinky but you know be great if somebody
could you know make this dirt smaller I
can only make things bigger dead bones
Orange dead bones you're probably trying
to rest to recover your stamina but at
this point the only thing you have is
apple juice and you don't have any
medical supplies so you're really having
a hard time getting any sort of resting
it out can only make things bigger bill
whatever your name is
so why I worked up a pretty serious
hunger from that battle so I I'm cooking
my my dead rat and a little spit that I
built on my shoulder roll roll to see
how well it cooks okay cool you'll be
able to tell if it's cooked all the way
through anyway you can slow cooking it
for 25 years well do you try to actually
cook it on top of your shoulder but you
actually it's not a very big flame it's
just kind of a little magically
enchanted fire it's not even that hot
you doesn't have to be Burt bothering
you so you noticing that it really isn't
cooking this rat at all and you're gonna
need a different fire source if you want
to cook it okay so I'm gonna I'm
actually babbles no bite of jerky that I
brought which requires no cooking okay
yep with that stop pulling things out of
my area wait would you say I'm just
gonna have a little bite of my jerky
okay sure
you uh you you bite the turkey it tastes
good
it doesn't really replenish you in any
way though you're just you're just like
this will top me off you you weren't
even that tired Roman you were you were
pretty good the only people we reach
they look really like jerky only Co is
kinda tired
everybody else is feel pretty third they
didn't they didn't lose a lot in that
battle can I take it
Inc about my apple juice sure yeah while
I remember Aaron I'm the good old days
I'm gonna make us some Sunny D yet so
pawpaws goes to take a sip of the apple
juice and realize that when he takes the
apple juice he actually see the memories
of Aaron and that's when he goes wait
where's Aaron and he doesn't even think
to ask nobody a union thinks to ask dad
what happened to Aaron
but dad's gone but at this point dad is
completely gone I miss dad
what's that all right - there were we
had a dad before we had a dad we had a
dad wait what if you got a hug what if
we make Randal you see you that I think
Randall is a very good dad dad yeah
cloud dad cloud
he saved me man save me so I don't do
you like some all right I'm still
digging away with my skull shovel go
ahead and roll thinking hey I'm rolling
yeah do you see if you finally broken
through some of the dirt wall here uh
no you're still just hacking away at
that dirt wall room and it's a lot
you're I'm kinda hoping that you have a
somebody comes up with a better solution
because it's gonna take you a while to
get through this the giant wall of or
you know if someone else helps
I'm totally gonna help I just want to
eat my rat first I'm typing it in the
corner fire over there Roma is the only
one currently dedicated to this
everybody else is kind of like relaxing
after the Battle of catching their
breath I'm kind of hugging this cloud 15
you successfully cooked the rat eight
would you like to eat it um I would like
to offer to share first okay everybody
it's it's a rat I mean if you want to
get a good meal only you are gonna be
able to eat it but I mean you could
probably share it with a couple people
oh I'll take a leg bone
you just ate some beef jerky yeah but
he's offering up rad know we had a rat
on the table as well ready for like 25
years
okay if you want to wait a while
jerkin really take that long Co no as
anybody else want to uptake co-op and
his offer to share the rant I want some
rant okay
I mean if there's any rat left over all
right you're gonna be sucking on the
home Justin yeah we already do you my
dad okay but you can have the wishbone
though yeah join me glad brother alright
Co Roman and dead bones I'll share the
rat and talking about good things yeah
the Reds not bad it's kind of flavorless
kind of really tough um but but it helps
you know what makes dead bones feel
slightly better Mexico feels like even a
little bit better he's just happy that
he actually successfully cooked things
shared it with his brothers and they
liked it so I'm ready to dig blinky I
didn't really like the rat I was just
trying to be polite I mean it's it was
fine
it's freaking rad it's Jesus he's been
through a lot okay he's why did he have
the rat in the first place are you
kidding me I don't know I'll never
understand it actually Co I need you to
roll the see if you can hear this
conversation okay bro let's see if his
feelings hurt Co you can hear the
conversation but you don't want to
really make a big deal out of this so
you really don't you're just like I can
hear you guys but I'm just not gonna
same also also that's not getting any of
the next rat that's fun right
you know the helmets really for next rat
I find well you know what dad always
said about him he was the specialist of
all wait what a clouds eat alright I
want to go back to the glass I need
anything alright so here so right now we
have Roman digging at the wall dad is
just run off Paz is coming the
realization the ball is drinking this
juice that he doesn't know where Aaron
is so at some point like posit you're
gonna bring this up do you not want to
remind your buddies what's what is your
mental process of being like you know
what the hell's it we're doing our
little where did the little brother Co
disturbing your sister nation right now
honestly I'm gonna keep it inside right
now because that little fucker was
really rude to me at first that sounds
like no no no he just he doesn't want to
cause any anger he's yeah he's really
not sure do you guys are digging I don't
want to distract do you trust dad pause
do you still trust Cormac and why are
you hugs I feel I feel kind of love but
it was that awkward tip is awkward yeah
okay I don't know still trust dad so
yeah it's kind of a bro hug it wasn't
like really heartfelt felt loved well
now you guys have the problem of you
need to get through that wall or you
need to follow up dad there's no other
ways out of here you got to decide to
either figure out how to get through
this wall or go down the other hallway
hey I should look for some tools or
something is there anything around
alright I'm just gonna run at it really
fast can I do that now Jake's Jake's
through before you can say Jake's just
like now I got to try this Jake blitzes
through the wall of dirt just powers
through it with his face running into
the next room when Jake when Jake when
the dust settles of Jake smashing
through this wall the entire thing just
collapses by the way so Roman and co can
see what's happening tons of beautiful
mermaids they're all just like giggling
and and you know beckoning over towards
Jake just yeah he's not gonna believe
what I'm freakin mine in in the corners
of the room Jake and also because the
distinct smell smell some of those great
mushrooms so wait wait wait wait wait
wait wait is that Randall right there
where is your cloud remember why you
trying to make me sad
do I want to take a mushroom or give one
I want to go well that that is so combat
hasn't started you get but you other
guys have to be careful walking forward
don't take big steps okay because
there's people we don't know about yet
Jake Jake should be in front of everyone
though cuz he wat walked into this room
yeah and you're all gonna follow Jake
after seeing the wall fall apart
although I didn't walk yeah yes Jake
blasted through the doors baking the
opening we got I heroically sprinted
into the room so the mermaids are
there's there's what can see you guys
can you come into the room you can see
mushrooms in the corner but again dad
warned you about these mushrooms you
gotta be really careful handling them
but you can also see these really pretty
mermaids I mean pretty by mermaid
standard they're green skin but you're
dwarfs I mean there's all sorts of green
down with it's totally fine
and they are just beckoning you one of
them is doing the AH blowjob motion like
these are very sexual yeah these are
very sexual mermaids beckoning you over
towards this little water and lot water
enclosed a part of the room to all of
your left you can see another one of
those walls and pause can pause can't
actually see it but Justin can see it
and knows that it looks identical to the
previous wall from the other hallway
that the skeletons were guarding alright
guys guys I'm thinking okay there's five
mermaids huh we kicked dead bones out of
the group say to me that you'll eat a
mushroom I'll bind you to a mushroom and
then eat it so you will eat a mush yeah
yes Robin we can go houses you see what
I did yeah you're a cheater I'm a
cheater yeah your cheer all right Roman
it's Randall to move the money over to
Justin's or hand
I'm okay cool inky I'm cool with the
spit rolls are you you handle pot
alright alright
twins forever man we come as a set wait
come here mate sit on your face yes okay
so don't like it this it's like being
waterboarded how you doing Justin the
Nimbus cloud has pushed this mushroom
towards you I will happily eat it you're
gonna just reach down and pick up the
mushroom they poked you do a save it for
later no just eat the whole mush I mean
if cloud dad whoa yeah they don't
actually understand you've never
explained what read I don't even know if
they know it's Randall honestly they
just know it's a cloud and it just keeps
puffing in and out of existence and you
just have like a peer push this mushroom
towards just an England ooh a mushroom
cloud that by the way I'm very sad that
you guys didn't get to explore this joke
if you mouse over it I purposely
labelled them earlier poisonous and not
poisonous that way when you I was really
hoping cuz Rome was the type of guy who
would figure that it would be like
Chanukah till robbed but I thought you
meant like red versus purple I didn't
actually mouse over it no why would you
guys have not moused over and clearly
see yeah I I knew Roman would do that so
it's just like a whole we've gotta trick
him he's gonna crab a poison must you
ever not even know it thinking he's so
cover but with Justin or he said he's
gonna eat it right yeah Justin's gonna
eat it doesn't half of it go ahead and
give it a Justin okay you reach down you
don't even need to eat after that you
just kind of eat a little bit of it but
it's just really rejuvenating like you
just feel
fantastic after eating that mushroom is
great and then you save the rest for
later putting in your Bobby
that one was labeled poison though yeah
I know it's it's just because so if you
mess the trick you cuz if you mouse over
it like when that's hidden you he's
making us think I'm making you the the
the mouse over factor does not
necessarily mean that could be poison
could not be a poison which way did I
label it alright should just assume that
all mushrooms are poisoned yeah ma'am
unless you're a trained mycologist can I
sing a song to the mermaids um are you
trying to put them to sleep or just
serenade just want to chill with them
are you are you gonna move up close like
how are you gonna do it yeah just do it
from here how do you want to yeah I
think I'd rather do it from the safe
distance so that they can't grab me with
their like tail things if they are so
you think I'm a Cygnus song of blowjobs
yeah let me let me think I got I can
think up some verses um-hmm
well okay so huh ready here we go
mermaid mermaid answer me this how do
mermaids take a piss you squat or do you
stand do you dig a hole in the sand
thank you the the mermaids all swim off
and just miss the water they are bad
news you guys gotta trust me I want to
push Jake in I wanna make them follow
them put a ring on it and then next
thing you know there's like all these
mermaid babies swimming around it's it's
just a mess guys they spawn like
seriously you can't have mermaid babies
in the mouth got no love for mermaids
combat has now started so Commodus comet
is now started we just ended Jake's turn
the mermaids resurface
immediately spitting acid towards Jake
yes that would have burned jawed they
looks like they do they were pen looks
like they convened maybe they were
trying to trap you maybe they weren't
either way at this point they want you
out of their mushroom cave before you
can steal any of their mushrooms clearly
and so they're all on just on the edge
of the water here these for spitting
acid this one is still moving into place
so I'm just going to roll for for things
to spit towards Jake one mrs. - mrs. so
six yeah yeah cat-like barred reflexes
yeah just you're reacting oh one one
hits Jake and singes right through his
loot man oh just it's not gonna have the
same sound it's gonna have a little bit
more whistle one more at Jake
this one doesn't hit Jake instead misses
but hits dead bones right sorry special
boots yeah
all right it is now bah bah bah bah
Romans turn okay do I see all this
happened you use everybody saw
everything except for Justin who was
eating the mushroom but when it also
when the when the poi spit started
happening he turned and was like whoa is
that the mushroom or is this happening
okay so if there's just like a like a
little lake a little river it's it's
clear you clearly it's a little lake it
doesn't go further out this is the edge
of the cave but it clearly must be kind
of deep as when they went down there for
a couple you know like a couple minute a
minute or two they seem to go they seem
to just completely disappear and then
come back so you're starting to think
maybe underground chasm maybe there's
another way out into an ocean or
something but clearly they have some
other where place to go other than just
being located here okay what does the
ceiling above the lake look like uh what
do they called stags lights little like
sides lake lights lots of
stones like tanks everywhere in the came
with his version everywhere Heights
select leg sites everywhere the cave all
coming down very spiky don't throw
anybody okay so perhaps if we had some
kind of explosion like thing we could
have slag heights fall down from the
ceiling yep okay some kind of earthquake
sort of thing yeah terraform what's your
turn I know I'm just you know thinking
out loud here you're thinking out loud
yeah thinking out loud uh okay so how
far away am i you're close enough that
you get to this clip this one right here
all right now with my holy water does
that just like lock up in place pull it
up for me
throw a flask of holy water at the
target within five spaces if the
flat-six you may prevent that target
from doing an action attack or booths
dead so basically what you're gonna do
is if you hit something with the holy
water Roman the next time I try to do
something for that person you can
interrupt me and say do something else
and then you may suggest what to do and
honestly I'll probably listen to your
suggestion as long as it's reasonable um
you can only you can only do it to a
single action but the unholy water
effect will last until at least combat
breaks okay I'm gonna throw a holy water
at the closest mermaid okay you toss a
file of a holy water and it splashes her
hitting her right in the face and yeah
it's gonna stay still okay does it do
basically basically lets room and get a
slight form of mind control
what makes yeah it makes it so he can
prevent that person from killing someone
essentially right they can't do
something we got a friend he can make
her a friendly well he'd just make it so
she's not going to do whatever very
dangerous thing she
was about to do and it's gonna be this
one okay Co what is your train
oh let's see what can I do you here
alright I'm going to summon my little
buddy yeah does this count as a one move
or a to move that's fine you can do that
you're gonna move to mushroom towards
them
yeah Randall's gonna offer them a
mushroom peace offering peace off Thomas
II okay yep I like it yeah and do I have
to do an action just before finding out
whether that matter like Randall's
things you can do at any time he can
just move things if it's something a
very that needs to be rolled they would
roll but moving a mushroom that's fine
okay you just push the Randall just push
the mushroom over okay and then I'm
gonna meditate okay co immediately goes
into his meditative state it is now
Devlin sister I'm just I'm just gonna
back up a bit it's gonna go over as far
as I can go so here okay and yeah I'm a
crack shot with a slingshot okay so I'm
gonna try and beam this one in the face
being here in the face yeah okay so and
that thing more often last by right the
peanut butter jelly bullshit yes yeah I
don't even know if ever cup well no
because I didn't use another attack 60
good job headphones 16 alright you pink
her in the face she falls into the water
you can't see her anymore you hit her
for three damage very good dead bones
pause it's now your turn
poisons being spit slingshots are going
off Justin just ate a mushroom Cogan on
the ground to start meditating Jake was
playing songs the performance did not go
well I thought it was good but if I was
if I was
J yeah I heard those are phenomenal what
do you want to do Paz oh let's see guys
are talked about earthquakes I have do I
should do this earth right here but you
know what let me move on I'm gonna move
up five spaces okay cam my five spaces
one two three four five what can be
distracted by the motion okay
and I'm gonna try not one you're gonna
mount a mermaid
Danny's Raider all right first off pause
you're not next to the mermaid this is
gonna be quite a leap this is why I'm
gonna do it okay out that Murr me this
is one of those could really backfire
and you end up dying type of things
oh boy okay pause tries to leap on a
mermaid I don't want to play this out
with your average above average roll
alright y'all gonna let it happen okay
you jump on this mermaid right here
you're you're not able to fully like
grab ahold of her you kind of just jump
on her shoulders and you're kind of like
Wibbly and wobbly you don't have her
fully under your control yet see you
like kind of kick you know she's well
she's splashing but yes you stay kicking
kick it's here so so you're gonna have
to you have to take another turn to like
rein her in as you're not gonna be able
to really do your normal turns just yet
on top of her back that's fine
can i I'm in the middle of rollers I'm
kind of like get her to control you know
yep she's resisting really hard you're
still on her back right now but your
next turn you're still gonna have to try
and spend my time dominating her okay
it's not the mermaids turn so the
mermaid on your back is gonna try and
throw you off into the water
she can't get you off her back so you're
hearing that the other two mermaids come
and start to grapple onto you so this
first one's gonna try and grab you
trying to pull you into the water that
was a terrible I was a terrible role she
fails yes shoot you're too slippery to
Wiley the other mermaid tries to grab as
well but she can only get one hand on
you from the side and one hands not
enough she's just--she's now this
mermaids now pulling on your hand so
like she's got you by the arm and she's
grabbing you okay nice this mermaid is
going to try and spit acid at Roman the
one that I threw stuff and one you threw
stuff at stop all right this mermaid is
gonna run away oh I got you said I got a
suggestion
do you got a good suggestion Roman yeah
I'm gonna have him spit acid at the
other one of the other two mermaids
okay the mermaids not gonna do that you
have to suggest something that's not
reasonable the mermaid wouldn't do that
just know when you suggest something I
don't necessarily have to do it I just
have to not basically do what I was
originally trying to do so for your
suggestion she wouldn't do it a half it
has to be a suggestion that the very
least I can agree her character would do
it reasonable it has to be a reasonable
suggestion okay those are those are
gills I've seen this guy is gonna try
and swim over to eat the mushroom okay
yep that's fine we're gonna roll the
remember he's gonna swing to try and eat
the mushroom
are you kidding me right now the mermaid
eat the mushroom ha
Roma came to this room specifically no
mushrooms the mermaid is now you know
much very regenerated stuff your flask
has no more effect on her regardless
she's feeling good she didn't really
take any damage but she's not under any
stress anymore like her she's been
reinvigorated from also hear from you
mister I'm gonna jump on a mermaid okay
hey Mandy at the roller lecture we gave
him many roles to fall off in the water
and he avoided them all so you know
together he's a high roller then you can
make the dangerous plates Justin it is
now your turn that's all the mermaids
yes
alright do I have any ranged weapons
Justin all you carry on you normally is
another bag of mushrooms completely
separate to the ones that's Dave but
these are only poisonous mushrooms
that's JIT that is really the only thing
you have you had a backpack you've left
it in town so you're right now all you
have right now is your mushrooms for for
a weapon though Justin you have like
this little board with two nails in it
and dad gave it to you so you know it's
not a great weapon for some reason you
still use it