all right I'm gonna I'm gonna toss a
poison mushroom towards the mermaids
what the ones in your bag okay yeah yeah
I just where the god rather if the last
boss this isn't our dad I'm going to
really piss 17 all right you throw a
mermaid throw a mushroom at the mermaid
this mermaid apparently has such an
effect fashion with mushrooms she
actually goes and catches it in her
mouth just just she sees you you're just
like hey yo hey you want this you
through it she goes she catches in her
mouth delicious negates the effects of
the previous my sure you can train them
alright negates our she trippin balls
now um she's probably about star
tripping balls but the mushrooms kind of
just have like an counteractive effect
this justin's poisons questions are much
more poisonous than normal so it's about
to kick in but right now she's not
trippin that's a slow about the drum
yeah it's a slow it's a slow reaction
for her Jake is your turn your
performance not go well last turn all
right well spiraled out of control so
I'm gonna use disguise okay yep and now
I am totally a sexy horny mermaid right
roll your dice oh good ma'am glad we
could play this with one hand okay okay
uh so uh Jake you try to make big do
with a mermaid um you you know that you
won't be able to talk to the other two
mermaids but you suspect because you've
seen what Justin's mushrooms can do that
even though you don't have the proper
materials to make this great disguise
you think you can play it off and
convince this this girl that you're also
a mermaid hey honey I'm I'm totally a
hot mermaid let's river tail things
together oh maybe are seashells we're
gonna see if mermaids like doing that
Jake is going to just randomly try to
rub tails with the mermaids mermaids no
almost mermaids do not like rubbing your
tails she kind of finds it quite odd but
she's starting to trip so she doesn't
really know what to make of it she's
just like what were we doing
is there any more mushrooms kinda uh
Jake dinner if you guys run maybe she'll
be distracted and I can just totally
love that with this mermaid forever you
can't even scissor I don't understand
why what was your proposition say that
again we can flop together we can flop
or tails together well yeah but what you
want her to leave so you can do it you
wanted to tell the other uselessly run
so very runs this place me to the life
of terrible sexual satisfaction with my
mermaid sisters look okay okay so Jake
is currently distracting one of the
mermaids who is that live the very least
not attacking and it's perplexed by Jake
here right now as long as nobody puts
any pressure on this mermaid she will
probably at the very least be entranced
until Jake fucks up again okay um what
do you mean again I'm a misunderstood
artist Roman is now your turn okay jack
off you turtle right I know I that can
be you didn't even be the weirdest thing
that would happen s room you guys having
fun watching us hmm no cuz I like it
when you in both enjoy it and obviously
one of them doesn't it okay so two
mermaids still trying to grandpas uh
Jake's trying to Las out with the other
mermaid but she's kind of like a
remember there's a rumor mill centrally
distracted 3y a copepod on one pauses on
one right now yeah okay uh I'm going to
sprint okay so the plan is for you
sprint and kind of go towards closer to
the middle of the room so I don't want
to like run along are you sprinting or
youtube moving five steps well you're
gonna use your turn to make it run for
it ah yeah I'm just straight up pollen
ass get haul ass okay roll for it
normally you can move five and how far
do you want to go here
all right you can haul ass we all into
in this ish area this good oh yeah I'm
kind of going like oh here for running
okay are you trying to make a run for it
I'm getting the hell out of here okay
freaking mermaid you can go here that
they're distracted I'm out all right so
Romans going to make a run for it Jake
doesn't notice this pause probably sees
it but he's kind of distracted the rest
you all know that Roman is definitely
making a run for the exit of the room
here for me right yeah this is
meditating yako is meditating so it is
now ko's turn this is number two so next
turn co will be when you get to do your
triple tertiary what were you starting
to draw there I was just doing the lines
12 yeah I don't want to look like a
swastika to be homeless god you guys
beginning shut up dead dead bones it is
now your turn all right so ass I see
Rome and all nasan like ya know that's
prime make sense I'm gonna move up to
five spaces catch up okay right that's
you that makes is your brother hey twin
stick together man we gotta bond wait
are you guys twins yeah right delicate
twins robbers that you use it difficult
wins yeah we're identical twins okay
dainik coins alright so how much my
what's the range of my own enlarge um
you knew from five spaces you can hit
pause pause all right I want to
specifically in large pauses ass all
right okay what to as big as I can make
you just i'm doing a crush up or is that
for grip it's the crush the Murphy we at
least make it like Nicki Minaj sighs
please no I'm making as big as I
possibly can this is this is a 20 mile
of shit that's like a JLo at least all
right pause dunks the pause becomes very
very big balls home runs very fast
becomes even larger as he's enlarging
and he just sees Leonard he just
flattens the mermaid into the water
pause is now kind of standing in the
water because he just squeezed full he
sat on the mermaid and he kind of like
got up he's like standing on top of the
one mermaid and had to have damaged them
I know it very much did you
were basically are drowning this mermaid
as you were standing on her head the
other two are thrown back from your
transformation state here wait my
routine ground round here for me sure
yeah absolutely drowned crushing her
throat you can get it is jeez get he's
crushed she's standing running her
throat Shakira like that she's standing
he's standing on the gills he's he's
suffocating her that would be okay i
will accept that suffocating her yep yep
he's crushing her with his feet and
large ask his ass actually still drags
on the ground so I just want to make
sure it's not going completely off the
rails here yep she Oded notes oz is a
snorkel does my ass look big at this
leaf no no it's fine you're beautiful
pause you're no longer able to mount her
anymore you were far too big but it is
your turn the two other mermaids are
scared crap to scare the crap and you
know that you are completely just
crushing this third reason you know what
aspect was here's what I'm thinking
right we FSU imma bring an earthquake it
has to take more of xtina's I'm bigger
too right uh yep absolutely yeah so
you're gonna create for tremors do we
have any one of those dirts Utley them
i'll just use something else i'm gonna
create for little tremors are you trying
to do this in the water pause I need to
know where your tremors are gonna be
weird to water in the water just all
around these mermaids are like on
capellini Jake might get hurt hit but I
don't care I mean you might get it no
you can aim these things pause oh can I
yeah you can tell me where the for like
point at the four spaces you want these
earthquake things to hit well obviously
there okay we'll try one they're dead
they're okay one they're dead they're on
this drop okay one on the one that
Jake's distracting yeah okay yep my
little steam to take like I don't want
dead bones okay yeah man so this place
ass is gonna be like the epicenter of
this earth like this yes the help this
is the biggest work of all time the Omni
torque all right roll for this
earthquake all right this earthquake is
nuts uh stalactites start falling
everywhere in the cave everyone else
everyone has to do
oldest air dodging these Roman roll yes
you were running these things are
falling the entire cave is shaking
German enrollment think Roman doesn't
get hit dead bones you actually have one
coming up on top of you so you're
actually rolling to dodge the earthquake
right underneath your feet Devils
doesn't dodge it he takes to damage dead
bones is thrown back there's a desert
like the ground just opens up here like
a spike comes out just hits dead bones
we're going to do these two mermaids
first this mermaid just gets completely
like a the earthquake kind of trembles
her but a slight that comes just
Pierce's her right through the stomach
and she just sinks to the bottom you
can't see that mermaid anymore this
mermaid tries to run immediately from
the the earthquake and she just goes
right under the water you guys can still
see her but she's dived under the water
this one that's right next to Jake Jake
do you want to try and dodge it away or
maintain your disguise I'm kind of
enjoying this right now okay Jake's
gonna try and keep it almost there guys
oh he's keeping today all right
unfortunately another earthquake spike
comes up and pierces through let's say
her left arm so she's got she's got a
stunts he's got a little piece of Earth
that came up from the earthquake just
cut her did for damage um she's still
kind of tripping tho but she's now in
more of a panic trip like she's freaking
out at this point she really doesn't
know what's going on this mermaid is
just completely going bonkers out of her
mind co and Justin I need you to try and
roll if you're gonna dodge wait how can
Co dodge yeah Oh cocaine complicated
with me here I need to roll no I
interrupt my yes I just wait I need a
roll we're gonna see if anything hits co
then chose not dodging we're just gonna
see if ending hits go so it's like an
ante rule nothing has co luckily just
rocks are falling down doesn't interrupt
his
meditations and then Justin are you
gonna try and dodge yeah oh yeah I'm
gonna roll Justin's gonna go and do a
barrel roll alright Justin you get to do
a barrel roll and if you want to you can
pick up and eat this mushroom head flip
okay guy just pick up and stash it my
pockets sure you can pick up this a
poison mushroom luckily you pick it up
with a glove so you're totally fine and
you stand you put this poison mushroom
into your pocket you mushroom collector
you that's great uh and you land right
in front of Jake and the mermaid she
doesn't notice you but at least puts you
in position to help Jake if he needs it
ok nice moves Pepe yeah if it's in a
three way you still have a move if you
want to get out of the water cuz at this
point you're standing and you're so tall
that the water only comes up to like
your knees this is a sweat his ass is
side yeah can I ok here's not taking
right can I turn around and try and
force a shit out on the mermaid uh no
that would be your action you were to
get earthquake this turn ah man well
then I'm fine with my ass being in the
water ok it's the shit that ball doesn't
isn't there a chance the earthquake just
flung it out uh this mermaid is gonna
come up and try and grab her sister no
rudeness the Clery that one she's going
to cry and grab her friend and pull her
under the water she is successful these
two mermaids are just on the water you
can still see them but they are the
mermaids at this point are clearly
trying to escape this other mermaid is
going to try and push paws off her but
that's very unlikely what is it alright
this mermaid using your inner strength
just tosses paws off of her paws lands
over
here she takes minor damage and then
rather positives minor damage and then
she swings over to also start moving out
with her sisters were they not try and
grab Jake if the costume is so
convincing I mean they these two have
already already underwater this one just
started to swim away towards the
direction of the sisters at this point
it's becoming very clear to anyone
looking at the mermaids mermaids are
just trying to leave hey there just like
we the mermaids play game plan here kids
was they just want to steal a human
maybe feast on in one of these Dwarfs
you know lure him over some blowjobs
luckily Jake blew that with this song
and at this point they just they just
want fuck out um it is now Justin's turn
just like I just wanted for new bomb hi
this is my turn again yeah that remember
that was your dodge roll that wasn't
actually what you did you were dodging
but you rule the 20 so you get to pick
up a mushroom all right the two mermaids
are still in front of you they're in
range that you could attack them but
they have now just gone on over the
water okay just cheat am I yeah I think
too I don't need one right I'm full I've
had my fill of mushrooms of the day Oh
Marshall I'll toss you mushroom if you
want it do it I'll since she was China's
now hey wow I thrown away or overthrow
just like a tiny little thing alright uh
you throw the mushroom pause catches it
pause doesn't need right away he just
catches in his hand runner this is
really tiny four paws I just like to buy
oh yeah diggity her thumb yeah just like
well thanks man he paused actually we
catches it crushes it a little bit but
it's fine in thanks dude butchered balls
later no problem I'm gonna use my spaces
to going out with cloud that okay okay
Jake the mermaid who you were seducing
was just pulled under by her sister
there's another mermaid who's not
really she hasn't really looked at you
she's just trying to get away that's all
you though you're still in your cheek
disguised as a mermaid you can draw
attention to this mermaid if you want
but she's in a panic running for a life
after the man that who jumped on her
tried to straddle her then multiply it
inside and crushed her almost
suffocating her so she's she's a little
bit freaked out yeah i think these
mermaids are done with us hey Justin do
you think I'm sexy oh yeah I come over
here for a little bit I ain't even
finish before just kidding let's let's
book out of here all right huh sprint
jake t cells guys Jake's making a run
for it now running let's do this uh-huh
okay give me a better role that's not a
rule I don't do a better role right
there's me 17 all right where did you
want to sprint to Jake are you catching
up to your friends are you just making a
book as close to the wall as possible
okay go all the way right up to the wall
here you're good yeah whoo all right
Roman it's all you the main roads are in
retreat okay um I'm gonna swing by grab
a whole mushroom that I see over here
and then make my way into into the way
into the darkness yep so prove that
apparently i still can't see even though
i'm looking directly at it okay it's
really dark so you're you're are you
joining to turn it one two three four
five you'll be able to do this without
sprinting okay yeah give it a roll to
pick up the mushroom okay I just want to
grab it and go I don't need to eat it
okay eight all right yeah it you grab
the mushroom it was poisonous but thanks
to your dad's advice you take note it's
not going to poison you you're just
holding on to the mushroom and you make
a blitz into this room revealing an
empty hallway and I know that it's
poisonous yeah you can clearly tell like
your dad was warning you and it's just
like dinna this one's purple this one's
not and even though you haven't tasted
it yourself you've paid a little bit of
attention to the effects on your your
group here one that's Lucy
that one's of generating yeah the
mermaids are just about to retreat koh
is just about 2am kozub aight guys i go
alright go you have awakened go you have
awakened from your state of meditation
and you may take three turns all at once
the mermaids are about to retreat you
can do whatever you want with this turn
man you should really go to hell that
fat ass shit I see the mermaids turn it
a run is it diagonal mousse or do we
have to move like it doesn't matter you
have 15 moves if you want so you can get
home pretty much all close as you want
Colin's right three terms of once co is
what you get to do right here's what to
do I'm going to raise pillars up from
underneath of them under the water and
try to fling them back out three
separate pillars a pillar for each a
lady I like this is fun okay I like this
yeah this would be fun there's pillar
number one on this one the top one okay
uh eight okay yep she gets thrown right
here on to the side she doesn't taking
the damage it just shifts her out of the
water she's now flopping on land all
right pillar number two the one right
below her yeah she also comes flopping
out right onto lamb and the last one
that one misses that one is mine pops up
around here and use my final couple
moves to hide behind pause this guy an
ass all right at this point no it's that
Minister Deb bones is your turn
definitely possible more turn yeah we
got one more turn yeah what a swastika
doing here what is well let's do it I
forget what that is though I get a move
out of the time I'm gonna that was
something that that was a thing
something it was okay the rest of the
swastika that's why it's all filled our
key bad Carmen pass your dead bones oh
okay so pause cows the big ass
earthquake tried to kill me okay
after I just gave him and watch you
again I gave you a beautiful ass and
clearly you don't appreciate it so I'm
going to punish you by using honor
chance go I just want to let you know
that doing that you just a lot out of
you okay goes for Spillers me stamina
each so you basically use a third of
your life force I kind of like below
half your you're starting to get a
little bit tired just to keep that in
mind okay okay so I am chaining pause to
this mermaid here let me see Helena
Jane's shack up the two targets a lot of
change which can be anchored to a third
so you're both mermaids to pause both
mothers to pause pause is the anchor
yeah all right um remember you can break
you'll be able to break these chains at
any time if you say no if we say that we
rake them I can I'm gonna malice I'm not
a paladin oh right only rover can break
them only you you can do this so I'm
gonna use my five moves to catch up with
Roman I need to do the role to make sure
it's successful okay well that's on a
roll good been 19 but I'm not gonna take
that all right both of these bland
mermaids are now chained to pause um and
those chains cannot be broken and any
damage dealt them yeah Stan the mermaids
mermaids have understand this concept
it's just kind of like when you hit by
the honor chain you can tell that doing
something would hurt so if they attack
pause in any way they would be hurting
themselves if any way but remember if
anyone hurts the mermaids at this point
you'll also hurt yourself when mermaids
can't be hurt you have to have Roman
break it if Roman ever says the word in
character you can reference it Roman as
long as you're not a character if you
say the word happiness you will break
the and when i finish walk up your eyes
I said turn Dinky's good just don't say
it just just leaving for punishing
fordable you have paws you're now the
anchor to tool and mermaids um mind you
that while you have no problem dragging
them around right now when you shrink
back to your normal size it's going to
be a lot of work dragging two fully
grown mermaids around they they each
weigh a good
I don't know 90 pounds hey Roman sup if
you say that word i'll buy you a game on
steam are you Brett are you prior to
giving real life are you refusing real
life money for the game world boss
dishonorable that's very dishonorable
yeah it has to be that specific one it
can't be a variation of it right yeah
okay so I need my say like I gotta you
know it's my dick your phone yeah that
wouldn't do okay you have to whisper you
by the way you have to whisper you don't
we get this business / to whisper oh and
that's how it breaks it's like it echo
by saying it that quietly it's like the
Chico something just happened I what oh
well jumpin so Tasha things okay I pulse
your timeline can I roll to see how loud
I saw yep is this your turn yes okay
it's for dad as well uh you go to sigh
but because of your newfound sighs you
actually don't really know how to
control the volume of your voice really
well so you just go and it's like not
even audible to you it's pretty pathetic
basically nobody's mace no laws yet
nobody's realized your discomfort in the
situation and everything's he's mine
died he's fine but that's it poss okay
this mermaid swims away combat is now
over these mermaids actually ask they
just start begging for their lives they
just start begging if you break these
chains they will just leave please just
just let us go we can sell them Roman we
can sell them on the black that's not
what i was at well i was thinking
something a little more short-term no we
get the bj's we were promised this acid
you don't want to put your dick in that
well if they do then i will say the
words i'll be stuck there forever yeah
but you won't have a dick let's meet at
it it doesn't mean that's all it's in
their mouth hey but they can still do it
they'll trick you don't do it don't
I know it's tempting but don't do it I
omeka you don't want to fuck a gift
mermaid in the mouth it's stolen oh good
he will just sell the other color
because birthday Jake Jake you're the
one who wanted to seduce these mermaids
what do you think of the idea of
seducing them again honestly I'm the
only one who got any from the mermaids
and it was kind of booze kind of fun the
tail slapping was there anything other
than mouth like some secret orifice we
don't know but jqj Kenny we're gonna
roll for Jake's knowledge of what he
learned about the mermaids when he was
tail flipping them oh my god Wow all
right uh in Jake's and Jake scientific
spritz and Jake's knowledge of mermaid
he actually has studied these in the
past that's why he was so originally
attracted to him he's just always wanted
to be with the mermaid it's his lifelong
goal in some ways to mate with a mermaid
mermaids do have small compartments
where they keep their eggs located in
front in a very squishy area mermaids do
not accuse do not want to get a blowjob
from a mermaid they can't really control
the poison in their mouth really well it
would not be pleasant it would just burn
mermaids do not have buttholes they poop
another mouth what was nothing each
other kissing me to fuck you that don't
do happen so do anything Jake Daly
military now Jake does all this jake are
you gonna share this information with
your friends I I have no choice I mean
those those definitely aren't gills as
loud at first no so the only really
thing are the shells by the way Jake was
right they don't even come off they look
like they're like like little booby
things they're actually part of the
mermaids body Jake was right originally
still get a shell job I mean I mean you
can't really I mean you're really two
shells push against your wiener this is
some pretty broad there's a tiny bit of
skin I mean have you relished
season I want to rub my dick against all
Jake knows that is what's Jake Jake's
now basically shared all this
information and I would assume Jake your
best bet would be to let the mermaids go
and but Jake does mention that cooked
mermaids are very very tasty we got food
they wait they're like cod so I can also
mention um what I suggest is that we
take them along with us and swing them
on the chains and then whisper penis
just the right moment so then they
become projectile what no I don't like
that idea is gonna keep himself or you
like the idea of keeping them yeah I
want to keep them as pets I'm really
named them they have names guys you
gotta keep in mind though that pause has
no problem maintaining this now but when
the enlarged wears off these mermaids
will you know be kind of key left you'll
need some help pulling the chains
basically that's okay John I was like a
later problem yeah I just I should carry
them over to the fire so that we can eat
them because I'm really hungry like oh
it's not right not enough for you
asshole like come on yet very big all
right go what if we kill one and keep
one as a pet I'm okay with that okay
it's compromised also Jake are they do
they have any parts that are awake
anything well if we kill one it goes
through to pause yeah that's fine yeah
pause would take severe damage you can't
attack either of them without breaking
the chains or no but you killed both
mermaid Oh the only way to brave it oh
okay because if you do it if you do
damage uh dealt to the tired the only
takes exactly I can kill it and it
caused in the mermaid would be fine Jake
if you release them on land are they
able to move um they flop around pretty
good but uh unless they can flop their
way to the water they're gonna dry out
in about an hour so so they're not gonna
get away then or at least we didn't kind
of keep them wrangled yeah they're
pretty they're pretty uh pretty stable
in place I mean those legs those pins
are not made for walking armor me it's
rare yeah how are they the real worlds
that James eggs the expert man yeah
we're okay look 20 expert um
what if you want me to tell them I
always can because you are the expert
but you explain what she's right we
hailed from the mountain home so it's
it's very unlikely that we have seen any
mermaids in our time in the caves mom so
to me there like 10 out of 10 rare but
like I'm a dumbass I'm a dumbass dwarf
like living in it in a mountain he said
10 attend that's mom that's really rare
have you think that you heard any any
songs full of folksy knowledge about
mermaids and your travels um I've come
across a few um might might be able to
put something together here real quick
don't forget that your loot is whistling
now for something yep unfortunately okay
okay we're gonna take a break we're
gonna take a break is this Vince oh god
we are two rooms in to the first I i was
playing this stuff on a mic man these
guys could probably get through all this
stuff for three hours and then we never
get anywhere in like it's fine man it
was like wanna beat everything no no
it'sit's fits good either way um we're
gonna begin I can't wait to eat a
mermaid yeah I'm straight it's gonna be
delicious do you guys want to keep one
as a pet do you guys want to take our
longer break right now how long he'll
let you guys wanted to go Jake I'd be
good no longer break yeah yeah I'm gonna
be screaming for the next like uh 18
hours quote my own so so what I'm I'm
cool to go as long as you guys Oh what
we'll do is we'll take a half-hour break
here we'll come back at ten o'clock
eastern so just on the hour here I'll
put on some of Jake's awesome music me
and when me and Jake get back here from
our quick little break we're going to go
through and show you guys some ignorant
and we're gonna come right back to maybe
finish the first dungeon maybe um signs
are pointing to not so we'll be we'll be
back pretty soon I mean Jake reported
back in the next 15 or 20 but then when
we start this DD thing it'll be probably
on the hour so a quick little break I
hope you
are enjoying the show and we'll see you
guys in a bit