[Music]
all right now we are back the the group
has now traveled to Pope and Slayer here
I'll let you guys dish up the cards
sorry chef cards men working on it oh
really yeah this is mine just Scrabble
your cards there oh my laughs there's no
really good way to do this type of stuff
like move the cards in between rounds
it's always really rough on the aisle
you just find a better way to move them
from round around do you guys have a lot
of your abilities anybody missing some
all right so on your way to hear what
happened to dad and Aaron they wait dad
just took off dad again
yeah yeah dad Aaron was on dad shoulders
yeah you saw him go into here but he's
kind of disappeared everybody
he really was dead then he just stole
everything so watching Aaron had to go
so we're gonna keep going but
unfortunately it seems that Aaron and
dad have disappeared extra car do you
have Evert you steal cars now no
somebody serious there's somebody made
this dead bones this yours I have one
already everyone got one okay good
can I steal Aaron's cards no you can't
we don't know where it is
Aaron's has disappeared with dad you
guys have just entered the dungeon right
now so Oh No let's put pawsley from
battle brother
we're just locked in here yeah I mean
you can leave if you want but I don't
have anything for you to do if you do
that you'll just go back to that town
and you guys have already exhausted
didn't burn down most of everything
so how is this gonna work is for the
most part you should always assume
you're in combat what that means is you
can only move five spaces in a turn
you're allowed how it works for anyone
who's not watched or it has hasn't seen
us before Jake you can move five spaces
and do an action so you can do five
spaces and then do a spell you can move
spy spaces and then do something if you
decide not to take a turn you can move
seven spaces so if like all you're
trying to do is sprint out of there you
can move a little bit further because
your action would basically be try to
run even faster okay Oh mr. Pooh's you
can't see what's up ahead it's really
really dark but you can hear screaming
okay you can hear screaming and lots of
sounds and it sounds like Cormac you
recognize the voice it sounds like dad
is screaming Oh dad go save new dad what
is Erin doing to him I don't know if I
could go out of it where's weird ergo
he's just a couple seconds ago dad was
carrying Mitzi it's fine look it's fine
guys you think he's in that foggy box up
there monsters Nightcrawler
for introducing dad - Aaron yeah you
guess wait wait are you regretting
exactly you lost their night yeah well
no you know Aaron's with dad we lost
Aaron and dad yeah you lost their net
dad you can prove you hurt you here dad
screaming which you would assume Aaron
must still be with him
they must be in trouble that is what you
guys are sorry you walked in the cave
you've heard dad scream and you know
that the last place you saw dad and
Aaron was how did he beat us to the cave
is he like some kind of human you Aaron
wanted you know what you Aaron wanted to
skip and I don't know if you guys saw
the first act of our show Aaron really
got whatever you taught me so Cormac is
just like whatever just fucking fine
we'll skip to the dungeon
plus I mean he was sharing that apple
juice which is pretty strong very strong
apple juice that's not not alcoholic
apple juice
Oh guys do you remember playing ball in
Cup with that I remember think cup and
ball when there were sword fight again
pause do the leader what are you guys
doing oh gosh wait I just feel this
would happen
did we rest up by the way in the yep
you're all good on your ways you've
taken travel days angry again no it
hasn't been a day it took about I'd say
it was a two-hour hike to get here from
where you were
but you've you've been you've recently
you know you had to there was a little
campfire where you and dad got the rest
you got to talk to him the six of you
deep down no he's not your father
but all having daddy issues because your
daddy was kind of a bad person you know
he seems like he's a good guy and you
know he's just nice to be around right
now he's it's like he's familiar he's
nice he's like less pedophile you know
how to feel yeah yeah well john carmack
you know like yep what happened i don't
think we ever took that tourniquet off
of Aaron's head I claimed that one that
was Jake you guys all you guys have know
right now is that there's screaming in
the other room I know we already know
Aaron's not in the campaign but you
don't know that as your characters you
assume Aaron is in the other room
with Daddy alright so clearly that's the
voice of our dad who's screaming ah hey
Justin what's up what's up you want to
like eat some mushroom or something to
go on ahead well here's what you eat
individually you you guys these need to
each decide this on your own are you
gonna stop and try to talk to each other
cuz of screaming or are you gonna run to
dad's help dad and Aaron's help my dad
the most stop does anybody else does
anybody want to actually I
nohow kara flying is the screaming yeah
like can you give us an example as to
what it's it's like that yeah he's he's
in battle you can hear you can hear he's
fighting with someone it could be Aaron
you don't know you could be playing Dark
Souls like we have no idea oh man we
want to get in on that I I don't know
what if he's playing Dark Souls wanted
to stop maybe you got an early copy of
blood-borne wow dude that doesn't come
out until the 24th that makes you scream
that yeah that definitely make him
scream should we go for that dead bones
and Roman are going to be running up
ahead the other pause is gonna be
staying behind Jessica be staying behind
is anybody gonna be running with those
two are you guys letting those two run
trying to be like well wait wait wait
anything I'm gonna swagger over there
you know all right you're gonna be
smooth walking but slightly behind I
don't know I'm excited okay I'm gonna
need you to roll for your swag walk is
it impressive it is six it's really not
that impressive your brothers are like
why you're running you're not why is
waggle by just wobbling some after dead
bones and Roman my case I'm small okay
Deadlands are Roman to run to the edge
of this fog and they can see into the
room now and they can see dad currently
fighting what looks to be three
skeletons okay Aaron is nowhere in sight
as they walk into the room Cormac
screams out help help please help come
on stop messing around for one minute
and please help as a skeleton surround
him
okay I know what you think we should do
inky is our turn now yeah I think combat
has combat is now started for turn order
let's just turn on turns we can start
with you'd be adjusting you know how
much it was yet you haven't eaten your
mushrooms yet you're going to but that's
gonna take just as Colonel let you try
to pull them out of the bag all right
can you pass the turn around to Roman
we're gonna have Roman take the first
turn and then we'll just go around the
board Jake I need you to hit the intern
button yep all right Roman you're up
you see Cormac being beat on by some
skeletons okay
what weapons do I have you have your
trusty two-handed hammer and you have
three separate pocket knives as you're
an expert at knife throwing it's like a
party trick you do you know it's a
two-handed hammer two-handed hammer yep
and little pocket 9s yes
all right Leakey I think we got it I
think we gotta save dad yeah I think we
gotta save new dad yeah I love new dad
man right Roman is your turn okay um I'm
gonna move I'm gonna move up here okay
and I'm gonna tack the skeleton and the
front with my hammer okay roll for me
generally on attacking you can assume
you were doing three damage just that
you guys want to count or anything like
that you swing at behind the skeleton
you hit him for four damage Roman the
skeleton turns to face you ignoring dad
after your immediate attack co-star is
now your turn
right so what has happened is these two
ran in okay
Roman got the quick first first foot in
there ran at the skeleton just
immediately started saving dad dead
bones is moving into attack you are
still mid mid swag walk as
the other three boys sit in the back
just being like just get some mushrooms
out with everyone okay um I would like
to summon my Nimbus if I could okay you
actually your Nimbus has always been
here just hovering in this design so
you're just you're just gonna you're
gonna bring it down anybody dead - oh I
guess there was dad oh well here's the
thing okay no you could play this that
your Nimbus has doesn't exist yet but in
which case you actually need a dead body
to begin in this ritual was what I was
thinking is that I have these pieces of
Randall okay oh no you didn't you didn't
actually bring any pieces of Randall
though he's like you left him in the
town like you're now thinking you're
like man I'd be really good if I had a
Nimbus there's probably some engagement
still from the glass there my speech son
waited to remember he avoided it though
I think he just didn't hurt him he was
clearly stepping on it you might have so
he still in there it's probably gonna
get infected so you might want to just
help yourself here okay and a role for
lifting my foot sure okay little blink
rolling your foot for alright yeah Jake
lifts a book Oh says you got any of that
glass in you Jake lifts up his foot he
has no idea what's on the bottom his
foot he's like so your answer is you're
not sure what's on the bottom of your
foot could be glass could be anything
would also if this you haven't washed
your feet in a long time Jake oh yeah
I'm a starving artist that's kind of
Randall splashed all over you and you
didn't dry off he's in your shirt oh
yeah I'm just covered in the essence of
Randall yeah okay wait that's what that
is
yep that's right cover him Randall okay
no if you if you will remove your shirt
and use it for the ritual you can you
can summon an abyss Oh Randall the race
you Justin I'm doing it I love when car
takes his shirt off just watch we're a
very weird family you blame us nine okay
so we're gonna get a Randall summoned
here
I gotta actually get you guys the art
a little cloud version of Randall okay
well so Randall's being summoned you
will have Randall at the beginning of
your next turn Coe you're calling down
from the skies you want to summon the
life force of Randall I was kind of
thought you might you know use Aaron
when you eventually find his body but
that's fine Frank's whole apple juice
can exist as well so kho-kho took his
shirt off k and he's like channeling his
energy to do something you don't really
know what he is doing because he's never
done it before in his life and I've
rolled a bite Laura lip yes you want to
do Cormac face oh okay yet you you bit
your lip but not as good as dad bites it
okay it's pretty good it's a good first
attempt dad evil dad probably dad would
be proud you know who has the wand
oh no Jade still has the warning yeah
Jake still hasn't yeah yes that was in
fact a wand in my pocket would you like
it I don't believe you let me check okay
oh I'm up here well we're still in the
issue so we need it's now dead bones
astern okay
all right remember we can't do anything
movie like that coaster and your turn oh
I'm sorry
there it is alright what kind of weapon
do again um we what were you again I'm a
seer soother I see you have a little
pocket wand ah c'mon yeah that you use
for little types of spells you know
little party tricks in addition to your
normal skills I know some little
telekinesis tricks and stuff like that
and you have a slingshot
oh it's think shot give slingshot sake I
just want to fling a rock at the
skeleton that's I don't know the one
next to Roman okay I don't get hit
you'll be fine now you'll be fine
I got good in
linkie you knows how to hit things link
Issa all right Roman because you can't
even see this happening and you just
attacked you just get trucked in the
head for you know a slingshot soon just
bounced you in the back your head little
minor damage it's probably wearing a
helmet it's probably yeah but it's
probably still gonna leave a little bit
of a bump does it dig off
yeah it Dinks off it makes them operable
pink bow can i glare back at him well
you need to roll Roman to see if this
actually distracts you or if you're too
focused on saving dad all right
luckily Roman you do not glare back at
him you are still focused on the
skeleton
sorry inky okay mr. Pooh's it is your
turn you're still waiting for just the
pull up mushrooms while biting your lip
as some does Co intensely channels of
spells what's the progress on me getting
these mushrooms
I mean Justin's literally about to pull
them out if you just want to pass your
turn you know I want to pass my turn in
all right all right you pull out the two
mushrooms I believe yeah I think you had
one purple one and one on purple what he
Justin what's up
I smell let you know that purple is my
favorite color dude oh really yeah if
you wouldn't mind add up the chatter
purple mushroom you're you're more than
welcome to it man thanks homie I
appreciate it all right Justin are you
gonna be sharing any mushrooms with Jake
is he being left okay yeah let me just
get a little bite
hey Jake you want to have like a mixed
salad you could have some my mushroom if
you want to you that would actually be
kind of cool I'd feel less bad about
taking some from you know just one
person
yes that's no worries dude so Jake can
wash it down with some orange juice yeah
if you want to pass your turn you can
also enjoy in the mushrooms here all
three of you together here this will be
your collaborated turn there's
definitely there's definitely not gonna
be sharing it here
I had to do it are any of you going to
be trying to share a bite or want to
save a bite for any of your brothers are
you just gonna be gobbling us like that
man okay I'm a bit like the skeletons or
whatever one again you know little stem
like with the stem that's kind of kind
of angry
yeah it sounds a little bit yep that's
just Beth pauses electors Claus is
allowed to be angry his character is not
pause can be angry at the table his
character is not though okay okay this
character can't do anything that's
perceived angry all right
I need some roles for eating the
mushrooms Jake is taking a bite of
Justin's
and of positive so he's gonna give you
getting a little effective both alright
this is awesome I'm so excited Jake
taking the first bite I need to know
who's saying the first bite yeah that's
fine okay Jake's takes the first bite
Jake do you invite the red one of the
purple one here um you know let's go
let's just go from you know from left to
right here let's start with the purple
one okay give me another roll okay be
Justin you know what you're having half
a blush room I'm having a half a
mushroom Jake could be fucking tripping
balls he's eating a full month
Jake takes a bite of this mushroom and
immediately can feel the negative
effects of the clearly labeled poison
mushroom so Jake will be taking stamina
damage every turn until he can get it
out of his system which will last at the
very least until you were done combat
guys does anyone have any apple juice
out right now
everybody should pause definitely has
apple juice on him and I just see that
okay I mean you know you don't have to
tell them you feel like god no do I
don't I think vitamin C enhances your
trip or something so I'm gonna take a
swig of my OJ okay is this before you
don't even gonna try the other bus sure
we're gonna go right to the OJ next yeah
man I'm in a bad way right now
alright take a swig of row J or all the
dice for me
Jake coos to take a drink of his oj gets
a nice clean gulp delicious does not
help in any real way with poison
coursing through his body but he cannot
he actually feel the effects of the
mushrooms even though it's poisonous
Jake turns to Justin and he kind of
looks like an animal what animal is
Justin look like to you Jake he
definitely looks like a mushroom like
what animal or object as pause look like
I totally also looks like a mushroom and
like everyone just looks like a mushroom
and then you give one more brief look to
co-star and what animal or thing does he
look like oh it looks like a wild
stallion with that shirt off all right
Mike hi how's the mushrooms dude and you
got to try some of this here to have
some of this purple one it's uh it's
pretty good I'm gonna eat my purple one
don't worry keep that one to yourself
okay well who's gonna take the same bite
pause Oh Molly I don't care you're gonna
finish the purple mushroom it looks like
it's gonna be fun he sees monsters of
wild stallions I mean for that yeah okay
alright pause you go to eat the mushroom
but you drop it on the ground 5 Samuel
contri pick it up dude it fell right
into a little like pile of like rat poo
I mean you can rule can I pick it up you
can pick it up but yeah but it's a
little covered in rat dog oh yes yeah
yeah okay you go and you actually
without thinking pick up the rat dung in
your hand
pause I need you to roll to see if you
notice the right time in your hand or if
you eat it okay
pause you pick up the piece of rat dung
and you're like wait a second this isn't
rat dung and you kind of brush away some
of the poop and you find a magic crystal
it's blue and white
but to Justin
Colten plaque and it seems to be it
seems to be glowing and pulsing well did
you see this this is the craziest gold
the black crystal you then pick up the
mushroom and did you still want to eat
the mushroom ah hell yeah
you eat the mushroom you are now
poisoned Justin you've now seen all this
happen
you still have your half well actually
you have a full mushroom here are you
gonna take the third bite you're gonna
pass it to Jake what do you want to do
uh you know I'm gonna call anyone else
want to bite his mushroom does anybody
respond you know what you might help me
flush this out of my system let's uh
let's say pretty okay it's all yours
give a shot Jake have a bite of mushroom
roll the dice take let's roll this hey
Justin would you be interested in
getting us a little rap about how that
crystal is black and yellow hey Jake
Jake rolls Jake takes a bite of the
mushroom and it actually cures the
poison he could feel under an immense
amount of strength coursing through his
body
he's more he feels more powerful faster
stronger everything good however the
hallucinations end you still look like a
mushroom though what gives there's half
a mushroom left who's eating the rest of
this mushroom and then that's it for you
guys this triple turn here Justin you're
holding it Justin didn't get any
mushroom I'm not getting any of this
well I mean you could pass this out man
yeah I mean you want to split it all
right all right put it pause are you
actually splitting it are you playing
just to seal the whole thing from this
offer yo can I just fuckin steal from
him yeah you can't he's offering it to
you so you could just eat the whole
thing and get none left to him give me a
stem I'm willing to like cuz what I want
to do is I don't want to like just steal
it I want to like bed belt bed down and
take a bite and bite his finger while
I'm attitude
[Music]
okay I just want to say this battle is
going nineteen alright you go you nibble
on Justin's finger it kind of hurts but
because you didn't do it in an angry way
more in like a fun way it kind of hurts
Justin but yeah it was excited it
tickles him mushroom also you to feel
the power of the mushroom the site the
psychedelic parts we're off and you feel
reinvigorated with immense strength
alright it is that my turn is my turn
was skipped the three skeletons all
attacked Cormac except for the one
facing Roman that one's going to turn
around and try to attack Roman so we're
gonna stop from the top here where's the
dice
what did you guys do with it - mrs.
Cormac yes john carmack lives one Cormac
actually Cormac actually Perry's and
just completely decapitates that
skeleton he falls into a pile of bones
on the ground so cool the skeleton Falls
to a pile of bones on the ground the
third skeleton is actually turning to
Roman here does he make like a xylophone
son when he collapses absolutely that's
yes oh man this skeleton just turns
around he's my rear all yeah you can how
much stamina is that no no my pet yeah
no I'm using to use it yeah yeah but how
much stamina reroll I mean three three
okay alright go ahead and read rule oh
you're so bad at this we're rolling
space I know
18 alright the skeleton comes and it he
hits you Roman but it hits you running
your armor you don't even really feel it
Cormac after seeing after decapitating
one skeleton now turn
to swing at the skeleton no longer pay
attention to him that just hit Roman say
be dad
Oh Oh dad all just ball it out with 220s
he swings at the skeleton and hits him
for three damage okay it is now
Romans turn mr. Roman okay I'm gonna go
and try and finish off the skeleton
that's still fighting me okay go ahead
and roll wait can I first yell at the
jackasses behind me he's nude dad yeah
hey guys I heard if we saved dad he has
mushrooms for everyone else Cormac says
it's true I do have more mushrooms get
over here now
Oh dad's about to be buying okay it's
not your turn though leave it hold on
okay
all right seems to be effective no
melted you and dad seem to be good at
morale you swing at the skeletons you're
kidding him for four damage the skeleton
falls into a pile of bones
mr. co-star you have now finished
summoning your great Nimbus cloud
so where can you pull up the Nimbus Club
card where's that for me I mean let's
see who knows yeah oh yeah at all times
a small cloud will follow you around
your Nimbus cannot be attacked or or
hurt by a physical damage once
programmed combats that means anything
until it comes back around your Nimbus
may intervene by moving a target or
object of normal size one space this may
be used at any time so at any point in
time you can move someone or something
one space over and you can do it as an
interrupt Kay your Nimbus represents
Randall Randall Randall the piece of
juice okay because of this you Randall
does not actually
have any emotional connection to you and
he's really not gonna listen to well
you're gonna have to work on a rapport
with him okay okay
Randall however Randall however because
of his movement
he's so Swift that you don't actually
move him as a person at any time you say
do this he's there okay
he's so quick in the what was that pause
he physically appears as Randall to all
of us - you don't know he's actually
Randall ko hasn't explained it
ko took Oh literally took off his shirt
started doing something enough goddamn
cloud appeared okay a sentient cloud by
though you guys are all smoking buck
eating mushrooms oh really sir if that
actually happened or if you know so we
are aware that we're no longer tripping
or we as no you're you're not you just
the tripping effect wore off because
you've both cure it but you still ate
mushrooms state if feeling if you eat if
you ate mushrooms pause okay and then
you have this crazy reaction and you ate
another mushroom and then you had no
reaction you really don't know what's
what right now he's only been like a
minute or two you're still in that crazy
trip even if it's wearing off but code
you don't have to treat this like a
moving moving around
it cannot be damaged or hurt you just it
comes in it but something if you want it
to be present on the board as an entity
you can if not it's just smoke in the
wind yep right now it is in front of you
is your turn I think I think my course
of action is clear okay
I want to roll to hug okay yeah you roll
to hug Randall your arms go right
through it
as it is a cloud and Randall kind of
backs off as you basically just put your
arms through him he has no idea
remember Randall was only alive for the
course of two minutes then he died and
now he's been brought back as a sentient
life again he really is really confused
right now it's a cloud but at the very
least you know maybe part of the
sentiment that you're not being angry
towards him is noticed okay that's
that's good enough if you want to do
anything else move or anything
mr. hug is that does that pretty much
take up what he can do for now
no well Randall was one brand of combat
that does that was not Randall that was
just Randall kind of just shifting as
you hugged him just being like poof
you'll still be able to use Randall at
any ed during anyone's time as like
think of it as an interrupt right okay
then I probably would like to send
Randall to go help in the battle like
save new dad okay I save new dad let's
move dad won over who's not one fire you
tell you till Randall oh you're putting
it easier to tell Randall to save dad
we're gonna see if Randall will listen
to you how are you telling Randall are
you being like demanding or like can you
are you asking as a friend or you asking
as a master I'm still feeling pretty
tender so I'm gonna be friendly about it
Randall could you please help us
save dad okay that's good brought back
all my tenderness that's what you said
you're gonna tell them to go save dad
yeah okay
Randall flies over does not know whose
dad is &amp; boos Roman back also Randall
now thinks that that probably is dad he
now thinks Roman his dad so hold on
though does he feel any any little weird
like you know because the way you well
know ya cuz you said go save dad Randall
now also thinks that Roman must be his
dad because the way you said it was go
save dad so that doesn't change the fact
that he still he still has to listen to
you and a little bit like he knows you
created him in a way but at the same
time you've now just established a type
of you know hierarchy like well of
course I gotta listen to you but you
listen to him so you listen to dad
obviously you can correct this error at
a later time