right at this point combat is now over
again because pause has refreshed his
growth he's still even bigger now than
he was I will warn you though he's not
gonna be able to maintain this he's only
got a couple more minutes before he goes
right back to his normal size which is
going to have a big effect on him
because he's now been really warped a
little bit he's gonna need a minute to
get used to balancing and stuff again we
just keep using enlarge and double down
on him and don't let him I mean you can
but at some point you will fail the role
and bad things will happen but not by
all means laws can also resist by the
way if he wants to yeah I know I know I
know we never offered you any mermaid
but we just killed this it's Motor Co
yeah dude if you want we can uh come out
again attitude is that yeah we come on
over feast then bring some kindling over
to my shoulder this is a really big
motherfucker here that's gonna take like
reading a big sweaty tears if you're
gonna move the ogre using pauses
strength you guys have to decide better
hurry start it right now cuz pause is
gonna lose it soon oh man just bite him
co eat it raw the ogre is dead that's
not it's not a rush
what it's not chicken it won't give you
anything bad countered I have just giant
hammer here I could fucking tenderize it
for you I'll be so easy to take a
fucking chew out of the shoulder blade
come on coach
what I'll tenderize it for you in fact
I'll do it regardless whether you like
it or not I would have role to tenderize
okay this is oh all right no no you
don't get to move Co you don't get to
move I'm not part of this you are
definitely part of this pause slams next
to him so that we can wait
interrupts oh you're gonna interrupt
with what I'm gonna interrupt with this
with a few things okay so just so you
know here's what's happening hey before
you interrupt pause has raised his
hammer with one of his hands it's the
bout to slam it down on this big old
squishy ogre okay right no I get it
yeah okay okay I'm gonna do one
interrupt then and it's gonna be I'm
gonna bring up a force pillar
just in front of me just in front of you
right there yep okay I'm gonna need you
to roll for that what's how much stamina
is that three mm what was that what was
that number or four okay so it's not
coming up in front of you buddy you try
to have panic you try to very quickly
bring up this force pillar sorry I'd
actually spawn it I hope it comes up
from underneath you push you towards the
Jager um to block you but you miss
instead you block the the what the
brother that you care most about
oh yeah like Justin I think at this
point just in front of Justin to block
ogre shit coming at him
where's we doing anything else I have
one backup sling okay all right I'm
gonna use my magic brain about troll
powers and move the ogre one position
out of the way the hammer okay pause
from your hammer now all right pause
swings down and slaves it on the ground
missing the yogurt pause when you swing
down the hammer you swing it down so
hard that you shake the ground a little
bit
a little bit of a poll as you do it and
that scares you because you realize how
godly strong you currently are all right
well nothing happens you guys go back
we're not in combat so by all means yeah
I want to I want to see the gym I go
that's all I want okay what school does
meanwhile the school kid boots goes
looks at the corner I want to look at my
head and specs this gym I know magic
shit right probably figured this out
wait wait wait when did stole you don't
remember the poop gym all right
Deb bones takes another look at this gym
and knows exactly what it is
all right do you want me to tell you you
got a soul you can say anything else is
fucking false you could send it to me in
Skype okay sure because it means like
passing notes in D&amp;D oh wow don't know
if they could save our lives or kill us
all
wait wait wait wait if cuz if Co is
asleep could we drag him over and make
you need some ogre I'm not asleep we
could be asleep there you go dead bones
that's you know exactly what that
crystal is from okay you if you vaguely
remember it should be very obvious now
what is yep yep okay okay I'm gonna call
it twin subtle did you hold on Roman
this was at a character unless you
notice something you need to roll to see
if you notice dead bones then you
brought up the whole thing all right
twin time okay I know you like I know
you like these chains mm-hmm this is
really becoming a pain in the ass he's
gonna start crying it'll be a baby in a
minute he's gonna shrink and then
they're gonna be fine
and you know what it's it's they're
they're not gonna shrink maybe the same
size he's gonna shrink and they're gonna
be fine that doesn't make any of this
better but it's funny to watch you try
and track
roll to see if paws can hear all this
community cause roll you twin like you
don't have to wait communication this is
just a normal board conversation and
whispers paws are gonna see if he can
hear it he he can make out most of the
words but not all of them so he's not
getting the full picture he the only
reason he said that was just so you guys
would know and you know a little bit
more come on
he killed dad and now he killed his dad
he's already changed then I don't need
to chain him again when he kills new dad
where the hell is new dad well so for
reference Justin remember the only
person who knows where new dad went and
unless you bring it up in a character
conversation his new dad left to go past
these skeletons and paws saw happen just
he walked right past the skeletons it
has not analyzing it you and I I do
remember seeing that red door the middle
and it did remind me of it but again
yeah just keeping it to yourself that's
the secret
yep pause and Romanian all right the hex
room we're keeping the goddamn to keep
the chains right okay if it comes to
having the carrying the goddamn
roommates you're carrying okay
he's gonna be angry he's not gonna be
able get hungry for at least like
another day maybe at most I don't really
know how this works
I don't know I have no news at 20 he's
probably gone for a week okay he cannot
get angry we are he this is this is the
best there's no way we can fuck this up
there are 50 ways fuck up a bull
situation it's gonna be fine just trust
me okay god damn it look don't make me
make your ass bigger - all right I can
do that
alright alright Twitter Jake
okay well meanwhile they're having a
conversation did you guys do anything
else while they were walking off your
boy fun I'm eyeing that ogre cuz I'm I'm
kind of famished at the moment see see
just in it what's up how do you wash
rooms do you think it take to get a
giant pause hi first mushroom he threw
you yeah yeah fucking dinky that's like
yeah it's even it's a quarter size as to
what it typically is yeah I think it
mushroom bigger yeah I can make mushroom
big guys okay Moz begins to shrink oh
you can still hold the two mermaids but
he has to drop the hammer down to the
ground okay do you guys in large a
mushroom I'll put pause to sleep and
then you stuff it in his face he's gonna
be don't need to force it how many it'll
take for me to get my score dude if
symptoms last for more than four hours
we need to see a doctor I don't think he
would Justin what do you want to do it's
your mushroom uh dude he's got the
mushroom and it's probably you have more
more just I can make it I can make it
big you want me to make it think I can
make it big please make it big make you
big
yeah make a pause this red mushroom huge
you can all have some yeah I'll pull it
out pull it out okay make sure you get
the right mushroom oh that's not a
mushroom pause that's your you know
here's the mushroom impossible you don't
want enlarge that one no it just says
poison it's not poison though that was a
trick that's mushroom I'll fix for you I
know you have to kit you got a cast that
you're gonna cast it yeah I'm gonna cast
enlarge on the big ass poison yet Reese
Pamela for you this C stamina but I can
eat the mushroom too so that's
Justin you better have more red
mushrooms ah I think I have one all
right okay uh you evaporate that
mushroom
ah it's just it's just like absolutely
tiny now I mean hey great we just wait
three minutes for white for the mushroom
to come back we mean to come back so
that's Tommy yeah sure yeah I guess if
we're gonna wait the enlarge will wear
off sure you could lick it up off the
ground I guess but is the effectiveness
of the mushroom reduced by the size all
right that's a scouting patrol who's
gonna walk into you guys now so much
time all right two skeletons walk into
line of sight of pause here once those
two the iller they notice pause and the
skeleton archer immediately immediately
runs back and this one just starts
clanking his bones at pause through
timid eight him I start chattering my
teeth at him at this point combat has
now started it was the last person to go
dead bones so pause it is your turn so
yes that's all I want to do sure chatter
your teeth you guys have wasted a lot of
time
mushrooms nineteen you chatter your
teeth and it makes the skeleton run away
so you know good job pasta chattering
your teeth the last guy who was clearly
going to be friendly you snapped his
neck and left left a bastard in the
world just like the other six bastards
you left to the world with you marry
murder their dad and replace them with a
stranger that they all universally pause
accepted because they're all having that
many issues look losing their dad
okay pause also you shrink again
oh the mermaids are still in your lap
but they're getting heavy now Oh God
I get really fucking happy guys alright
my turn
nothing is happening on my turn the two
mermaids are just begging to be let go
they say they say pause if it's
mushrooms you want we will give you our
entire supply if you just please let us
back put us by our water no Justin yeah
I love these mushrooms right now I mean
they're amazing Jake pretty down with
the mushrooms alright so these two five
females here these mermaids they
promised me their entire crop of
mushrooms if I let them go now I know
dead Bo's is like that's made of super
rare but we could be fucking like the
Heisenberg of shrooms we can summon an
exactly right you guys want to like help
me up maybe get these girls often you
know we do a little three-way business
here hmm
I will chain you to his ass shut the
fuck up down I remember pause that
regardless mean you have to you have to
convince Roman because one was the only
one who can unchain them rude humble I
put him on he takes them off if Roman
guys who are all fucked
well I'm saying here okay me Jake
adjusted we'll split it thirty percent
and you are why are your just addressing
me you need to be interesting both of us
we're a set man is the way it's always
been ever since we were kids come on so
I'm not being angry here I'm just
repeating the truthful here that bulls
is a piece of shit he's forcing me to do
this and he's forcing you to do this as
well hey I gather your anger of our
total income it all you got to do is sit
on your ass
and all we do is tell the truth dude
you're basically a baller for nothing do
you really trust these idiots to sell
shrooms or I'm not eat them all do you
really expect
I just I just gonna put this out because
your characters know this that the
mermaids and the mushrooms pale into
comparison of your original goal of
working for Miss 'van to get paid dragon
treasure troves of money well you're
saying exactly but you're the one who's
breaking around birthday oh all you guys
are messing around with like oh let's go
collect some mushrooms let's program
these mermaids Jake thinks too rare for
dwarves but what if the dragon gold
isn't like any use to us I mean it's not
any your two mermaids and we're not
dragons we don't spend dragon money okay
I want to sprint desperate sure you're
in combat everyone's kind of spending
their turns just talking sure um so how
far can I go don't you roll you
everyone's just talking so you can just
walk right up to him no no their person
has like appeared yet I want to scope
out the situation a bit well everyone
else is talking you look around the
corner and okay and you can see tricks
dude you can see a goblet the size of
the Stanley Cup it is attached to the
floor and in gems are just flowing out
of it just endlessly onto up the piles
around the Goblet there's a bunch of
skeletons picking through the gems kind
of sorting them at the back of the room
you can see a fountain with a lion's
head you can see a lot of torches you
can count you know at least half a dozen
skeletons in front of you some of them
much better armed than before but you
can see tons and tons of gems this is
why I pointed this out because you guys
were one minute away from a room filled
with gold and you're trying to stop
mermaids and
the mermaids we can also keep his pets
and just alright nobody knows this but
you right now though Co so they're still
gonna be arguing about drugs for a while
cool
now you also see the skeletons are all
talking at each other and one of them
looks back and sees you peeking around
the quarter phone wait can we roll that
sure so the skeleton turns around you
see them turning let's see if you can
dodge it you're gonna roll this now you
play he placed it so you get rid of the
20 on the corner the skeleton didn't see
you coming but you gotta remember they
know of the giant mermaid wielding man
in the hallway still right yeah they're
just figuring out how the fuck do we
deal with this problem
that's it for my turn again well I
basically at the poo everything depends
on you going back because all these guys
need the information so or you could
just not tell them in which case they
can continue you arguing for the rest of
the stream yeah no no it's cool I'm
gonna write okay if I can yep guys
there's a fucking gem vomiting goblet in
there and the Goblet is the size of New
Jersey are you embellishing the lucky
Jersey okay guys what's a goblet
there's also a lot of skeletons though
also the gems might be tricks probably
ten people
dude like as in are for kids yes either
way it's great was the best we should go
in pauses finally his giant enlarge
spell has worn off Oh God no problem the
mermaids fall off to the sides he's
smaller than fucking penis already
rolling pause because of the ER of
long exposure when you shrunk you
actually shrunk a little bit too much
and it's gonna take a while for you just
to regain back your normal size I don't
know how to explain it it's magical does
that mean is a good thing like after
editing sorry what'd you say pause is my
health affected or anything like that no
you're fine right now
just making sure it's yeah your your the
smallest of the brothers there's no I
check to see if my my penis is back to
its normal size yeah but we already know
my body sure yeah we'll see if your
penis thing different it's good thing
the mermaids didn't fall on him because
anyone get caught in a pain loop until
batshit out that means seven paws it's
actually smaller than normal homeless
because yeah so it'll prob it's probably
fine it's probably gonna go back to
normal but it is smaller than small at
least it's thin as well okay it won't
hurt I promise
is that your pitch for the lay the
mermaids you know it won't hurt you why
are you giving them the option we don't
know if they have like the same Anatomy
as as we exist so we know it's mushy no
Jake described it when you guys were
talking about murmur it's earlier he
talked about you know that the mermen to
have a sex act that you can put stuff in
use of the egg sack it's bigger than a
vagina if that's what you want to know
pause it's like I mean is there only a
tail or hey pause now you can put it
right between their teeth without them
opening their mouths oh my god that's so
true Coe I got flossing stick yeah if
you ever like chew beef jerky to get
that fucking meat stuck there don't
worry pauses penis is here yeah look I'm
just gonna put you all to sleep at the
same time the ogres the ogre apparently
still alive starts whispering something
nope not one well Jake's can let's put
everyone to sleep but you guys can all
but Co specifically can hear the ogre
whispering Jake you're gonna put
everyone to sleep down and try to sue
these at least you have a power nap here
heard of an ogre giant and green
expected to make us its latest cuisine
the hallway conundrum we hadn't foreseen
I just hope those mermaids are over 18
Oh beautiful Jake everyone is to sleep
even the mermaids the ogre the mushroom
dude the skeletons you you could just
you can hear it just echoed through the
hallways just everyone except you is
asleep all right awesome
I'm totally gonna hit up this mushroom
right here because I need to heal the
mushroom is so kind of tiny though
doesn't matter I just need a little nosh
it's got a lick it actually who has
mushrooms that I could anybody have a
good mushroom I think only now I don't
think I think this is the last good
mushroom that you guys have all right
let's do it
chow down all right Jake goes and eats
the the mushroom go ahead and roll Jake
see how effective it is it's quite small
might not be as powerful as a normal
mushroom oh it still gives you the
general effects starts to slowly top you
off yeah you'll be back to normal
stamina in just a few minutes here he'll
be all rested up so these guys are
asleep Jake how long did you really want
the mount for cuz you basically do the
perfect ballad you can be it but it's
gonna be a 20-second song you put it
asleep for a couple hours however long
you want I want to pick up that chalice
and see what happens okay are those
skeletons gonna wake up before I get
there I mean I can't really tell you ah
all right well let's give this a whirl
okay you're just gonna walk try to sneak
past the skeletons and steal the chalice
yes the size of the Stanley Cup bolted
to the floor by the way oh so I can't
actually take it's more think of it as
two
like a really great it's spewing gems
like gems are coming from underground
and it's being funneled under this
glorious looking chalice goblet like
just gems are spewing out of it and
actually because the skeletons aren't
sorting it because you put him to sleep
any I mean it's starting to fill up the
room now because nobody's dealing with
all these gems so mm-hmm
I wonder if maybe a handful of gems
would be enough to appease these yokels
into actually acting huh well I'm
probably gonna die but let's go for it
you're gonna try and sneak up to steal
some gems just a handful alright give me
a sneak roll I mean this is you this is
a twenty sleep Jake you can get away
with a lot you'd have to get a pretty
okay give me a good roll cheek none of
these there you go there you go oh god
it's so close to rolling on one all
right
you sneak up grab a big pile of gems you
don't have anywhere to put them though
so remember you burned your backpack and
your pockets are filled with your action
figures I mean you could leave the
action figures here and buy new ones but
you wouldn't want to
I was just mental you know you grab your
shirt and you kind of like make like a
little you know you grab it you're gonna
put the gems in you're gonna carry it
with like the bottom of your shirt yeah
make it a background yeah make exposing
your belly you know you can just kind of
like lift it up and carry some gems out
bare midriffs style yes let's do that
okay do I roll for that handle is asleep
uh you can roll I mean all right I'm
gonna roll for the bare midriff this
isn't the wake anyone up that's just to
see how many gems you're able to carry
oh I rolled it straight off the table
and you rolled nine six you can get a
good amount of gems no more than a piles
worth all right let's hightail it out of
there and report back once everybody's
awake so how long are these guys
sleeping for say let me uh um or you
could just wake them up
you just wake them up if you want wake
us up with a tune I can I don't want a
teabag pause just just because sleeping
counties rest
Wow
it's very well the sleeping does count
as rest but only if it's very extended
and it is just gonna make you more
hungry so it's NetZero it's not gonna do
much for you right I'm rolling to t-bag
pause real quick just a little freaky
thing so here's what's happened is you
you lean over it's like bull you in
order to pause uh you know while you
while you were gone looks like he's kind
of got back to his normal self normal
size he's back to normal he's just
laying there on his back now after you
roll him over mouth wide open you squat
over top of him okay you pull down your
pants slip off one of the legs off your
right leg you do a little squat really
spreading your legs you know you've been
it's really sweaty in this dungeon it's
kind of hot we're kind of a little bit
stuck to the side of your body so yeah
so actually while you're squatting down
a little droplet falls off one of your
testicles lands right on pause his cheek
on the side of his face you squat down
you see you get them right in there
while you while you have the balls in
pause it's wildly open mouth pause kind
of has like a little reaction and goes
and does a little movement with his
tongue and it kind of you know kind of
feel like okay oh those are more than
you bargained for but I mean you liked
it easier older brother easier senpai in
some ways you've always looked up to him
and culturally you know deep down you
know that hey it's okay for a brother
delivered brother in urban society how
we in our society view it is just
completely irrelevant because you know
that this is just brother on brother
love you leave the balls in there for a
good you know thirty seconds every now
and then is tongue just slapping against
your testicles finally you pull up zip
up and pause it's none the wiser
all right let's wake everybody up then I
think we're all pregnant now that's how
we say hello in the mountain homes it's
like our family handshake I really hope
it's not
you want some gems all right Jake starts
waking up you're only waking up these
guys right not the mermaids or anything
yeah not the mermaids they can stay dead
wait for a while he's asleep
all right everybody it was asleep you
walk up slowly wake each other up
everybody wakes everybody up
Jake starts playing what happened is my
mouth tastes like sour cream and onion
there these are they're all sleeping
though if we'd been here a few more
hours that would have been salt and
vinegar so you know feel lucky there is
no real turns right now because she's
not combat isn't started so you guys can
just do as you do check out these
big-ass gems hey check it out gems I
wonder where those came from
oh snap carefully wake the ogre because
slacking I heard before I fell asleep
with some whispering okay so when co
wakes up he goes to wake up the ogre coz
he really wants know what's going on
everybody else is very enthralled by
Jake here and his gem collection Jake
you want to tell him what's going on
well basically I just fell asleep I
guess like the rest of you guys and I
just woke up and all these gems are
right next to me remember your song I
need you to roll the see if you remember
distinctly hearing a song you want to
see if you remember how you went to
sleep yeah dead bones you don't remember
anything okay good because I could
perform it again for you somebody
somebody got completely d2
and uh yeah I didn't take the murmurs
teeth did a the most important part
remember though you want to come it god
no those teeth can go for so much money
I'm making this up but I don't know I'm
sure it does meanwhile end up to all
that acid meanwhile none of you've
noticed ko is waking up the ogre go
please roll to wake up the ogre okay
this is why has it got
I mean the ogres kind of dead
he's just is barely alive you go to wake
up the ogre the ogre is not waking up
you check his pulse
the ogre is dead now you can come back I
mean go just wanted to know something I
know just dead ogre
what's up who's naked by the way just
let you know he paused those pants by a
pause at this point you're still wearing
the ogres pants which do not fit you so
they're just like giant parachute pants
okay massive bears your pants right now
it's a one janko's nice razor put your
put your head through the fly and it's a
onesie the pause poncho