all right hello all right you all right
you guys ready to the second act cell
here let me uh yes in the next room
right no no no so we even close to the
end of the first act so i'll give you
guys some hints so this this is a very
much a trial run of on from rome's life
and I've learned a lot I've learned a
lot I've learned that sometimes we're
just going to run at a time there's just
no way to do that like I planned five
boards today and I honestly thought you
guys could get through in three but at
the same time I know us and I know how
crazy we can play sometimes so I also
know that it's kind of like I have to
prepare them in case you guys decide to
play fast okay so basically what he's
saying is uh you know thank you guys for
coming out tonight no no we're
definitely we're gonna play until
midnight midnight Eastern so we're gonna
play for another two hours that is like
my hard limit I'm just at that point I
won't be able to uh that's when I take
obtained my dming Oh cat oh that's evil
that's your the worse so I wrap it just
takes a long time to try to fuck a
mermaid no well you know what I think
what it really is too is this is more
people than we would normally would have
we had a full eight person roster and so
when you have to go around the table
eight times you know in anything it's
obviously always going to take much
longer than if we had to go around for
which is we're going to pretty much plan
to do like five people shows maybe six
with a guest now well we'll probably do
something five or six but at the same
time I mean this this is just how I was
going to eventually be sometimes
sometimes we're going to have long games
sometimes we're going too fast games
nature of D&amp;D I think the Indians are
still going on to this day is it the
nature D&amp;D when we burn down a tavern we
insulted oh come on let's win this you
know no no no you gotta be honest though
Aaron played D&amp;D like exactly the way
like anyone who's never played D&amp;D would
play like the first thing you do is come
up to tavern first thing is he's gonna
be i'ma burn that she to the ground I
was actually like
this just so cute and he's doing it just
like how I used to do insisted he gave
it Randall Randall Randall Randall
Randall was all director asked about
that and I love no regrets yeah that is
well I mean new dad's pretty sick too
like condoms but a lot of D&amp;D well a lot
in D&amp;D I i have like I've watched people
do it live and the Dungeon Master will
have a really linear like everything and
it's not as fun because honestly getting
being stuck in the town even if it feels
like I'm trying to egg you guys on I
don't really care there was so much left
to do in that town he doesn't even go
into the house is there behind the for
its didn't mean anybody and like it's
it's so much fun because what I like to
do is I like to just make a lot of
things and then just be like all right
go to do in whatever order you want or
not do them or because that's how you
get those kind of like rolling dynamics
of very very silliness and fun plot like
right now we're where we at we got paws
he's still large two mermaids chained
and mermaids like we're discussing what
to do with the moment yeah we're at a
comment the mermaids are not attacking
all right away Hiro hold on let me let
me describe it so we can get back in
here okay so combat is ended okay romina
Devlin's of stops printing they're no
longer worried pause is still enlarged
but it's going to wear off in the next
couple minutes pause you got these two
mermaids who are too fucking dumb you
get these two mermaids who are very
docile towards you there at this point
they're just scared for their life
they're chained to pause via the honor
change which can only be broken if Roman
cuz Roman is the Paladin whispers the
word penis whispers penis Egan since the
whisper as to with it and it has to
whisper it has to be in character as
well so but basically we whispers being
is it they break he would never betray
me and do that it's the chains effect
make it so if anybody hurts pause or
anybody hurts the mermaids the other
will get hurt so if you punch a mermaid
pause gets punched if you punch pause
the mermaid sea a punch so the permits
the mermaids kind of know this the honor
trains to just when you get hit you just
kind of know the rules of it maybe
they've known about it before maybe one
of them is a pallet and who knows
but they know the effects so they are
just now completely obedient to pause
but the same time they're not loyal in
any way they're just chained to him and
there is the threat of what happens when
pause is no longer enlarged here he'll
be fine so we're at a combat you guys
can discuss what to do with the mermaids
and how you're gonna approach moving on
from here on out okay so first of our
most I no dead bones is still very keen
on Salim visa I want to write or one is
a pet so whatever his head out of ten
rare either time Roman Roman I'm
resident wizard with dead bones we're
finger banging each other is cool what I
want someone does what I want is I will
carry i will carry these two fuckers
okay I'll bring glasses of water poured
on them so they don't dry out I like it
if ya you enlarge my penis you know it
wears off like this I can enlarge yes
every time you do we do it how about
this how about this whenever you need to
eat it yeah that you know what I'm okay
with that whatever you give me like
you're like a devil I need me and just
too easy go around the back I'm like say
no more you're done haha we're good now
you can sort this what I like this what
is going around the back me in this
context cuz there's a couple ways I tell
you to take that it means whatever just
impose okay that's that's good perfect
and the good news is my only going to
four times as big it Justin will still
easily be able to accommodate it alright
so we aren't you I think so does that
mean you want does that mean you want me
to take the chains off boss or get Roman
to take the chains off ah yeah I just
don't want to die you know I said I
don't want to like really really need to
eat a mermaid you can't even make out so
we probably wait until we're away from
the water where they can escape yep guys
I think we should discuss the difference
between needing and wanting with uh mr.
co-star here I think you need to do less
dragging those mermaids down the end of
this hallway and see what's down there
then we could talk about what we're
gonna do from there see that put the
heat on me I need to carry them if i
trace them yep less talking more dragon
shy guy you're right you want you should
hurry up before you shrink man pick them
up pick them off of your giant ass
yeah but I'm on your giant ass cheeks
all right mermaids don't want to be
picked up but so you'll fuck up huge
dude all right I need you to roll dice
for them to pick up the first runway
well you grab the first mermaid what are
you grabbing her by the hand how you
holding this mermaid you find a fucking
tail no respect the tail upside down is
holding her like a fish pick up the
second one so you flopping yeah she's
just trying to sprawl the other the
other second one starts to sprawl around
she doesn't want to be picked up she
bites you in the hand pause take you
don't take damage but yeah you think
twice before trying to grab this one
she's white oh that are made a lesson
definite just Justin of even eating
mushrooms again sorry sorry I'd what's
up what's up your suit seats that
mermaid a lesson yeah look at his face
he's been eating mushrooms did you say
that what clad dad eating mushrooms us
up I just want you to go over and teach
that mermaid her place what what I mean
you go do that dead bones you're not in
combat what are you walk over to
yourself you're those things they spit
acid I don't want to abuse a mermaid I
feel bad about the whole situation they
were just gonna leave I think I think
you should just eat a purple mushroom
it'll be too high to making a choice at
that point right so she's eating
mushrooms yes those aren't the good ones
fuck justin and those are the battlin
know you want to see things trust me you
do know when you eat them it's just like
in Batman Begins and you like see bugs
and stuff crawling other people's faces
Oh kind of want that yes yeah he's
eating mushrooms not meth it might be
fantasy man Justin what do you want to
man you're just gonna have your clown I
just want to hang out with Claude des
okay with clotted you're useless yeah
dude I'm having a good time you guys you
guys discuss your slave trade here Jimmy
Jake you're the mermaid expert in what's
the UM what's the play I don't like to
turn into one again and kind of uh can I
be chained as well uh yeah i mean if
wait Devlin's all
the cast another chain you know it's
like a ploy that you want oh you guys
could trick the mermaids Jacob be on the
inside Matt you actually want Jake yeah
you'd be like this is great that's what
that's what I've always wanted but I
want to be like a super butch mermaid
now okay it's okay per man dude your man
do a role do a role for me Jake all
right all right let's do this I'm gonna
be like the butch s mermaid it's gonna
be so good guys we could be the first
guys know yeah okay steaks ah so needs
co so Jake Jake goes over here he
grabbed some kelp as a watch / call it
he puts on his disguise he's really not
happy with it though he doesn't think
it's really gonna work too well Jake if
you come like you're hiding behind pause
cuz you didn't want to you know come out
you can like it I'm a super horny
mermaid dude I don't know if these
mermaids are really gonna buy it your
changes to have some fun with me tonight
I'm a mermaid I really like what made
butch were made juicy keep try talking
to this other mermaid to see if she buys
it from you 05 ask are you doing what's
your sign there's probably Pisces cuz
you're a fish thanks yeah what's up I'm
uh I'm dick Lord yeah the mermaid isn't
buying it at all oh just she just says
you can't wait for me oh my tail is
twitching you knows that me just get
away from me she's like trying to flop
the mermaid looks towards pauses can you
just just pick me up odd but only I
really don't mind just leave please
anything than this pause please all
right get the fuck over here Bobcats no
means no then Oh cuts the mermaid by the
tail olema Narian pause you this
disguise is not gonna last much longer I
give it just a few more minutes as well
which gives me the hallway that's all I
gotta do spring move that John acts like
all right two steps for him yeah I could
spray it right they'll be getting out of
the way are you guys coming with the
paws are you interested hey
Justin do you think I'm sexy hell yeah
do you like my job who is this hot
mermaid is this is uh well I mean it's a
hot mermaid that apparently is coming on
to you very much but yeah but you like
sleep I guess the jet bones are fucking
Justin did not actually see the sky the
sky so let's that's fine that can happen
Justin that what that was just for you
buddy okay nice bars we're gonna walk
over here Karen the mermaids is
everybody coming with Baz is anyone
staying in the room anybody doing
anything else in the room before we all
leave here I mean co starving but that's
what it all the quickie with this
mermaid will be right there you ever eat
out for seafood you guys are okay okay I
know work we're done we're coming you're
done okay freaked out I'm not trying to
impress anyone uh who are you okay cuz
you keep disconnecting okay yeah I don't
know what's going on but i'll try to
take a long soak oh look Carrie Yuko
don't worry um mr. Koosman booster is
coming along too and so is Randall the
cloud all right uh pause as you were
walking uh uh right around this corner
yeah the first thing you see is a giant
ogre oh my i walked in the Lord you're
still huge paws but you've got these
mermaids you've got your holding these
two mermaids you just turn around the
corner and he just immediately the ogre
can hear you he just turns around and
looks you right in the eye and you say
to the yogurt hey ogre you want homie
and then I tried mountain you're gonna
try and mount the ogre who is probably
the same size as you honest hell yeah
dude um while holding two mermaids yep
you can met with your legs hey what is
what if he's using him to throw the
Marines around yeah the mermaids like
it'll spit them so they kind of hook and
then he's got like a basic a saddle like
a like a mermaid morning star yeah okay
like a link they both grabbed arms
13 all right pause jumps up lanes
directly on top of the ogre mounting him
holding the two mermaids in combat has
now started great it's just pauses turn
co you're up for all you guys know is
you just saw pause go fuck you he just
said fuck you over and then jumped down
the hallway you just saw you can hear
lot ochre sounds you guys have fought
ogres you're pretty sure you know what's
around the corner are you pretty sure
you know what's happened it's probably
an ogre alright well I'm fucking killing
Rick Benedict okay I'm gonna go back
here and investigate these mushrooms see
what they're all about you're just
investigating you're not picking I want
to figure out what they are before I
reach out touch him okay give you a roll
see if you can figure out which mushroom
is which all right you look to mushrooms
they appear to be one poisonous mushroom
and one of those good for healing yep
mushrooms oh yeah just gonna eat it give
it a roll you pick up the mushroom you
start to nibble on it get it get a taste
for its flavor and then finally you
swallow the whole thing and you can just
instantly feel the effects of the
mushroom just bolstering your strength
you can just feel your strength just
regenerating oh oh you just feel like a
million bucks right now co you just feel
like the best guy in the world hell yeah
this is way better than fucking a
mermaid dead bones your turn says you
you still the sky now nobody actually
saw Coast slink back and go for the
words the mushrooms mmm Justin Justin
didn't see it but he knows he's got like
he's got he's got my justin has
developed mushroom senses that he can
tell that somebody just musta ate a
mushroom there's one less mushroom in
the world now yeah he just knows
somebody's been eating mushrooms okay my
bedroom sense is tingling
how what am i what's my current state
how am i doing so far you're kind of
surprised you're a little bit in shock
cuz pause walked around a corner it said
fuck you ogre and then just jumped into
the hallway here lemon and now you can
hear him wrassling the ogre who am i
doing stamina wise stamina why's your
pretty pretty well everyone is pretty
topped off with the exception of Jake
Jake said around he's half tired okay
doing he's doing okay but he's still
Jake's kind of still tired out from that
time he punch through the wall got it
and then got in and then got blitzed by
a bunch of mermaids he tried to seduce
so I'm gonna just move them to the
corner and see what i can see okay tell
me exactly what I'm seeing um so one
thing to keep a note is the enlarged
spell doesn't actually enlarge
everything of pause pause is actually
butt naked I don't know if we ever
established this it causes causes
clothes ripped off pause has been
bringing them with him he's brought
along all those possessions just for
when he unfreezes yeah he saw the head
but pause is currently completely naked
um sitting on top of the ogre you know
his dong kind of just like flopped over
top of one of his eyes was my dog local
camis uh dead bones whatever happens
this dong look on a scale of one to ten
how awesome is my dog she pauses this
kind of since it was mostly focused on
your ass not everything is to scale so
it look I can't even see it yeah Wow
okay I mean it's big pause cuz your size
but it's apparently is not excessive for
dizzy okay so dead bones you go around
the corner and dead bones are in I need
you to roll uh you were potentially
about to have a seizure odeon what you
just saw is so horrifying that you are
about to go into a potential panic
attack you're fine you were able to keep
it under control you can continue with
your turn here so so naked giant Paul is
straddling straddling the ogre the
yogurts got what looks like a one handed
mace the same time pause has these two
uh mermaids by the hands so like he's
literally holding on to the ogre by
squeezing his legs around his neck which
is why the penis is kind of flopped over
onto his head cuz he's just he's holding
on with his legs while he like flails
these two mermaids back and forth and
you can just hear them screaming and
wailing they're not comfortable right
now all right I think I uh man what this
sounds like the utmost in comfort I
don't know what to do I think all right
I'm gonna have what does the oh let's
see what's the ogre look like is he
pissed is he oh the ogres and little
confused boss doesn't actually tried to
hurt him pause just this we went around
a corner and a giant naked dwarf holding
two mermaids just said fuck you and
leapt on him the ogre is really confused
he's hasn't started attacking he's just
kind of pain i'm going to try and
communicate i'm glad just say hey oh
girl you you okay uh okay we're gonna
see if your diplomacy to even that ogre
notices we didn't notice is my little do
a role for me for seeing if the ogres
even noticing you what this is all going
on the oh you you start going up start
talking to the ogre calmly but you'd up
but he's he's dude he's got a naked
dwarf or two mermaids on his shoulders
he's not really paying attention to the
tiny little dwarf yeah all right pause
it's your turn now I mean your mountain
I I did mount him so here's what I'm
thinking right I pull up my spear and
ask him what the fuck you doing at these
hallways ogre were you pulling that out
of yeah where's the spear he says what's
a weapon you can't them you can't hold
it but you never wait you have to drop
one of the mermaids yeah you'd have to
drop on the mermaids to do that what go
drop the mermaid I don't care she's not
valuable to me it's only two dead bows
okay you still chained to herself pause
drops the mermaid the mermaid lands
takes minor damage the damage is then
reflected on to pause the damage dealer
pause then grabs the sphere which is
almost
like a toothpick honestly and point but
but but he pulls it towards the the
ogres head jailer jugular and says the
fuck you doin here okay and recio the
ogre react sudhir over we're gonna see
how the yoga reacts a high role here is
going to determine how angry this ogre
is that this a lower roles just gonna be
like more confused than justin ii will
be how I would describe this just just
thank you so much for destiny so the
ogre doesn't really want to fight you
pause he's just like get off me why just
dude he'll but he's not he doesn't
communicate so he says gagarin Walker
sound car broker sound that's a pretty
good Lisa that's what he says to pause
really good ogre he doesn't really
communicate in your language but he
hasn't attacked or anything he's just
really not comfortable he's not
panicking because again you got a
toothpick point is i just lanka making
like random stones can you block him
like a llama is making fun yeah yeah
yeah oh yeah yeah could I see how how
much it affects him yeah don't want to
fight this alright uh pause attempts to
yell t ogre just making some sounds it
seems to kind of slightly annoy her good
the ogres not too happy alright so at
this point the ogre is the ogres turn
he's gonna try and throw you off um he's
not successful but in the process he
does throw a mermaid who still changed
you Lance right next on the ground and
you take one day fucking god same with
the mermaid also the way this mermaid
landed she like broke one of the bones
and her fingers and she's now kind of
crying in pain don't break the mermaids
pause yeah you broke her pinky so do
what the ogre did that yeah that's for
that damage King I'm trying to stop him
he's an asshole damn
um so the the two mermaids are the two
mermaids get together here and they're
like flopping around they both start
shooting acid at the ochre because at
this point they're tied to pause they
have no choice they just see this ogre
they know this auger could back up and
kill them they just immediately try to
start shooting this ogre in the face see
welcome it's a defense mechanism the
ogre takes a little bit of damage and
inherently so does pause and the mermaid
because of Honor chains and then the
second mermaid shoots acid at the ogre
and again does a little bit of damage
which also affects pause pause your
stamina is depleting very quickly in
your current situation okay lots of
every all this stuff happening is slowly
depleting your your energy and you're
about to shrink so Jake it's your turn
you did shit's going down over there
because of where you're standing you can
see some of it you can hear a lot of it
what do you do man I'm gonna move
forward a couple spaces huh and then I'm
going to use my double down spell to
increase haces size by double while he's
on top of the ogre yeah okay ya know
this this will work networks that works
all right let's roll let's roll all
right you get away with it yes all right
uh pauses spell to increase the size is
slightly refreshed and he's made even
bigger he is now bigger than the ogre he
just called yo he crushes the yogurts
now the ogres just down on the ground
and pauses sitting on him we in this
process of him getting bigger the chains
kind of flipped the mermaids up they do
like little flip and little in the air
and then the land and pauses lap oh so
they're back on top of the only
lucky bastard right 91 wait you gotta
use some extra giant voice boss your
extra by now oh you're extra extra big
is that it's just yeah oh god just
echoey I was in an aircraft hangar hello
lady alright so idiot different it did
work Jake Roman it is your turn now then
okay so we have an ogre who is now being
crushed by raw crushed I pause I pause
you you you you at this point you can
assume that at some point you've at
least looked you and Justin both know
what's going on you've kind of you have
knowledge of the events occurring here
that doesn't mean you have any idea on
what to do next though you steer
spitball ideas can I okay let's do this
I'm gonna move up next Jake mm-hmm going
brother hi can I see anything past them
down the hallway uh Roman starts to
focus and all you can see is up in front
you can see an orange bowl and you can
see light sources coming from over here
so the next room is lit like the
previous rooms were okay a nice though
yep I'm gonna cast blushing a strength
on pause oh Jesus Christ okay give me a
roll room in the phrase I got a Rovers
yeah the phrase doesn't matter for the
rule oh okay Roman you try to catch
blessing a strength on the palate in
here I'm is just blessing strength three
Stan wasn't once then um you try to cast
blessing a strength here but it doesn't
work too well it seems that the
multiplying effect of paw is getting
bigger and bigger it's just made his
spear a little stronger and it's not
gonna have any noticeable effect but for
the sake of it what is the phrase that
process this show when deals damage with
your powers combined i am captain planet
okay okay okay i'm not saying oh you
never remember cause if you don't say
that
and you attack while blessing and
strength is active your strength will
just inherently miss you have to say it
or you won't be able to attack if you
say it I will say the words you wish me
to don't do that don't ok co it is your
turn so can I hear what's going on oh
yeah but at the same time code because
of your general melancholy you're really
not paying attention like you came over
here starving you ain't a mushroom and
now you just hear a bunch of like
screaming and panicking and the you know
wait I thought I felt like a million
bucks wyman coffee no you're just
melancholy in the sense that you know
you came over here you do not care about
your friends your way more you know
you're just topped off a good all my
friends who wouldn't get me a mermaid
steak yeah about half dead over here but
we as good a much yeah that's fine there
are friends were pits for other hunters
you can go back to caring about them
that's fine I'm just saying like right
now personally your character could go
either way you could have another
mushroom you could go back to the fight
you know you're indifferent you could
just leave look right you got a lot of
brothers I'm sure they can handle what i
was going on in over there anyway you
know this it's just you know what
happens all the time i got spares
whatever happens I probably still have a
brother to left yeah you already lost
one today probably so try yeah that's
fine honestly that's okay you got new
dads and so you know more brothers is
still on your plate your body right yeah
exactly alright so i won't be sprinting
back i guess i'm gonna get a meander on
back here feeling better i guess about
here oh no you can you can run all the
way up if you want like your field said
i don't give a fuck no you well yeah but
you feel like a million bucks you don't
give a fuck but if you want a rock up
there cuz now you suddenly care that's
fine you could run past just this bill
ok just as much as are great and it's
like I know that you had one but that's
nerdy knows what's going on here I know
I'll just I knew that you had a good my
face that's exact expression yeah I'm
gonna hedge it I'm gonna hang out with
Justin here and get a scope on what's
going on
okay Justin gives you a feel Justin
fills you number some of the details
tells you yeah they made pause bigger
he's sitting on an ogre right now I
don't know you want a mushroom yes just
ok I'll justin has all sorts of
mushrooms but mostly you probably should
not eat dead bones it is now your turn
all right so pauses giant sat on this
video logger ever maids are hanging out
I don't fucking know sorry with do I
speak ogre make an even bigger role I
gonna roll achieve a single yeah let's
see if I know any ogre um you're not
sure you might speak ogre your night not
your yummy you speak like what you
swings similar languages did you know if
you you're not sure you think what the
ogre said was please get off me guys
stop touching things dead bones sorry
just let me do the touching for the
stuff you you kind of know that the some
of the sounds over sounds a lot like a
lot of these like really Reggie races so
you could try talking to them but you're
not sure what would get like if would
actually get across or not depends on
what you say just want to look back
around it's like all right either I got
two options bro I'm either gonna make
this a fair fight and make the ogre
bigger look or I can soothe him to make
him not angry what do you think still he
could still be confused or confuse
doesn't yeah maybe be less likely to
attack or I could mermaid on it back
yeah I could make the mermaid big too I
don't terrified of having giant mermaid
20 loose well that running but you know
clearly of the twins you're the smarter
one so what do you think I should I
think we need to double down on
operation make pause giant Steve already
make pulses bigger even bigger even
bigger I don't know what why hold on
hold on
no it only goes it's based on its normal
size damn it's like Rob thought of those
or so you can't you can't you can't
enlarge twice and I would I wouldn't are
you doing it because if he rolls low the
card even says a low role will inversely
affect any given I'll shrink a movie
role slow but um at a crossroads here
but hey you can roll 20 and then you
know pauses just be the size of the
dungeon he'll be cramped at that point
it'll be like is there any like debris
or anything obstructions in the hallway
that we can see only pause it's like
it's a very great great tunnel cement
floor it's it looks like it's been
carved honestly we're pauses pants where
is pants oh yeah was he holding them he
was holding them he's got he's kind of
just got them on his side he's got it
like tucked in under you know monk
mounds of fat oh no no yeah just a dwarf
beer belly roll he just kind of put it
under there cuz he's huge and he's just
reacting really quick you know house
keeps all sorts of things in his dwarf
belly rule that's fine sure he does is
it possible to run around the two of
them oh nice to run around no you did
you'd have to you Dennis wish you'd have
to squish is it over squish against the
ground right now yeah he's down on the
ground New York has his face visible uh
yep his face would be right towards you
so looking at dead bones he's kind of
like the eye he's like a dog on the
ground it's from also sad though he's
got a fat dude on top do of course he's
designed give a peek guy here here's the
problem we've already kind of made our
bed with this one we can see it haha
yeah you're probably right OH what are
we gonna learn not to touch e it was on
a car that things what's sultry so
pauses pauses pant I can't pause the
pants aren't visible to me I can't see
them uh no pause you can't see pauses
pants right not unless you just want to
reach into his beard you can see his big
heroic dong though I don't know if I
want to reach it oh my god those aren't
pants
that's not you know what no I'm gonna go
up I'm gonna try and reach in to pause
this bowl and roll I need his fucking
pants man how can we not know but this
is so obvious alright alright den BOS
walks up he starts to reach around pause
pause is not paying attention he's
trying to deal with all these mermaids
and stuff a dead ones comes in he grabs
pause his pants and his wallet Oh Sees
little his little kool gold purse so I
gotta run pants yeah and pauses 584
pieces of gold do I have his Jim that he
picked up and started under you do can i
store that away you can can I put the
pants back Maggie yeah now you need to
roll to see if pause notices if you're
gonna try and put it back though okay
you don't up all right cause notices you
putting your pants paws you just saw
dead bones like he's like reaching into
your underneath your belly gret touching
your stuff do you care are you paying
attention this is a few anyway you don't
know he's probably taking anything
you're just kind of confused why pause
reacts by just laughing season edibles
doesn't think the whole for erection for
paws of each owe all of us alright
because of this strange situation here
we're gonna roll for just to see if paws
has one of those awkward boners where
he's naked skins touching skin he's got
these two hot mermaids that he's playing
up around got a remount the ocean he
keeps getting hitting the bride he keeps
him great he keeps growing in size all
right those paws have a boner no he does
not oh I didn't finish by backing up a
little bit yeah sure not even like a
half
back over to Roman I want to be back
next to Roman there we go all right
pause is your turn you got the ogre
pinned on the ground you get these
mermaids in your lap you've just been
tickled hmm let Lee ogre at this point
by the way is whimpering like a dog okay
is it yeah he's whimpering okay so uh
I'm sitting down right now right yep
like so if i were to lower the mermaids
would that actually hurt me no I don't
know you could just place them down
background that's fine so can I attempt
to snap the ogres neck then yeah you're
gonna put the mermaids down and snap a
stick yes yeah sure go read it fuck this
oh goody good fucking wrecked all right
uh you move down and you snap the overs
neck the ogre is now dead nice good job
bro can i scavenge for for loot oh let
me forget sure you can yeah I want to
get hey hey I got a thing it wasn't just
feel impose okay uh you look down the
ogres got some really big pants you can
look that in your current size seems to
be you know pretty beneficial do you
wanna do you want those you take the
overs pants do you want to shoes uh what
kind of shoes are they uh they honestly
they're not really shoes they seem to be
handmade they're just another air
jordans know they're just literally been
a lot of them okay you don't take the
letter e boots lovely boots are still
there and then there's a hammer with an
inscription on it Oh read that take yeah
let's dip let's pick that up let's take
out big would that be when he shrinks
though there be food squish him so he's
got to be careful I don't don't what I
said I'll read it pause picks up the
hammer read the inscription and it says
to the best dad ever loved crunchy oh no
dad guess you are some today
sighs dead murder him yeah careful cloud
dad what in the hell is calm down