you got these two sleeping mermaids
stuck to tiny paws pile of gems pause at
the end of day you're still the older
brother what's the plan here man you
gotta you gotta get right now the
brothers overall just I don't think I'm
gonna be able to go far I'm fucking
tiger than average and I'm having to
carry two female it's like Justin Justin
will help wait Rob mm-hm how Paul's has
it been an hour yet no since we've taken
the mermaids away i would i would say
there's probably only half hour the
mermaids are asleep but if you're trying
to ask if they're dehydrated you look at
them they're getting a little less green
a little more brown on the skin color
there Oh No samee who are sprinkled with
orange juice that might be worth more
I'm not sure droid mermaid you know what
I'm sold I'll do that i will rehydrate
the mermaids using one of my two at
bottles of apple juice okay go ahead and
roll you sure you want to give those
mermaids apple juice Oh Jacob sighs Jake
I told I don't know what's gonna happen
okay and roll ok ok good hydrogen what
happens when you give mermaids um apple
juice yeah well do Stephanie goodnight
really pisses them off like really busy
bee buzzes him off he already pissed off
whoops all right pause puzzling sound
starts pouring apple juice into one of
the mermaids mouth waking her up into an
absolute craze now she's flailing she
goes to say Apple salute hassles yes
absolute craze okay bye ghost tries to
slash at pause she's absolutely in a
blitz now she misses she's frantically
panicking as she's you know basically
suffocating on land tied to a more
manage gave you some bad well a little
commentary there um no she's not really
a threat she's just panicking alright
Justin go knock her out
oh this why were you any good yeah so
you're not the boss of me you're not my
new cloud that we're older than you
right where's cloud dad cloud I can make
him do it all right that's if that's if
cloud dad wants me to whatever he'll be
fine can we just ignore posted let him
handle it yo yeah we get absolutely no
pause yeah I like that plan suddenly a
large loud sound I mean you guys know
what's coming your mouse over it anyway
day your dad shows up and that shows up
daddy he comes running in he says I need
your help sons hmm ok John dar has an
entire kobold army protecting him I
didn't want to tell you guys but I'm
here for alternative motives John dar is
the man who killed my father and I he
want and I want revenge I wanted a guy
who killed I want daddy wants help
killing daddy's murderer new father yep
wait new father-daddy kill his kill the
guy who murdered his dad so your
granddad basically yeah yeah Hotel
avenging grandad you know we can I speak
up yeah everyone I want to let you guys
know that uh I saw our father walk
through skeletons and they did not be
aggressive towards him why you dad you
explain what the hell just happened
there that was after that super awkward
fucking husband Jamie well guy oh my god
dad you're so cool when I grow up yeah
Cormac explains that they're just like T
Rexes only in reverse and so if you keep
moving they can never lock on with their
eyes to see you because they don't
actually have eyeballs they're just
seeing with some sort of magical sonar
they have but as long as you flow like
the wind and are constantly moving
Felton's can't see you as long as you
were silent and quick you know it's
gonna be a fucking awkward hug you could
have told me that he was busy he just
wanted to see if he I mean it wasn't
responsibility he under like yoga you
guys have to understand that I mean he's
not your surrogate father right and he
didn't want to burden
you guys with this this job yes the
issue yeah well I mean he just thought
he could get it done and catch up with
you guys but he actually thought you
guys would be done by now and he could
meet in the next dungeon but hey you
know he's here to see what's been going
on he asks hey what's with the mermaids
dad bonesy can you wanna you want in on
this papa you want it hey new dad you
want a mermaid well why would he want to
mermaid you just go we don't get a
mermaid at the super story is no 1i
mermaid now we as candies for wait
there's mermaid superstores yeah
mermaids aren't that rare I mean they're
rare for dwarves but wars over the
mountains mermaids are like every ocean
you can go to it's a fantasy could sell
them to some idiot outside yeah come on
give a corner as a punishment for her
policy are these otter chained who honor
change these I did all right he walks up
he goes to the first murmured whispers
penis no he's a power breaks the chains
and then he's it and then now unless one
of you wants to interrupt he is taking
his sword and about to decapitate the
mermaid on the left nope maybe what you
want to stop daddy from decapitating a
mermaid nope I'll interrupt ways on why
wait go no let me interrupt yep I like
them over the movie i believe i
volunteered to interrupt first took it
down cuz i was gonna drag who co please
uh with your interrupt what are you
gonna do i am going to try to bring up a
filter to protect the mermaid you're
gonna kill new dad look Noel why do you
wanna bad what does everyone hate Newton
it's the last dad God Oh much better
than old I'm sure he has there's old day
mija oh oh do excuse i'll i don't really
trust new dad myself i'm in the same
boat mommy yeah kind of no lakers all
right uh you try to go some of the
pillar but dad is way too fast for that
and dad slams down the acts as fast as
he can or the sword as fast as he can
uh oh and just slices off her head he
then grabs cuts off a piece of her tail
and he puts it in his knapsack wait wait
i was still changing me though no
they're both broken the penis breaks
them both this one's still asleep by the
way this one is the one that was going
crazy he just put out his misery dad can
we add how come you kept the fin uh beef
turkey brief jerky son they're really
really tasty helps with stay on the
problems when you come up with mermaids
you just cut off the fins huh no it's
like beef jerky it helps with soon
that's why put the other one please can
you keep it cuddle yeah I want a prat no
you can get one when we get home we we
can't carry we can you maintain who you
named it okay how about about this okay
um how about I take the mermaid into the
other room okay and I'll call my friend
and he'll come pick her up and she'll
get to go live on a mermaid farm right
near a really nice ocean and you guys
can visit her later I'm not it's gonna
flush her I'm not an idiot dad if you
want me to kill that I'll kill myself
then fine please just kill it look we
have stuff we have to do we got to get
this done she's she's sleeping honestly
I've already I've already alerted the
the bow pants guards he knows there's
people going around his dungeon right
now secure is gonna come up yeah that's
what still asleep just does anybody have
a pillow wait it's suburban I don't
think I can suffocate it weighs leave it
yes you can just walk away sure to use a
pillow for god sakes the enzyme exact
fix let me cut its throat no I got I'm
interrupting okay ocoee hello wait he's
the car just going on top of the mermaid
errs and lifting it up it's uh no it's
going in her mouth it's grand all went
in her mouth went inside Oh is he
suffocating her yeah yeah okay roll the
have Randall kill kill her no this is
the gentlest way all right he's gonna do
out that
this is the general knows a straight-up
gangster Randall refuses to do it like
go code tries to make Randall do it
Randall does not have that much trust
with co feels is not ready to take a
life Randall just refuses to do it good
on her head okay look look I will teach
you how to be a good father one day go
to your baby but not today you're gonna
smash the mermaids head just smell smash
the mermaids head with my human nature
make your dad proud okay if you get over
a 14 I'll say good job gonna win right
Rome in the swings Roman is really
nervous to impress dad you can't do it
oh he just you can't you can't kill a
really hot sleep in mind it just feels
weird so what do I use this fling with
my slingshot I seem just like rocks or
some shit right dad walks up to Roman
and says oh no I'm not disappointed in
you but will it's just something we're
gonna have to work on do you understand
me I'm gonna do this for you to know
I'll do it for you today okay cuz I just
want I just want to get this I gotta
kill Chandra dude he killed my father
you guys are wasting all this time did
you wait John receives you killed Craig
or did you kill crank or cons do know
who killed Craig or did it why why would
you kill a giant ogre pause I had a bad
dream that he stole my xbox 360 and
broke it he's the most passive guy he is
the guy who told us about these tunnels
this is where he lives why would you
look dude he's got four kids jump up a
piece of paper it's never gonna be flat
straight again let it go wow you and uh
you inherited metaphors from dad all
right core Cormac Sri or fake dad here
is going to just put the mermaid out of
his misery but first where does that
he's gonna walk up and be like oh please
can can I can I take out this mermaid
if you really want her as a pet no idea
know if you really want her as a pet and
you promise to carry her on the cloud we
can keep her but if she gets in the way
she dies deal actually okay well what
about this very similar okay listen
Randall on a mission it's a very same
thing but he's just gonna take her back
to the lake and let her go no no dad's
not okay with that no dad is not okay
with that these mermaids we don't know
their alliances they could they could
tell bokken she either dies or she comes
with us I will let it come up with us
just so you guys listen to your dad bye
dad and yeah it's not over till it's
over okay you know you do this no you're
in timeout go over your are you acting
here a little bit okay you're both in
timeout you go go over there in that
corner okay you go over there by the
dead ogre think about all the dumb
things you've done today and how
disappointed it makes your father that
he has to come in here and clean up this
mess from you okay my real dad Roman you
want to give us another chance wanna
impress daddy yeah yes I'll to 10 past
at him whoa is that co you want to do
some mushrooms over here I'll take dad
plan okay don't even carry lineups Roman
Roman if that mermaid even mushrooms eat
if that murmured does anything to get in
the way of you know anything at this
point you're gonna take it out you
promised you promised daddy you'll do
that I promise okay all right where's
where's those other two boys thought you
were packing the mushroom are you guys
smoking mushrooms over there we're not
said that you can't smoke mushrooms dad
okay look I don't know I don't know what
kids do these days come on just get oh
wait this is this is a regenerative I
told you idiots you're supposed to save
this for you know boss battles or
something the foot you just eating it
who's eating this mushroom Justin he's
at full goddamn just then you look upon
what are you even done in the last hour
Justin what have you even done I'll do
cloud that is so much better than you I
left you for an hour and you all you did
was kill the ogre and bring a bunch of
mermaids with you why
even know why you're here to make a
bunch of money with pretend dad and
you're sitting around juggling mermaids
as if you're some sort of trap like I've
dad dad I found a whole bunch of gems
this gem is good are those like poison
desserts those are good you can have him
probably hedging no Jake give me dead
you did really good Jake okay dad can I
have a hug I need this right now but I'm
gonna we're gonna see how get a hug this
is okay okay roll for it I hope it Shrek
see it's a great hug dad this means so
much to me Jake between the mushroom and
your emotional high you're just feeling
on top night world right now can I try
and just like eat that mushroom like
like as dad's hugging yeah Jake cocky
little shit you're gonna be a timeout
for a while go ahead dad are you doing
this sneakily are you sneaky yeah yeah
okay father 20 so of course yeah great
pause pause reaches down eats the
mushroom just inhales it starting to
feel better dad doesn't even care at
this point he just he just you know what
he's having a good emotional hug with
his his boy Jake and then even whispers
the Jake you're my favorite son oh man
fake head is really good look was gentle
I need to do down sir get into the
pedophilia and he's like yield addict
these gems know you are among my
favorite bed-stuy all right come on so
are you guys coming with that or what
hey Jake I let about you while you're
hugging I don't daddy right now fuck it
dude like I'm the first man on Mars fuck
that as NASA mission deed meet me and my
mini party you're gonna hang in here oh
you're gonna go we're kind of trapped by
this column oh it's just walk over top
of the yogurt it's fine oh come ons are
such babe ruth crew so we're not leaving
the dungeon I knew he was done you know
we're not leaving did you did you not
some Roman but the guy who reeled my
father is here he's done all right
here's here's what you guys are gonna do
okay you see these you see all of these
skeletons who are sleeping for some
weird reason I need you to go just go up
to every skeleton just kill them and
follow me into the next room okay do not
talk to the lion fountain why not
because wait look and I sing to the lion
film do not you see the lion fountain
remember how our original plan was to
come and talk to this lion fountain yeah
plan has changed we don't want to go
that route anymore we're gonna work look
because we have enough we have less
because well do you have a good reason
dad Aaron's dead that's a pretty good
reason okay maybe we were just getting
along when when I I thought you guys
would find his body he didn't when we
came into the first room the skeletons
caught us off guard he was still on my
shoulders just just bricked him right
against the wall ranged that corner in
the first rare and blossom erin was a
boy girl whatever I didn't I mean I felt
something it was weird i know i don't
even know you guys make fun of her
whatever anyway anyway she died okay hey
Rob yeah and I rolled to press f4
respect know that you cannot roll for
but here's here's the thing okay that
the reason why we I didn't think we
would be able to take the the lower road
through the water because I knew we
wouldn't all be able to fill it from the
boat but I think almost all of us can
now in the boat that is in you know by
the river so we can ride the boat
together sneak up on Bo pin take him out
go be rich men together will you be a
happy family again you know what I'll
introduce you to mom huh you mom is
great you guys can meet new mom cope it
right so here's the plan okay here's the
plan I'm gonna I'm gonna go go up ahead
I'm just gonna scout ahead because of
you guys follow my co doing with the
mermaid I don't know coach doing things
will see that in a second I'm gonna go
ahead okay i'm gonna i'm going to scout
ahead because if you guys all come here
make too much noise i'm going to come
right back here in two minutes
all i wanna eat well a couple minutes
ten people say let's say just cause it's
a 20k i want you guys to go in the next
room here well hold on there Jake we're
gonna go in the next room you guys are
going to kill all the skeletons grab as
many gems as you guys can stuff them in
your pockets as much treasure okay and
then we're gonna we're gonna go kill the
guy who murdered daddy you can just take
those gems and put them off to the side
Roman they're yours now yours and dead
bones is everybody okay with this
where's where's co-star he took the
mermaid did so what have you done co
have you just walked away with the
mermaid okay in the time we have a
conversation co has gone and released
the mermaid the mermaid by the way co
while she is now kind of awaked she kind
of saw you in her like she likes all you
while she was waking up that you were
like carrying her with the nimbus all
together and she's puckered her lips if
you'd like to kiss right before orbs
were something else kisses with you dick
let him do it oh god damn bj see if it's
worth it she pucker your lips for a kiss
guys look when girls popular lips they
typically don't like it if you just
unzip your pants and shove your flaccid
dick in her mouth and let's go is what
is cold look into it let's go Whistler
find out unless co was already rocking
walking hard in which case co your
motives are not pure and you should feel
bad that you were just walking around
holding a mermaid with a stiffy I'm
asking chat if I should do it or not
okay they're answering maybe she's girl
like that whole you know it's a lot of a
little overwhelmingly kiss it's kiss
okay you're gonna just roll a dice for
me okay dad what is this lion but if
you're also 20 can actually put its
ticket or mouth I lovin it iulian kiss
it's a pretty good kiss you know you
feel a little bit of spark she gives you
a little wink and a tee he dives under
the water I got away anyway about this
time is when a Cormac says where's
co-star and I'm assuming you're walking
back oh and you're gonna be like here
dude right
what's going on still hanging in the
back of the party though okay daddy
daddy what is this lion can I go can all
talk did you should not listen to me
Jake Jake first come around the corner
for home sake get over you grabs Jake
pulls you aside Jake what you're gonna
do you're gonna go out there silently
just start decapitating skeletons gay
there's a full room of skeletons they're
all asleep did you do that Jake no oh
did you do that dead bones yes that's a
good dead bones good boy putting all
those guys to sleep all right what
you're gonna do is are gonna go up there
to capitate them meet me in the next
room is everybody down with this okay
but can we talk to the lion or not no do
not talk to the lion okay meet me in the
next room after you've stolen all the
gems and decapitated all of the skeleton
Jake I'm really fucking high that line
is saying something look what bus you
can talk you can talk to it if you kill
the skeletons first nah man it's telling
me not to kill skeletons like what if we
just wake the skeletons up and I'm like
a skeleton party Roman wouldn't your dad
be mad if I chain these idiots together
no no he would not I want to use honor
chains on Paul's Justin Jake Oh is the
anchor something the anchor is Justin
because he's being quiet you damn Jess
coder Justin are you resisting yeah was
this thing how much stamina disability
33 all my things like three yeah classes
all three sixteen he resists because you
use the anchor the entire spell fails
and you take three stamina damage for it
as all three and rye though so that's
right alright let's go play with
skeletons dude wait all the Hans our
talk what do you want to do so once you
go in the room even though combat
they're all asleep we're gonna have to
start combat so whoever goes in first
that's where we're going to start on
turns and then when it rolls around to
all pass all you guys all take a turn to
see if the skeletons start waking up and
you guys kiss I lent you should be able
to go in and kill skeletons very easily
yeah we could I push that one into the
fire you don't even you just crushes
head you take me help you before we go
in can we have a kill the skeleton song
no no you don't need a song I could
paint ideas about video it means daddy
why do we need motivation under than
that why do you hate newbs montage cuz
do death is a dick dad yeah but you
can't come back he's the only dad we
have able to get back down you've cloud
that too what's it here yes I collapse
or 32 years old why do you care about a
dad as much because you killed our first
one he raped you as a child got you that
was all you all right be because you
guys are yelling we're gonna roll to see
if the sum of those skeletons wake up in
your heated discussion here and one of
them does from the yelling combat has
now started we will assume pause just
went and then I went justin is your turn
some of the skeletons are starting to
groggily get up and you can hear the
bones jingling in the other room oh no
all right uh see guy I could move over
to the skills and that woke up up here
right yep all right i'll move up to him
yeah i was gonna beat the shit out of
him so you just gotta charge in right
first like you're like oh shit these
guys are fucking up dad's plan yeah like
these guys are waking up we gotta get a
handle on this quick ok good all right
go ahead and roll all right you swing
your trustee board that you know dad
gave you with the two nails in it and
your three makes it so you get a
splinter oh shit yeah it's a really
hurts I'm but you also miss the skeleton
ok Jake is your turn alright let's see
let's see um I want to go can I can I
could I sprint to like here one two
three yeah but you wouldn't be able to
attack I wouldn't be able to attack damn
i want to push that skill into the fire
so bad to you can probably get to the
one York justin is yeah but could I push
him into the fire uh it'd be more like a
like a like a grab in
see example all right let's try to
grapple him and then push him in yeah
hey this would be good all right kind of
roll all right you grab the skeleton you
push them into the fire the CL who is
now on fire nice that's all I wanted to
see all right I'm Audi ok is now Roman
sturdy ok so my dead bones in the Boz
now wait yeah you have you just you knew
when the voices started getting raised
that shit was going down so you just saw
two of your brothers run into the room
charging at skeletons um do I remember
the noise that I heard pause making with
the clicking enacted clanking said that
that's scared the chattering oh yeah
sure unique you understand the
chattering you could probably replicate
it yeah all right gonna move out a
little bit so it's all better coverage
here and I'm gonna try and make that
noise okay aired them off yep scare them
up all right uh you walk up and when you
go to make the noise your throat is just
completely like you kind of like gag and
you have a little bit of a coughing fit
and it actually ends up waking up the
skeleton so he just is just a wake down
because your coffee 50 Roman cuz of this
coughing fit you don't really take any
damage but the start next round you're
not gonna be able to move more than
three spaces because you just feel like
out of breath because of all the
coughing you're doing from choking on
your own words a little bit give it
you're nervous to disappoint dad Morris
what's going on I think so costar you're
up you're at the very back with the
cloud here yeah um good meditate okay oh
there's meditation one okay meditation
has begun it is now dip on string so
these guns around this one's in the fire
so what happened is as you were yelling
at some point when you stop
yelling and you heard the echo when you
started hurting the bone chill jackals
and then all your brothers just sprung
into action so you're not really yelling
at paws anymore you're okay developed in
what's going on all right no more paying
attention to pause got it yeah cuz you
remember deep down you want to impress
dad and you're worried this might
disappoint dad if you just probably this
is probably gonna disappoint you dad a
lot oh this is really gonna go well for
anybody so a dad went this way yeah he
went down this way yeah I'm kind of
gonna just use my thing to sprint okay
how far now I can rolled cfii spring
roll yep just trying to see if i can
find dad making fix the problem Blaine
pause before Klaus gets chance to blame
me um you start running just sprint you
can no go no more than six though it's a
pretty crappy run two three four five
six okay you're writing to go get your
daddy yep yep I'm gonna get dad yeah
okay it's gonna work boss you're up okay
well i noticed that he's running away to
be a little fucking tattletale I am
gonna summon uh a moose so I can try and
ride to go catch dead bones can't get be
angry at me pause can't be mad i'm not
i'm worried okay okay so gotta roll for
that is this is nice yeah 17 all right
um to do three stamina one two three um
I don't have a great new scar pause but
here you go this is your companion moose
just comes dashing around the corner and
comes right to you you need to name him
fossil you need like as he comes you
need to come and give them a little
rubbing the head to seal the pact here
and then you have to use an a little
robert moran okay thank you hygiene
rubber red I can't wear your country
dead bones yeah okay remember not to
disrespect it pause I suspect to get
would make it not your ally anymore
you better treat robert moran with the
most utmost respect I will don't worry
all right so it's a white Foose is the
wife of boy who's all right at this
point in time skeletons are starting to
wake up the skeleton moves out of the
fire on fire to swing at Jake Oh Jake
Perry's the attack swings the skeleton
against this wall and the bones just
completely shatter just basically when
the scale that goes out of the fire Jake
does like a little alley oop with
skeletons body sends him flying a
flaming jake takes a little bit of
singed damage but the skeleton is just
instantly killed oh you very nice the
skeleton wakes up the Skelton wakes up
this skeleton is going to try and shoot
Roman here with a bow and arrow 14 Roman
takes a little bit of damage these are
the two skeletons move into position
after the arrow is shot this one moves
towards Jake two skeletons swinging at
Roman one misses one misses one skeleton
attacking Jake and don't even don't even
step to this oh this one hits Jake Jake
a bit damaged all right oh my damage um
jus you also hear the fountain say
adventurers come quickly to me I can
hide you from the skeletons from The
Lion King I don't like that statue haha
I'm going to get new dad this
now there's no Justin's turn clearly we
fucked up all right I on my job as I say
everyone I don't know if I trust new dad
I think we should hear that that line
fountain out you're all fucking day just
talk to it you know and and then I'm
gonna attack the skeleton right in front
of Jake right so move into position roof
from here here do won't be near the fire
away from the fire away from the fire
okay go ahead are any swing all right um
the skeleton have seen Jake do do it
does the exact same thing to you I
leaves you and you go flying over here
you take quite a bit of damage they're
just so from that hit oh no you're now
down on the ground after being thrown by
this skeleton it is now Jake's turn oh
gosh we need a Hail Mary here what if I
put all the skeletons to sleep again you
can try we could probably manage that
remember it's really hard to hit
multiple targets like that like there's
one two three four well there's to scale
it since still asleep but there's one
two three four five six still awake I
will trust my bard prowess but you're
gonna try and put all six to sleep I'm
gonna try I may fail have brothers this
may be our only chance I'll be worth it
it'll be worth it I'm still getting new
dad mmm lalala huh all right let's do
this we're here in the dungeon and stuck
with these fools we'd war van
adventurous stubborn as mules that
that's not a real dad we don't need his
rules let's talk to the Lions and steal
all the jewels roll the dice for me
let's see how many you put to sleep all
right Dan 120 pretty solid serious
no one else can it really bard again
yeah man like everyone who plays bars
classes retired three men all right Jake
I mean it was a great song really that's
cool but only on to know only this arch
is going to sleep it's not gonna affect
any of the other ones Wow let's kill the
hell out of them yeah what have been
great for some people get the panties in
a bunch Roman all right I'm gonna take
my two-hander I'm a swing at the
skeleton this guy over here okay oh
right you smash against the skeletons
the side of his body you completely
break his arm off and you do for damage
coaster is your train ride no it's not
oh you are charging that's right he hard
you know all right one more channel for
mr. kuester weapon thanks Joe yep you
got ourselves into this pause is your
train wait what oh I'm sorry it dead
bones it is your turn damn straight all
right I'm gonna go one two three and see
what i can see ok first off dad no dad
is not there uh you looked so you look
you're looking to the room ok and you
can see for cold standing by a campfire
uh-huh um you can see the lake damn no
probably connects to bow pans lair yeah
and you cannot see that so I can't see
new dad you don't know where new chadwin
oh god I don't know where new dad is but
you can see more threats up ahead so uh
feels like you actually have like dad
issues in real man I just appreciate dad
I'm not gonna fighting man I'm not built
for this shit I'm a cheerleader at best
that's how that's my lot in life well
I'm dead bones I'm just gonna keep
moving with my turn I'm gonna roll the
see how far I can go you got your still
you're running around yeah I'm gonna go
gonna go fucking take your dad up thing
is a 19-point 1919 yep yeah I'm gonna
walk over here okay uh uh you can get
just in front of the fountain but not
yet not close enough so I'll say he's
there let's say here all right I'm gonna
I'm gonna appease these fucking morons
and talk to the fountain okay pause is
your drink yes uh let's see you know
what I'm just gonna okay can i roll the
dice to see how hard I respect my my
dear right now I mean sure I gotta suck
my waifu okay to see why you were trying
it okay if you want to know how much you
respect it yep do you expect respect
robert moran the answer is uh barely
barely alright sounds about right so you
know what I'm gonna actually take my
well if I'm riding my mousse how far can
I go um if you were writing your mousse
let's say you have a movement speed of
10 ooh yeah so I'm gonna go up help Jake
out and I'm gonna throw my spear at the
skeleton so yeah reading your moose all
right you're gonna throw either your
sugar at point-blank yeah that's not
really point-blank that's one block away
yeah okay yeah well I mean yep go ahead
and roll ok son of a bitch you throw
your spear it goes right through his
bones you don't even hit him just the
native speaker is now embedded into the
wall right it is skeleton time um a law
allowed horn is played and it echoes
throughout the entire dungeon wakes up
skeletons all of the skeletons begin
running to the room dad went to hmm
they're just ignoring everything they
just want to move at this point but now
we can talk to the lion they're gonna go
dad outline is awesome photography
they're gonna kill new dad uh combat is
started but only if somebody wants to
continue attacking the scale
Elton's else they are just going to
blitz out of the room Valentin when this
horn has played the gems stop spewing
from the goblet there's obviously still
gems all around it but gems have also
stopped is the fountain flowing fountain
is still flowing does anybody actually
want to stop these skeletons now that's
good well no I think I bet yeah it's not
a trip one into the five I miss New dad
I don't want to fight anymore skeletons
whatever new dad I'll get a new dance at
a guy you can t walk by skeletons once
he can take skeletons and kobolds okay
um so we're coming up here on midnight
I'm actually probably good for another
hour but is there anybody else that has
to bow out because of just how late it
is for Sunday yeah yeah so we need a
good reason Roman for you to or would
you rather just somebody play as you you
can pick one of your brothers to play as
he's dead bones can play as mean we can
control devils from now on you will play
as Roman but you although you guys are
similarly mind you still have to play
for him if you try to do things as right
think Roman wouldn't do as this current
character okay not allowed okay and you
will lose control and it will be given
to another brother Roman if Deb bones
loses control who gets it who's like the
second in command it's killed me but
it's gonna be Co yeah it's a D'Amico
yeah that's gotta be Co it's ok he'll be
sleep guys all right i'll come back
addicted of mushrooms and who knows
alright well let's take a quick
two-minute break here just to everybody
get a drink and stuff well Roman sit say
takes off and then we'll come back we'll
do one more hour and try to resolve this
camp there's no way we're finishing this
camp a try to finish up the campaign
enough but my son's life this look at
let's convene oh it's loose they'll be a
mess up again with you ok cool