[Music]
in the middle of this discussion a man
comes in the bar and approaches Jake and
and he recognizes him
Jake you recognize this man it is
clearly Cormac an assistant of Annisa
VIN an associate of yours he says hey
what's up chick and I say we're here
with my brother he's really mad he's
getting revenge for his dad my guitar
down peace I couldn't find my mandolin
in time somewhere downstairs how many
instruments here Cormac Jake says it's
great to see you
he's glad you're here the wizard of this
town you already know him miss 'van
actually has a request of you guys it's
gonna pay a lot like you guys are all
gonna retire forever the plan he's got
it's a great swindle great little like
robbery the you guys can pull off I mean
if you're into it it's gonna be
dangerous
and if you're right and if you are
interested to uh you know you can meet
him at this giant lodge he points it out
the directions over here to meet up on
this event and get the get the you know
the raw details of what's gonna have to
go down did I interrupt sure why does
this have been fighting his lower lip
that's Cormac that's not that's not
really excited yeah he's really excited
about this cool mission he's actually
gonna be cooking he says he's gonna be
coming with you guys if you will accept
his help I'm not gonna lie that's the
same look that our Father gave us before
he touches us and is gonna trigger you
yeah you trigger face can you sing him
out of here please before I do something
a lot of em huh rancor mark this is
getting a little awkward it's not a cute
magical girl over there
I think which was diff you left way with
the green one here know that yeah I
guess the one if you mouse over it says
mail elf that's that's a boy no no the
the wench the Earl lady bar you don't
you don't know her just just some random
girl on the winch Aaron the biter and
ignore this motherfucker yeah okay so
Jake and Cormac are apparently
serenading each other and we're doing
some barbershop tags and Aaron's gonna
just slip past here cuz you know after a
mental breakdown in front of his family
the next thing he wants to do is you
know go hit on a lady in the middle of a
tavern so just I'm just feeling really
lonely right now I just you know my
brother and I talked it out and I sort
of got over it but I'm still feeling a
little emotional right now what's your
name my name is Samantha it's very nice
to meet you
it's beautiful name it's really
beautiful um what time do you get off oh
well I'm actually working I'm actually
looking to get involved in a job what do
you get here what are you boys here in
town for I'm worst of all I'm a girl oh
that's right well I mean the rest of you
are boys the term I mean technically
it's the works I can say you know what
are you guys I'm not really trying to
make any associations to gender at this
point I was just semantics really wait
who the fuck did you hook me up with the
lady warrior yeah why did you want to
talk to the bar boys Oh
dude she blew you come dude she blew you
complete off you're talking to lady
warrior how did you drink anything
no all right a little apple juice that I
has in my satchel you had apple juice in
your satchel well I wanted fresh apple
juice but I keep some around in case
these bars don't have apple juice okay
that makes sense it's a little fermented
at this point but Oh God
well my mom you you are talking while
you were talking to this woman you
didn't even want to talk to she is
interested in offering her aid if you
guys would like another companion on the
adventures she will only charge you 300
goal today which because I don't you
know this I know you guys don't know the
economic
cool today's equivalent of you know 200
bucks us Wow - come on are we well-off
Dwarves
yes you you you have a decent amount of
money I'd say individually all of you
are carrying around no maybe like a
thousand to five thousand gold on you
each okay we're like upper middle class
yeah yes you have you have money but
you're not but you you're still working
we're conservative talk radio listeners
we all have gold investments yeah
Michael Jackson yep the see definitely
not not Michael Jackson in any way he
was very far away from Michael Jackson
his first name actually wasn't even Mike
he just told you guys that
that's how messed up you know what I'm
furnace I didn't know remain remember
your character still doesn't know that
fact that's just part of the knowledge
you know oh your character does he does
anybody have any knowledge about dad yep
okay
egos trying to think really really hard
to see if he actually knew his father
deep down wasn't Michael and you know
what he's still unsure he's deep down
he's he's starting to think his father
might not actually have been Michael
Jackson but you know maybe he was I am
yes not all of us girls Aaron are you
interested in the lady warriors
assistance what are you interested in
the Lady Warriors assistance assistant
and getting my pants off your remember
your else are you a are you a girl who
likes girls is that what we're gonna
know I like all thing I'm pansexual okay
okay very good
so the lady will come join you in your
party and you guys build the you know
you won't play for her this is how NPC
characters they will just react on their
own but because
has introduced her to the party here
she'll most likely kind of ouais
attribute to staying near Aaron because
Aaron is her you know she's the talking
point she's she's she now knows Aaron
she's talked to him a little bit they
connected on a girl level you know then
maybe there's maybe there's a spark
there we don't know it's fucking
misogynistic dude we just connected all
right god I'm sorry that is that it's
good point
man the AI in this game sucks hey guys
what do you think a lady warrior huh
she's my new friends I think she's all
right I don't know how she fits all that
in there is that what you said to her
you can she sing hold on no she's gonna
roll the slap are you gonna attempt to
dodge this yeah sure I mean yeah go
ahead go ahead and roll to see if you
dodge the warrior slap you definitely do
not only wait we we know really yes yes
we're gonna start using class abilities
a little revoir
okay okay that's great so just then
Justin needs to roll for shiver Lea
basically Justin's gonna use an ability
to jump in front and take the slap for
his brother oh go ahead and roll here
buddy shit
very good Justin Justin jumps in front
and takes the hit that's pretty
impressive damn dude nice work all right
lady has no interest in working with you
guys now though you just now do Devlin's
just completely blew it she thinks
you're Orange
okay well the bar wench is coming back
to see if you guys needed a refill
I need a refill of your friendship in my
life she's she doesn't really like you
know dating customers she's flattered
but very much not interested all right
look I'm not looking for a date I'm
looking for a serious committed
relationship what do you what are you
what are you looking for
she's really getting creeped out back
off a little bit and just says again
she's just really not interested she's
just trying to work the day she's
getting off in about two hours here and
really just you know she's not she's not
having a good day today she actually
found out today that her dad died and
her dad is not actually Michael Jackson
apparently that is a really popular
rumor going around like people father's
like to pretend they're Michael Jackson
and she's she's having a bad emotional
day I lend a caring hand to her and say
you know I can relate that exact same
thing happened to me and I think we
should talk about it roll dice roll okay
come on 20 come on 20 all right
you walk forward trying to say you know
exactly what you're trying to get across
there and fall completely on your face
and actually chip your front tooth check
this out all right you want to get a
tourniquet on this immediately I'm
trying to win her over
I'm doing wingman duty here man
trust me on this one oh damn
the bartender moves up towards like the
edge of the bar this is our problem here
guys cuz you guys are now starting to
surround its employee starting to get
slightly worried no there's no problem
we're just trying to give a helping hand
to our friend what was your name lady
bar wench the bartender is now gonna
have to ask you guys to leave know that
she's already clearly politely declined
out she's backing up again she's gone
behind the bar counter now and she's the
bartender has now asked you guys to
leave sucks core mugs like hard to get
Cormack walks up and says asks if you
guys would like to follow him or if you
would rather meet him at Nyssa Vince
banner banner do this events manner it's
the place you guys are going to make all
this money today yeah I don't know where
it is so we better follow this dude well
I say we just
there because like I said I got urges to
kill him right now the only custody was
forward thinking like a lot of ale right
now and I kind of fucking yeah
motherfucker get out of here
which way do I go to get out oh there
were the doorways the doorways over here
Oh guys I'm gonna lose it
oh okay Jay can you please roll dice
you're gonna go over here and see if you
have to throw up oh god you're gonna be
able to hold it in oh I do come on 20
wait what happened Jake you throw up I
was a head reverb on that ego what are
you doing no what's going on here what
are you trying to do did you just jump
on the bar the counter I just thought we
could be friends anyway this guy okay
the bartender ego you're gonna jump on
top of the bar table apparently no no
don't put a heart around it tonight can
I knock him out so yes carry him over
that's fine I blow the younger brother
yep go ahead to roll out ego I don't
want the cops come walk do you what do
you want to try and resist this at all
aranaut yeah I'm gonna use rolling fog
okay yeah go ahead
after a great start there we go rolling
fog to fog up the joint and get the fuck
out of there with my winch I'm gonna
grab her with me and she'll come with me
okay
pause you go to grab your little brother
he rolls out of the way he rolls out of
the way and casts a special fog in the
area starting to make it really hard to
see in the bar right okay the bartender
and the and the lady in the wench
because of this fog immediately start
moving out of the vicinity kind of reset
the one girl is actually screaming cuz I
mean one dude just started like spewing
fog out of his hands it's not looking
good I chase after lady wench girl can't
very good
the bartender gives you one last chance
he's like dude you need to just step
down right now or it's gonna get ugly I
I go look I'm having a really bad day
and I just I just need somebody to talk
to and they reminded me of me as a girl
I guess the baby
the lady wore the lady bar which
actually comes up he says larec look
dude I got to tell you something I'm not
actually a girl you need to just step
down all right that's that's a
deal-breaker we're we're moving on well
I just I my girl character is into girls
yeah I know well but she was up the
whole time I mean no I said I was
pansexual so okay cool yeah the the fog
is now enveloping the entirety of the
bar cause I'm gonna need you to roll
you're gonna have to come out of here
choking or coughing you have a little
coughing fit as this flammable gas goes
down into your lungs very good you get
out of there no no problem slightly
probably peeved at your brother the the
bar wench and the elf and the warrior
they all just kind of like move out even
further because they just want to get
away from the fog fuck this shit I'm
gonna do my Kamehameha blast on the
entire goddamn all right you're gonna
cast your flare so flare you can
customize it in any way what are you
trying to do with your flare really I
want the bar to burn for 40 years
okay I don't know if you have that exact
ability but you can try that in your
mind you're trying to create some sort
of explosion that will burn forever all
right very good
ego shoots a flare into the bar and
who's got red Justin will you put this
entire thing on fire the entire thing
explodes because that is the rolling fog
is now encompass the entirety of the bar
it's
flammable he's now excited it I'm gonna
need everyone to roll to jump out of the
way of the oncoming explosion I'm
specifically Aaron and pause here who
are in the front of the doorway and are
about to take the brunt of the blast
leap out of the way oh my gosh nineteen
so it's alright I mean he cast that he's
fine when actually mountain okay go
ahead pause try and mount them mid roll
over here's rolling it towards the fog
that it pause seven alright your
Mountain fails you go which way you
jumping you jump it over here here
towards my friends over there you're why
I'm not sure who are your friends
I'm Jeff well I burned their fucking
town so obviously they're not my friend
anymore so my family members all right
you're you're completely clean pause you
try to jump on Aaron as he's running by
you fail you're gonna take a blast of
the face of this explosion I love lots
of the face don't worry I need other
people rolling now dead bones I'm really
far away do I really need to roll that
is not far man you're a couple meters
away this thing that's going up in
flames and that's how you really you
don't roll this way roll that way you're
fine you can get out of the way Justin
alright 16 good we still learned good
rules please Jake you're gonna have a
big trouble dodging this because you're
still mid barf yep also I left my loot
in the bar yeah that's gone hmm
you you can roll we can roll y'all roll
to tell you how damaged it is we uh you
know what
I think it might be salvageable it might
be salvageable we might need to restring
it but you're going in during the
explosion here
so you're like you're like mid barf
stream man it doesn't matter I'm like
he's the barf - put it out yeah that's
that's the whole point make it last I
have entered into the fog never drifting
again
yeah I'll reveal this part for you since
we're close to it oh yeah there you go
I was just 1 square off all right let's
go in here and get my loot okay it's mid
explosion so what do you try are you
trying to like dive through the
explosion to get your loot like you're
like oh shit my loot and you're gonna
it's right near the door cuz I was
hanging out with dude bro
before our macro john carmack alright
fantastic that was we're gonna try to do
better rules than this next time though
Jake that's all I got my loot can I roll
to like just walk away from the bar like
a badass well if you just roll the 20 so
here's what's gonna happen okay you go
into the bar you've grabbed your loot
the explosions coming you kind of duck
and we've died dodging all the flames a
little bit singe as your clothes but you
get out completely unscathed
and like reflexes you have a choice
would you like to grab the hand of your
older brother and pull him away you know
you know let me borrow some of that
chivalry let's just get him out of here
do you have four Oh
you didn't take the borrow ability you
can't do that ah well then fuck it
forget it
alright go you're the last one to jump
roll out of the way oh great and co you
kind of a little bit you don't get out
of the way you also get hit by the blast
alright he gets hit by the blast cloth
of fireball that you just caused in the
bar man the whole thing's on fire well
what happens does he die no I just you
just you just took some damage you just
got singed a little bit that's all
how do you know how much damage I don't
know if you load up the stream you can
look but right now everyone's fine pause
and you were a little bit you know
exhausted but everybody's fine
of course we gonna be burning just 40
years though yes no that's what he tried
it like when he was picturing it to
throw his little spirit bomb he's thing
I'm gonna burn this fucking thing for
forty years but then he just kind of
threw it was a very wild unpredictable
flare he did which is what the hell I
was like 18 for that shit it should be
at least like 25 25 what years okay
it's just explosion that's how fire
works in your mind like a little a
little flame on my shoulder for 25 years
like I'm my pauldron there yes that's
that's fine yeah there you go on that
Barbie no except that you your brother
co has gotten a little bit burned and
for some reason the fire just keeping
and he's gonna keep that as a reminder
of what you did air and just give me
this little flame on him is just gonna
be burning forever he's like 25 fucking
years man you see this I gotta have this
for 25 years because of you
good by the way excuse me my name is
thanks sorry you're some sorry thanks is
your name Thanks there's things yes and
thanks the monk confusing all right the
the bartender everybody else is
screaming on fire Cormac comes out
yelling what the hell what what why is
the bar on fire hold on hold on this
bitch was all like yo I don't want
anything to do with you and I was like
shit man I mean come on really the bar
down that thing's gonna be burning for
at least 20 years or so cuz my fire no
ahh that size of yeah it's like that's a
20-year fire if that's what Cormac
thinks it's probably 20 years back I'm
gonna be cross with you if you don't
smarten up buddy I got I got flames that
can burn for 25 years and don't even
fucking try to say 20 all right fine
it's 30 years okay it's a thirty year
fire very good core core max a little
peeved but honestly he doesn't really
care about the bartender this is a town
that they're staying and they don't
really care whatever he's sick he's
shady motherfucker he doesn't he doesn't
care he looks at him he's like
look I have a job for you seven you guys
interested are you just gonna be dick
around letting burning buildings down
all day I put out my hand for a secret
handshake this is a handshake you and
Cormac already know are you just hoping
that he like knows about the secret
handshake we will roll for know okay
we're gonna roll to see if Cormac knows
the secret handshake Aaron is trying to
make happen he does oh so you get a
little bond of hands you do like one of
those fist bumps you know will to twirl
a the fingers oh he fucking knows yeah
he knows it was like ah very good
I see you also know the handshake of the
George Klan George Jordans the George
Klan very good how long its name George
everyone is named George in that Klan
you know actually you look familiar
Aaron you look you look much like a man
he used to know also named George well
not he wasn't really George but I mean
in the George Klan everybody has to be
called George his name was like George
Mike Mike Jackson what yeah yeah you
knew my father your father really Wow he
was a great man I mean look yet he has
probably a pedophile no really in the
George Glenn yeah head full uh-huh
really yeah that's what I heard what a
night is that true that Wow you kiss you
guys murdered your own father that's
well are you really that far away
okay good yeah yeah yeah all right in
the middle of this uh stunning
revelation we're gonna have mr. missive
in here over here he's gonna come out
it's got a car to the bar see the fire
and be like
just facepalm right away very upset you
know you guys were supposed to come here
to meet up for a plan and he already
knows that you're a rambunctious crew of
gentleman things like this happen all
the time especially because of your
little brother and her little sister and
he's not really he's not really pleased
with you guys he just walks up and he's
just like what did she do Aaron he's a
known by the way so you're actually even
taller than him you got like two or that
one to two feet over top of him in
height wise small little wizardy guy
wielding a rainbow we staff he's just
like what did you do Aaron did you burn
down the bar that's gonna burn for at
least 20 years man look my my siblings
can vouch for me they want to you know
explain yeah I do I talked with this
therapist the other day it appears as
though he's diagnosed with IE d which is
intermittent explosive disorder and it's
just kind of like a big temper tantrum
and he's got out of control because he
didn't get his way with this this woman
who turned out to be a male and
apparently now this building's pretty
for like 30 years or so
25 actually 25 sorry all right miss 'van
is going to walk up and try to put out
the fire does anyone want to actually
intervene yeah dude yeah kind of a shame
about the whole bar and everything but
um yo could I touch your rainbow staff
once can we roll for that can I touch
his rainbow staff you're at weight are
you gonna like do that whole thing where
like you asked permission but then
before he answers just kind of touch it
anyway
yeah I'm heart it's already like in my
mouth okay go in the middle of God
blames are you trying to touch it with
your hands or the mouth also he's aiming
his staff at the bar to cast a spell to
put it out okay carry on okay so you're
not gonna try and put it in your mouth
it looked like candy I'm sorry it's not
candy it's his wizardy staff man I'm
really messed up right now oh okay you
just say can I try to kind of put my
shoulder just just my shoulder
oh great right there yeah okay
does anybody else actually want to stop
missive in from putting out this fire
yeah I do
what the fuck it's my fire okay well you
know what I I want it I want to stop him
he's gonna probably like burnt
dissipates house down because of this
probably best that we just let this this
stupid bar burn okay
this event understands your your logic
he's just like yeah whatever just get
them pause please get them under control
okay therapy whatever a muzzle just I'm
a girl get her under connector pills
back at home yeah I promise you we will
get them as soon as I we get back there
okay just just just get her under
control I can't have this happening man
like I came here the people are good
people like this that's gonna be like at
least a couple hours of work once he's
out of here like you know how long it
takes that you know how long it takes
out to put a 20-year fire it's like 20
minutes of magic you just fucking hurry
up I fucking hate gnomes wait a minute
wait did somebody let him drink apple
juice oh yeah oh no not again
all right I talked about this and every
time and every single time juice needs
good
you know you're not supposed to empty if
I don't serve some apple juice in me I'm
gonna hold smash everybody all right all
right miss living here is that he's
conjuring up some apple juice all right
miss miss VIN has conjured you seven
bottles of apple juice oh how am I gonna
carry all this shit doesn't even he
doesn't even expect you to care at all
he's expecting you to carry two for you
you care to oh that's so nice hey you
guys can have try to win you over I'm
trying to lose anybody wants some apple
juice
I would love some apple juice I do not
have any psychological trauma ruleset
here will juice you don't need to freak
out every time you drink it make some
apple wine jerk oh yeah you can start
fermenting know what I'm gonna share it
with all you guys
here have each person have all thank you
thank you thank you it's buddy okay
let's just have everybody up
what if you don't want anybody wait what
if we do want this apple juice you are
you are you not drinking the apple juice
I don't we don't know we don't need a
bar okay we can make our own bar dead
bones doesn't want to drink the apple
juice though is that okay I'm pretty
high tolerance I can take this let's
just do it okay uh average their
friendship miss have been is just this
still face bombing he's just he gives
positive no he's like look dude I don't
understand how you guys can spend this
long on the place where you just get the
quest so here you go here's what I need
you to do okay
this is guy his name's bokken he's some
sort of skeleton king he likes to
collect lots of rubies he's got tons and
tons of money but all of that is paled
to comparison because he has the
location of an abandoned dragon den one
second
yep can I can i bug aaron to bring him
over into a corner where Nissel bin
won't hear us yeah sure all right I mean
this one was mid conversation that's
slightly rude yeah fucking fucking okay
yeah that's fine okay all right
what's that so brother killer dude I'm
really worried about deer your your your
explosive impulses that's happening all
the time here's what I'm thinking okay
mr. Finn he called you up apple juice
right yeah what if we steal that one of
his so then that way always have apple
juice you know what I think I've
forgiven you for killing your father
see we could work this through man you
could work this through you want to seal
your seal that wand yes I do
I hope I so do okay this heaven walks up
and just gives you the goddamn wand it's
it's not even he doesn't even care about
this he's just like first off I can hear
you you didn't walk off that far you
walk it's a couple feet second I don't
care I just need you to go find the
location of this abandoned dragon den
that's all I need all right whatever you
want as long as you give me the wand
guys guys try look at that one delicious
missive in hands the wand to Aaron Aaron
here you go you may have the magical
rainbow apple juice summoning
he also watches you how to conjure apple
juice so you will never have unlimited
magic juice but it's how do you how do
you conjure now he just has to you you
just has to really think about what he
wants and the one produces it but really
it's only the cap it's only limited to
apples and juice okay I do have a wand
okay does it pour out gently into the
cupboard is it just like spurt
everywhere
oh no he actually summons it bottle and
all it comes preval maisie like you just
spray people down with that could be
like an offensive technique what are
allergic to apple juice or people that
are allergic glass she's not glass no
meat no they monitor comes free bottle
then it's like a milk filled with apple
juice no the bottles come out in spurts
no they just he just he just conjures it
with the one aims at a location a bunch
of bottles appear how do they not break
them all they they appear on the ground
it's like you know in Star Trek when
they like digitize something in with the
Replicators they just got another great
yeah it's like it's just getting like
beamed in it's like and there's some
bottles of water on the ground or
bottles of apple juice on the ground is
it absolutely you know it does it does
use his his stamina okay it's like I
have the one now right you do have the
wand alright I want to conjure a lady
bar wench that really wants me okay you
haven't fully mastered the one but by
all means go ahead and try to carry all
right I'm gonna try here we go all right
you can't successfully conjure two
bottles of apple juice one of these
bottles though however one of the
bottles is actually sent in it is just
kind of like hopping but you can see
that it's alive now
yeah you've conjured miss 'van is
actually just keys of like walking up
he's like why don't you do look you got
to give it a name
alright um Randall what we how did you
you just conjured life we have to kill
it right away miss Randall
how do you kind of life is it living
this is the beginning of something great
imagine the possibilities creating life
out of a wand Jake Jake Aaron has handed
you the rainbow wand miss 'van has now
explained he's left a note
if paws needs to check what to do he's
now started to move back into his house
because he's just like I'm done with
this is that dude just someone to
fucking living breathing bottle of apple
juice I'm adding it yeah well yeah
shakes his head and walks away I just
wanted a that this is a really huge
moment for pansexuality