but anyway it is now dead bones turn the
sorcerer we're gonna try give me one
more roll to see if he can take control
of the sauce hilton's you know what he's
gonna die right he's just going on down
with a fight he's a necromancer yeah but
he's got other necromancer skills right
um in my experience necromancer's kind
of assholes and if they're gonna lose
their gonna do something real dirty okay
yeah what are you sensing corpse
explosion okay I mean you can't there's
no like real bodies down there anywhere
on himself on a cell phone ok go for it
I love it you're gonna blow up real body
it's in character character yeah let's
see how necromancer's our dicks the ride
sore loser man it's just everybody died
today so I'm still with Chrissy ok he
tries to corp explode it's successful he
kills himself damages a few cells
skeletons in the way your body is now
gone dead bones it's fine um a bunch of
skeletons are knocked over in the
blowback but uh that's that all right
romie rome is running roads just runnin
you wait he feels like a little bit of
sad is like a little single-tier like oh
yeah he heard dead bones scream and
again it's like it's the twin connection
even though he knows the gym it's like
you know ok beautiful body will no
longer grace our presence and I'm gonna
roll the wrong here ok 88 ok Roman can
get about here sit too with your little
quick spring there's nothing impeding
him that's for line all right pause
you've now learned that there's
something about you that makes it so the
skeletons do not want to kill you it's
your turn ah
I don't longer fear them so I like I
want to come down here okay with rather
scelta by like his hands just dance for
a bit okay it's okay it's in character
Johnny nothing yeah no pause is probably
going insane hear me he just saw me blow
up that's you know that's gonna be yeah
and his pet well no so dead bones his
soul is in the crystal that Roman holds
ya dead bones his body is blown up that
one's is technically alive if Roman
figures out that Oh freedom Rome has
just gotta find an idiot so love video
obviously uh so you and the skeletons
start dancing the skeleton doesn't
really understand what's going on and
then kind of just blows you off and how
do you move to the side an asshole was
that it pause it just gonna hang out for
a sec skillet man I mean there's nothing
else like you do is blocked okay I could
move like two more space no no no this
this is gonna be good pause this is this
might wrap up your character if I get a
good roll here so skeletons all start
moving they're still trying to run
towards where the horn was the horn was
blown I think once here and then again
code blue it here so they really want to
get through this dirt pile a shame co
kind of blew it a second time because
then they would they're gonna start
digging at the dirt pile we can just
assume there's more skeletons piling in
just everywhere one of these skeletons
are piling in running past pause pause
can see just exactly five spaces away
Robin trans dead mangled bloody corpse
it's just gruesome buzz I need you to do
an insanity role because the last five
minutes have been so nuts with the
mushrooms remember that mushroom cloud
that exploded kind of you got a little
whiff of that you're about to
potentially go insane okay you survived
us insanity robbaz you are not going to
be going insane and joining bogans army
of skeleton death hey
meanwhile this guilt assert kalan at the
dearth pile which you guys should have
done right away but did they start
clawing at it they break through the
first one they're coming at you alright
Justin your trip on the mushrooms is
starting to wear off you're going back
though you're going back into panic okay
you do know that co is in great danger
regardless if you can't do anything
alright so I'm informed everyone that
through my through my mushroom visions I
saw that co was drowning jake would you
believe a Justin mushroom vision or are
you to panic to even consider that this
is happening this is nice remember good
no no that's when you're in character
you can talk to me though Jake does your
trick no it's not a trick ok i restrict
you once today so i don't need to do it
again yeah me and yeah i already did the
joke um I'm believing it I'm getting
I'll believe I see you and Justin got
that good mushroom buddy believers okay
Roman can't actually hear this like you
even if you're trying to show that Roman
is not paying attention he's freaking
out he's just running he thinks his
twins ii died you know I romanesque Jake
to you can you think of any way that the
two of us combined can save Roman can
get there there anything we could do oh
it's fine not Roman uh coach it Jake
remember you can't actually talk back to
Justin you can only click it'll be quick
so you can't actually give just an any
real character advice so I asked him
that his response was alright so you see
kind of xylophone dat me ok what's your
this mail cart I don't know someone just
dragged it up I think he wants you to
mountain that's a wrong class I don't I
think he wants him to just try and mount
it without any way yeah sure yeah if you
want to jump on Jake's back by all means
I don't want to jump function yeah
that's a terrible idea I don't think you
just do it either wonder Jake's
abilities Jake in disguise Jake and put
things to sleep and Jake and double any
effect the double effect could be used
on your
if you had something you think could
help batter rot the only thing I could
think of Jake is that you double down on
me throw in the hell out of you know
what that's like a boomerang throw
there's no way fine if you double down
and you roll a 20 anything else Jake's
just getting thrown through a wall
remember Jake's born even throw through
a wall once okay okay well I
passionately invited other than I'm like
this is terrible idea i've just been
eating mushrooms out of a ticket wait a
minute I don't need I don't need to be a
skeleton anymore at all oh it's up man
hey it's got a nice disguise max hey um
so yeah you could probably like I could
double down you could throw me through a
wall I like it not really through all I
figure just down the way way down the
hallway this isn't wall right in the way
I mean that's like three days earlier I
mean you'd have to move into position
and even will still you're not gonna be
able to throw them to co yeah it's true
dude look I tricked go with the mermaid
okay all right so I just want to see
verdict in kilgo on its way out i'm
sorry i'm gonna advance towards the gems
yeah and take some okay yep regard self
some gyms grabbing something some gems
and I'm gonna try to Sprint's away yep
all right you can't sprint you can move
to like here okay okay Jake's your turn
okay um I think I'm gonna do the same
cuz yeah fuck it is the chance let's go
get some because gems Chism's m yes yem
his excitement it's a poo jam all right
oh oh no I put him in the fog oh let me
put the gems over here in my game
collection good Karis me kilts it's me
money been alarm and then I'm gonna
sprint the hell away give me a roll all
right let's do this
on 20 come on 30 well if you're old 30
you guys should catch up to co / d hows
it he yeah that's the joke oh why I know
I ok here you go uh you can move right
up to Roman if you want to catch up to
Roman yeah mount me Roman all right go
you can struggle to escape unless you
have a new idea or you're going to be go
to a very critical state as you're
pulled deeper dip in the water and most
likely drown is you know mermaid food I
basically apart from serendipity I have
one move ok I'm gonna raise the fourth
pillar under myself oh ok know that I
can allow that's that's good 1 2 3 you
come flying out of the water do a little
flip laying right on Randall he pee
explodes into a puff of smoke but that's
ok cuz Randall doesn't know he's gonna
make that's that's like a parlor trick
do I have any move left yeah you can
move down yeah but the mermaid has just
swam away she's not even bothering to
chase you I'll leave his gym you again
no no no I'm leaving the tribute oh
you're leaving oh yeah my dreams review
you're trying to catch up to your old
trigger yes that's mine those are my
chips down here all right here I'm good
I'm good this is gonna be interesting I
think I think we're actually gonna get
to probably a terrible conclusion but
hey is it terribly don't lose well I
mean this get not completing the
campaign is a terrible conclusion
general I thought that's a lead not to
lose to die that's my me do you really
think your character devlins has had a
win I mean I'm still technically you
blew up your body and your encased in a
gem that you're hoping your twin brother
figures out how to get you out you have
over twinsies and you didn't explain it
to it didn't explain it to him all right
Roman ski but guys look on the bright
side as soon as we're out of here we can
just go to the bar and have a drink oh
find a new tan yeah Romans just gonna
keep trying to run six okay Roman can
continue to run the he's unhindered he
can get all the way around the corner
all right pause it's up to you pause
your story is a little bit different now
you are kind of locked in with these
skeletons but they don't seem to harm
you I mean if all these guys leave
you'll end up being able to just kind of
walk out so yeah it's up to you decide
what you want to do personally well I no
longer fear for death so what I want to
do is I want to like just dash forward
run into the dungeon yeah I wanted like
dive deeper I'm gonna confront popping
out of the front other than killer pause
you actually can feel vampire strength
in you um you feel lighter you can now
run seven spaces by default and spring
Wow even up higher than that I'm gonna
spread though you're slowly gaining some
sort of vampire strength from the bloody
pool all right you can sprint pause I'll
let you move 12 spaces Wow 12 oh my god
was being very generous at this poor
five pause dick do what he does well you
guys ate leave died Ted loved' 12 okay
very good you look around the corner you
can see into a hallway there's nothing
in these hallways just wait those aren't
pretty ladies yeah you can who's when
you when you walk into the room you can
see piles of golden rings and bones you
can see three dressed skeletons that
look much more powerful but they're not
paying attention to you they seem to be
doing some sort of channeling of spell
you watch as they turn the Rings and
bones into people skeletons and they're
just kind of this is some sort of
skeleton creating factory that you've
just walked into also can i roll to see
how creep that i am yeah but before that
you also spot some mushrooms in the
corner just you were you were
specifically looking for things like
that to you I was like seeing it
this is so weird with the parties this
split 60 okay no you're not freaking at
all at this point pause this is normal
to you you're going through a crazy
metamorphosis slowly turning into some
sort of vampire okay I'm cool with that
all right the skeletons are gonna
continue digging this is the only thing
that matters so we're just keep doing
this dark metamorphosis okay exactly i
don't like this i have more turns and
we're at a combat the skeletons can
break through this dirt just cuz okay my
friends really comes back oh yeah it's
literally not gonna matter it won't even
be flat trans I think we'd like to
return yeah like a turn when they get
here we're done yeah um justin is your
turn all right and continue sprintin
okay from now on if you guys are just
gonna be sprinting I'm just gonna move
you you know 10 so this is this one um
Jake yeah I think I'm going along with
them okay you were just gonna wrong hand
in hand but Justin you guys get one
together to be running him Roman the
same thing club my god yeah he's got
he's gonna get into that room yet that's
my trick haha I'm coal into the camp
it's uh Europe yep I'm gonna run to my
gems here okay collect them can't
collect gems um yeah that's fine Paul's
again boss we're right back to you buddy
everybody else is just leaving so you're
the only one who really has anything to
do I know are you gonna continue moving
in I'm going to continue moving in okay
as far as I can go 14 so pause you can
move 12 spaces again 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9
10 11 12 so before you pause stands
another one of those gates you don't see
any skeletons surrounding this one
though probably you're assuming the
skeletons who were carting it were
summoned by that horn instead of running
through the halls lot of new dad's back
there Justin
Jake are you both just doing the exact
same run hearing still yeah we're just
hand in hand frolicking on out of yours
so the so the skeletons at this point by
the way are not even chasing you so for
this because they're going towards the
horn which was blown over here so at
this point combat is now over but for
the sake of just winding down the game
let's just assume combat is going since
they're all basically about to ya in the
game for your characters so Jake and
Justin you guys just running together
hand in hand yep let's do this bro Roman
Roma's gonna be running past but he's
gonna see the gems and I'm playing to
the character here Roman see some gems
just out there in the open Roma's gonna
try and take these gems okay give a role
to see if you can steal the tribute gems
he's gonna try and steal these tribute
as tribute gems he's Roman you know he's
Leakey's that that is very in character
that's very oh but Roman grabs the gems
and pockets them damn straight repeated
mr. kuester you now have your gems as
well uh-huh all right um I'm gonna move
towards the door but I'm not gonna
sprint big about here yeah are you do i
do I know the effect of the horn or no
um cuz of his trance state would he have
mmm no the thing I don't think what I
was thinking i'll tell you what i was
thinking if i don't know i'm gonna turn
around and blow the horn to let my
friends go yeah you don't oh so i do
know that no it really just depends if
you think your character would have ever
been able to figure out that the
skeletons are chasing the horn and
honestly for you they probably you never
were given any indication so i think
this is perfectly fine not as or like
haha fuck my friends as a I'm just
calling my friends that we're leaving
yeah that's right no i'm totally asking
like to be fair right let's go door go
ahead and go the morn give it a blow
I've been rolled i meant roll the dice
but i actually have to see how well you
blow it yeah but i was pretty good oh so
close alright you blow the horn
skeletons are rampaging through the
dungeons
um back to pause pause song right here
so can I is there a way through this or
do I have to like doors open doors open
hell I'm sprinting in okay I don't care
so far I like I fear nothing right now
creepy bro wearing skeletons regular
skeletons your own band with the mission
pause you blitz into the room the room
is filled with treasures these these
guys weren't here that they had left
earlier you run into a room just filled
with treasure everything miss van and
your new father described bope and is
there that's not no okay I was like that
that's not it thought it was a dragon
here is dopin is here and he's holding
by the neck your new dad okay okay you
may now communicate with poping as when
you enter the room it looked like he was
just immediately about to kill your
father what's up what do you want to say
to him he's looking at you oh no I'm
just here for show uh bo boppin the
skeleton well you want to do anything
else or you're gonna let Pope another
turn I mean I'm a black Pope and do
whatever he wants that fucking new dad
all right um we're eight open can I can
I come a little closer to you you can
come closer how close no close as you
want at this point pause we're not even
technically in combat yeah we're just
kind of open doesn't do anything he's
just staring at you squeezing the neck
of of your new father and holding a
sword in his other hand rattling by the
way oh yeah yeah yep wait does Pope and
speak English or does he just chatters
chatters you know chata runnin Paul's
I'm a chatter at him I'm totally gonna
chatter of him boban extends doping
drops your father to the ground and
extends his hand kind of holding out
wanting you to put
your forehead against his hand kind of
like beckoning you to cum cum tube open
I don't do that i will i'm open okay i
need you to roll to see how like you
know cool you look while you do it ok
secrets only focus on the swag calling
it now Paul not cool at all you look you
look like who's real dork anyway sorry
Babu sorry Bo pan can sense your vampire
blood that you are now one of him and
undead he hope he puts his hand on your
forehead and says you may join me you
may become my heir you may become my
friend but only if you slay this man do
this for me young boss your name monkey
serves baby the mother Spanky the monkey
do this for me sir Spanky the monkey
because he knows your name he's
basically talking to you through
telekinetic powers do this for me and I
will become your only father Cormac he
throws Cormac in front of you Cormac is
begging shriveling beaten he's begging
for his life pause Baggins you have a
choice if you kill Cormac you will
become a minion of Pope in the skeleton
Lord if you cannot you're gonna have to
you know to do and something else are
you gonna be sake your other brothers
bonus you can say Justin and Jake you
have to remember that you have gone
through so much trauma in the last 10
minutes and the vampire disease is
really infecting you but you can't feel
hate you still deep down pause you know
hey you can't feel hate you can hear it
knocking at your door telling you to
give in but your brother it's foolish
just that dumb idiot is and you just
watched him die well that you know of
as foolish as he is still is protecting
you from the evil in your heart oh it's
so sweet suck advise you against cool
shit even in death thank you yeah well
I'm not doing this on a hater I'm doing
it because it's actually seems cool I'm
joining his fucking Legion that's sweet
all right oh this place is filled with
gold jewels and rings ok roll to uh
attack Cormac how you doing it just
slicing his head off no I want to drain
him of his blood though pause I need to
know what weapon you're using my teeth
your team he's a vampire your teeth
haven't grown to be able to do that now
you're going to have to use one of your
weapons to kill garlic the the bow pin
beckons you to come you something to
save you will you listen to him I will
use the ax use the X and you will be my
son respect for this axe uh you're in
luck Cormac actually has an erection cuz
he's all near close to death so
technically it would be in character to
kill carmike your fun chopping wood ok
I'll kill him that wrong head if he has
a boner I will kill them all right you
you pull out your pristine X that you
only use for trees your dad who's
apparently turned on by the thought of
you killing him tries to block it with
his hand you swing down the axe you
missed a capitated him but you slice
deep into his shoulder uh you hit you
hit the bone your father falls over dead
you have blood all over X it's ruined
it's no longer a part of you you don't
even care about this act just you buy
enough you don't care about anything
pause you are now I mean you don't
open so you're not even Paula's he's
just being a just a minion of bolsa
mindless me now so he's dead now he's
Undead coke blows the horn but the
zombies are the skeletons are so far
away that the only thing that is
actually going to matter for the sake of
this and I really wish you to blow the
horns we'd probably be done is you know
there's still all these skeletons and so
now they are barreling down this hallway
oh damn it oh so this is going to be a
game of dodge skeleton to get out of the
dungeon for the sake of speeding this
along we will assume that by the time
these skeletons get to the doorway so
are you three getting to the doorway
mm-hmm and we can finish this out so
just then we will go with you clearly
the four brothers here that are
remaining all they are trying to do is
leave the dungeon well I guess five
brothers phone account Devils let's try
to be the dungeon so I would not
actively try to fight them because you
know the horn is blown and there would
potentially be more coming you
specifically Justin know what the horn
does yeah yeah I'm informing everyone
exactly what the horn done telling code
not to blow the horn don't belong
anymore man it attracts the skeletons
yeah thanks a lot co oh thanks a lot
thanks a lot thanks I did everything
freakin musicians always doing a special
helmet right God so I guess I I guess
I'm sprinting towards the exit yep while
i'm charging my role I'm beckoning to
cloud dad that I've always loved him
he's always been my favorite dad and if
I fail please carry me Justin Justin you
go into your pocket you have an entire
bag of mushrooms you grab three I mean
this poisonous goes back to going deep
into your body but you just blitz out
you're home free whoops she's gone you
just need your just home free at this
point Jake
you're up oh all right I'm gonna sprint
as fast as far as I can you could try to
sleep oh well if they advanced on me
maybe we'll do that but I'm gonna try
running around the side here those are
dead skeletons yeah we'll see how many I
can get to sleep before I uh before I
before you run might be able to put
sense them I'm trip over dem bones whoa
come on um you put one skeleton to sleep
the closest one no no I wanted to sprint
oh you're sprinting oh man that was a
terrible sprint now you can only move
five spaces here it's those are pretty
happening I'll let you do another action
I thought you were to play music but if
there's some basil just sang a song
Ricky always does yeah yeah I thought
that was weird oh that's only if we get
surrounded ok ok ok that's your backup
uh yeah you're only gonna be able to
move 5 that's not gonna let your sprint
at all one two three four five I mean
that's still enough for them to not get
me in this turn I hope hey bro mr.
Romans just gonna try and sprint man
he's getting out fortunately an
aftereffect picking up all those gems as
he doesn't know which gym does dead
bones his gym he doesn't know she's got
a pocket full of gems oh boy a bad time
for everybody oh boy he rolls he
stumbles on the ground falling oh go
you're waiting here for your brother's
it's your call if you want to mr. help
us back out help however I'm gonna leave
all right and then there was to the
skeletons are moving in and this is
slightly awkward but they're not really
going for you they're kind of they're
just covering the exit when they get to
the exit they're going to turn around
here so for this turn you're fine but
you're still gonna have to blitz pass
skeletons and do anything here oh you
should try putting to sleep again man
Jake yeah oh yeah can I move up to him
before trying to put him to sleep sure
yep you move your five spaces it's
trying yourself it's they still
yeah you two are just gone now 1 2 3 4 5
all right all right I'm gonna try to put
him to sleep Wow one two three four five
six seven eight Jake that means like an
eight-team just let me know gonna put
them all this Leary's asleep isn't that
bad or four I looks him I'll take like
four give me oh there we go give me the
song attention all mins of the wizard
named Cooper he spins a good yarn but I
think he's a goober I strum on my Lou to
put you in a stupor so we can dip out
while securing our future nice sick is
been on par yeah i Henry nice make an
album hahaha that's afternoon right I'm
the bard all right give me give me the
role then weird in a day's work that's
gonna love it farewell friends all
future birds will be at this level 14
all right you can have you can have
these ones to sleep it's great nice yes
that's fine Roman Rome is running okay
give me a run do it to it Roma's ben
kerley stumbling yeah and Roman is so
divine intervention that okay that cost
him three yeah I'm not letting him
stumble again I'll pick him up his love
for his twin is a gate while your
students survives you and you got up
again yeah um you're only getting the
five that's all I'm gonna get to drive
yeah your league is still gonna turn uh
he could be right next to Jake but yeah
you can do something else if you want I
don't know what else you can do but I
don't even know what else I can do yeah
yeah all right would it be character it
with Roman throw a gem at a skeleton I
mean I don't think he would think he
would either yeah I think he throw money
at skeleton nice that seems stupid
especially even by Roman stand I guess
he throw you know what he throw like it
there's only like three awake he throw
like an unholy water unholy water at one
of these dudes okay well that's trying
to try
to fix the situation a bit you know how
much is on holy water 334 and you missed
completely oh I mean believe you just
you know what you hit you hit this fire
over here and you put out its out
slightly darker where you are it helps
help you all right the skeletons seeing
someone go to sleep are now confused but
thanks to the dark corner over here they
don't immediately see you we're gonna
see if the skeletons can search to see
who's putting people to sleep this might
be our new home Jake yeah I believe we
might die just skeletons see no one and
there now just stumbling around looking
around trying to figure out what the
hell is going on these skeletons get a
little worried they're all walking
around our kind of searching all right
it's all you Jake okay um can you sneak
past the skeletons do it try without
energy look 30 just book it all right
okay okay bucket bucket bucket look good
come on it all right i'll give you a six
you can start running past the skeletons
in 2 3 4 5 oh god they're gonna kill me
instantly Jake you have a lot of stamina
these are the same Skelton's you're
fighting at the beginning of the dungeon
3 or you can take a hit or 26 you don't
like to date need 20s they hit you with
20s bad times outside of that you're
probably fine yeah Wes you can try Jake
rawr you can try single him I have an
action yeah you just you just did a run
try singing again but mostly I could try
singing again put him more to sleep um
it's always it's always an option man
alright let's do it keep cranking it out
all night do you have a man if you keep
cranking them out he is a musician room
the maids and ogres we split out the
hallway I hope that I helped even in my
own small way
ah poor brother pause with his tiny
pecker came to some mermaids what a
homewrecker okay give me a dice roll all
right let's do 60 oh all right um this
was a ton of fun guys I hope everybody
who watch enjoys the four brothers
escape we have honestly Roman not really
he's I don't think he's gonna be a fan
of the rest of brothers I think after
they get out he's gonna way he's gonna
go his own way just this was a
discovered the power of the gym we don't
know he's yeah Rome Romans gone off he's
kept that gem he's kept apologies he
didn't sell any of the gems really yet
um I was thinking of the extended story
universe in which he just keep forgettin
sells them who knows fondos yeah who
knows Devon's we don't really know we'll
never know what happened to devils are
now left early the three of you brothers
saddened by the loss the other brothers
uh got wicked stoned off some blush
rooms that Justin was still carrying as
he is a mushroom wizard what about poor
I love a guy who looks loud dad sir
spunky the monkey uh spot force monkey
the monkey nobody killed bokken I mean
at some point here you guys are gonna
get to come back to Pope and Slayers I
got bad news for you he's got a new
underling uh mr. Spanky the van key
Thank You the man thank you read what
happened to mermaid why food you know
what happened to mermaid wife who have a
mermaid waifu uh yeah I don't know she's
sort of awake o calls avoiding three
maids they didn't go he was like kissing
it was just the kiss dude like hey hey
little bring up things buzz what are you
doing let go he know just did you've
already ruined many things
so just that just for the sake of it
i'll show you a couple things there was
Cole bolls in this room how'd you fought
these kobolds you then get to fight the
mini boss of this dungeon it's basically
a trap you want to sneak around those
kobolds is how I planned it out you guys
could have always gone through here with
Cormac Cormac would have eventually came
to this part where he had you have
gotten here when at any point where
Carmack wasn't with you you would have
met John dar who's this poor innocent
old fun beggar what's your father it is
Li murder just a random man because he's
crazy there would've been these two
boats these two boats can they're like
little canoes they can only fit three
people so had we have had the full party
you'd have had the awkward problem of
you can go to the boss but not with
everyone and we slept fine yeah because
there wasn't here you guys would have
been fine but yeah I also really hope up
and brought John Darby I would I would
talk more about boppin but it will
probably reuse him and again mhm and
yeah I'm trying to think of all the
other little things what what happened
Magnus von Vanessa van had miss him and
turn out in the end oh this has been
honestly there's there's three more
storyboards like like at this point miss
have been probably got a report from
Cooper because Cooper was technically
evil he was cursing he was going to give
you curse stuff had you have properly
done the trade because Cooper wasn't
actually sent here by this van he was
just he was just here to loot ginger you
to pause ma'am also the to confound the
turtle King what yeah yeah depending on
your conversations with the turtle King
I let that completely open ended for so
many things ah you could have met the
turtle King once again he could have
been there and it's like super awesome
he'll last Ross he's been Kim and
basically like I was telling the guys am
preventing story look at this tiny coo
coo bur we I put coober in all five of
the maps and he's potential I getting
even discover him in the first one
because even gonna Spence matter but
Cooper was in all of the levels so like
I forget what we had in I won't show you
the other levels cuz I'm sure we will
we'll use them at some point or at least
I'll look at them and change them around
but at this town kuber like you get out
of conversation with Cooper and all
sorts of things i think i'm going to
treat him as the where's waldo of this
series we're we're just there's always a
cooper on the map sometimes he's obvious
sometimes not he's just my god miss man
sees random to me oh y and this Evan had
tons of treasure for you guys to take
lots of items and stuff he had a hot may
encounter you could mess with there was
two other Dwarfs that you could have met
with that would have given you some
bullshit quest to go slay some things
but they would have upgraded your
weapons and giving you proper weapons
for the adventure no just killed or head
sex with them anyway yeah I know yeah
probably I just mean it's nice to think
about I just try to make as many things
um the sword in the stone there's
absolutely nothing to it it's just the
sword in the stone like even if you guys
broken open you would have just got a
sword it would had nothing on it I was
just like I'm gonna put this here
they'll probably waste time on it son
yeah I'm glad with how everything went
myself yeah I was it was a fantastic
interesting set of yeah it was it was it
was pretty solid anyway thank you for
everyone for joining us it was very very
long if you came in late i'll have this
up on youtube very very soon i'll be
working to get it up probably as soon as
tuesdays we'll see how that comes out
this is a show again that we did the
show all for Jake thanks for having Jake
you were honestly awesome man like my
pop great dude I would love to have Jake
come back in the summer anytime you have
time dude I will make time for you guys
it was a this vacation time for me it's
pretty much like the only time I do not
focus on music well except for the part
where I focused on music the whole time
for those of you wondering co just wants
you to know that this was ko's stream of
day because it is 2am already we are red
dude it was little it was long we're
gonna have to figure it away because the
idea of how I want to do that this is a
show we're going to be trying to do more
in the summer we kind of brought it up
early because we really wanted to help
Jake out obviously there's a lot of
things we need to fig
route especially time management because
I don't want you to I like the rate you
guys cleared everything I wanted a
resolution but I was ok with the
resolution you guys had it wasn't
beating the dungeon but that's the thing
as long as there's some resolution
that's fine but we'll have to think
we'll have to figure out ways to I guess
I'll to figure out ways to put our human
dungeon yeah well Bart for continuing
campaigns yeah not really much you can
do yeah like we might have the I think
while it would be nice to be able to do
multiple campaigns I think we ought to
just play it out that sometimes we might
have decide it just has to go longer
just the show must go on or fewer people
will probably do for you yeah well what
would be a little be a smaller will have
to do tests with fewer people and things
like that and see how it works but I
think we have something really fun that
I that people will enjoy and so we're
going to mess about with it more make a
really awesome and then come back and
summer to just keep doing this show
every week if you guys like it and shout
out to aaron one more time for you
Nicole guy here PJ can show no much
showing up with us very busy dude showed
up um and please check out nervin
seriously well not joking about that we
did this specifically if you watch the
stream please please please just go take
a peek at it that's all we ask and
that's it we have on 984 backers right
now we I bet we can get to a thousand if
you guys get it to a thousand we will
stream this another time before some
summer so like maybe next month yeah so
sometime in April if if before in this
stream I'm going to play music for 10
minutes to rent us out if you guys
actually want to do this and I know it's
a stupid sales tactic I get it but i
really like Jake he's a fantastic dude
yes I want him all I wanted to have all
the love when he when he's dumping all
this time into this project like
seriously guys that's that's that's that
the real reason we did this if you guys
make that happen we will do it next
month regardless of all the stuff we're
trying to plan with it I we will make it
happen yes sir thanks everyone thanks to
all you guys pause step bones Justin
Jake nurse co it was now the fun thank
you this would be the part in the show
we took about but we can't take it back
we're bound with it yeah BAM you guys
all enjoy and remember this is all a
show her again Jake congrats dude you
gots to get word to it and now I'm
terrified because I got actually make
the thing that you're fuck I tell you
will your lies have been brought I know
the feeling yeah all right you guys all
have a good night and I hope you all
enjoyed see ya
fun with thousand backers all right
April middle the month it's yours we're
doing under our realms live next month I
will see you guys all then thank you for
watching you guys have honestly been
awesome see you then