[Music]
all right I want to conjure some I want
to conjure some orange juice okay I'm a
Floridian dwarf um Kate Florida how much
juice do you normally drink though is
that like do you have like an obsession
- orange juice like Erin has apple juice
like a gallon of it you also know that
Howard so you have no idea how to use
the wand is Erin with you is there I'm
gonna show you the one are you just
picking this up and start shaking it all
right here's gonna randomly here's what
you gotta do buddy
you just gotta you gotta wiggle it and
twist and flick and move all right
that's it it's all it takes all right so
I'm taking it and kind of like making
jerk-off motions with it okay that works
a slow jerk-off motion like staring into
your eyes
okay I'm gonna I'm gonna roll for this
well there you go yeah you successfully
create a giant bottle of orange juice
it's gonna take it's it's gonna be like
this big just think Pierce it is a eight
foot tall I don't want to calculate how
many litres that is I'm not like those
inflatable beer cans but it's it's
absolutely huge
is it sentient everyone here is
impressed is anyone here not impressed
by this and I roll to see how intently I
stare at Jake jerking off the the wand
yeah by all means go ahead and roll for
that okay I need to roll two for
something yeah yeah okay you are very
intensely watching him some of his
orange juice every we wrapped attention
just Kosar drunk that one would you like
some orange juice
I was busy I want to roll for friendship
with Randall yeah 17 all right
co-star approaches Randall that's Roman
I'm sorry
co-star approaches Randall he's trying
to thanks thanks approaches Randall he
leans down to reach reach out his hand
and Randall is going to
Rando is gonna be a little bit he's he
like is interested but he's kind of
scared he's kind of just going on the
ground just kind of backing up a little
bit
oh he can't talk no he can't you didn't
summon him with a mouth man he's just
the is just a jumping bottle
he's just an enchanted bottle of apples
Mexican jumping bean how do I know what
he's feeling then you Randall would you
like some orange juice dude he doesn't
even he doesn't even know how to feel
he's we're gonna have to spend a lot of
tender moments yeah his bottle language
yeah
can we roll for tender moments right you
are rolling to see if you coast art and
Randall and pause Jake are all having a
tender moment learning of language
learning the language of Randall oh it
is very very so tender yeah all of you
are just having a very heartful moment
dead bones just a pause do not give a
shit they're just like we want to roll
cuz I want to pick up and throw the
bottle in the air do it let's do a oh
man okay so wait before they cannot
connect earthquake okay first off calm
down you don't you don't ever have to
jump to your abilities only get that
bottle Baz before you can even
earthquake to try and interrupt him
because we're gonna assume they're
walking up you don't even know their
intentions so you're gonna have to
basically roll a 20 to stop them from
doing this because nobody knows Romans
just walking up it's gonna pick up the
ball and just chuck it so nobody's gonna
plus you guys are all intensely having a
moment here with Randall you're not
paying attention to your surroundings
anymore yeah but you don't know
Randall's in danger this is this is a
random act on a group okay well you're
gonna know so Romans gonna walk up and
I'm Roman are you just grabbing Randall
by the with the hands grab grab and
Randall by the hands and fling in there
yeah so you you've grabbed Randall and
you just chuck him 20 30 feet in the air
catch I want to do something what would
you like to do dead bones
I would like to enlarge Randall well how
big are you trying to make him four
times as normal so you're gonna go the
biggest and larger can just say guess I
can make him just trying to make them as
big as I can it's the inky plinky combo
it's thinking black guys I think I think
Randall's the first boss you created him
down man I got I got a role for the
enlarged okay yep enlarge Randall up
well okay okay okay it's not four times
it's one and a half times bigger yeah
he's he's he's a big how big big is this
now cat leader yeah he's like a
two-liter bottle of Randall he's he's up
in the air he's just been enlarged who's
gonna try and catch him who wants to
save him I will there could be multiple
people trying to catch him if you guys
want or it can just be here and roll for
a gentle pinch
you're gonna try and help okay yeah I'll
help okay Aaron moves into position to
catch him
Co I'm gonna need you to roll what or
what are you doing I'm gonna I'm gonna
send him up on a gentle color of
capturing Randall so you're gonna propel
you're gonna summon a pillar of dirt to
throw air into the air to catch him
gently yes yeah okay a very tender
that's a tender pillar sure I mean Rob
yep
can I possibly get distracted because I
see some mushrooms in the in the
background
sure but hold on so the pillar comes up
but it doesn't correctly land with Aaron
he kind of gets shifted off focus he's
flying in the air but there's no way for
him to reach out and grab Randall he's
too far so now Aaron and Randall are
falling very quickly to the Grandal oh
god someone yeah you could try it saw
someone you
really far away though Justin well I
could only toss wait you tossed the
bottle the giant bottle you can toss
gonna toss that burner yeah really yeah
yeah Utah's probably the bottle or
headphones I'm throwing dead bones
towards both of them and it's his
decision what he wants who he wants to
say okay so your general direction yes
except he's not gonna be able to decide
because I'm putting him to sleep with a
lullaby okay so hold on he's gonna be
flying through these oh but we got to do
multiple rolls but at this point we have
to assume you're in combat because
apparently you guys are just fighting
with Randall am i rolling for this toss
yeah you're gonna roll for the toss and
at the same time Jake is gonna try and
put everyone to sleep okay three so you
go to grab dead bones and you grab them
and you go to like just grab them by the
arm and you completely miss you put your
hand right on this junk Oh God just
little socially awkward dead bones just
turns to you and that is a lot of you
know bling you know just did it in the
punch maybe meanwhile Jake starts
playing a song Jake I'm gonna need you
to play this song huh
ah we must all go to sleep and if
Randall dies we should leave all right
it's my barred song if your song
oppresses chat I'm gonna need a I'm
gonna need a verdict Oh how's Jeff
feeling on this song was it impressed
basically in order for this dis to work
all of his songs need to be based on if
they impress chat so Oh in that case hmm
are you gonna do it too over to impress
chat right this is the one that counts
this is the one that counts you got to
impress chat or if this doesn't work oh
you're up in your lullaby game aren't
you I saw the best song ever I tend to
agree are you going are you singing
again or is that your song that was my
song okay we're getting the eight out of
ten ten out of ten here comes
comes no no I'm making a fully it's
making it making it are we gonna do a
vote every time okay easy it's easy
don't worry all right
you let them vote oh they're impressed
so they're very impressed since I have
this very very slight pause in
everything going on you your adventure
now is to go find Bo pin you all Phegley
heard this pause that's all the details
so anytime you need information on what
your job is
pause will be or your talking point he's
got a little novel that missive in Rotom
I've every all the details he possibly
knows so he's chat impressed Co oh yeah
they're very impressed all right
everyone is put to sleep including
including the barmaid and the other
people who are trying to put out the
fire and watch it you guys asleep camera
asleep does he dream the Jews Randall is
asleep yep Randall is asleep everyone's
asleep
ego falls asleep in the air so he's not
even gonna be able to roll to this fall
he's just everybody's gonna fall and hit
the ground rule to have pleasant flying
dreams
alright it was a pretty fuzzy ego in his
dream state tries to flap his his arms
and it actually helps with the fall
he takes slightly less damage Randall
shatters two pieces soul is dead because
Randall is going to be landing because
of his new size directly on top of CO
and Roman Romanenko you're both going to
get hit by this in you're both asleep
but it will wake you up because you just
got splash for some OJ or is just his
hand still on my job well we sleep no
because he did like a little touch and
there's like oh okay
they didn't keep it there you didn't
make it off to see if I kept it there
you can roll to see if you kept it there
sure yeah that's the direction you like
to go in a second okay you didn't keep
it there I'm sorry okay okay okay I want
to roll to see if I realize that I'm
covered in Randall
I mean it's pretty obvious you wake up
and you're just immediately like why am
i wet what happened what how long was I
asleep because you're basically asleep
for maybe ten seconds the lullaby
instantly sends you into like REM sleep
just like boom you're out but so I'm
having like lost time you just lost time
you have no idea what just happened
and currently everybody is sleeping X
besides you and Roman oh shit
and Randall is now dead oh dude I have
no idea what happened I can't believe
Randall's in pieces man that's crazy
Randall's in pieces no remember you're
having you meant happy flying dreams
you're still very happy in your sleep
you think you're like a bird or
something remember you hit the ground
lapping your arms dude yeah here's on
the ground flapping your arms as you
sleep yo snap out of it okay we fix
Randall he's shattering the glass pieces
there's no sign of movement anymore yeah
well you were asleep I talked to NASA
penny said there's nothing we could do
gotta wake everybody up and a canoe
Randall can I roll support everyone a
delicious mimosa
you only have orange juice did you bring
any liquor with you there's a burning
bar right next to us
yeah I had this excellent cider right
here that's been fermenting for all of
five minutes let's wake everybody up and
have a little bit of cider in memory of
Randall
yeah well pour it on the ground for him
okay all right PR so Jake and Roman and
Co I'll start to wake people up Justin
in dead bones come together a broken
Randall lays on the ground as you all
kind of more in his passing can I roll
to t-bag Aaron I thought you woke him up
is Aaron still asleep
he's groggy okay so you're doing this
while he's awake yeah yeah
all right so Jake pulls out his penis
and walks towards Aaron but Aaron does
wake up right away Aaron do you want to
resist this advance you you literally
see you like dude why are you pulling
out of your wiener you're my brother I'm
just gonna put my balls on your head is
that cool I mean I guess I don't mind if
that's where they want to be that's
where they're gonna be let's do this
sorry I'm stepping on Randall's remains
here to do this but uh was anybody upset
that he stepped on Randall to just slap
his testicles Rob I'm talking about
little sisters yeah everyone's awake
this is wrong can I interrupt before
yeah go ahead
yeah go all right Jake sir remember I
fucking killed dad reconsider what
you're doing right now doesn't fall far
from the tree
you know I'll back off and I also have
glass in my foot so yeah that's good boy
I need you to roll to see if that hurts
can I roll to see if I get my dick
caught in my zipper when is it back up
yep first we're gonna roll to see if you
Jesus Christ first we're gonna roll to
see if you cut your foot you do not
you're completely fine and then we're
gonna roll to see you know how will you
zip up your pants here all right that's
good come on big money oh yeah oh and
you do not catch your dick in your
zipper so crowbarred this is really his
actions really harshed my tender and
want to roll to see if i need to pour my
cider into his loot into his loot okay
we're gonna be the progress that it
played a lot of parties you go to grab
your cider but remember you just shared
it with everyone
you don't actually you're not even
holding it right now like you go to grab
your cider off your shoulder you're like
oh yeah oh man I'm not awake yet all
right so you're all here you're grouped
you moron Randall you've all blown off
some scene apparently you all had some
issues that you
to deal with but now you're all as a
family together you have the planet come
with this no no that never happened like
as it was happening back up as was
happening here yeah pause pause asked
said dude you need to back off for us
you're going on my list and Jake backed
off so there was no a little groggy here
Yeah right but if you if you ever do
want to put your dick on my face let me
know why is that okay
you got so upset about your dad but your
older brother that's okay that's what
brothers do man there's a girl okay
family all right yeah that's how we bond
that's like our family it's the sack are
we doing the sack this whole time
Oh Lord hey Jake I'd like to formally
apologize I didn't realize that Aaron
would be 100% okay with that so I
realized I stepped over that line and I
I just I hope I don't come across as an
aggressive pass hole to you CDM we're
family if you do rest assured you will
have balls on your chin okay that's what
we bards do we just leaving this orange
juice here or was it alive my canteen
real it's just some orange juice
what's my I rolled to top off my canteen
yeah you're gonna think my planning
you'd have to climb up top high and like
open it up though it's a really tall
bottle all right let's try what I say
like eight foot or something it's huge
okay we're still learning how fog of war
works that's okay let me find it you got
an eight you're smoking john carmack
over there so like just watching ya
mouth open just like he just can't
believe this because basically you guys
showed up in town blew up a bar started
summoning things in the wand some of a
sensitive being really excited he
existed somebody threw him up the air he
died got really sad but
when that is balls were involved that
was 10 minutes that was 10 minutes I
guess of your lives easy come easy go
heat-seeking does he still want to give
us a quest or is he just like done with
it no he already up the quest you ready
no what you have to do look apparently
that's a good point I forgot that's a
good one too Cormac comes up to you a
little dazed and was just like are you
are you guys ready to go Jake by the way
you were not able to climb that orange
juice I know I got my shirt stuck on the
edge of it yeah fuck did I just see
about you durable face get the fuck out
of here he backs up and he's like see
don't do you want me to come or not I
really can't read you guys for Paul's
freaks out anymore can I just I want to
use soothes spirits on so he can't feel
anger for a day I don't be angry for a
day yeah how much stamina is that for me
3 3 yeah just do that okay go ahead and
roll dead bones and your your inter
targeting the emotion anger yeah pause
is not allowed to be angry for a day
okay oh all right
yes yeah you're not allowed to be angry
for a couple of days there you feel no
anger or hatred inside of you that's
weird feeling you my my father do you
want to join us
sure well I mean that's what I was here
for I've been tasked with this event to
show you guys having yeah okay fathers
dad look-alike Kim get with us he said
his name like Jackson for some reason
you know be really cool is if you would
let us call him dad oh yeah hey um
before you join us would it be cool if
we called you dad um like it I don't to
be like to Ford anything but you know
I'm gonna roll for this you know we I
have a younger brother Cormac really
isn't sure how he feels about this
because one he really just wants to get
on get on with it you know help this of
it out but at the same time he's really
not comfortable with seven kids with him
yeah
I have a younger brother okay he has
mental issues because I killed his
father and my sister sister sister
sister sorry sorry what the hell am I
doing with you car back I am so sorry
but yeah but just I think would be very
helpful if you could just join along in
last call you dad for for a little bit
yeah it totally wouldn't bring up any
repressed memories anything of course
all that in a while
fine for call Mike look this is really
weird but if you guys agree to come with
him now and not do anything silly and I
mean don't mess with the totem pole
don't go pick those crazy ass mushrooms
don't try to steal be like the sword in
the stone that the town notes if you
leave this town if you leave this town
alone okay
and you come with him then fine he will
let you refer to him as dad what if we
only do one of those things Cormac says
if you meet him by the exit of town in
ten minutes
you'd be called dad Elsie's leaving
without you and finding someone else to
help go find the Pippins lair or both
his lair guys was there dad human all
right McCormack's gonna start walking
away just don't ask the town's folk is
there anything written on it there's
nothing written anywhere it is just a
sword in a stone I wanna grab it okay go
ahead and go ahead and are you trying to
just pull it out try to pull it out okay
go ahead and roll mom know things okay
Roman goes to pull the sword out of the
stone but cannot won't refuses to budge
I try okay oh dude guys I have an idea I
want to try something okay okay
Aaron there Aaron goes to to pull the
sword of the stone but he kind of like
when he's going he grabs the sword by
the actual blade kind of like gets a
little paper cut almost on his hand just
mix them just a little okie doesn't even
bother pulling it out at that point just
just like never might have to sit this
out nature's disinfectant oh right I'm
gonna try kicking pause in the shin just
okay you successfully kick pause in the
shin it hurts him Oh why'd you do that
you fun guys angry no yeah you can't I
called the fun guy and all I said was oh
that's that's a reaction of pain that's
right you're just confused yeah you can
still be confused why'd you do that fun
guy you know just testing things good
you guys knees roll for sneeze can troll
the sneeze you sneeze
mangles feels good tonight can I roll
you antagonized pause with some
Chumbawamba absolutely all right let's
do this alright yeah pause uh what's
your feelings on Chumbawamba dude I
fucking loved you
who doesn't love Chumbawamba alright
Jake you're playing a really good
rendition of Chumbawamba but pause
actually likes this song and either way
even if you didn't like it he's not
really gonna be able to be hateful like
pause you can't really trick pause into
being angry he physically can't we can
yeah yeah it's not that he's not allowed
he can't he has no emotion anything he's
normally happy about he has to replace
with another illusion
you're not angry at all one more thing
want to try one more thing yep go ahead
as many things Cormack is now walking
towards the edge of town he's now
leaving okay I want to knock pause his
hat off okay 13 paws Co is moving to
swipe at your hat do you care now okay
pause this hat falls to the ground his
head has kind of you know dirtied up a
little bit happens that anyway is that
like a chef's hat or what no it's like
it's Native American headdress it's got
going on there really if you didn't make
fun of it yeah one of those Native
American dwarves huh yeah you are you
mad about no I just I'm saying I'd
appreciate it doesn't offend you at all
you're having your essence like a turkey
man well the turkeys provide us with
food you met at a turkey Justin what are
you doing I'm looking at these mushrooms
okay okay good I'd like to eat one okay
yep
which mushroom would you like to eat
what kind of poison are we talking here
there's no indication that mushroom is
poisonous I'm just gonna you know what
I'm gonna roll to see what so much yeah
I'm just gonna grab wildly and I'm like
man a bathroom mushrooms okay you grab
in you grab this mushroom on the left
you eat it and it tastes delicious and
actually you can feel it just empowering
you replenishing your stamina seems it
seems to just be giving you more energy
than you're normally used to that's
awesome yep some mushrooms like this at
a concert one time drink drink
you take your fucking drinks aside a
drink
sorry I'm I you brought that song back
up I love it really saying this all
night dude a mushroom make the song
bitter oh you're a chef right cookie I'd
love a mushroom okay Cormac Cormac by
the way now is completely out of line
site he's now walked past the tavern you
guys can see that he's he's gone he's
he's about he this is your last chance
if you'd like to leave with Cormac else
you're on your own to find a where where
there guys we can't abandon dad okay
Justin you're gonna be taking those two
mushrooms with you
all right great hey Dad how's it going
we're back it's going I'm glad you guys
are finally ready to get some work done
today yeah fine I'm waiting stereo heard
that before
is everybody coming are you doing Aaron
do you have a limp or something are you
it's just it's hard to look over there
okay well all are you gonna get together
and you're gonna leave with Cormac and
you're gonna go to the Pope and Slayer
the mission as paws is telling you in
Cormac your new dad mentions the goal of
this is to Wow I sprained my ankle damn
it he got to roll to see if you sprained
your ankle rolled its brain all right
you sprained your ankle god damn it
yeah does anybody want to help I'll go
back and help him okay
dad help all right that core monster
calls he calls dad your boss was gonna
help but Cormac walks up he just walks
out he's like I'm not your father
but do you need me to carry him do you
want to go on my shoulder so I'll put
you on my shoulders if that'll make you
feel better
guys could we go to Dairy Queen look you
help me if you help me deal with this
Pope and thing I promise I will take you
to Dairy Queen afterwards yay I kick my
feet except it hurts because one man you
get really good you kicked really good
yeah slightly hurt but you're good all
right and you're gonna ride your daddy
that sounded wrong you're gonna be
riding on top of daddy you're you're on
top of daddy not be on top of daddy yeah
oh hell yeah okay
I remember when daddies do that to Aaron
over a Harlem sign you can roll for out
on us I you sigh very you know mediocre
it's just like a is there any risk of
like psychological break here well every
time you roll the dice it's so Lisa risk
of anything rolling the dice is very
dangerous rolling the dice gets robbed a
little bit