good job doofus plain wrong for anyone
wondering i am not purposely speeding up
this game in any way i understand that
some of the things that look like
they're happening are too you might
think are to end the game this is what i
intended and how they did it so okay
sesame in Roman yeah okay so blinky here
look Sankey really sad just like I don't
think we're gonna make it I don't know
don't think I think we're done I think
he's like yeah no pause really fucked us
on this one god fucking dammit pause and
all that shit whatever Rome would say by
the call my monkey I don't know and then
you blink he goes yeah I think I can do
something I think is what all can you do
say I don't know you won't like it say I
don't you will help I don't know if it
will help it'll help me it's like I
don't I don't know if that's a good just
at look promise miss this I'm gonna get
all right something's gonna happen I
want you to pick up a gem as soon as i'm
done and jin just take and give it to
someone eventually if you survive I
don't understand any of this I'm so
sorry and then I take at the gym and I
use the gym okay so dead bones pulls out
the gym that he stole from pause earlier
in the adventure he channels the gym in
his hand a bright light is admitted
bright green light is emitted and dead
bones doesn't necessarily look different
but his eyes now glow red it is now
Romans turned I bones Roman does not
actually know what has happened that you
know holy fucking it was you some sort
of power the gym it has changed him
slightly but he said it was okay and
we're still twins I'm gonna trust him
Kenny's gonna he's gonna just move back
and let dedbone let what's his fucking
name blinky have some room maybe back
off a little bit okay and then cast uh
you know what's Roman god what's wrong
we got
I'm go throw-in hun holy water its paws
look cuz Romans just he's you know
Paul's never like new dad I think me and
Ron were pretty on board with their dads
worst add any dad's kind of a jerk so
let's just roll this for Roman to get on
pause Jesus alright you throw the unholy
flask you hit robert moran okay well
that's you know that's fine too so
robert moran the next action he would
take you may cancel out it makes them
different you may suggest something
different okay pause it's all on you now
man ah you've now seen the Cape collapse
you know what's coming you're still
mounted on top of robert moran who just
got hit in the face by a glass bottle so
if i were to throw an object how many
spaces can I throw it oh you can
probably throw it around ten I'd say you
can throw it may be 54 really well 10 if
you're lucky okay you know what you're
trying to hit I'm gonna move up four
spaces here okay I'm like right here are
you bring him around with you no he's
staying there just a case now I have one
more flask of apple juice what I'm gonna
do is I'm gonna throw the apple juice
into the blood pool open for I have no
idea what I said okay something happens
yeah oh boy that's gonna be funny when
it resolves okay you throw the jar of
apple juice it crashes into the blood
nothing happens I'm move back to your
face oh great all right one two three
four five and his friends coming
contingent and some more moving and all
Jesus Christ all right skeletons are
barreling around the corner at this
point all of you
you can see what's coming you have but a
moment to react before the skeleton army
collapses on the rest of you for the
love of God do something productive Oh
Justin yeah we'll Jews would do
something but I know it wasn't my friend
um rocks that's it man is it hmm I could
attempt earthquake I could attempt all
right good what what I think you should
do dead buzzes you should have larger me
to make the earthquake call and
effective Paul's I'm gone man dude you
don't know what's gonna have what to get
some my chakra fuck it's gonna say it
you're dead you shouldn't be telling
that they don't know that's gonna happen
character they don't know shit yeah in
character they don't know that something
bad is happening so for my turn I'm just
gonna eat a bug haha do you have any
more bed well how many mushrooms are you
eating you're just like 20 shit just cuz
I just wanna I just wanna you know enjoy
my last moments on this on this planet
god damn it Justin okay go ahead and
roll you're eating the mushrooms just
two I mean you're panicking thinking
eating mushrooms is gonna make it feel
better holy shit Justin yeah you up
because of your mushroom whispering
abilities you can sense all the fungus
in the dungeon eating this mushroom is
causing you to trip out in your panic
attack but it's letting you realize
something that blood there's only one
type of blood that is clearly not
affected by everyone knows if you throw
apple juice into a pile of blood shit
happens there's only one type of base of
the world that blood doesn't affect
vampires you know this found the
mushrooms have told you this fact oh you
also know that that horn clearly
controls the skeleton whoever blows the
horn the skeletons barrel towards but
you don't have the horn
that's it and even if he blows the horn
it's kind of a problem how about we have
known to communicate with co right um
probably not know if go ahead eat in a
mushroom recently maybe but you don't
have any sort of mushroom telekinesis
you're just like you're going on a bad
trip you can just see like numbers going
now you can like anything anything else
you want to do in this turn Justin you
don't need to roll because you know
exactly how it's going to play out if
you decide to do it alright so everyone
sees you as you have learned a special
mushroom power it poisons you it hurts
you but you can like see math it's a
pretty good description alright so
everyone saw me eat these mushrooms yeah
I turn to realize I could talk to
mushrooms I can see man I think if I
talked to Jessica I just not using this
voice oh dude you don't look too hot
like how why did you eat you I see pause
just spew a bunch of zeros and all right
shake your up man you should take a look
at Justin okay go man all right um I'm
gonna go cower in the corner over here
okay now and I'm gonna sing a requiem
for for poor pause cuz he's not gonna
make it through the next turn okay let's
do this mMmmm rest in peace pause we
hardly knew ye may heaven hold mermaids
a plenty to screw thee ah but why is
your junk still so shriveled and little
it's like an enigma sunk deep in the
riddle thank you
I expect a full album after all that
Jake songs we'll see what your anthem
does that wasn't only targeted to
basically raise spirits i guess going
every much it's a rally I'm the other
life in drums no no jake has to roll oh
yeah I saw him clearly pressed rat but
it wasn't doing anything which is normal
thing so I see how well it inspires his
friends haha nah nobody's listening Jake
it was a great song trust me we were all
this thing but in game nobody was
listening as they're busy travilah balls
and uh co so you were outside of this
room you are don't know what's happening
you had this plan to go see some kobolds
and bribe them with gems the couples
have already bounced all right well i
only so seeing that obviously have to
change plans I had a plan B which was to
maybe try to bring tribute to the
mermaids and see if I could solicit
their help but that's that's a trick
that's far plan yeah but I can't really
do anything else so I guess I'm just
gonna hey Kyle you should do mmm she's
spirit rush man just start meditating
sure you start method you can make it
guy reconvene over here by the gems and
then sure spirit rush go ahead I'm
meditating the game will be over before
I could go go ahead and roll kill ok
look dude maybe you'll roll 20 and then
I'll just let you take all three turns
right now okay like Superman get a five
percent chance to save the game oh no
you're just you're just meditating
that's sad walk yeah oh great my turn so
uh dead bones use the gem which
exchanges his soul for the soul in the
gym a common thing that I used to do in
my silly show and so inside the soul
which dead bones knew because he
recognized this gym was a terrible
necromancer an evil terrible necromancer
the dead bones you know is in a gym
because dead ones didn't explain any of
this to anyone
can't possibly no dead bones is alive in
the gym he thought well I see said to
roam and bring it to someone yeah yeah
yeah bring it to someone save the gym
that's only know right so dead bones you
are now playing your turn as a terrible
necromancer and you've just been really
real one do I have it what abilities you
have um all your necromancer you can
raise the dead and control them I
control the dead yeah we lesser a dead
you can definitely control them okay and
I'm a powerful necromancer I assume yes
all right so I'm just gonna walk up like
a badass ignore these two idiots Romans
like were you going miss what's going on
what's that fight is that five or is it
four that's four I think one two three
second one more yep over next to pause
just put the hand out to stop the
skeleton army okay roll dice oh man he
still gotta roll dice when you're
fucking all-powerful Commissioner man
that's the you're not a coover I wish it
was a cougar that's pretty seein some
dang that was so not 17 dude if it was a
one I would have just had this all being
dead bones head in the gym did nothing
again didn't I I was in dec amazing this
whole time now it was just the mushrooms
all right you walk up to start trying to
control the undead mm-hmm but a more
powerful and dead as controlling them
your powers are not working no pause
Europe buddy we just roam good turn Oh
Roman get stirred yep so we're in used
the GF right now is on the is on the
ground resume so Roman would go pick it
up I'm gonna go pick it up SS is stored
away you can assume at the very least
that Roman understands what happened
even if all the other characters don't
because it would just be too awkward
you've know what happened you know is it
something different the gem if you if
used by a willing soul exchanges places
with the gesso and now Roma's gonna just
take his hammer out and try and break
this fucking gaming fucking god roll the
dice to break the cave in trying that
multiple turrets of people never bother
trying to do
fuck Roman starts batting away at the
rubble but you cannot clear it fast
enough to make a passageway through he
makes a bit little bit right yes okay I
thought that was obvious i thought you
everybody just be like oh I start
digging away I mean last time Jake rain
through it all right pause sort I didn't
think that would work again pause dead
bones is tripping out you don't even
know he just started he just walked up
and raised his head and said stop my
minions you just like the fuck but
Justin's over this just Justin stripping
out Jake singing to himself in a corner
Roman is fiercely swinging his hammer
out a wall robber ran scared all right I
do a reality check i feel like a bloody
way he tried to run away no Robert ran
started just know we just started moving
into the corner he's really scared right
now ok well let him do that then it's ok
i am moving my my four spaces there it's
okay robert moran ok it's ok can I add
something to the to the animal I mean if
you want to use your holy water he
hasn't done do I really want to use the
suggestion ok kick him in the nuts why
he hasn't disrespected them yeah but you
know maybe you don't like this me scared
he's a scared animal there's a bunch of
skeletons he's freaked the fuck out you
don't approach a wild animal is freaked
the fuck up you just wasted your holy
water he's nuts what's it gonna do he's
not wild he's my pet yeah when two
minutes that's rough man all right pause
you can console' robber ran all you want
but you got to do something about these
skeletons or tunnel or anything man
please can i check for hidden walls yeah
you can't do with that seems like the
only thing we could do at this time I
mean as much as I would love to say
there is a good wall for you positive
there isn't this is the you search the
walls you can see a dead end you know
that there's no way to get through any
of this stone is there anything else you
want to do and panic before the
skeletons barrel down on mr. necromancer
I'd like to confess my sins
to who to Robert breath yeah yeah you
know he's the only one who's actually
fully respect me all right now go ahead
you know Rob bran I shall let you know
if I die I loved you so much I wish
nothing but fucking death on dead bones
way before this all happened that piece
of shit is the worst thing that ever
happened in my life my wife got killed
okay my two children got eaten by bears
and I still hated fucking dead bones
more than anything else in the world
know that I love you and I hate that
piece of shit robert moran is a
stampeding the skeletons whoa seeing
your passion robert ran is going to
sacrifice itself to buy you some time
boss that's Noble yeah no good that's
always so close dear Lee's the deer runs
through just smashing skeletons to their
sides moving them back and forth making
a path small path room to go through and
just disappears into the wall of skill
ram the skeletons are all kind of taken
back very few of them make any advances
because they're all dealing with Robin
Rani just charged into probably certain
death alright Justin it's your turn you
are still tripping balls on mushrooms
you take to damage all right and you can
see math still though you can still see
all the odds of the things you would
like to accomplish hey Justin wants two
plus two all right so in my great ass
what was that get a grip man all right
uh I think I see pretty good odds that
uh that if I throw Jake at the rocks it
might get a little more yes you can do
it do to rub
roxrite going Jake aroma yeah I'm good
Keith super hard head look at it that's
that's Fitz it's it'll work ok I'm gonna
break I saw the art pretty good saw the
odds yeah he knows it's gonna happen ok
please alright uh Justin grabs Jake
spins him around tosses him um when we
gonna play this he tosses him through
the rocks Jake was flying through jake
takes a lot of damage to for this so one
two three Jake's gonna take two for that
Jake was flying through the rocks
opening it up for you guys ah yeah thnkx
the body of Jake you're awesome you can
still move you can still move Jake
however Jake can I get you to roll we're
gonna see for conscious that's had a
couple of brain cells like this might
have knocked you the fuck out so he's
still bad headache oh he's got like two
turns to meditate we are going to run
seven gonna kick some ass thing or
whatever the fuck they say um I'm like
so youryour know you got super
unconscious you're just you got knocked
out you're knocked out right now you're
down on the ground um so is your turn
now Joe Jake so I need you to roll to
see if you can actually get up from your
turn alright receive if I can do this
we're gonna see if you can even if we're
going to stay in conscious or if you're
going to play a turn here all right you
can get up you can only move 3 spaces
but you can still play out your turn
normally okay okay so I have a turn um
um mm-hmm so I can only move 3 spaces 1
2 3 I probably don't want to be a
roadblock there ah what if I were to
cast my double down on undead bone man
sir um you have the dead bones you have
to double down something and typically
as the feeling of a speller effect on
actual spell what if i double down
meadows like you can you can double down
co
meditation stands yeah all right let's
let's let's wait who else has stuff that
could be doubled I could I mean you
could double Roman no double down Jake
isn't it an interrupt like you can do
that funny yet you can do it anytime
that's not you don't ever have to do
that in your turn basically how it's
supposed to be you could use it on your
turn for something like co-stars here
but what you're supposed to do is when
somebody does something you double down
using some of your strength on our the
month but right now the only thing you
probably could double down is co who's
currently meditating yeah or or I could
just make just meditate to license my
twice is fucking being able to see
everything and maybe he'll be able to
uncover something incredibly profound
easy or maybe you'll give co6 turns yeah
all right let's do this let's double
down a coat okay go give me a roll
what's the double down costs three I
think mm-hmm well wait wait wait give me
a give me a real role we actually roll
it let's throw that thing zero it there
you go 18 naoko game co no no no co it's
double fast it speeds it up yeah yeah
you're getting double turns now it is
now co-stars turn so he gets two more
turns next turn Cove you honk leash six
turns at once as long as your meditation
isn't interrupted that's the crazy run
to the entrance from here do whatever he
wants in a second try he can do whatever
he wants dead bones and Roman dead bones
you don't actually have a turn anymore
you can control the necromancer but
remember he works much differently um
honestly the necromancer probably isn't
going to move the necromancerr all he
wants to do is control the dead he's
probably going to try even harder to
control you can try even harder to
control the day yeah he's gonna just try
and overpower the young he's gonna prove
who's the bigger Lich in this fucking
place yeah and that doesn't listen
enough now he's still not able to
control it Roman on the other hand Rome
is just gonna fucking sprint one was
getting now
okay 13 he's a parka number now Roman
could go all the way up to co if he
wants oh you ever wear that oh let's go
run zipco good fit yeah um it's now
Paul's turn pause they all your buddies
are starting to make a break for it
Justin's the only one who's he just kind
of threw he bade the opening but he's
kind of being left behind Robert man
just killed himself it's all you man oh
I actually know he's dead no you didn't
see him you just saw him run into a boat
it could be alive ah you know what just
is probably way too high to comprehend
what the hell will happen if he dies so
I'm just gonna bolt on out of here Oh
buzz that's a little out of character
character bream he's an asshole no not
towards Justin and if it was dead bones
aroma would make sense it really doesn't
make any mushrooms last time I feel
fucking hatred you can't so many
physically can feel it you can't be
angry pause you have you like I mean I'm
not saying you have to take just have a
good review we've been playing this game
for eight hours i'm pretty sure 24 hours
has passed it is i ruled the 20 oh yeah
it was a 20 it was like a very long time
man I'm sorry just shout some numbers at
me on your way out give me a heads up ah
fun then all right I'll allow it no you
can you can do know you can do this no I
what I would do is at me being really
really shocked that etho Ren and saved
us etha what who's he thumb problem
doesn't seem your name and yeah buddy
okay that's his public name Oh secret
name is Keith yeah so Rob confirmed okay
yeah yeah yeah exactly make sense uh I
don't know there's not much I could do
you can go take your revenge on you know
that's my brother you didn't like
together yeah like you at this point
you've seen dead bones is like trying to
like work with the Goblin something is
fucked up with dead bones like both your
brothers are obviously in tired are
freaking out
I mean if you if you want you can run
under the sink that you are completely
panicking that's fine all your other
brothers are panicked you can do that
but you can't actively just be like fuck
justin you'd have to do it for the
reason of panic wait i have i have a
theory uh-huh I'm staying here long
coming up your way you're walking up to
the scale I'm doing this let him do it
okay the reason why I'm doing this is
what I even went up close to them they
didn't actually attack me they just they
shot arrows at me fucking I have this
theory that there is my turn all right
the skeletons run past pause they don't
see him as an enemy probably has
something to do with his vampire blood I
was hoping you would just stay get
trapped the skeletons run past they
begin to mall your brother oh alright
let's roll the sea of the necromancer
can live I'm just going to roll commence
your former brother yeah he's not very
strong well he's in your body that's
true so the necromancer spirits are
pretty tough no it's your whatever
strength you have so that's six we're
just gonna do truckloads of damage to
he's still alive yeah he's barely alive
at this point okay I mean that's not you
remember you're in the crystal I just
grabbed I'm fine really kind well kind
of to explain the crystal you don't play
sleep am i where no you're not aware you
were just asleep at this point that's
fine you can actually become aware but
it takes a long time of being in the
crystal before you can kind of like
awakened inside of us should have talked
to the crystal dude all right one of the
skeletons will have actually run by and
we'll attack Justin as they swarm and
hits Justin for minor damage alright
Justin that's all you the you're still
tripping still tripping yeah you seen
numbers you almost dodge that skeleton
but he threw a couple too many ones in
the string of ones and zeros he was
throwing at you you have just seen that
the skeletons or ignoring pause
uh you can see your brother dead bones
dying you are in full panic mode but i
mean the the mushrooms are keeping you
level-headed enough to make decisions
that you think would help yeah I hear
they're still whispering to me about the
vampire blood and I'm like I get it now
mushrooms thank you for your wisdom now
I'm wondering is there enough damn
mushrooms is there enough vampire blood
on pause from do like rub it on us I
mean there's no way you would know that
right now you just see a ski sea of
skeleton so you've no idea blood is left
and you really wanna become vampire well
I just I just want to live okay yeah so
I don't know I I I could run I mean just
to keep in line one of your brothers may
be charging up you don't Renesys I know
this but I mean running in this
situation would be very just to knee I
don't know unless you have something
else you want to do to attack the
skeletons your only other option really
is to run I'm just running okay freaking
out I see the math give me your wallet
give me a roll cuz you still are doing
like a panic room sorry you are doing
like a panicky I'm stone trying to run
nine okay so you would you just
basically get just out that's all right
get okay Jake it is your turn you've
just double downed you just double down
co-star yeah you can see he's super
strong you can see us another one of
your brothers has gotten out yeah that's
all of us let's just go home let's book
it looks so straight up book it um-hmm
what other what other tools do i have in
my tool bag can I do that a second time
i would not recommend it though she
wouldn't recommend doesn't mean don't do
it I mean roll20 and you roll a 20 and
yako gets 12 turns we can watch and kill
the entire skeleton army sure but I
think that's like it's three percent
chance right oh yeah that sounds like
not not a terribly bad odds
he fails I probably explode or something
yeah yeah this could be what our
explosive spiritual energy all right
what else do we have so I have doubled
down and I have disguise in disguise can
Lola by I could try this amazing it's
like a super powerful Lich Lord or just
start clanking instead of talking this
time you know oh yeah I could do that i
mean you can you can wit you you can
improve your disguise there's bones
everywhere from some of your earlier
battles so a lot of skills it's really
magical a lot of skills all right where
do I find these they're just all around
you it's hallways are filled with bones
in this room okay got it right next to
you it's gonna be I'm gonna pick stuff
up and I'm gonna be I'm gonna be a new
skeleton okay yep going in with that
blended and strategy the pauses yeah
from now on I have to click so let's
roll for that remember you only have to
click when you're in character so just
don't ever same thing other than clicks
right okay you look just like a skeleton
now okay if you can't talk to your your
allies they won't be able to understand
what you're saying all right go you have
six turns you may move a total of thirty
spaces if you don't sprint can you write
you are unleashing all your inner monk
spirit built up over the entire dungeon
to unleash the greatest turn ever
created what would you like to do it's
got out you know you should do know you
you so know this state you're in the
state you would and you would have
awoken and just like every you just know
everything that's happened he's gone
into the Avatar you just yeah you're
super super senses you can just see hear
feel all the information that will
happened when you were in your
meditation stance is coming all that
information is coming in here you're
ready to go let's go now do I have to
can I do more than usual or as I start
to do like four of these here I mean
that's so this just one
action and remember yeah that's just
going to be one action action all right
cool all right and the role for that
bring it up a for spiller there to try
to close the hole to prevent any of the
evil from getting out okay you managed
to do it sure all right and I'm gonna
remember when you start at the beginning
of the state you were at full standing
up remember abilities like this will
quickly drain it with six turns of
abilities so just keep that right yeah I
know stone pillar comes up yep yep doing
another one right beside it or in the
vicinity o.o this time where were you
trying to aim it that's the great unit
where this is ok you don't get it there
so you get it here there's a gap there's
a tiny little passage but it's clearly
blocked off with these two at this point
okay there's a little way right through
here take it into this part but other
than that it's completely closed off all
right you have four more times or more
turns and then do one more for spiller
okay be safe sign and I'm gonna do it to
try to fill the gap right there there
you go 33 wall yep guys grab some gems
and let's sprint the fuck out of here we
don't even need the gym just leave hey
no we can take the gems i know the
Holies take some gems I think Liam's ok
I'll leave him ok roll the same Angela's
you can take gems if you want since he
isn't so these guys at a combat now
they're not in a combat the Comets still
happening because it was already here to
turn rule I you still have to infuse
I've returned yeah you khoa Skrull
pulling at his tourneys echoing his
sentiments and then that's fine he's
gonna book it out of the dungeon all
right oopsies you take the fire with you
too all right oh yeah yeah you can
probably get a far can I go ok it's like
you're a you co you can get right into
the mermaid room you run all all the way
along the mermaid room you pass it dead
over you run into an empty room so the
goblet with you rip the chalice out of
the ground left there's still plenty of
gems if anything we need to be poor
taken you still have other actions you
could do
it's up to you man you're when you're
home clear now at this boy game I'm
gonna leave a little tribute from my
friend should you do not love her okay
co before you leave yeah she comes up
and decollete for a kiss ok cool okay
you do it by yep give me a give me a
role in the dice you lead him to give
her a kiss CL CL confident you are
pretty confident she tries to grab you
it's her twin sister and she's gotta
pull you under the water oak oh yeah
you're perfect turn I fucked up oh uh I
mean technically go you've done you
probably still have one turn so you may
now play it out but you've just been
pulled underwater by the mermaid right
who is now trying to kill you yet again
gonna bring Randall to me ok Randall's
floating above the water Randall can't
really go in the water ok yeah Randall's
afraid of getting wet something about
his previous life what I have yeah I can
fucking you can't really you can just
try to escape stroll yeah you can
struggle that's all I can do can I try
to reach up to Randall maybe get lifted
out sure ok this is gonna be really
satified co raises his hand out to grab
onto Randall Randall extends his cloudy
it actually forms into a hand they go to
grasp pants but Randall is still a cloud
the hand is pulled through co gets
pulled underwater go is now currently
drowning oh hey well cause got a new
problem for him to deal with hey did
nothing wrong he's got like you guys
will not be able to get there in time to
save him he's got to figure that out
himself he there's he's pretty much all
on his own I saw my way through that
much
The Courier ushering yeah so Justin
somehow you know okay so you know that's
happening if you want to echo it to your
friends and try to figure out some
long-distance way to save them by all
means