A long time ago in a galaxy far,
far away....
STAR
WARS
It is a period of civil war.
Rebel spaceships, striking from
a hidden base...
...have won their first victory
against the evil Galactic Empire.
During the battle, rebel spies
managed to steal...
...secret plans to the Empire’s ultimate
weapon, the DEATH STAR...
...an armored space station
with enough power...
...to destroy an entire planet.
Pursued by the Empire’s
sinister agents...
...Princess Leia races home
aboard her starship...
...custodian of the stolen plans
that can save her people...
...and restore freedom to the galaxy....
Going somewhere, Solo?
It’s too late. You should have paid him
when you had the chance.
Jabba’s put a price on your head so large every
bounty hunter in the galaxy will be looking for you...
I’m lucky I found you first.
If you give it to me, I might forget I found you.
Jabba’s through with you.
He has no time for smugglers...
...who drop their shipments
at the first sign of an Imperial cruiser.
You can tell that to Jabba. He may only take your ship.
That’s the idea.
I’ve been looking forward to this for a long time.