do these guys today on it's alive we're
gonna do a little special edition out of
the kitchen where I mean ol Vinny we
went upstate it's camping mana nice
little multi zone fire cooking in the
woods baby perfect for cooking on and we
cook some cool stuff other than
hamburgers and shmores well you're that
I were in the woods play - this probably
cost you twenty two dollars
hope you brought your wallet Ben so uh
let's go real man down I'm gonna get
fired
[Music]
Oh any Pope any look who showed up but
don't worry got all the hard work done
already gathered these rocks here for
the fire pit got somebody's heart we've
already split up I hiked it in you know
we're not that far in the woods we come
up here for the you know further for the
night for the day you take a couple
trips a couple loads you know no one
said it was gonna be easy Vinnie and
what we're gonna do we're going to set
up a little oh here let me put my beard
now
I picked this spot cuz it's got an
excellent beer holders so what we have
here Vinnie I'm gonna start a fire back
here
let it burn down because we don't want
to cook over to the direct flames we
want to just cook over the coals so uh
and then this will be like our our
charcoal factory and these will be our
cook zones okay once this burns down I
can scoop the coals bring them in here
bring them in here I got some grill pans
over here and some and some wire racks
cast iron you know perfect for camping
flat it's a little heavy but it's not
that bad you throw it in the backpack or
a couple other things I mean whatever
it's the heaviest you know kind of
heaviest thing these little rocks I used
as little levelers so I set this up like
that and then I got no resting racks or
sheet trays so you can cook your
vegetables on there it gets the smoke it
gets the flame it gets the heat and then
this can be for like your solid sear if
you want to get like a nice cast you
know so we'll set that up we'll get this
fire going
so we're gonna make some kindling some
good stuff to start the fire with I can
just see if you Oh hand off hope no a
guy cut his thumb off doing this not to
go jinx in myself
hello will gather some twigs alright
we'll build a little teepee action you
don't want to choke it you want to make
sure you get nice air flow vinegar later
alright make sure you bring a little
flame unless you want to you know get
your Flint or your magnifying glass both
reasonable options big fan teepee method
allows good air circulation and then we
get this nice kindling we made and once
this stuff is gone
then we're pretty rock and rollin I feel
about that Benny oh yeah you put a
couple bigger logs on there get a nice
bed of coals going you know this this is
a pretty good size for cooking
you don't need massive logs when you're
gonna be making me fire that's great for
if you want to you know sit around the
fire for like you know five hours and
roast marshmallows and talk about better
days and shit but we're not out here
doing that right now we're trying to
make a fire to cook on may be but
tonight Vinny will go down and we'll get
some larger ones to come back for the
old campfire sit around you know we'll
drink whiskey and reminiscence what a
beauty morel mushroom found in the woods
not planned that don't get you going you
know I can't help you yeah that's a
beauty coming ain't gonna find this in
the campground that much well you might
slice that up on the cookie little steak
anyhow we're gonna be doing alright
fire burned down we got a nice bed of
coals here what I'm gonna do is shovel
out these coals and we'll make a nice
little bed here rake them in and that's
going to be the fuel for our for our
cooking sturdy here let the heat up a
little bit and I'll start prepping the
meat get that bone hot going oh yeah so
we got a little hot zone up here little
cooler over here for the veg this is
plenty this here if you wanted to get a
real hot spot I could bring like a
French skillet and you could place that
right on the coals you don't want to put
that over flame if I were to put those
steaks over the flame it'd be just be
way too hot when you move things around
you know it's not like you put thing one
you know that's it and then in the back
we're putting more wood to keep the
coals up okay so notice the little juice
is good stuff flavor bombs dripping onto
the rock I mean I like to rock it all
but like means any better so I'm gonna
let that drip into the mushroom zucchini
let that get nicely nice we'll cut that
up and get eating huh mm-hmm paid for
worse that's for sure yeah so uh got
your little three zone fire cooking good
stuff in the woods don't get much better
or not huh Bon Appetit baby you owe me
something Brad Leone hey guys I'm Brad
Leone oh dude we can't do that
hey guys I'm Brad Leone I can't do that
seriously hey guys I'm Brad Leone from
hey guys I'm Brad Leone you might saw me
cooking some food in this here cast iron
and you're gonna wonder if possibly how
I was gonna clean this all you need is
since you have to fire a little steel
wool get it nice and hot
just a little rub you rub with the old
steel wool wipe it down with a little
rag and get back to cooking
good huh little Pilsner in there but huh
butternut Vinny oh yeah
put that on your magazine VIN oh yeah we
both work there