so see each fire you ready to tango
alrighty so we're down here over in
Portland Oregon we came down for the
feast
we're over here with gold elias from
olympia provisions me and today we're
going to make a little sausage Oh get
out of here with this the USDA making
fun of us oh yeah the US care of the
USDA scared of the
[Music]
[Applause]
just to start off we're gonna tell us a
little bit about what we're gonna be
this will be making a multiplied sausage
so we'll take lean meat and white
protein we're gonna throw it in the bowl
chopper and it creates a - and mine
just like mayonnaise - and mine and then
you throw in fat and that gets particle
eyes and then the leaves fans all these
little fat particles so when you cook it
proteins fine are you when you eat it it
tastes smooth right nice boys that's not
all should be grainy like a lot of those
sausages out there comes one it becomes
one so I just go check this apparatus
out here this so yeah this is that what
I was saying this thing is gonna roll
around those blades get spinning like
crazy we put the meat in make our
emulsification put all the ingredients
in fold in the fat
all right cool so we've got our
ingredients yep and then went over here
we got some spice so yeah this is the
game here but this is stuff right
there's a cultured dextrose we got
yourself some celery salt there
we got garlic and then the seasonings
chili flake cumin coriander we ground
those earlier this is rosemary extract
that we put in water I thought it was
beer we'll get that later and this is
ice dump it in there the whole thing yep
and put that next one in do you see how
good I am at delegating this is the time
I'd like to reflect on that's not too
much huh well this bad boy can handle
we'll see huh that's what we're all
about learning together
Wow man is rightly that huh that's a
beautiful thing man we're gonna turn
that into paste we're gonna turn that
into a move to the Gatien boom science
Vinnie so this will give you a nice even
mixture as well
yeah man this machine is cool I gotta
say I could do anything
dump it in dump in
and then I iced rated ice right in here
always cold
turn it down he turns up it's it 150
seconds that since we got about we got a
few seconds I heard you mention that
comes in you can already see the colors
changing after you're looking for is
your lean ones here you're starting to
see it stick together start forming
little legs in there between the protein
sounds complicated but it's kind of
literally yeah it's free yeah so it's
amazing when you eat a bad sausage you
see how easy it is if people get up
stove you can manage meat baby that's it
all day let's see why did that right we
can stop now you can see it's nice and
particle eyes yeah most sausage people
do eat it really oh yeah it's pork I'm
gonna kill you tastes like a hot dog hey
something like that get there oh it's so
good texture melty and you're cold it's
actually pretty good yeah you need a lot
of that I don't know if I should I mean
I don't even know if you're gonna die
now so I can't believe you for teasing
yeah all right Roger that here it is 30
seconds 30 seconds I just mix it now we
gonna empty it
we're never gonna chop the T Oh God Oh
would you look at that good yeah make
sure that falls in the right spot
oh yeah baby like that huh that makes me
feel kind of good that does relieving
man you know who's gonna love this my
mom
ever since I was little she always had
my dad make her cheese hot dog and they
would just split the hot dog and put
some like you know anyone I got a BS
cheese in the Senate or tonight we're
gonna get her some of this yeah
hey that's gonna blow up get this
cleaned real quick kind of reminds me of
remembered ghosts yeah oh yeah you were
making - let me teach you the ways that
trick everybody loves a little Swayze
remember yeah whoopee was in that
Patrick it looked me right have to go
walk away Patrick was the ghost he was
dead yeah everybody was in there by
herself right whoopee I love his another
where the hell's whoopee whoopee
oh she sees Patrick no but that was
whoopee right there he was Pat right
like I was Pat you were a different girl
what yeah buddy
Oh
[Music]
we just got done chopping up all the
meat mixing all the ingredients can you
tell us now what we're going to be doing
with that we're gonna stuff it and what
this is stuffer oh yeah Vinnie you
getting that the dumps over here you can
watch it fall in there Vinnie just
rewarding so what do you what are these
casing these got hog casings which isn't
a temple yet exactly this is a break
right here set that see where we're at
oh wow it's just oh man when I do this
back home sometimes with friends or with
my dad yeah you got the hands and you
don't have that nice portion control no
it's I'm always ripping them and yeah
but they get out of whack they're too
long you know then you got to go back to
how you used to do it all you know right
just spin in the opposite spin it in
exactly crazy thing is it's not that
hard is it beautiful work you're doing
there all right I see what's going on
see that and this goes right on here
kind of give it to you a little one
finger in between each one there alone
so the smoke get in there yeah hold on
cut cut Vinnie all right here we go oh
man he made that look easy
here we go feed it through enough close
it there it is Oh God
look at that no hands right off the bat
I tell you what whoever set up that
machine sweet job
this is oh god stop no do a little cut
here huh yes sir good trim that up in
sausage-making that will happen that
will all right it's inevitable right
forbidding ready for this firing a whole
bed
Oh Oh God oh no oh no stop Wow we've
lost our case in here Vinny I'm gonna
try to troubleshoot it get in there
there we go already Vinny fire at home
fire in the hole Oh sausage slinging
baby
certain things you just can't teach huh
well yeah like today like screwing
things up we're not going to stop all
this sausage because tomorrow night for
a feast Portland little eyes and I we're
gonna be stuffing sauce to drain on
sight grilling them up cooking them so
if you're in the area well actually you
won't see this in time so never mind
Oh fire it all you see they go shooting
out of it Lois why is that lack of
professionalism where's that start is it
sometimes you get a BK thing let me hook
ya yeah a little but you want to keep it
nice okay keep it nice but you're gonna
want to keep it nice it's just like
cooking you know you got to make a
little adjustment so yeah you know you
definitely want to make it nice see we
did there
Bartol we're slinging sausage now you're
back
oh god I got it so you got to find that
sweet spot shut up in oh here you go now
huh
[Music]
[Applause]
so we stuffed them they're all set ready
to go now it's obviously still raw yep
so what you like to do is smoke them yep
and you haven't spinning over there got
those chambers that you got a nice
little blend of woodchips in here
we got a 2/3 apple 1/3 Hickory the
Applewood right sweetness and then the
Hickory is uh gives a better color and
also birds good but what's so great
about these is this is truly just a hot
plate nice smoke then in the back it's
got a little fan runs off into Weber yep
and once it's in the chamber and gets
you know distributed over the product by
cool so let's go take a peek in this
chamber let's get a knife so we can eat
something out of it you have a knife
funny I do actually
look at that thing that's a classy
gentleman always there just finished it
up right now
now that's also got everything Hey look
at that huh that beautiful skin totally
got a nice little that smoke kind of
covered it'll close to the legs let's
give it a little cut first oh yeah nice
and juicy chatters bye buddy uh-huh now
when you get these are that package
you're gonna eat them now what's your
preferred method just grow them up if
you're a patient person you can put them
off to the side of integrate you know
indirect heat you just let it up let it
behind us slowly plump up and get crisp
but most people don't do that so they
put them directly on a grill they burst
open the outside burns the best way for
anybody at home I always say bring them
to a simmer in hot water or beer yeah
and then just crisp them up on a grill
so obviously we don't see pigs running
around thank goodness it be weird can
you source report you're looking for a
nice quality pork you probably have good
relationships with your farmers
absolutely and we're only getting better
at it as we keep growing we keep giving
you know we've been able to purchase
more pork and then set better standards
that are also helping the farmers out we
all grow together in Oregon making the
best quality pork and also give it back
to the land so the land I gotta say you
know tip of the sausage do you because I
think it it reflects in the product it
really does yeah I mean if it if it you
can't polish a turd right speaking to
the sausage can't flow in some dirt
there but oh he's right all right so we
just wrapped up over at the sausage
making production facility they got a
little restaurant right down the street
Olimpia provision south east cute little
restaurant forever in town swing by we
got him to cook up some of the stuff
that we made we take a bite of this how
many
great snap great bread you put yourself
a little
well pickled onion on there something
little mustard many of you live in the
dream got that nice little cheese pocket
in there that emulsification that's how
it's got that real nice kind of like
bouncy all uniform texture throughout it
nice amount of smoke on there real good
crispy snappy skin and that all they did
was reheat these get yourself a little
cold beer something like the pills in
there or something real crisp refreshing
and you're doing all right man
bone Appetit anything yeah I get it
Cheers
oh yeah what would you sell you tell me
yeah we are what was your soldier tell
you