I know a guy cut his thumb off doing
this not to go jinx in myself
[Music]
Oh Benny Sleeping Beauty welcome to the
party babe don't worry I got breakfast
going you know spoiled you rotten Vinny
we got our percolator coffee pre-ground
coffee brought it with us because we're
smart and then yeah I got my little
setup again my little three burner you
know a two burner but three zone
everyone learn more about that little
three-part fire that I invented you can
are there's another video you can check
it out right here yeah hi rendering down
a little fake in here Benny and then
we'll add I got some sweet potatoes and
baby Yukon Gold potatoes speaking of
which Vinnie before you joined I got a
little little boo-boo I'd cut one of my
fingers cutting them potatoes what's all
setup it's clean you know a good tip
bring first aid kit
hey guys I'm Brad Leonie and even I
bleed
that's why you gotta bring first-aid get
into the woods with you no dude no so
look I prep this all up for us already
add some onions sweat them out like that
man
that makes me happy then looks like our
coffees getting there nice I'm dying for
a cup of coffee been a cup of coffee in
a nice shower maybe we'll find a little
river these are the guys that got me but
but boy was it worth it uh-oh it looks
like my fingertip you can see my fat is
dripping down that way
so I'm gonna add the potatoes down there
and let them pick up some color and that
that's saucer bacon fat
we're just let those cook for a little
bit you slay some about you know what an
eighth inch thick so you know they won't
take too too long to cook you know I
mean fiddle around with the fire you
even get a little more heat straight
from the charcoal factory Oh hot baby
sweat maybe you should just want to wash
it oh in to a bagel store you know next
time we come out of here Vinnie very
getting a nice piece of half-inch steel
tack weld that right on and then we can
have an extender you can go right in
there whoo-hoo make a pizza oven you
livin you learn you know that's what's
beauty about this stuff every time you
come out you'll learn a little bit
something you could tweak you know first
time I came out cooking the woods
didn't look like that so we got this
nice little sausage wheel pork sausage
all right nice we're gonna put this in
the old cast-iron when I'm at a Laurel
just to get things nice a little spin
though get that all mixed up yeah well
let that Brown up it's got a little
cheese in the sauce if any you're
looking at your phone guys texting Oh
being coffee's ready bud have a little
have a cup of joe
I will rubber wait Benny you're getting
the blue one not bad Vinnie Stumptown
baby ah Stumptown coffee there's one
things you know and yeah when you work
hard for something it's always a little
better right
like if you're out in the woods all day
cooking and then you come back home and
take a shower it's like oh I was such a
good shower cuz you earned it Vinnie
let's put that over the heat a little
bit yeah we don't need this cast iron
see it babe yeah I got a lot of cast
irons here what's it to you as you can
see this isn't exactly you know the
ultra wait you know backpacking gear but
that's not what we're doing you know
we're out here just cooking food in the
woods picking up some Collard potatoes
are probably just about done and I like
to sweet potatoes man underrated I don't
know if they really are I think everyone
likes sweet potatoes suits Vinny now I
went and cut off my seasoning finger so
we're gonna go lefty make it rain
seasoning a little unstitch to season
everything season you a Vinny oh look
what I found from our last little visit
Vinny a little crustacean friends he
liked it so much he stuck around huh
you know we come back here a few more
times we'll start to decorate the place
a little bit people stumble across back
here I wanted to make it look like
someone's living here you know let's get
weird now maybe make sure you get a
great shot of my hat look I got a little
green garlic let's start sweating that
out in there it was a decent amount of
bacon fat in there that's a good fat
barrier for the eggs won't be all nasty
sticky I don't think that don't take
long you know everyone knows that cook
an egg well you'd be surprised
we'll make little dimples okay like kind
of like a baked egg thing you can find
recipes for baked eggs on bone Appetit
calm and then we'll heat up on our
English muffins
let's turn into a feast this is sweet
and I'm all how I'm happy right here
yeah let's get a little way go under
that's losses a great word Wingo
I think that means fire right sounds
like a song by what was that dude that
that the pit bull or something way go
sir getting a little bored up here in
the woods you started talking about
things you know hanging out with
freaking Vinny all day I've talked to a
tree
no offense video love you you got these
stone fruits apricots peaches plums just
do have them pitted them gonna do a
little drizzle drizzle it's Molly yeah
yeah toss you toss huh
let me a looks good right there call it
a dish no look little pinch of salt in
there we'll see how this goes it'll work
small in batches in case it starts going
a little wild on us who English muffinz
some people call them Engel muffins I
think in England they just call them
muffins that might not be true you know
I usually when you toast an English
muffin I get it you gotta learn little
nooks and crannies I like just treating
it like a little bun I might not even
cut this bad boy open I think I'm just
gonna rip it and just at the top you
know put these right over here just let
them get a little toasty now these I
just want to put a little color on there
the natural sugars in them just
caramelize a little I'm only gonna cook
one side and then right when we eat them
I got some real nice Greek yogurt we'll
do just a little smear of the Greek
yogurt in the pit hole it will call that
a little breakfast dessert let me crack
the eggs Vinnie we're just gonna make a
little dimple you want them in the air
but not crazy in the air you check our
peaches whoa dad nothing you know it's
got its own sugars it's just a nice
little I mean fruits delicious that's no
so good we'll keep this right over here
in the cool spot just let that kind of
you know the residual heat from them
will just kind of make them a little
nice I didn't want to cook them to mush
I want them to hold their shape and we
can just bite them let them cool down a
little let's see how it goes it's just a
little bit this will add just a little
creamy tangy nough stew it maybe just a
little sprinkle soft again a little bit
more of that crushed red pepper flake
and this stuff is nice because it just
bleeds into it it's not super spicy but
it's got big flavor all right let's go
check on the eggs that's not look
too bad yeah that's just about done a
little parsley to the party
black pepper well custom spice blend
when I go camp into cooking and stuff I
just like to make little custom blends
of spices you know that you can use on
several things you know that you can are
very versatile you know cuz you can't go
bringing everything I mean we tried boy
it looks like breakfast with me huh
gonna make myself a little plate a
little Scooby scoop mmm I pay for work
I'm saying that a lot lately
alright not a bad little plate for a
little woods huh got a fruit we got our
little crusted up cheesy sausage and we
got our nice little egg hash look the
yolk still runny just like you know what
this is all about is uh you got just up
your camping game anyone can just crack
an egg and make a couple strips of bacon
or something but we got a whole meal
here man let me try that fruit looks
good huh hey zoom in make sure you get
my nice finger a little mixed sweet
potato regular potato green garlic Hoshi
thing I got nothing to say it's
delicious but I have tea
I mean breakfast is good at home you
know it was one of those dreams it was
awesome but I you know I wake up now I
don't remember what it was something to
do I was in a car in like this country
but I don't know where it was wasn't
where wasn't the United States like
random people you know pop up and stuff
there's like what are you doing here why
are you here - I don't even talk to you
fancy cars there was a castle I don't
have a castle that's why I love dreams
you know worried about my dreams how you
stay out of my head