a lot of people get concerned about
botulism
we're going to do a little fermented
garlic in honey okay and that's two
ingredients that's it
well sometimes there's a third but we'll
get to that later I start with just you
know really nice raw try to get you know
the best one you possibly can local is
best I mean you want to use the best
quality you can get raw raw raw and then
we got some really nice garlic I get
this from the farmers market
Pete's k-y-t's farm they're some of my
favorite medicinal grade garlic and
Andrew Nolan how you doing
all right so I just peel off the layers
over the garbage can I know that's a big
a big no-no in the food world so just
get over it it's just uh you know it's
it's within it's because well alright
you know sometimes when he gets
crystallized and it gets like it gets
like too thick you can't really pour it
some people oh there you go jump right
in
I'm not a big microwave fan alright I'll
just say it you know I think it will
kill maybe some of the microorganisms in
it and that's the stuff that we actually
want you know it's like a two-part glue
or epoxy you mixed one and the other and
it becomes the epoxy with garlic there's
the same thing like you have something's
eating it's a self-defense mechanism
that the garlic has where it'll form a
thing called allicin when something is
crushing the cell walls it thinks it's
getting eaten or attacked so it starts
to make the Alison and the Alison is
what's really really good for you and
garlic just get in the skin off the
garlic sometimes it's tricky but if you
give it a little crush kind of just pops
right out there's a lot of prep so I'd
imagine in the videos the Department
will be like rear ear ear and all of a
sudden that's all peeled and nice
botulism will not survive in an acidic
environment below four point six on the
pH scale I have a little pH meter and I
test it if it starts to get above four
point six sometimes I'll just splash it
with a little apple cider vinegar and
that usually will bring it right back
down my leaves a little Nibin zon no big
deal actually no then let's cut them off
hold on we'll trim off any of them
little boom-boom spots right look at
that oh nice nice crush you see that
bruise happening that's that Allison be
informed so yeah we've got our garlic in
there and I'm going to do is just cover
it with honey and you want to just make
it nice and submerge so yeah yeah get
this pin oh yeah it's the stuff bud all
right so it's nice and see how thick it
is now weights you see okay you get a
couple days in the liquid starts to get
drawn out of the garlic and this will
turn super watery again best garlic the
best honey you can find get it from your
farmers market or like that weird guy
that sells it off his driveway in a few
days it's very it gets very active it
bubbles it foams up a little
so you got to leave some headspace
otherwise you can have an explosion you
can have a you can have some problems
very very important you know I do it
once or twice a day
you got a it's called burping so what
you're doing is you're letting the gases
out and you'll hear it when it's
fermenting and you go it will get the
shot later don't you worry then and you
can keep it out you know people say you
can keep it out room temp for like like
a year and the garlic it'll get darker
in color the texture changes it gets a
little chewy it's like little freakin
garlic candy and you know FDA not
approved but it is very very good for
your immune system I believe I believe
it's been since Tuesday right Tuesday I
think it's Tuesday anyway you can see
look it's cover pressure popping up and
that means the gasses are building up in
there I'll burp it now oh yeah did you
hear that one little pop when we first
started it was a really really thick
honey and now I mean it's it's it almost
looks like it's not even honey and we
didn't add anything else so we'll let
that guy sit back there and then all
right Vinny hello look it's got some
nice pressure there oh yeah whoof you
can smell it look you see you got some
nice little white bubbles on the top I
do have some older stuff here this one
lookout liquidy that is all right this
one's about six months old sometimes I
like that just a little splash apple
cider vinegar you can add a pinch of
cayenne and you can top it off you know
if you say it's getting a little low you
can just throw some more in and let that
ferment away and look this is nothing
but garlic and honey look at liquidy
that gets you start feeling a little
froggy a little sick just shoot that
back you can do this every day mm-hmm it
loses that real spicy bite that raw
garlic eyes
pretty good stuff all right romantic
garlic honey boom you know my philosophy
of him it's all about preventative
maintenance okay say with me preventive
maintenance
I'll probably get sick tomorrow