I don't speak much French I don't really
speak that well English but uh boy it's
fun to say butter in French
alright then so today we want to make a
little little butter from scratch here
and you know if we want to make a little
cultured butter so if you can get raw
cream that would be grave you know a guy
somewhere at a farmers market who's
willing you know bring in a couple
quarts for you or something that would
be ideal because it's not dead
aka pasteurized I guess it's right
Claire I mean all pasteurized is
pasteurized at the end of the day well
put Claire so that's we're going to get
so let's go grab that out of the walk in
there Vinnie remember the low temp
pasteurization this is a trickling
Springs we get in that Whole Foods and
it seems to work really well and for the
life-force I just put a little bit of
kefir and that will bring the life back
into the cream to get us our culture
defect which is nice on butter so for my
recipe we're going to get four cups of
cream give it a good shake because the
you know the fast kind of sets up to the
top there cream cream cream top make
sure we get that all in you want to get
all the nice solids because that's
that's the fat which is essentially the
butter because uh in our next step what
we'll be doing is separating the liquid
from the straight butter fat because
that's that's what butter is the fat of
the cream in that poor job huh who's
better than me then and look at that
color event it's not white alright beige
it's cream the color of cream food
alright
so four to two bottles which is four
cups of cream I'll add 1/3 cup of kefir
you should get around 3/4 of a pound of
butter and about a cup and a half of
buttermilk
we'll put the lid on give it a good
shake alright so we've got that nice
mixed up nice now we take the lid off
clean the rim a little bit nice nice
alright so yeah she's both any reader
you so put that on there and that's just
to keep you know foreign objects out
bugs or you know stuff just things that
contaminating it but you want it to
breathe very important so you want to be
open like that we got our culture we got
our cream in there and we're going to
let it do its little funky thing
depending on how much Tang and cutting
and culture taste you want to it
I usually go I go like two days pretty
solid two days so yeah so it's Friday
now I'm going to write that on the tape
we'll check in on this on Monday it
should it should be done and then the
fun part comes where we can start making
the actual butter Oh Minnie you know
your your listen Benny come on in here
but get a look at this this is the good
stuff so now we're going to pop the top
on it all right I'm just gonna give it a
little shake you don't even really need
to do this but makes me feel good and
then we're going to pop it in the fridge
just for a little while let it cool down
to around all right just a little bit
cooler like 60 65 degrees or something
and that will help with the churning
process which we're going to do with the
stand-up mixer oh yeah
creme fraiche buddy whoa smells good who
doesn't like butter it's pretty much it
it's a perfect food
fancy spatulas that you put in the gift
that actually would work better yeah
would there you go oh good idea no and
that's why you get the big bucks babe
let's go penny quit horsing around oh
yeah nice reach you gotta have the right
tool for the right job how was that now
you could do this in a different vessel
that would make it easier to get out
that would probably be who view I just
don't have it right now now it's going
to happen pretty quickly and it's going
to go from looking like whipped cream to
some kind of frosting too it's going to
start to break and when you get these
little yellow chunks and it started to
look a little soupy that's when you want
to stop and slow it down a little
voila
no look see that not amazing there's
your buttermilk in the bottom and
there's your butter now you could do
this by hand if you don't have a mixer
it just you know takes a little hard
work which you know I kind of I almost
wish we did it that way you know for the
sake of uh I don't know who cares
cheesecloth can't live without it
look at that buddy buttermilk huh we'll
scrape all that butter in there I wrap
this up a little bit here so alright we
want to squeeze out so we pretty much
got two cups of buttermilk
nice fresh cultured buttermilk oh it
smells good though and you check this
out button nice this is three day
smells good we will wash the butter
because what you want to do I'll explain
it in a minute babe all right here we go
so you have no ice never going to fill
it up with a little water make a real
fancy thing called ice water all right
for my next trick Vinnie you got a
little bit ice water in here and we just
want to kind of work it you could do
this with your hands but it gets a
little messy and what you're doing is
you're working out the last bit of
buttermilk that's still in the butter
will do this step a few times and you
see look you see the water it gets a
little cloudy that's the residual
buttermilk coming out all right so we
can strain that off okay okay
so I kind of like doing it with my hand
right in the water and just really just
kind of need it so while the butter is
still cold I like to just give it a
little pat dry look at that that's a
block of butter now I like that a little
bit of salt this is just you know
regular sea salt and then you just like
to fold it in so you go the salty glad I
like salted butter I mean bakers and
staying out of the the most common
butter and you know in kitchens is
unsalted
I don't really bake too much so I like a
little bit of salt in my butter whoa
it's smelling good buddy Oh get some
nice nutty cultured but raw milk still
still illegal all right you're like it's
like a hundred illegal thing yeah black
market cream baby get the good stuff
well I'm gonna work on that
I need a cream guy