all right so we're going to try alright
alright thank you
that's it today today we're going to
make a little fermented beverage called
tepache and it's just a fermented
pineapple drink with some spices very
nice very refreshing departure Tupac J
tepache VIN they call tepache oh it's
this tepache
[Music]
so you want to get yourself a good jar a
jar that can close you want something
that can get a good seal on it what I've
done I rigged it up a little bit is
where I put a little rubber band on here
and I put that over there so it keeps it
closed Vinnie are you recording
but what double rubber band does
patent-pending is itself purposes so if
it were going to explode it would just
go back and it would just let the
pressure out ginger is very active when
it comes to fermentation by its own I
mean there's a thing called I think they
call it ginger bug where it's like a
fermented ginger product and I wash this
really well I just nip some of the tips
off ah you don't need to peel it but
what I do is I will crush it open it up
you know get the juices going then we'll
use these peppers I don't go cutting
them up otherwise I'd be wearing gloves
but I just have them to open them so
I'll cut the top off you don't need that
and I'll cut the bottom off I don't wash
it because it tends to wash off the
outside skin tends to have a lot of its
own yeast on it and that's that's very
good for fermentation as well and then I
like to cut it into a big quarter like
that I cut a little bit of that off of
the the inner core I think it can make
it a little bitter sometimes the rhein
it's a little woody but if it's real
right it's kind of good I don't go crazy
I just cut like a half inch of that
little corner off you see alright and
then I just cut it up into pieces all
right nice chunks we'll do that with all
of them pop the old brown sugar in here
I'm going to add a little bit of water
now so I'm just going to get a little
bit of water in here not much because as
we put the more pineapple in we won't
know how much so they could you know we
don't want it to be too full and I'll
just give it a little shake I just want
to dissolve the sugar and the brown
sugar it will sweeten it not that you
know pineapples plenty sweet but it
it'll sweeten it and will give it a nice
dark color they use another ingredient
in Mexico I believe
brown sugar is an alternative I forget
what it was called which uh I get what
you call it one more time for the camera
Rick if you don't feel yeah now we got
that all mixed up we'll add some more
pineapple in okay
up-up-up I got this cool little tool
that this company called crowdsource
sent me it looks like a giant Bible go
get it go and it's for a fermentation
say you're making sauerkraut or I want
to use it I just want to break muddle up
that pineapple little pop up up up keep
things down yeah that can't hurt you
know all right ginger I'm in a cinnamon
right in there go give it a nice little
shape over the segment and we'll muddle
it back down crowd source if you were to
taste that now it'd be very very sweet
but when it ferments the bacteria and
yeast eats a lot of the sugar so that's
it just a splash more water there we go
fermentation a lot of jars aren't made
for fermentation and so you kind of get
what you pay for it's worth doing a
little research there's a lot of glass
bottles or just decorative if you prefer
a man on those things will blow up on
you get very dangerous
yeah if any things have blown up on me
all right I don't want to talk about it
oh no that was the basement Brusco that
was a failed attempt at making a
homemade hooch I took the bottle I went
to open it thing turn the stand so be
careful back then that wasn't in a
fermentation grade bottle you live and
you learn all right so we're set here
you're going to let this sit room temp
it'll start to bubble it should be very
active come Monday
this is the shop and you don't screw it
up blow up in my face all right not as
much bubbles as I thought let's give it
a little stir they feel those bubbles
coming up that's all the fermentation
happening so now what we're going to do
we're going to strain this and then you
could drink it straight from there what
I like to do is I'll put it into these
fermentation bottles so I'll cap these
and we'll put them back on the counter
for about two three days and that's
where it'll it will start to carbonate
oh yeah it kind of smells a little bit
like it's a little eesti a little biri
biri I don't know if that's a word but
uh it is today folks this is not a new
shirt many thanks for asking
had this for a while I picked it up at a
good old secondhand store I check out
those details up so it's got all these
little threads on the inside looking a
little like poop you know I don't know
and the outside it just looks like I
don't know that's cool man sir one of my
best shirt sir I forget whore today for
the show all right back to business
Vinny now we're just going to pipe this
stuff into the bottles make that nice no
spills no spills all thrills oh now just
like what they I don't know if you've
seen the kombucha video and I really
just want
oh god oh god Oh cut cut then whenever
you're doing a fermented beverage in
glass bottles you want to leave a solid
inch of head space on the top of life
what that does is give room for the the
pressure to build back up and
reconstitute itself into the liquid I
believe but it also prevents it from
exploding and then that you just want to
cap and you want we're going to let that
hang out back in the fermentation
station over there for about three or
four day three days let's do two just a
two and a half three days see now I was
even thinking you might be able to add
water to this and and do it again you
know this is a Test Kitchen so maybe
we'll do that
little spicy that's that the ginger and
the habanero that we put in there but
that's nice I like that and it's got a
little bit of sweetness but not as sweet
as you would think given that we put a
cup of brown sugar and pineapple which
is super sweet to begin with but there's
enough sugar in there for the second
fermentation to create the carbonation
it's magic Vince something short of
magic I like to rinse him off because
you know thinking I don't want to have
to be sticky and stuff you know it's how
you get ants any forget the numbers but
I think the population of ants the
humans on earth is like 100 to 1 or
something so we'll come back and we'll
uh we'll pop some bottles and we'll
taste it there's the finished product
come back in two days
like yourselves up wait at mic job
should have been a spy for me
how do I do it last time oh that's it oh
no that's not to where we leave off I
added a little bit of brown sugar like
two tablespoons just to give it a little
food it's very active as you can see
lots of bubbles going on in there so I'm
going to pop the top and it should be
pretty active oh yeah boo-boo
so it works we got a nice little second
day we'll bottle that up just like we
did with the first so doing two rounds
you can double your yield
I have one in the fridge Vinny you want
to chill it before you open it
oh yeah carbonation pineapple ginger is
very active you only want to go we went
two days and it seems like it worked out
just fine
oh yeah that's the stuff what kinda like
beer a little little little eesti in a
good way pretty nice little sweet you
get that chilly I'd say a fermented
drink so it has like probiotics and it's
you know promotes good gut health which
we're big on but if you wanted to get a
little wild
this would go really nice little rum
maybe even a little tequila it's
afternoon we can start drinking debo ah
you kidding me oopah cific oh oh oh I'm
gonna do a little beer in there my band
of you you always nice it's nice you
don't meet another it's got a nice funk
splash Sweden I say huh oh that's pretty
good this is really good I drink that
all summer long
oh you heard it here first now a brief
word from our sponsors oh what's that
VIN oh we don't have any Oh but man we
got some good beverages and Bon Appetit
hey meal what's up bud what's go ahead
and taste that for me not poisonous
close your eyes where are you on a DJ
yeah watch it with a little bit of the
Pacifico in it oh shit
let's go try to fight rap oh no rap oh
you know where Apple is no no I'm not
going in there no way dude
you got to respect a man's boundaries
let me try it huh we got a couple that
shit Vinny got bladder by the Statue of
Liberty almost looks like a science
research vessel that's where we're going
to shoot next Finny little place called
Ellis Island