I really just want
oh god oh god Oh cut cut VIN Oh tragedy
over here this your first time making
some Gucci for sure looks like it
so here we got a good close-up of a
Viscomi or the mother and this is the
the light this is the force behind
making kombucha we're going to feed the
scoby some further make the kombucha so
what we feed it with a sugar and tea and
the ratio that was handed down to me
the master formula is for one quart of
water you had 70 grams of sugar and 7
grams of tea and we're doing the times
10 batch so 700 grams of sugar 70 grams
of tea so we'll start with the sugar
it's a lot of sugar I mean we're not
going to lie here but again the end
product is actually rather dry because
the scoby it it eats the sugar I'm going
to do a nice like a gun powder gum
powder green tea and for 70 grams I'll
use 68 green and 10 grams of black will
pinch for good luck then from there
that's it so this is 4 times 10 recipe
water already brought to a boil I turn
it off we pour this in stir it around
let the sugar dissolve you don't want to
overdo just steep in it it's like making
you're pretty much making sweet tea so
while that's steeping we'll take a peek
at the girls here I have 4 different
vessels okay this is the scoby it's
layered almost like if you can zoom in
and look at it it's almost layers like a
laminated biscuit you could peel back
the layers where I can start peeling
layers and I can you can give it to a
friend and they can make it at home all
right Finn quit horsing around back to
business here so I got some cheesecloth
ok wonderful product line that in the
fine mesh Chinua and then we'll strain
that into another vessel a couple more
minutes now and then we'll refrigerate
it what I do is I use a little less
water and then I'll add some ice cubes
so it helped chill it and it'll also
speed up the chilling process all right
we'll put this in the sink okay this
goes in here like so okay
tell me the walking by that's castle on
I ordered last week got job is mine no
you didn't order it I don't think you
ordered please get this Oh Vinny's my
witness cameraman doesn't miss anything
classic I ordered it where is it but he
never ordered today's crazy gene whoa
whoa pg-13 and family show since the
days been so busy haven't even gotten to
unpack the fresh cut it shouldn't look
so messy in here usually this will be
all unpacked but me and all Vinnie
Vinnie over here we didn't get to do
that yet so that might even have to wait
till tomorrow cuz we got boots to make
them up we got a good steep going right
behind the car
so again Chinua fine mesh strainer and
some cheesecloth
all right that's Kobe food man we're
going to have a couple happy girls over
there
so from here remember I was saying that
I I did the water a little say I needed
ten quarts I only put eight in so we can
put some ice cubes in to help chill it
so we can do this a little quicker
science and science yeah we'll put this
right on the wall
never ends then here we go
coming in hot sharp dangerous Chris
Morocco is on fire so we'll wait till
that gets to about 72 degrees and then
we'll we'll do the old siphon into the
into the scopes you don't need a role on
this one we're cheating how to keep it
in the walk-in and now we're just
bringing it up to the temperature and
then once that's you know we just don't
want to shock it if it's too cold it can
shock if it's too hot it can kill it so
we'll get it to right around where it's
at and that's quite all right and and
then we'll feed them so Sam Whitley
folks that's it I'm sure there's far
more sophisticated ways to do this I
don't have those I will just use the old
gravity to do this for us I get that
little siphon siphon hose and I got you
want to get you sure you on in on Brad's
room all right good look hold this
oh there's no free rides no free lunch
under in Brad's world you see that
little hole there try to sneak that down
there oh wait I lied to you don't do
that yet oh my god
boom right there
we don't need you anymore Andy I'm out
I'm out so good we'll fill this up all
the way to the top then we'll do this to
doll them and then it's it's and then
it's a tasting game until until it gets
too sweet the perfect spot the balance
of tart sour and sweet and then from
here it's just every day you test it so
I keep a straw I slip it right down here
coming here get this Vinny I slip it
right down on the side just a little
pinch pull because it was so sour here
just because it's been hanging out and
there we haven't had time to feed them
this will probably happen really quick
I'll let this go for probably what's
today Wednesday Friday I'll probably
bottle all right so this next step
very sophisticated tool best Globes in
the biz but you don't want to touch that
with your hands either bacteria in your
hand very bad way mold am i right in
there now you want to make sure that
your tea is still a little sweet not
completely sour very important for the
second fermentation you see I only
filled in a little bit but I have
several vessels and I'd like to do I
like to make a blend of them all because
one one could be a little more sour than
the other and I really just want oh god
oh god I'll cut I think you said you
always want to leave a little bit in for
mom because she needs it so yeah you
want to use a bottle that you can seal
real nice I like using square ones are
not so good some of them you got to be
careful you have to get ones that are
fit for food-grade and for fermentation
because what we're doing next is putting
this tea in these bottles with a little
bit of juice with fruit juice and it's
going to it's going to have a secondary
fermentation it's going to start to
carbonate and it's going to build up
pressure so if you have a really cheap
or bad pour glass bottle it can explode
and it has this is important you're on a
label and make sure you put you know so
you remember which flavor you go and you
can you got to put the date on it so you
can keep track of how long it takes to
to do the double fermentation I got some
really nice in the sky out of grapes
fresh and I juiced them and we're going
to we're going to try making a kombucha
with that now I like to use a lot of
like already packaged bottle juices
they're pasteurized so they're dead but
they had a good flavor and they have the
sugar which is the most important when
you make your own it'll it carbonates a
lot faster because it's just a eager to
live man so yeah like I said you know
this ain't rocket surgery so I don't
really uh highball everything you know
I'm a really big measure so that's how
much we do we'll call it must
oh I like that I could come up with
little names for me no I'm really
creative so this is apricot I just write
apricot and then you can mix them til
you can really put anything in it we've
done the fresh berries juice them and
they come out fantastic all right so
let's bottle a few real quick see where
we're at so then yeah I got this big old
my bottle and jug and then just fill
them up you want to leave well you have
to leave you got to leave a little bit
of air on there to try to let those
little bubbles settle and then I'll come
back and top it off but you want to fill
it to about right here
and then that's it you seal it up you
want to get this tight real tight though
he's got to be airtight
like a frog's ass watertight you can use
just regular wine corks but these seem
to work really well you can just keep
reusing them you got to push them in
pretty pretty good as far as it'll go
wait that's that wait about I was going
to put a date on that wait about four
days and then don't open it you know
just let it go
little patience you start falling boots
doesn't like to be messed up you just
got to let it do its thing
so yeah you add all that juice but when
it's done it's not real sweet because
the living organisms microorganisms
inside here eat the sugar and produce
the carbon dioxide science so that's it
Brad's bitchin boot Oh God
this is going to get me fired oh we have
successful carbonation look at that oh
that's beautiful thing