yeah man I'll drop the boot Hoopa drives
the movement like I'm off from one of
those uh those railroad things you know
me and Vinnie we're heading to
Mississippi oh stop you every time
bottom down Vinnie and we're not waiting
on nowhere huh say being stuck in the
snow a rocket you know pump it up more
I'd turn around and drive it forward
[Music]
I'm gonna need your focus anything of
this Oh
oh that felt good like a scratch you've
been trying to get so we're here at my
buddy Dan Suarez his house at the Suarez
family brewery up here by Germantown
hold on start over Dan where are we ah
Livingston there's more into beer than
just putting some grains and some water
in something I mean everyone knows you
know they just go to the store they buy
the beer but there's a lot that goes
into it and there's a lot of life
involved all right I got one job grains
in the bin hey just in case how do you
turn this machine off I got you on the
ammo guy in Saving Private Ryan you know
you're never gonna run out but
it has some sugar in it now but it also
has starch in it and a starch
yeah exactly but it's all that starch
gets converted to sugar by the enzyme
yes science which is exactly learn
something every day Vinnie I got some
German at me it shits in my blood
oh yeah look at me look Jeremy little
Dutch
[Music]
I can see that again
so we just did those 18 bags of malted
barley into the grinder and what why do
we grind it almost every kernel gets
split so then you're exposing the starch
inside of the kernel it will be very
cloudy and chunky and I'll recirculate
it and then 45 minutes later it's like
crystal clear yeah wort Vinnie WRAT year
I did know man really it W all our team
wore is that you like get on your finger
wo wo RT hey why is he so important in
beer making process without yeast it
would just be like sugary hop T the
yeast eats the sugar yes he introduces
what is alcohol produces alcohol and co2
but it also kicks off tons of flavor
ooh we're going to call this so
breakfast the breakfast hooch no there's
no alcohol now man it's just sugar it's
just like oh pretty nice so Dan's
pumping the finished wharf clarified
shoot through the pipes into the cooking
vessel that what do we call that damn
handle yes yes boil kettle and then from
there we're going to boil it add the
hops what they do is they take fresh
hops and they turn it into a powder and
they pressurize it and make little
pellets Dan and correct me if I'm wrong
but this is just as good as using fresh
cones yeah same thing
right see it hitting the liquid
you
dan just got off the phone with the pig
farmer he's gonna come over around 4
p.m. Eastern Standard Time and pick up
this this spent grain pigs go nuts of
this stuff har-har-har it feels good on
your face
forget the pigs send this rate to the
spa oh oh by no means is that underrated
alright Benny quit fooling around we got
work to do
yeah Dan's wearing glasses and gloves
and even give me any protective gear but
uh you know
you know but your friends are we're
gonna be miss Frances messing around
Sani all day if you even get us on your
skin for a second and your skin starts
turning white and it'll burn oh really
yeah and then forget if you get this in
your eye it's like Jesus Christ I let it
get that shit out of me hey Brad stand
over here I'm going to wear gloves and
glasses you can hug him he'll liquid in
your eyeballs and what so this is where
fermentation will take place yeah where
we'll add our yeast from another conical
and it will flash chill after we boil in
here will flash chill through this heat
exchanger into there and we'll add our
yeast to and then hopefully by tomorrow
morning it's a this is the flash chilly
so cold water goes pump that way
boiling work get pumped
and then they exchange heat and then we
return hot water into the hot water tank
and by the time it gets the work gets
here it's nice and cool
yeah like touch to telling you got to
taste all the ingredients FINA
Oh bitter tiny not too bad
I mean that's a nice consistency
beautiful nice pale pancake batter
creamy now I'm going to hook up the keg
and we're gonna harvest hey could I have
some of that yeast this one right here
yeah you can take some I'm a steal a
little yeast for back home back in the
back in the in the BA Test Kitchen oh
yeah good luck bread how'd that work out
oh Jesus Christ
nice flick there dance
yeast is in here we know this we're
gonna pipe it through this is our little
side glass well here we go dance coming
mmm right into the keg oh oh yeah
nice thick yeast looks good right yeah
it's going on alright we're going to
take this keg over to the fermentation
vessel where we're going to add to pitch
the yeast into the beer and that's where
all the fermentation happens all the
life force begins to eat sugars create
alcohol create all that nice depth of
flavor that you'll get you get in beer
and yeah you really can't do it without
the yeast the word is filling the tank
from the bottom and now we're pretty
much good to add this whole can of yeast
word not to be confused with wort as
we're pumping the word and this is
getting kind of mixed niche then desert
as we're pushing it in science then you
wouldn't understand so we got our
fermentation vessel filling up with the
yeast filling up with our completed wort
that mixes up in there and then inside
here is where all the fermentation
starts happened and once all the
fermentation is done the yeast settles
the beer stays up top yeast is down here
we'll pipe the beer into another vessel
filled with just just the beer whatever
yeast didn't settle in the first vessel
will settle in the second that's where
we'll carbonate it from there pipe it in
the bottles and kegs and start drinking
some beer I just came in here not
knowing much about beer other than how
to drink it and we figured you know
working with Dan we did the grains we
did we made the war word start over
Vinnie we got the wort going it's like a
goddamn you in there so pretty much what
we own what I learned the most and what
my favorite part about the beer making
experience is how much life force is
involved in it without the yeast there
is no beer and without beer there's a
lot of unhappy people Suarez family
brewery really hitting home runs over
here so thanks to them for having us and
let's go drink some beer he's a Magic
Man
that's what it's gonna play out I'm
pretty much dude straight down the
center yeah that's like sausage oh
that's a goddamn Simpsons episode I'll
take a dump beer right there that look
good that looks
there you go sir
[Music]