Jesus Christ they got to put a bell on
you all right guys today I'm it's alive
we're going to set up a couple pieces of
bone the short rib boneless chicken
thigh and some experimental shrimp with
some Koji I've done all of them about
the shrimp but you know it is a Test
Kitchen so we'll we'll give it a shot
which was out for a week yeah you know I
never claimed to be an expert we're just
learning together Vinnie
[Music]
all right Vinnie let's get started with
the Koji and what it is is just it's a
rice that's inoculated with a mold
it's the alive part it comes like this
check this out
well granulars and what I do is I turn
it into a little powder just throw it in
a good blender so I just blitz this wood
you gotta be careful I don't know I'm a
little it gets a little powdery and it
gets in the air and it's got mold I'm
always scared to breathe it you know you
start growing things in your lungs or
something oh you see that smoke get away
from that minute and that's it that's
our powder suits they moved it on me
Benny oh here we go you know you get
people down here really nice you know
they we share the walk-in and they come
down here I had proof nice Bowl in the
short rib it's one of my favorite
culture it's relatively cheap you can
usually get it for like 10 bucks a pound
and then I got some shrimp just shell on
regular shrimp I'm what we're going to
peel them real quick I've never done the
Koji with shrimp but you know we'll give
it a shot so it tends to like make it a
little sweeter it gives it a little
little funkiness over time and when you
cook them nothing will caramelize faster
might be good might be bad but you know
we'll learn together
all right recommitting and these are
just some boneless chicken thighs so I
got my powdered coach and what I do is
just sprinkle it on it then you just
kind of like work it and Pat it in you
want to use a decent amount yeah you
know I thought about wearing the gloves
it's not harmful to me I'm not gonna
look at my fingers or rubbing my eyeball
I'm gonna wash my hands after you could
use gloves I feel like we use gloves for
everything you know I'm not like
preparing it for other people maybe just
some other you know coworkers and stuff
but there used to there used to my hands
good devein them I'm not going to okay
soon
depakote they're smaller and they're a
little more delicate it'll probably take
less time than the chicken and the beef
the beef taking the longest so I'm going
to put it right down here uncovered all
right I'm gonna let it breathe right in
here Benny
oh you can really see the difference
especially in the in the bone the short
ribs got a little darkness on the edges
there nice firming up today's Friday
come Monday all the shrimp will probably
done given the size of them and the fact
that its seafood you know it's not going
to really hang out as long as well as
you know the red meat or even the
chicken maybe we'll just cook a couple
shrimp real quick what do you think
where you think that give me a nod then
after it's been sitting in the coach you
want to rinse them and you see that
shine it kind of changed the whole
texture you know some would say oh why
cook them with olive oil you know why
not I'm not going to add anything to it
because I just want to see how it tastes
by itself we'll just cook those up all
right VIN oh yeah
it does make it a little tougher but not
in a bad way not in like a chewy way hey
Chris Clare anyone you guys want to try
this three bud oh my god nothing else no
salt no nothing
that's nothing got a little bit of
sweetness very good I like the texture
they're good for 36
oh stop it Chris maybe we'll do one
without we're gonna cook one with the co
John here in the Test Kitchen we bounce
a lot of ideas off each other we help
each other and that was a good idea
Thank You Claire ah ha look at that then
coach when one's getting a little cozy
crust uh-oh Claire I think you might be
on to something
I like what happened it's nice adds a
nice flavor
does it add something back to the
exterior that's got to look dried out
the shrimp delicious I don't think it
needs to go much longer at all then then
the four days it could probably even go
to win three we'll put the chicken in
the beef back in into the reach-in
because I don't know that can go the
extra time especially the beef the
chicken will be fine look at that almost
looks a little funky right but in a good
way I think the sweet spot might be like
three days with the chicken but what
won't say maybe this is the sweet spot
will say so let's give these a little
rinse
I've got dark the meat got shrimp a
little bit or old down here yeah you go
baby
now I solved it at the end because I
just want to see how its taste how it
cooks for the sake of science we're
going to do it just like this and this
is on pretty low so we're gonna let them
just cook nice low and slow damn ghost
town down here see it gets a little
glaze easy there then almost looks like
we applied a little sugar to it right oh
but we did not that's a hell of a crust
on there and we didn't add anything to
pop this over here but yeah nice color
Thanks
this would be great over some rice I
mean Christ throw it in the taco throw
it on a piece of bread throw it on
anything boneless chicken thigh you
can't go wrong with that
the chicken is surprisingly tender it
needs like a little so why you're coming
sure what's second time we're here joy
so I was good right what's it smell like
sweetie
you ever rub your body with Koji no but
that could be a different video maybe a
different website the chicken was a lot
better than I thought it was MB very
juicy really because it was thinner to
the boneless thigh it really penetrated
from both ends real nicely just a home
run on the week I mean I think you can
go five days that's fine if you're
worried about chicken hanging out in the
fridge but um shouldn't be a problem
with the shrimp that we did we left the
Koji on and gave it a nice little like
crispy kind of crunchy little texture on
the top which is very nice I'm afraid it
might burn if you did that with chicken
some people like that charred flavor you
know some people call it burn there you
go Koji koji rub your meats why not you
got some friends over they don't you
know Koji is you're telling them you're
putting it on your meat it's been
sitting in there for a week
just tell them after you know that tray
of carnage hope nobody gets sick save
some of the prep work for you guys you
know I don't want this to just be stuff
laying in a bowl ready to go like I'm
some kind of Hollywood star you know do
our own prep around here and I found out
I'm the only one who calls you Vinnie
I guess most call you Vincent