check tech me me me me me all right
today guys gonna be making a little
corned beef right now we just got the
brisket and I got some pickling spices I
like to make my own I got a couple
little things that aren't traditionally
in there but I like it and we're going
to set up a little curing brine that
takes about five days and then from
there you can cook it and that's where
you get your so we're going to make the
corned beef
[Music]
so we've got a brisket this is about
five six pound pieces what you're
looking for two and a half cups of salt
five teaspoons of the pink curing salt
and a half a cup of light brown sugar
and one Guinness for good measure that's
for the brine and then our pickling
spices chopped up ginger we've got some
coriander seed some allspice mixed black
and yellow mustard seeds juniper berries
some cardamom pods mixed peppercorns a
couple chili de arbol cinnamon stick and
some fresh bay leaves I got a little
skillet going over there on medium heat
oh yeah that's a beautiful thing already
we need to do that I just want to keep
it moving you don't really want to go
walking away and getting distracted
just get a little toasty you start
getting a little fragrant and that's
pretty much it we're not really looking
to put much color or burn anything here
you can start to really smell the
individual spices right off the bat you
can smell the clove you can smell you
can smell the clove you can smell it
with a magical penny stand by the recipe
calls for a 1 teaspoon of cloves which I
happen to forget you don't want to go
too hot you'll start to hear things
starting to crackle I'm starting to hear
it now a little bit and that's a good
indicator that you're getting pretty
close right from there away from the pot
you don't have a mortar and pestle I
highly recommended still crackling come
on Benny stick your camera in there just
give everything a nice little crush and
I just like to crack and open up the
spices oh it smells wonderful I know we
really got to work on a way to get those
smells into the camera
Alex Lainey how are you you got one go
ahead take ZnO
[Music]
very nice right all right we'll see you
later going so from here I have my
vessel this is what we're going to put
the brisket in to cure so I got two and
a half cups of kosher salt 1/2 cup brown
sugar like so and this is the pink
curing salt and then just you know
little Guinness you know st. Patrick's
Day and from there this very important
you want to make sure that everything
gets dissolved in the liquid so from
there we're just going to add the spice
mixture in there mix it up nice add the
beef cover it five days and then you
know what we'll see what happens
that smell is something else OOP I want
to take a half a cup of this and reserve
it and that'll be our cooking spice for
when we cook the corned beef leaves you
with a cup add that right in okay so
boom we got our brine here nice piece of
meat now here's a little thing I like to
do can I take a little cake tester and I
just like to prick some little holes and
especially by the fat the brine
sometimes has a harder time getting
through the fat than it does just
straight onto the beef brain itself and
then from there we just go right into
the brine oh look at that no overflows
the brisket tends to float a little what
I like to do is you get if just a plate
that fits or anything that's food safe
that can you know handle being in water
and I just like to place that right on
top of the meat there you go that's the
move right there now from here I just
wrapped with a little plastic let me
know what are we doing bud oh there's
some cracks all right Oh Mia's got crabs
doing the old Brad wrap oh yeah oh yeah
they love that oh yeah they're gonna
they're gonna hate you for that well
you're gonna throw that in the ocean -
yeah I know wrap around some dolphin
why he is doing that is because it acts
he's got a little ice pack in there and
the layers of plastic wrap which we
recycle afterwards it acts as a little
insulator and becomes a he's got a
little cooler now you got yourself some
crabs this weekend but oh came over here
for the plastic all right no big deal
all right so from here we'll drop this
in the fridge now I'll see you guys in
five days there we go
you better get the door bud so let me
take the the old plates out yeah that's
our guy
we'll give that a nice rinse you don't
have to go nuts getting everything off
because we're going to cook this we're
going to we're going to boil it
essentially here I just got a nice
little stock you can use Dutch oven or
just like give you a nice little sized
stockpot so add in our spices there
she's heavy
right in your water and we're going to
let that boil for like 15-20 minutes
watched pot never boils then you can
walk we're just around then he just
loves filming me paint me Vinny like one
of your french girls hi I can't work
like this
so that's cooking away and now we'll
turn it down in heat to a little
medium-low throw a little cover on there
and we'll let that go for about three
and a half four hours happens over time
low and slow magic all right me look
Benny corned beefs all done nice
fork-tender
yeah buddy that's it I'll put some green
cabbage that i-cord come up some carrots
and some red skin potatoes and an onion
I put that all in there let that cook
for about 40 minutes and then I pull it
out and serve that on the side nice pink
nice color that's from the curing salt
so the grain is going like this so you
kind of want to cut it on the by you
want to cut it against the grain
[Music]
alright check this out finis look that's
what you want you want to be able to get
grain separation not falling apart but
separation get yourself load Guinness
right there yes by the st. Patrick's
days it gets I can hear the bagpipes
going
let's go focus here and that's it
corned beef cabbage st. Patrick's Day
Bon Appetit all right no more Benny
we're done does that mean V to get our
work done
oh sweet nectar a little late in the
game four o'clock afternoon shot you
know we had a little we got put on the
back burner a couple celebrities in the
house I mean old Vinny but Benny we're
gonna have a little beer before we go
looking for a sponsorship me drink your
beer make me nervous be a cop