hey guys today we're gonna be cooking
some st. louis-cut pork ribs I got a
marinating with a little spice creation
and we're gonna throw them on a campfire
here and I'll show you a cool little
takeaway for using your empty cooler
[Music]
so yeah I got myself set up on a nice
little three-part fire here so we got
our little fire in the back that's
produced in charcoal for us to feed into
these two chambers I got these grates
about anywhere from like 10 to 12 inches
off the coal we just want to gradually
pick up some nice color start to cook
these through a little bit and then I'm
gonna make this little sauce that we're
gonna baste on and keep turning and
build like a nice shellac from there
wrap them in foil and then in the cooler
they go we also got some corn on the cob
that we're going to char up with the
husks on see what's great about a good
cooler it's just an insulated box
designed to retain that cold temperature
it works the same way if we're if you
put hot things in there it's going to
keep it hot the same way like a thermos
works for cooking for Karthi the coffee
is my favorite way to cook ribs one of
my favorite ways is you grill them real
nice and then rattmann foil and put them
in the oven for a couple hours and they
come out perfect so we're kind of gonna
turn it into like a low temp oven miss
this little setup when we leave any have
a cool little kitchen but wear your
gloves
Eirene get that Corcoran we'll get that
corn on the cob going I love cooking
corn on the cob like this you know I
don't I don't peel it you know or
whatever you call that what do you call
that what do you do it Tuscan corn like
corn Huskers from Nebraska keep them
right in here and just put this right
over the the cooking surface if you're
tight for space sometimes I trim that
off so just keep turning them let them
get all charred up on the outside the
inside when you're done they comes out
perfect nice and sweet tender kind of
steams within the husks so when you're
working on a system like this over coals
you'll start to notice little patterns I
mean you can adjust if I put dragon
coals or certain areas you find your hot
spots you know I've see if this one's
picking up a lot of color this one's not
you know switch them in and out you just
got to keep an eye on it and just kind
of work the grill so now there's a
little bit of a dry rub on it next part
we're gonna do we're gonna build a
little sauce that we're going to brush
on the old ribs they're just whatever
wherever you're into some kind of just
stubs appropriate stubs legendary
barbecue sauce and then I'll put a pinch
of this stuff in this is our the dry rub
that we've rubbed
down with well had a healthy amount of
that olive oil only the good stuff
Google fashioned Budweiser oh yeah pour
some of that right in there
yeah save a little swig for yourself and
yeah we'll just mix that up you want it
kind of loose but you're also kind of on
it a little thick you know you don't
want to just run right off and that's it
that's all mixed up ready to go oh yeah
all right let's go get a basin we'll get
that going and we'll just start mopping
it on you just want to brush it on nice
you don't want to go crazy heavy so it
all trips into the fire
I mean somes gonna oh you're just really
we're gonna do this like 15 times on
each side so it's you brush them on and
then you flip and let it kind of bake on
now this part you really don't want to
walk away from too much because the
barbecue sauce will start to burn a
little bit if you just let it go as soon
as I flip it I start to apply the next
batch the sauce is starting to just like
bake on it and become like its own
little you know it's crusted up it's
bacon I like the word shellac it just
starts to build layers of caramelized
basting sauce meanwhile we're turning
our corn every so you wanted to get all
charred up in there don't worry about
the husk the kernels are they're not
gonna really any color on they're just
gonna be perfect
all right let's assemble the googly Nia
this is how this is how it comes
together all right we're knows one of
them stupid-looking winter hats watch a
big puffy palm ball on top no no no we
don't roll that way
no I can't say that
all right reckon we're almost ready to
get them in foil oh you didn't bring an
industrial you know camping I think one
of the best tools you can bring if it's
a - oh yeah sure it's a tool it's tin
foil you can make a lid you can make
whatever we're gonna use them to wrap up
these ribs lock in heat lock in the
moisture and let them steam in here hold
on hello what's up hat look a bit oh
good
yeah I like to do a nice little double
wrap cuz you really want to make sure
all the the heat and the moisture gets
locked in there you know might seem like
overkill but trust me it's not so we're
gonna take those and throw them right
back on there and just let them get nice
and hot inside the foil we cooked them I
mean technically you could eat these
ribs right now you know you would just
be Herman or chewing them off the bone
like a dog but now what we're trying to
achieve is connective tissue and some of
the tougher you know fibers start to
break down and I think that happens and
in most meats around 165 160 something
like that 160 something like that like
that so by wrapping them in the foil
getting them hot in here throwing them
in the cooler they carry over their heat
and they actually continue to cook as if
this were acting kind of like an oven
that color on the core and that's what
you're looking for that's I mean you can
even go harder I think it can really
take a hammering you want to do a good
10 minutes like this so crucial
don't just wrap them and put them in
there it'll be a better product when
you're done if you let them spend a
little bit of time on the on the fire in
in the foil I'm gonna go ahead and throw
the corn right in the cooler and then
real quick we're gonna just stack the
ribs right on top and again the more
things you add here the more heat to
trap the better the pose that baby
immediately a little latch Oh on there
alright there's our little campfire oven
all right if you wanted to you could
throw a little locks on here
boom no one's getting in not Vinnie not
Smokey the Bear nobody so we'll go ahead
and put that right over here we're gonna
go take a little walk come back and say
two hours all right let me get my
fucking spirit back here this here huh
it's been a day look at that steaming
baby oh yeah oh they're ripping hot grab
one of them there here's the corn close
the door to the oven alright let's open
peel this baby up mine the finger the
the old glove here you know he
distracted me I'm cutting up potatoes
with the mandolin then he starts talking
about freaking bow hunting then go oh I
can shoot a bow whoo-hoo I can also cut
my finger off thanks VIN oh yeah oh yeah
ripping hot who's hot hot to touch oh
yeah yeah the meat is kind of coming
it's right there man it's perfect
well-seasoned all the way through that
dry rub really penetrates it the meats
tender as can be I don't need them to be
pulling the bone out because then you're
just eating like this bit it's delicious
I mean I'm not complaining I like eating
it off the bone you know that's part of
like the rib the rib things let's see
what the corn looks like oh yeah still
hot man you can't beat that oh yeah
sweet not mushy so what I like about
cooking corn in the husk just stays nice
and crisp and poppy but cooked all the
way through super sweet super sweet bone
Appetit I don't know what to say you
know what's that when you're at a party
or a dinner and no one's talking what's
that mean foods really good right corner
table freakin ribs might as well be
sitting in some barbecue joint oh no no
we're in the woods Vinny there you go
man push yourself get out there in the
woods and cook some different foods and
hopefully you can try this technique let
us know how it goes and yeah get in the
woods enjoy it cook nothing really good
ma'am
I feel like a bird of paradise you know
they do that nutty they're going around
there like throw rocks in the air
build like little weird little
structures or like woo a female Vinny
I'm just look I got built I built this
baby are you impressed you want to mate
for life got these new glasses over at
Rite Aid mmm you know a twenty bucks man
I got ripped off but I they made me sign
up for you know you got to become a
member and then you can buy one get one
free but only if you give me your phone
number and you know date of birth and
the birth certificate of your first
freaking child then you can get in the
Rite Aid Club Joe gave a bunch of false
information suckers I feel that's to
brew stop the car real quick yeah I love
Subaru man you know all-wheel drive
reliable hey I'm Brad Leone I don't
always drive but when I do I trust
subaru subaru get out there enjoy the
wilderness
no but really give me a car do we have
to do the tent nowadays these things are
pretty straightforward it's usually just
a couple pull oh Jesus Vinny I mean come
on bud this is funny but