today Vinnie we're gonna be making one
of my favorites a half sour pickle we
would be doing this in a field then he
picture the cucumber vines growing
around me
oh not around me better you know in the
background
Hawks buzzin rabbits hopping okay
[Music]
some people like the full sour but for
me it's a little tomb I like it a little
too mushy the full sour for me a pickle
should be bright in color a nice crisp
to it so I picked up these little
Kirby's little cuties here I gave him a
little wash but water and that's about
it basically what we're doing is we're
making a saltwater brine and then we're
gonna add some spices garlic I like to
have a little bit dill and then it's
real simple you just put the cucumber's
in put the old lid on and then pop it in
I put it in the fridge for about 10 days
that's it and you end up getting just a
perfect perfect pickle
check this out Vinny this is it's got
science written all over it but I got my
little project book so for pickles I got
this on the old Internet and it's just a
saltwater brine the percentages so I'm
gonna go with 3.5% and 2 quarts so we're
gonna need 66 grams of salt we'll pop
that right on there here Vinnie I'll
turn this around for the sake of
television so we're gonna save any 66
right grams that is okay top top top
and then I'm just gonna add the water I
use is like room temp you know just
going to dissolve the salt so now I'm
just gonna get that a little a little a
little shake okay okay
[Music]
all right so what I'm gonna do next is
I'm gonna add all my spices like I got
some real good garlic from the from the
farmers market
I could give it a little crush we
explained that in that one and I think
we put that into that honey garlic honey
episode but with garlic when you crush
it it's kind of like a two-part epoxy
you know it's like a two-part glue or
epoxy you crush the cell when something
is crushing the cell walls and it makes
a thing called allicin so it starts to
make the Alison and that's like they
were super what's really good for you in
garlic then the Alison is what it's
really really good for you in garlic I
believe I believe but we I think we
talked about that in a different episode
so I give it a little crush in just a
little slice each op and that can go
right into the brine thanks grace and
then next we'll add celery seed you know
you have to go measure and just uh I do
it by how I you know I'm feeling it out
you know a little celery here we got a
little dill seed just a little bit and
there's little stuff called fennel
pollen it's kind of expensive but you
know it goes a long way little dab'll do
ya and we'll just do a little pinch of
that in there your night huh and then
also I'm not gonna do it just why maybe
I do a pinch what the hell all right
that's right it is this is a dill pollen
little pinch of that in there okay and
then I like to put just a little bit of
dill fresh dill in it and what I like to
do a little wild card here Vincenzo is I
got some of these little cherry peppers
okay I don't want to spicy I'm just
gonna cut out that top green there and
you know whatever kind of pepper you
want
yeah that's optional if you don't want
to go spicy and then don't do it what's
that look like me looks like a brain or
walnut
yeah great story Matt what's that stuff
in peppers that's hot
kickass kiyose well Claire the stuff in
peppers that's hot how do you say that
kick at capsaicin thanks Claire
she's a little half sour ourselves
perhaps oh my god Claire it's perfect
half salad Claire oh my god perfect
Claire half sour Savitz this is how
things happen organically all right be
pay attention so just gonna slice these
thin here throw that on your sandwich
with the pickled she zoom right in yes
should we grab a couple rows yeah
if any hold up your pack are you come
with me bud mmm little crepe cake oh
Claire what are you doing oh all right
all right just gonna throw a few in
there like so or C Wells Orson Welles
okay what's Orson Welles Citizen Kane of
the movie Citizen Kane is in Citizen
Kane a movie it's focused around
rosebuds sounds great thanks man
all right now we're just gonna throw the
cucumbers into the bride okay I'm gonna
push him bad boys down a little and
that's it but look I'll throw the lid on
this give a little shake for good
measure of in get all that garlic into
that but oh you know what I forgot that
silly me
is the do a little mustard seed in there
and I read somewhere you can to help
them keep crunchy and firm people throw
like oak leaves in there and stuff all
right here mustard seeds too can act
that way not quite sure why but I'm sure
Google could tell you Oh
highest proof oh you know what maybe
I'll have a couple black peppercorns
then all right boom we'll pop this in
the fridge for ten days
I like to go in to the fridge about
every day I like good every day because
it's fun and just give it the old turn
around you know the old who just to get
things mixed up in nice to make sure
everything's getting all happy in there
takes note one thing's called snow
globes pickle pickle snow 811 half sour
Brad I mean there's probably
four-year-olds I can write back all
right let's go
oh I've been perfect brought to you by
something oh these are some old ones
kind of sad situation we're gonna finish
these up today but these are been in
here for over a month
certainly still very well I mean I have
lots of crunch to them big flavor
seasoned all the way through me come
back in ten days I'm going on vacation
so see you later oh hello rapper you
like pickles this is not sweet half sour
dill garlic looks like it's got a nice
green color yep get in there Vinny so
this is ten days cold Brian
[Music]
hmm nice it's a good Shamu football good
crunch ready to crunch you come berry
but still infuse the flavor well very
well seasoned yeah are like a hammer
cheese sandwich now and then would be
all good I knew I liked you check this
out any really really penetrated into
that part of the cucumber and will cut
one open yeah you can almost see where
the shade starts to get a little darker
in there and that's just the brine over
time starts to saturate it which is nice
as long as it retains its nap oh yeah
that's now you pick that up Vinny so
yeah mix it up a little ham dough
sandwich and be letting you know it show
up to a party everyone's bringing you
know they got the hamburgers you show up
with some homemade half sours you know
Oh Andy what's up bud yeah here speaking
to the microphone have one yeah
Vinny can't get his equipment together
huh you don't feel so good great too
salty I'm right there right there it
does at the end you get up it but that's
personal preference but the overall
crunch texture boom so yeah but pop that
back in the fridge and got yourself a
little half sour there I think ten days
has been you can start to eat them but I
think you got a solid month in the
fridge before you start to lose some of
that crunchiness that shouldn't last you
a month you know I can eat a couple of
those a day no problem yeah it's perfect
then put them in whatever you want you
know just go great with little bit like
a little tuna melt who doesn't love a
tuna melt I do let us know if eyes
anything you'd like to see me enroll
Vincenzo here for men put it in the old
comment section well uh we'll try to
crank away and do one of those bon
appetit Minnie OH
vacation was great Vinny best lobsters I
ever had and then we had steamers and
and the beach of any grass is blowing in
the background you know what else you
wanted a life yeah a couple million
bucks Bugatti well we got to wrap this
up but today what's today the Torah the
21st we got that big old soul America
solar eclipse today
total eclipse many we're not gonna see
the totem we'll see a partial or
whatever the call on it that's happening
pretty soon maybe we should probably
wrap this up bring our pickles
downstairs and we can go check out so
you know the Earth's gonna get weird
vampires gonna come out and it gives the
we got pickles
[Music]