I don't know I really don't know what
I'm doing let's look today we're going
to be doing a little lacto-fermented hot
sauce and it's just a little microbial
process you know because the peppers
they're they've been picked but they're
still there's still a lot of stuff in
there that's alive and doing weird stuff
botulism Chris this guy is botulism no
one's had botulism since like nineteen
twenty that might not be true
[Music]
I got some Fresno's and some habaneros I
like to do a little blend because the
habaneros they have great flavor really
not very floral but they can be super
super hot so I like to cut them with
some Fresno's we're working with chilies
you want to use I will you don't have to
do whatever you want you should use some
Platt I got latex gloves because you get
the chili the pepper oils that get on
your hands
get in your eyes go to the bathroom you
get yourself in a row ah a real world
too trouble there it's happened before
it's happened before it's wrong no good
so we're gonna go get some gloves all
right Minnie what I do is I just trim
the top I mean people you know maybe oh
your waist and peppers yada yada yada
but I ain't got that kind of time that's
enough so now I'm going to cut all the
caps off I'll take the seeds out it's a
little tedious but you get a good you
get a good yield on it a couple little
seeds in there no big deal we're not
going to go nuts
but we got all the tops all the seeds
out a little bit of dried hibiscus a
couple mixed peppercorns four cardamom
pods we could use five if you want
little big deal we'll use just a little
pinch of that Morosco they're nice and
then the garlic Vinnie always crush your
garlic we're going to use six
tablespoons of just regular old sea salt
and then we'll do the same with sugar
now I'm going to add two quarts of water
I like to add just a little bit first
all right give it a little shakey shakey
you don't get everything just a little
little dissolved until then I'll make it
a little nice you know
oh yeah little pro move right we learn
this from mistakes you put the peppers
in first and then your border just in
case your vessels too small you don't
lose all your you know I'm saying so
we'll put these bad boys in there all
right that will measure the water now
Chris you know percentages we're going
to give this a nice little shake all
right we'll let that sit very important
what you do here so it's fermenting so
it's going to be releasing gas and
pressure so if you left this closed for
a week and a half I mean this has a lot
it might blow up what you have to do
every day is just they call it burping
and what you do is you just let you just
let the UH you just let the gas out when
you open it all the bubbles will rise
and you'll see that it's very active
it's Jesus yeah well let that go for
we'll come back in about a week and a
half you ready then Oh
well it made a little that was a little
anti-climatic for the video but yeah
they look spinning you see all these
little bubbles coming up that's a good
sign that fermentation is started so I
like to do sometimes Vinnie I like to
just go in there and massage them a
little break them not break them up
because there's still pretty firm I mean
there's still peppers then that'll
release some of the pepper funk wah
there to help we'll all get to
fermentation really going full burns the
nostrils a bit Vinnie all right so we'll
go another week sometimes if you get a
little white silky film over the top
some people think it's mold or it's bad
it's ruined it's just a yeast that
naturally occurs sometimes no one's ever
gotten sick from that might want to
fact-check that all right all right
Vinnie so we left off ouch we're going
to give it a little agitation you see
all the bubbles coming up
you're catching that on your high-def
camera Vinnie we're gonna give it a
little burp really get one shot here one
shot one kill like Tom Berenger
ooh
hear that this could go a few more days
you know given this a holiday season
over here Bon Appetit Oh God
you know 2016 is exhausting we're going
to have to cut it a little short so what
the next step is what we're going to do
is we're going to strain off all the
liquid
look at that color isn't that wonderful
great well put all this into the blender
and then we'll add a little bit of that
uh that that table Brian oh god these
things you know Oh God
Oh Vinny then he do not put that in all
right so that's enough I think Vinny if
we need to add more add more start this
baby on low
you ready for that turbocharger thing
that's the stuff
that's the stuff in it look at color
nice right well
look at that color baby vibrant freakin
glow-in-the-dark nice smooth consistency
but not too watery I've done this a
couple times like that you know I had
never really got a measurement of the
actual brine that you put into it
is somewhere around like a cup or
something I smell half of it on the
floor you better off adding less
blending it and finding out you need to
add more because once you add it you
can't get it back all right so next step
I got these real cute little bottles
here you put your hot sauce in there
beautiful color it's great on anything
put on eggs put a pizza put it on making
tacos but on whenever you want great
little gift to you give this to somebody
a homemade hot sauce you the hero
whatever is left over I just keep in
mason jars right in the refrigerator and
just fill up the little bottles when you
need to now we got all this really it's
a the color is fantastic look at that
color baby Hey look at that color
beautiful color look at that color isn't
that wonderful
the color is fantastic and I call it a
table Brian and I put it in a little
little woozy bottle like this and
sometimes you put that on the table
little pop-pop put that on your chicken
on your salad or whatever it's going to
be my retirement plan open up a table
Brian company so that's that look at
that no waste absolutely no waste hey
Emile we ought to get someone who knows
something about hot sauce to try one of
these buddy nice little heat its Fresno
and Oh zing oh it's nice right it's not
it doesn't have like a vinegary quality
but you get them yeah gas it by putting
soy sauce and hot sauce on the same time
you know I get into that big big you the
big you oh that's fantastic
cheers Bon Appetit tip vinius all I got
for you bud Claire you want to taste
something yes
taste the table Brian first I don't know
I haven't taste it it's like it's salty
a little spicy though florally go okay
well spicy habanero not crazy but not
crazy it was a little though good Brian
Oliver Oh
I'm saying fried chicken sweat oh stop
it
garlic hibiscus you finish yeah yeah
tingles and nostrils a bit well we're
also spooning it into our mouths you
know the habanero
yeah that's does Vinny that's his Vinny
rushed us on the fermentation well he
needs got to go to Virginia for
Christmas so we had a yeah way to go
Finn
yeah everybody's getting one in their
stockings
[Music]