Binney you hear that nothing just
sizzling shrimp
[Music]
mimimi
all right set up here in the woods we
got our multi zone fire all dialed in
ready to go if you guys want to learn
more about how to make that incredible
multi zone backwoods fire tune in do we
have another way no no no no check out
just say that check out a previous
episode we did about that check this out
we got a nice little thing going all
right set up my little work area we're
gonna make a little dinner back here
got this pretty sweet cooler and it
really allows me to bring other types of
foods into the woods other than just the
usual stuff you know hamburgers and hot
dogs you know say no baseball game so
what we packed up in here check this out
bin and get in here so we got some
oysters patagonian wild red shrimp very
nice we've got some langoustines all the
way from friends down in New Zealand and
then I got some salmon collars that I'm
soaking in a little soy sauce bear with
the bag they're gonna get real pretty on
the grill first fish we're gonna do
salmon collars put those right over
there let them smoke let them cook a
little just skin side down first I got
the shell on shrimp so yeah we're just
gonna throw these right on the grill now
I'm not gonna clean them or nothing just
throw them right on cook them through
but now I'm not crazy and then I'll put
them in the cast iron over there we're
just hanging out put a little butter in
it some spices and we'll do like a
little spicy kind of buttery shrimp
thing I mean how bad could that be he's
gonna want to flip these little these
little bugs up real nice little shrimp I
just wanted to get a little smoke a
little char on to the skin so as they
start to you know the ones in the hotter
spots I can just put right back into
here you know I need to invent something
for smoke in your eyes you know how are
you doing over there Vinny oh yeah then
maybe they call that goggles now the
thing how here's a good little little
tip hot when you're cooking fish if the
skin doesn't want to release weight it
will when it's ready this one's starting
to move around look at the color on that
huh
and what's nice about the collars is
that they're relatively cheap as they're
getting more popular they they seem to
be getting a little more expensive their
fatty they're delicious
but they're also kind of tough you know
it's not like a big floppy flakies filet
we called the collar because that guess
that you know the collar
it's like right behind the head before
the fillet that little chunk there where
that little fin is the fan well what's
fin then fish have several fin they got
these fin I think they call them the
pectoral fins and then they got I think
the dorsal okay different species have
all different kinds of ends Vinny this
that's a different television show right
much they understand understand topic
don't really need to too much put a
little bit of lemon in there let that
get a little color all right I got a
little bit of spice so custom blend here
I'm just gonna let that heat up and then
I'll put it off to the side again I'm
gonna have a little bit of butter to
these shrimp let that melt start getting
nice a little bit paper
I got a mixture here it's like a little
little riff on like Old Bay now you got
another little thing here it's kind of
like a leper but it's called it's like a
morass but beer you know the salmon
collars you can tell when they're done
you start probing around when the meat
goes from that leg almost very glossy
deep almost red orange to that more
opaque
you know lighter pink the fish is done
and the collars can really take a
hammering of heating there so fatty it's
almost like you want to cook them pretty
hard
the shrimp shrimp cook pretty fast
anyway the best way to check is to take
one out cut it open the shrimp should be
white all the way through not too like
that translucent raw kind of shrimp
looking I mean again this isn't theirs
these are references these are ideas
that hopefully you guys can find some
inspiration on get out in the woods and
cook for yourself it's not like Oh cook
this shrimp for 15 minutes because your
fire is gonna be a little different your
hot spot might be a little colder than
mine Yatta Yatta Yatta so it's like a
you know you guys know what to do just
do it not just because I'm sitting on a
Yeti cooler but uh IRA tell you what it
was a pretty surprised on how well I
mean those fish were were ice cold you
know we're not twenty-five miles off the
in the Appalachian Trail slepping all
the you know cast-iron and stuff like
that so you know save your comments
alright we're you know we walked in
about 15 minutes
I just want to get into the woods and
get out of the kitchen and just try
different things
look at those shrimp that's a beautiful
thing so the shrimp are pretty much done
you know let them hang out let's try
this bad boy out I've never cooked these
in the woods it's pretty much I think I
mean you can eat the claw but I think
it's all about that tail baby so let's
try to get that a little little chat up
then we'll flip them around get those
claws of cooking I want to finish him in
the potatoes yeah langoustines very
similar it's almost a little mix between
like a giant shrimp and a lobster I've
been wrong before
maybe we should google that one whoa no
huh don't use your tongs here bonehead
lemon squeezy squeeze so we just melted
some butter in there I put a little bit
of that Old Bay riff on there and some
scallions and a little bit of green
garlic in there too that'll be a nice
little sauce for the Lang goes for the
shrimp or whatever you want you know all
right we got some nice juices coming out
of the heads of these langostinos are
starting to happen pretty good tails
starting to curl little usually it kind
of cooks like a small lobster so I'm
just gonna place them oh alright for me
like a perfect grilled oyster is like
70% raw so like the outside gets a
little color doesn't look raw it looks
cooked but in the inside when you eat it
it's just piled little ocean popper man
ooh
ocean popper Vinny no cut don't fill
this so you guys haven't learned
anything you want meeting that film son
you certainly don't say Vinny don't film
this so you got your flat side and then
you got the cup outside so I like to
take the cup side down and as they get
hot they'll start to pop open a little
oasis like I said they really depend on
the size cook times go and how you like
them because you can just eat these raw
so let's face it it really comes down to
personal preference as soon as they
start to pop open is what I like to eat
them soon as they open up all right you
just put them on a little plate let them
cool off a little oh this is it babe so
it's got that little inductor on top I
like to cook oh yeah
look at that bud like I said cooked on
the outside a little but you could tell
that's raw on the inside sill ooh boom a
little appetizer everything else is done
we're good to eat no meaty man look at
that
cooked all the way through oh that's
good ma'am
I'm not just saying that that's good Oh
get some more oh that was God that
shrimp there oh look I'm gonna peel oh
god yeah oh yeah we're gonna have any
huh you know that buttery salmon oh good
god tell me you don't like salmon I'll
tell you try caller perfect fatty it's
almost like it's almost like salmon
belly oh it's delicious
let's try Lango Oh God Oh looks like
crabmeat right in the old butter sauce
huh that was awesome
the tail doesn't want to come off that
means it's not cooked and a great way to
open these bad boys up similar to a
lobster tail just crack them with your
in your hand like that push those little
spikes in oh jeez and there's how God
maybe you don't do that oh that was good
Vinny
all right what I'm gonna do here take my
long time do the old long stretch I'm
gonna pull that little heat element out
now cuz we're done cooking
we have enough little coals under there
just to keep our food hot all right we
could all gather around the campfire me
and all my friends so you stumble across
someone in the back of the woods here
cooking man that smells a little funny
hon I don't smell like hot dogs
hamburgers little bratwurst
hey all great all fun but look at that
spread middle of nowhere with the very
cooler do you bring anything in the
woods brought Vinnie man I tell you what
I wish I had this at my house it's fun
to cook on so
a lot of work but as soon as you get a
little system down like so you can
really just start to have fun and play
around and start cooking with different
ingredients and I mean I don't know
don't get too much cooler than sitting
around a fire next to some mossy
mountain here eating langoustines and
salmon collars and some some pretty
gnarly looking shrimp bone Appetit baby
oh the Bears worried about bears yeah
well we clean up real well you know
we'll get a big fire going later any
seafood trash and we'll bring our cart
we can you know if you have garbage you
can put it up in a tree or you can hike
it out but um we should be fine you know
hope so
no a Vinny I ain't noodling man you know
I'll do a lot of things but I ain't
noodling for fish okay bring my own
seafood pal all right
noodle and that's how I go noodle end up
sticking my hand in one em holes pulling
out snapping turtle missing about three
fingers all right I'm good freakin new
one you going noodle and then and take
so bud but I want to fly me down
somewhere go noodle more than boys knows
what they're doing
guess I'll do it stick my hand right in
there
oh Jesus Vinny did you do that no no I
don't know if I have a corkscrew
[Music]
I don't care of any didn't cut my leg
off
urgent care well we got this nice tape
don't worry about that Benny
everything's good babe just don't look
at it don't look at me then