all right maybe me check that check all
right I'm gonna hit those keep those
marks look at it feels like we're
standing on clay all right okay wear my
sunglasses all right Vince all right all
right so we're up here in Duxbury
Massachusetts Rhode Island Creek oyster
farm kind enough to have sup here show
us their operation from the moment you
know they start farming them to the
second you eat em oysters are should be
very much alive you know we figured that
would be a perfect place to come up here
and learn about oyster farming since we
since we love them so much and yeah take
two so I think this is a take three
start from the beginning
boy stur farming company take five I was
good all right we're gonna be wasted
farmers I didn't like that one bin
champagne and your oysters and that
sucks kind enough nuff me an old Vinny
no-nobody right yeah I thought that
dramatic exit was gonna be
[Music]
[Applause]
this is this is the lab we need many the
science lab we need alright science
penny oh you know this is Vinnie this is
that uh that ecto stuff remember the
higher the the juice boxes the ecto
Slimer juice remember that the hi-c made
it Slimer stuff ghostbusters
I have anywhere around here Island Creek
oyster and we made it into this is what
your hatchery so this is where you take
baby oysters raise them feed them I'm
assuming this is algae you're growing
this is algae so we're you're growing
that and you're feeding the baby oysters
and your mating adult oysters in here
raising them to a point where you can
bring them out into the bay
yeah there's two things we grow in here
it's oysters and oysters food okay
everything you see around us is oyster
food and we've got millions and millions
and millions of baby oysters when they
grow out in here until they're about the
size of a flake of ground pepper okay so
at that point you can hold 800,000 of
them in the in your head in your hands
cupped like that weighs about two pounds
from that point for you flash-forward
eighteen months that same handful will
weigh about 200,000 pounds and take up
an entire acre of Duxbury Bay pretty
pretty rapidly so it starts as a larvae
where they were actually a little
swimming oyster critter and then once it
gets it mixes and it gets what we call
on that when it all happens you know in
the sperm it's okay what are we calling
the fertilization that's when it becomes
a seed yeah so once it gets fertilized
then it turns into this free swimming
larva cruising around eating algae and
then after a couple weeks it forms a
shell so then after the hatchery which
are in where do we go next next step in
the process is the up Weller's alright
so they're in natural habitat water but
in a in a unit or something actly
all right well maybe we go check that
out humming Vincenzo what do you think
so they made this little system Vince
where the water comes pumped up from the
bottom so they get a bit constantly in a
flow of water that'll keep them alive
and feeding them right and it allowed
them to grow yep so they're you know
they're feeding off of the abundant
nutrients in the water column here in
the Bay and it allows them to eat to
their heart's content and what we're
doing today is we're they're going to be
going through a great
the groups that have hit the quarter
inch mark out to our nursery system and
the ones that aren't quite there will
come back into our up Weller you got the
bottom yeah we'll start following him
into that there we go
you've got some extras we'll just rinse
them out it's tough right here of any
question million bucks I don't know if
that's true very nice hey Vincenzo is
this your first first boat ride
it's our first boat ride Vinnie you want
to hold me over the front we're heading
out to our oyster Plexus you'll see a
bunch of basically floating houses or
all the different farms out here oh that
tumbler looks like you guys are mining
out here so that's our sorter all right
so tanner he's our resident high
schooler all right tanner hey what are
you doing Tanner you got 15 seconds
Tanner made quick we got we're taking
the seeds with sorting it with these
ones we've gone back in the upwelling
these other ones they're gonna move on
something bigger very cool we made it
I'm gonna get some good shots of before
the before the drought before the tide
of any pay attention but we're working
so get this guy these came rate from
that little the upwelling system we were
out on the docks and how long have they
been out here these guys have been out
here about three weeks about three weeks
oh yeah yeah look how much they grew
there Vinny get in there one for about
I'd say about doubled in size huh yep
all right and what are we doing with
these again all off so these are coming
up to our the nursery system up in the
back River the back river
[Music]
backfired baby
now why why do you want to drop boys but
in a riverbed as you can see the water
is quite murky there's a lot of growth
here in the lot of nutrients warmer
water so you drop them here so the
oysters will essentially grow fat a
little faster but it's one of the
reasons why the island Creek oyster has
that unique flavor profile to it it's
it's the mixture of the estuary water
and the sea water that together gives it
a combination of brine and really nice
earthy flavor to those go all right
that's it when they go to high school
they they're not on the bottom they are
they are Island Creek oysters are bottom
planted how the hell you get them either
by picking or we dredge them so that all
when I go to a restaurant I eat an
island Creek oyster it goes through this
whole stage that we did and they finish
on on the mud bog ah just like mother
nature would intend our aunt Dottie
products are grown in trays what you
guys will see out in a shake wish I'm
low tide
hi guys hello this is Brad and Vince the
crew so they are taking the market size
deutscher that they have dragged up
earlier this morning and they are
sorting them by size and counting them
up 500 counts these are market size and
these will be bagged up and shipped
Manhattan tomorrow Wow
hey Benny look I found your relatives
crabby bastard trained to do that
so it's a little flat little shy we're
gonna throw that back then a nice cup
okay what about this marriage Andrew
what do you guys do these monstrosity
right down here these are jumbo yeah I
got a little small but a good cop
maybe a little Tommy oh well that's
looking like a Keller all right easy
Vince go flat kind of a little cup maybe
throw it back yeah yeah give a little
time now would you how does that work
with like I know she was filling it
before about breaking off the new
Vince I found another one of your
relatives you know what that is
horseshoe crab yeah pretty stork
sumbitch there you go bud I ain't here
to do no harm
alright be enough with the horseshoe
crabs man come on so remember before of
anything when we came out here it's a
little skiff with Olaf and we pulled
those bags of the seeds out of these
remember this was all underwater and we
actually drove over those cages over
there but God the oyster gods are on our
favor then scrub your camera don't worry
about Vince's camera all right God is
speaking to us Vince look who joined the
party a little Vinny afraid of the rain
so we sorted them all out by size and
these are at the right size where we're
gonna bring them to finish into the into
the Bay waters at two years is when they
pull them and that's when they go right
to the the restaurants in the consumer
following me here then what do you think
man we folds up this whole little video
idea and we just become oyster farmers
up here huh not a bad life duuuh stirs I
mean this might be a stupid question but
you might want to pay attention to
oysters can they move like clams
we're gonna go Vinny did you hear that
about the winter so in the winter they
take every single Easter out of the
water and they put them in the basement
of that house down there go ahead take a
look
they have like a big root cellar and
they can stay out of the water that long
and then come springtime all them go
back out here Vinny oysters that's a new
way of serving an oyster Vinny oyster no
one's doing that yeah that may be the
stupidest thing ever said nasty I stand
here and you're the the founder founder
old order owner man with the plan skip
Bennett from Island Creek oyster when'd
you get started how long you been away
stir-fry I started growing Clarence in
1990 clam chowder and then they all died
in 1995 minutes switch noise there's so
many different influences that
create the flavor nuance you know these
are exposed for a long time but they're
also really close to the opening of the
bay here to where pure seawater comes
back so when we started growing them out
here I was sure that these were going to
be super salty and they're not literally
yeah yeah real sweet
they almost have like a crab meat now I
know a lot of in some places they're
using oysters not just to eat they'll
put them in polluted water systems well
they do that in like in New York in the
harbor they're trying to grow some
oysters but even out here they're doing
an ecological service by removing
excessive algebras and they can remove
nitrogen to turn nitrogen back into gas
it's a perfect food oh good googly
moogly reminds me of the time I sold my
fortune 500 company and now it's just
golf and Rose a hard day or Easter
farmer will have one of the gentlemen
maybe show us how to properly shuck an
oyster Vinny it feels a little weird
don't film this one come on man so what
we like to say about these things is
these oysters take two years to grow
okay it takes two seconds to screw them
up not to jump in front but I see how
you're holding it and you notice I can
oyster usually has a CAC up you're kind
of that's where you're gonna want to put
the cup down yeah if you think about you
you want the cup to hold all the meat
and you definitely want to hold all the
saltwater inside yes part of the
experience right you're getting a little
sip of Duxbury Bay water in New York
City when you're shucking if you hold
the oyster in the palm of your hand you
have the hinge that little pointy part
pointed back at you so what you want to
do is you go into that pointy part right
there the other thing the reason why I
put it in my hand facing away from me
the adductor muscle the little thing
that holds the two shells together is
right there and those are the two key
points you're trying to separate the
hinge is where the two shelves attach to
each other and the muscle is which keeps
the shell attached to the oyster so you
want to go in and like a 45 degree 45
and the oyster will tell you
yeah you know a good one it just kinda
it's like putting the key that just pops
exactly wants them exactly so what you
do is put it into the hinge and then you
twist back and forth and you wiggle and
when I say twist and wiggle I mean
you're going back and forth like this
and then you're twisting the knife oh I
even wanted the pop oh there you go what
you want to do at this point is you're
gonna twist the knife all the way around
so that's perpendicular to the shell
what you're doing is you're popping that
shell up oh mine broke yours bro user
error you start over you watch this yes
you can do oysters surgery let's do a
stir jack
so you can you gotta cut the muscle out
you do the Philly flip as we call it and
you flip it I just bottom belly is
exposed screwed up what you call it the
Philly flip I think Philadelphia okay
getting back to the your standard shucky
so now we want to remember that muscle
is right there and this is the number
one way people screw it up what you want
to do is you think about it like you're
peeling an apple or a potato or
something you want to grind this knife
right along the top the top of the show
so the goal is that when you take that
top shell off there's no gross meat
dangling off of it so you grind it along
the top like so clean so if it's good
then you got no meat on the on the top
shell there so you might have some
schmutz in here well smoke you just take
your your pinky and kind of clear that
out so now you're looking at it you can
see the muscle and this is another part
people screwed up because what they do
is they go in and try to use like the
sharp blade of the knife to cut away at
the muscle and what you end up with is
scrambled oyster so what you want to do
here is instead of using the blade of
the knife again you're taking it you're
putting the knife kind of on the shell
and you're just clearing it away I'll
just kind of scrape them just like
you're peeling a potato so that way the
blade isn't going into your oyster
exactly because if you do the blade
you're gonna cut through the meat of the
oyster I've been doing it wrong the
whole time vincenzo there you go this is
the first day of the rest of your life
yeah
there you have it you clear it away and
then you savor it Cheers
cheers buddy that's how you shuck an
oyster VIN pretty sure I can eat about
four dozen of those absolutely
yeah that's good enough we're starting
we're trying to be quiet no we're done
one of the main kind of folder
differentiators with oysters is the
texture right so you got an oyster with
a healthy oyster is a nice toothy bite
plump Bobby it's got a nice plump but is
not like you know chewing on a flat
water that's why you'd want to screw it
up
this is why this is
alright guys there you have it we
learned all about oyster farming takes
two years to grow them as you saw it's a
lot of work they're kind of high
maintenance you know kind of a little
needy
thanks Island Creek oyster for showing
us how they do it boy stirs I mean no
brainer cleaning the water clean protein
for you just win-win situation so buy
some oysters learn about farming I'm
gonna work on a farm do whatever you
want to do get out there get dirty and
get involved in your food huh bone
Appetit
not a bad day at the office you know
what I always wanted to do Vinny he goes
guys my whole life Vinny my whole life I
want I wanted to do rulling to be a
rower I always wanted to do growing that
hoo-hoo-hoo going fast working together
cutting through the water yeah I want to
be a row of in Hazzard they push with
their legs right say who knows the other
way so you push and then you you pull so
it's like whoo right
[Laughter]