we're not live here baby we have the
option to edit that thank God
[Music]
nowadays these things are pretty
straightforward it's usually just a
couple hey I'm Brad Leonie another
useful tool the hatchet that sucks
another useful tool to have in the woods
patent-pending what's that all about
boys better get on that but I were like
gods out here Betty creating life oh the
reason why my little favorite storm
stabs dog the 6-year vinegar of uh Oh
God you know you're gonna drink beers
you better not be throwing them in the
woods I find you you end up on the grill
baby I'm just joking yeah but I'm a
professional
Vinnie where the hell are we in New York
Connecticut or something oh geez oh I
broke the bucket Vinnie hope this works
it didn't work buh-buh-buh did the tooth
oh my butt's getting a little warm
Vinnie but I tell you what I ain't
wearing I ain't wearing no damn goggles
in the woods Vinnie oh god smoke I don't
think so pal my eyes you kiddin me oh I
can't see
yeah there are no tapes it's called
suffrage baby what the hell you doing up
there Vinny haven't you learned anything
you get hurt it's far away from help but
you know it's great about getting hurt
out in the woods when you have a Yeti
they say you want to put it you know if
you cut off your Oh cut your finger off
throw it in the Yeti head down to town
get that baby stitched on ya freakin eat
birds then he know it's good bird
watchings great where's my binoculars
Vinny gotcha babe creeps oh look at that
tree Oh Vinny look like an old maple
someone cut oh it's everywhere
oh boy it's amazing well maybe we should
maybe maybe I shouldn't say this but
like you know sometimes you ever just
drive and like you're paying attention
you're driving I'm never I never like
I'm not crashing the car nothing but
like you almost like I don't wanna say
blackout cause I'm very I'm not sleeping
but like I yeah you start driving for a
couple hours and all of a sudden you're
like I don't know what the hell I did oh
man pretty sure that's a serial killer
stick-up train tracks no hands no feet
I got hot air on my hands cool breeze on
my face
oh you worried about no hands on the
wheel don't worry dude I'm certified up
to 200 miles an hour driving with the
hand I can go in circles is turns
forever I got to kill um I cheated well
it's great about charcoal factory if you
cut yourself and grab one of these nice
ripping hot charcoals take a little swig
of that Brown from last night
just brown it off man I'm just joking do
not burn your finger turbo advice let me
cut that maybe I don't need a lawsuit
alright
oh why when you had this fire has kind
of got me in the put me in a dark place
thinking about mortality
I love nature Ben
well I think we're here sure beats yeah
well you know that's not true
well of where we work you know I do
I mean what's better in nature but look
at the smoke going through the trees
okay and the way the light goes to the
tops of the oak trees there you know
it's art pity you know my favorite
artist is Benny mother nature so I were
here visiting an old friend old mother
nature burn baby like Hendrix you know
bring that shit up from the dead
[Music]
oh hey were you doing any foam Benny oh
you got a text message Vinny real cute
all right sweat and passion over here
you checking text messages do we have to
do the 10th so I got this this 10th from
a friend
polar I know that it's all about I've
never set this up so you know this would
be fun for everyone nowadays these
things are pretty straightforward it's
usually just a cup of pull Jesus Christ
and then take that throw over your
shoulder for now okay I see what's going
on Oh
setting up tents up but you want to do
this before it gets dark that's for damn
sure
oh Jesus baby I mean come on bug are you
kidding me I'm not doing hey I'm not
doing it I never seen such thing like
damn like me yeah good job polar
No all right I like the cook don't like
setting up tents any nice especially
tents in our mine all right do this this
is funny but Oh Fanny oh yeah I got a
can for you Brad really easy to set up
to build a freaking house by now look at
this freaking thing it's probably pretty
good what's up no no no it's not pretty
much built Vinny flip it on there's an
instruction in schools this is bullshit
you've done this before Vinny well let's
put on a camera helmet no no I'm doing
real good way to get me aggravated hope
that's what you're going for because
it's working
we'll see a little trial and error waste
of time
this ain't right Vinny what the hell is
this gonna work oh I see
all right maybe it's not I gave right
you fire it up you know I can't
emotionally
all right polar maybe all you know we'll
see oh I see if we get strong wind I'm
gonna go freakin flying in this thing
like what was that lady with the freakin
tornado
she got a murdered tornado movie Vinny
Wizard of Oz end up freaking Wonderland
there whatever the hell that wasn't so
bad you know
part of it is you gotta get a little
pissed off you got a curse you got
kicked around all right
that's frigging thing okay in this thing
oh I got a door okay maybe I'll throw a
couple steaks in fires looking good
burning down let's check out the fire
real quick take a break from this thing
that's it buddy okay let's go let's go
kanoon let's go noodling this is either
gonna be great or terrible husband
I know
[Music]