money you know the thing everyone likes
to think they're good with despite the
evidence provided in every episode of
the Suze Orman show Tina what do you
want to buy hi Suze thanks for taking my
call
I'd like to buy a Mercedes s550 it's
about $1,400 a month that is true you
are denied oh I want to get a lead time
to believe p.m. back so deny so tonight
it's not even funny I'm going to deny
you again
I would like to buy a study abroad in
Iceland I want to go to the famous elk
School in Waco Vic and get a
certification as an elf spotter here's
the thing I'm denying you yeah of course
is because no one should be spending
$4,000 to get an elf spotting
qualification in fact if you go to last
week tonight calm right now you can
print out a free official elf spotting
certificate which I promise you is every
bit as valid as the most expensive elf
spotting education
now go spot some elves now now what one
of the big reasons though Suze Orman
denies so many people is because she
thinks we should all be saving for our
retirement and before we go any further
it is important to acknowledge there are
people who just do not have the money to
do that for systemic reasons that we've
addressed on this show before and will
doubtless address again on giannios sad
tastic 'el circus of misery and math but
tonight let's talk about those who can
save for retirement the target audience
for ads like this we ask people a
question how much money do you think
you'll need when you retire then we gave
each person a ribbon show how many years
that amount my last it's trying to like
pull it a little further and I was
trying to stretch it a little bit more
got me to 70 years old I would have to
rethink this thing that's that's
actually a pretty creepy add because
it's basically people walking toward the
date of their own death the only way it
could have been creepy is if at the end
of their ribbons it said exactly how
each person was going to die
but look it is true it is true that as
as we all live longer you should
absolutely say for retirement if you can
and many do we currently have around 24
trillion dollars sitting in retirement
assets and that figure doesn't even
include the wealth we have in stockpiled
beanie babies so let's call it 24
trillion and 32 dollars and a lot of
that money is in the hands of financial
services companies so let's talk a
little about how they work which I know
sounds boring but as a favor to your
future self it is worth watching this
for 20 minutes because you could easily
make small mistakes which could
seriously cost you down the line so
let's start with financial advisors they
are the wholesome friendly faced experts
that you see in ads like this one from
Chase through all life's milestones
trusted advisors are with loop every
step of the way generations
thanks for helping to plan my retirement
you should come celebrate this I'd be
honored to land for your
with advisers you never trust wait that
is a clear example of deceptive
advertising because nobody invites their
financial advisor to a wedding if cousin
Barbara finds out that she didn't get an
invite but you're chase guy did she's
gonna flip her shit on you but there is
something you should know about
financial advisers even their name means
less than you might think the Financial
Industry Regulatory Authority warns
customers to be aware that Financial
Analysts financial adviser financial
consultant financial planner investment
consultant or wealth manager are generic
terms or job titles and may be used by
vestment professionals who may not hold
any specific credential so financial
analyst is just a fancy term that
doesn't actually mean anything sort of
like brand ambassador or the John Oliver
effect meaningless completely
meaningless but even many well
credentialed financial advisors are paid
on Commission so if they recommend
something for you it may be because they
stand to make money in fact sometimes
they're actively incentivized not to act
in your best interest
take annuities now certain types of
those can be very complicated investment
products that have high fees and would
only be appropriate for certain types of
portfolios but some financial advisors
push them hard just look how Suze Orman
reacts when a caller who had just
inherited eighty thousand dollars asked
for some advice we have talked to a
financial advisor and he recommended
that we put it in an annuity I knew it I
was go before you said that I was gonna
say wait wait let me tell you I could
tell you what the financial advisor said
today did that adviser also say to you
that if you put that eighty thousand
dollars in there I'm gonna make about
four thousand dollars of commissions did
he or she happen to tell you that as
well
oh he or she Thank You Suzy Orman for
pointing out disingenuous financial
swindlers can be women too hashtag lady
crimes
hashtag feminism
and yeah why not and and Bronchos
pushing annuities may not just be
getting money last year Lizabeth warrant
released a report on sales perks in the
annuity industry ranging from free
cruises to luxury watches - and this is
true this tacky superbowl style ring
which is absolutely ghastly but I guess
at least it makes it easy to spot
brokers that you shouldn't work with oh
hey nice ring a win but I'm gonna guess
that you didn't get that playing running
back for the Green Bay Packers
now generally it is currently legal for
financial advisors to put their own
interests ahead of yours unless and this
is interesting they are what's called a
fiduciary because not all financial
advisors are bound to act in your best
interest but fiduciaries are which is a
bit weird it's like finding out that
only some restaurant waiters are
forbidden from ejaculating in your soup
why is it up to me to ask you which kind
you are I'm sending this chowder back
I'm not risking it you take it back but
financial advisors are just one part of
this if you are lucky your job offers a
401k retirement plan and if it does you
should probably take advantage of it but
you should also know they can be a gold
mine for financial service companies and
while it's not unreasonable for them to
get paid for providing a service there
can be a lot of different fees there are
legal fees trustee fees transactional
fees stewardship fees bookkeeping fees
finders fees and the list goes on and on
I honestly wouldn't be surprised if they
also had an elf spotting fee but
remember thanks to your new
certification you no longer have to pay
it go spot some elves and I look
seemingly tiny fees can really mount up
thanks to something called compound
interest now whenever retirement
companies like Prudential mention that
it's always as a positive that if you
start with a really small investment by
the time you're ready to retire it will
have substantially grown it's hard to
imagine how something so small
can help with something so big but if
you start putting that toward your
retirement every week let it grow over
time or 20 to 30 years that retirement
challenge might not seem so big after
all holy shit
is it just me or did that last Domino
fall really hard that might be the most
upsetting commercial involving dominoes
that doesn't involve the phrase Cali
chicken bacon ranch but but compound
interest works both ways
meaning while your money add ups adds up
your fees can really add up to assume
you're invested in a fund that is
earning a gross annual return of 7% they
charge you a 2% annual fee over 50 years
the difference between your net of 5%
the red line and what you would have
made without fees the Green Line is
staggering you've lost almost two-thirds
of what you would have had two-thirds of
what you would have had is gone so think
of fees like termites they're tiny
they're barely noticeable and they can
eat away your fucking future and one
place where your 401k can be full of
termites is the funds themselves
generally speaking you can choose
between low fee index funds which
basically just try to match the average
returns of the stock market or for a
higher fee you can get an actively
managed fund with experts who will pick
and choose stocks for you trying to beat
the market and companies that sell
active funds really believe in
themselves at MF s investment management
we believe active management can protect
capital long term active management can
take calculated risks active management
can seek to outperform
because active investment management
isn't reactive it's active okay that's
not so much a coherent commercial as it
is a drinking game where you do a shot
every time he says the word active but
the problem with active management is
that even many Wall Street experts find
it difficult to consistently beat the
market and there is sometimes
embarrassing evidence of this like when
a group of professionals were pitted in
a stock picking challenge against a cat
named Orlando
Orlando's method he throws a toy mouse
at a grid of companies very scientific
last year Orlando's pics returned nearly
11 percent while the prosy gained just
3.5 percent oh my god let's all agree
that the wolf of Wall Street would have
been way better starring that cat course
close you know instead of drugs there's
a plot holders instead of drugs his
downfall would come when someone busts
out a laser pointer in a meeting but
that cat wasn't a complete anomaly there
is growing evidence that over the
long-term
most managed funds do no better and
often do worse than the market it's
basically the plot of Charlie and the
Chocolate Factory if you stick around
doing nothing while everyone around you
fucks up you're going to win big and the
thing is this is not a secret even some
of the people charging those fees know
that this is the reality one of the
ultimate dirty secrets of the fund
industry is that a lot of people who run
other fund companies I'm own index funds
in their in their own accounts and don't
talk about it I'm unless you put a
couple beers in them Wow sometimes I
invest in index funds might be the least
interesting secret anyone has ever
divulged small trunk it's right up there
with my favorite movie is the constant
gardener and one time in college I got
totally wasted and read the entire
Wikipedia page for rope
so so so don't tell anyone don't tell
anyone
so so between Financial Advisors high
fees and underperforming active
management the entire retirement plan
industry is a potential minefield and
you need to pay attention and the reason
that we know about this is earlier this
year we actually decided we wanted to
set up a 401k for our employees and you
might want to learn from our experience
because here's what happened we reached
out to the production company behind
this show Avalon television and we asked
them to take care of it
a couple of months later they told us we
have your plan it's provided by John
Hancock and we said okay fine and we
went back to work by which I mean we
went back to googling teacup pigs eating
ice cream but but then but then in March
representatives came to our office and
gave our staff presentations on their
new plan it's the kind of thing no one
in their right mind wants to sit through
honestly most of us spent it on our
phones googly teacup pig kamar top hat
comma shopping comma beer and boom boom
we hit the jackpot but but unfortunately
for John Hancock our research is
starting going through the documents and
started adding up the fees which came to
a combined 1.69
percent and that was before we paid a
$24 per person per year fee and the fees
on our funds so they asked John Hancock
why the fees were that high and and we
were told that it was normal for a
start-up plan at a new company and
Hancock gave us a lower number that it
would come down to over time when we
said okay okay that sounds fine and our
researcher said wait no that is not fine
that number is still higher than experts
have told us that we want it to be look
leave this will figure it out
one of you will just go back to googling
teacup pigs in teacups or whatever the
fuck it is that you do all day and we
went oh my god is that a thing that
exists and yes it was yes it was
that was the rest of our afternoon right
there
meanwhile our researchers took the
Hancock contract and sent it to
financial experts who flagged an
intermediary fee to a broker 1% the
first year and half a percent after that
and remember that could add up we did
some very rough estimates and and with
35 employees contributing just six
thousand dollars a year after 30 years
half a percent could apt could add up to
roughly a million dollars that number
was so high you'll never guess what
happened
Janice in accounting actually gave up
I'm serious
Caesar chase one of that she bought
cupcakes for the break room yesterday
and she adopted a kitten she named him
tuppence so anyway we asked who the fuck
is this broker and he turned out he was
a guy Avalon who agreed to pay to help
them set up and support our plan and we
asked him why didn't you present us with
low cost low frills plans like the one
from Vanguard and what are we paying you
so much for and he said well first of
all our plan was probably too
complicated for Vanguard and that he did
a lot of things for us like acting as
our financial advisor although as we now
know that term doesn't necessarily mean
much in fact if you go to our website
right now you can print out a free
official financial advisor certificate
and there you go congratulations you are
one to
and although our broker has other
credentials when we asked if he was a
fiduciary he unsurprisingly said no as
for his fees he said they would come
down and last night he sent us an Excel
spreadsheet showing how they could come
down as our fund assets grew
unfortunately in that spreadsheet he
made an error which meant that our funds
interest didn't compound correctly and
when we pointed that out to him he sent
a second sheet showing that his original
math had been off by more than ten
million dollars which does not inspire
confidence in the man who as he
repeatedly reminded us was helping us
navigate our very complicated plan now
our lawyers at this point say that I
have to tell you that both the broker
and John Hancock claim their fees would
come down that they're competitive
within the industry and worthless for
the services they provide although you
should know we decided early on to pay
almost all of the fees for our employees
because we were soaking embarrassed
about the situation that we've got them
in and we're going to be leaving both
Hancock and the broker and I'm guessing
off that they've seen this show they
will be happy to let us go
just just so you know we'll be replacing
both of them with that stock-picking cat
cause he seems to really know his shit
the whole point of telling you this is
if you don't pay close attention all of
this can really get away from you but
here is the good news it doesn't
actually have to be that complicated and
it might be getting simpler back in
April the Department of Labor issued a
final rule requiring that all advisors
handling retirement accounts act as
fiduciaries
beginning next year and that is great
because the financial services industry
fought this rule hard they even launched
terrible attack ads you might have seen
one like this on TV it's these new
regulations they're pushing and
Washington that worried me they want to
make it really hard to get advice for my
financial advisor no more help from an
even with our IRA and 401k savings only
if we want to pay a lot more I will
never get the information we need we're
gonna call our senators ok ok to be
honest my only takeaway from that ad is
that that guy is definitely fucking an
it's so obvious it's you need to leave
him non threatening wife character kick
him to the curb and while the rule has
gone through anyway five lawsuits have
been filed by financial services groups
attacking it and legislators in the
House and Senate have passed a
resolution trying to overturn that
fiduciary rule although just a few days
ago the president did veto it and by the
way that is something I think we're
probably going to be seeing a lot more
off because President Obama's last year
in office seems to be moving from
bipartisan solution to by Felicia and
and look I am NOT saying all of this is
not complicated we spent weeks just
trying to understand our own 401k plan
but for your average person trying to
save for retirement it doesn't need to
be this confusing the truth is as long
as you remember a few key things you're
probably going to be fine and we wanted
to outline them for you so whenever you
are ready or able to save for retirement
please come back and replay this video
from this exact spot enjoy hi I'm Billy
Eichner and I'm here with a bunch of
King ribbon and I'm using it to show
people how much money they needed to
save for retirement
oh look at you you're so precocious one
tiny thing
these are fees that's your record
keeping fee that's your wrap fee that's
your monthly participation fee that's
your 12 B - one fee that fee goes to
some middlemen you don't even know about
and that's your fee for not knowing
about a fee fee and here's what you've
got left to retire on try ribbon dancing
with this you look like an idiot the
problem is that idiots like Karen here
make shitty choices when it comes to
what to do with their money Karen if you
had four thousand dollars would you
invested in your 401 K would you go to
the elf school in Reykjavik off school
no you clean your furrow 1k idiot the
only elf you should be studying is
Kristin Chenoweth she's a delight come
on out here Kristin Chenoweth hi Billy
I love elves and who wouldn't want to go
to rake today okay not the Tony Awards
go shoot shoot that was Kristin
Chenoweth the point is the best invites
most experts can give you is to do five
things number one start saving now in
fact start saving 10 years ago invent a
time machine use it to go back and start
saving money then kill baby Hitler next
average people like you and let's face
it you're very very average should
probably just invest in low-cost index
funds and leave it alone you should
check on it about as often as you Google
whether or not Gene Hackman is still
alive about once a year and he is he's
still alive he's writing novels now
third thing if you have an advisor ask
if they're a fiduciary if they say no
run if they say yes but they're wearing
a tacky Super Bowl ring run if they say
yes what they're wearing a class ring
run that has nothing to do with this I
just think it's very strange when a
grown man is wearing a class ring
because a fiduciary number four as you
get older gradually shift your
investments from stocks to bonds here's
a way to remember it
every time they pick a new James Bond
gradually switch more of your stocks
into bonds then go back to wondering if
Daniel Craig is actually attractive what
do you think Doris I'll be so hand
so no he's not he looks like a blonde
chimpanzee and a tux and you know it oh
I wish this was veep
finally try to keep your fees like your
milk under 1% because just like interest
compounds so do fees and even 1/10 of 1%
can really fuck you like this bullshit
Kristin watch out
oh that reminds me
one last tip don't forget to die Billy
I'm not dead
Oh Kristen you're even shorter now oh
stop
coughing disgusting excuse me Oh
retirements no Kristin Chenoweth's for
harmed in the filming of this piece
you