our main story tonight concerns
government sports for nerds these days
we are all focused on the presidential
race the biggest most prominent office
in all of government but I would like to
talk about the opposite of that one of
the smallest and most obscure forms of
government special districts that's
right tonight we are talking about
special taxing districts so hello people
watching for the first time because of
our Trump piece and also I presume
goodbye goodbye thanks for checking in
but just so you know special districts
are small units of government with the
power to take tax dollars to do one
specific thing you've probably heard of
a fire district or a water district but
they can be set up for almost any
purpose and there are way more of them
than you think special districts over
the past half-century have really
proliferated to the point that we have
about 40,000 of them in the country now
in the account for about a hundred
billion dollars of spending a hundred
billion dollars a year that is 16
billion more than Russia spends on its
military and when you include school
districts special districts are the most
common form of local government in the
country and that's crazy it's like
finding out the highest-paid athlete in
the world is Harold I mean who the fuck
is Harold what sport does he play why
don't people talk about this all the
time how am I only hearing about
Harold's now you're making me feel a
fool special districts are so ubiquitous
and sometimes have so little
accountability states may not even know
how many they have or how much they
spend a few years back Idaho launched an
investigation of special districts with
objective one being identify how many
special districts there are in Idaho and
when Kentucky investigated its order to
found that 40% of its districts that
were required to didn't even file proper
budgets I mean this is this is an
extraordinary mess as one of my good
friends says you can't make this up 2.7
billion dollar system of government
operating because of the lack of
oversight and accountability at almost
every level has been permitted to become
a level of ghost government yes
ghost government and that is the
shittiest idea for
go story I've ever heard assigned of
course
from ghost dad and that was a bad idea
before context changed the way we felt
about Bill Cosby having the power to
walk through walls before then it was a
bad idea after it was horrifying but if
you think about it it's a little weird
in a country that talks so much about
government accountability that a huge
amount of our tax dollars go to fund
entities that most of us know absolutely
nothing about you may not even know how
many districts you are living in right
now a school district may overlap with a
park district a water district your
sewer district and so on such that it
wouldn't be at all uncommon for one
person to be finding themselves within
the boundaries of ten or more of these
districts that's right think of a
special district like a cult it can take
your money and you may not even be aware
that you are in one although it is worth
remembering in a special district
allowing the leader to impregnate you is
not mandatory no matter what the guy in
charge of the library district says no
matter what he says with his words or
eyes and if you're thinking we'll look
what difference does it make what
districts I'm in well it can actually
make a big difference one person that we
found paid a thousand dollars as part of
an irrigation special district that he
lives in in north central Phoenix his
neighbor literally across the street is
not a part of that district they're
special district bill was $7.00 1000
versus $7 look the only people who
should be paying a thousand dollars more
than their neighbors across the street
are the assholes who cover every square
inch of their house with Christmas
decorations they should be taxed and
then they should be imprisoned and then
they should be told their lights were
better last year because it's that one
that would hurt them the most that's the
one that would sting and it is important
to note here in theory and often in
practice having small entities with a
single purpose can be a great idea
take Litchfield New Hampshire in 2007
they chose to create a mosquito control
districts to you know control mosquitoes
it's run by two men who as you will see
from an amazing YouTube video of one of
their public meetings are almost
heartbreakingly conscientious regardless
of the fact that there is no one
in the room which I'll stand for the
Pledge of Allegiance I pledge allegiance
to the flag of the United States of
America and to the Republic for which it
stands one nation under God indivisible
with liberty and justice for all
cheer we call the roll acting boys cheer
mr. heo present I'm here all members are
present come on you have got to admire
their dedication to the rules these two
men are so scrupulous they would sit at
a broken red traffic light for six hours
in the middle of the night red is red we
live in a civilized society red is red
we stay in fact they ran that 43 minute
meeting so meticulously they even took
input from the public with predictable
results any members of the public
wishing to speak see hearing me
oh I guess when you're a member of a
ghost government it's only natural your
meetings are going to be attended only
by the ghost public now that that is the
best case scenario and and many special
districts are like that chugging along
just fine with no major problems but
some like the Isaacson Municipal Utility
District in Texas are not because an
audit recently discovered $70,000 in
losses and that the district builds
residents for water with a disturbing
consistency we're not all professional
accountants or managers we may not have
looked at things as closely as maybe we
should have I mud has been billed for
thirteen million seven hundred twenty
one two hundred gallons of water every
year for the last six years rain or
drought or weather no change
same number now no charges have been
filed there but that level of
consistency is weird the only time the
exact same amount of water should appear
in a document year after year is in
shambo's Ryder yeah Shamu gets thirteen
point seven million gallons of water at
his tank at all times and not a drop
less he's a fucking artist I'm obviously
kidding you can keep him in a wading
pool if you want and if you want to fuck
his blowhole that will be an extra
twenty the point is thanks for visiting
SeaWorld
but but in Kentucky in Kentucky the lack
of supervision led to outright
corruption with over $100,000 being
fantastically misspent by one former
assistant fire chief the report claims
the garret volunteer fire department in
Floyd County used taxpayer money to buy
things like flat-screen televisions
chewing tobacco and fireworks
investigators say they also found
hundreds of pornographic videos on
department electronics alright alright
porn and chewing tobacco obviously
inappropriate but you know what really
upsets me the most they're fireworks
there are fire department
that's what hearing EMTs have been using
their budget to stage scissor races
they're your natural enemy but that
behavior was nothing compared to what
happened in a fire district in Rhode
Island you won't believe the undercover
video we gathered on the man in charge
we spotted him drinking during the day
then driving the fire department vehicle
back to work we even had him taking the
public safety vehicle to party up on
Federal Hill drinking and apparently
smoking marijuana this is you smoking
what looks to be pot so God maybe you uh
then share the cigar with your friends -
I don't know that's a cigar yes it is
you know I got to tell you chief no
one's gonna buy that yeah I'm pretty
sure they'll definitely buy it
that's a cigar just like that's flour
for when you want to bake one tiny
cookie that's honey for my tea I use a
very specific amount and that's just
some quarts I keep laying around
I love quarts
look corruption is not unique to special
districts there are clearly problems in
all other forms of government as well
but when special districts only have one
job it makes it all the more noticeable
when things go wrong
take Evergreen Park Illinois the County
it's in has four different mosquito
abatement districts to prevent the
spread of West Nile so it had to be
humiliating when this happened
the mayor of West Suburban Evergreen
Park came down with West Nile virus the
mayor got keen West Nile look no one is
expecting a zero percent failure rate
here but if you're surrounded by that
many mosquito abatement districts
shouldn't there at least be agents
willing to take a mosquito for him come
on
and one of the most interesting ways
that special districts are different
from any other form of government is how
they can be created seemingly out of
thin air
for instance in Conroe Texas a company
was hoping to create a new neighborhood
on undeveloped land they wanted to form
a special district which him issue bonds
now to do this the law required a vote
but remember no one lived there yet so
guess what they did
when Tim Kellerman saw someone
installing a mobile home next to his
house recently he asked them what's
going on he told me is none of my
buddy's business this man and his wife
moved in on Monday and signed a
nine-month lease with stingray services
after that he said they're moving out
they're the only two people who could
vote on five hundred million dollars
worth of bonds for the new housing
project two people voting for five
hundred million dollars of bonds and
then leaving it as if in the Lion King
Simba's father looked out over the
plains and said son someday this will
all be someone else's problem and they
both often never came back
and that whole process is perfectly
legal in fact this wasn't the only place
where stingray services provided what
they called turnkey voter trailer
election services they won't even
advertised on Craigslist with an ad
reading eligible tenants will vote in
and serve as election officials for the
election which takes place in the home
oh that's right you're not just the only
voters you're the election officials and
your trailer is the polling station it
makes you wonder what they didn't just
throw in some bullshit ballot
initiatives just for fun oh and on the
motion that Jenna start cleaning out her
fucking hairbrush because it's starting
to look like we have a cat we seem to be
tied one to one and once once a special
district is created you can be pretty
sure no one is going to be watching what
you do because remember that New
Hampshire video when we found it on
YouTube it had zero views zero meaning
those two guys themselves didn't even
watch it that is anti viral as videos go
and voter accountability is pretty
unlikely - one county in New York found
turnout rates for some special district
elections could be as low as 1.8% which
might be because that county held on
average one special district election
every ten point nine business days with
not a single one taking place on
Election Day which just seems inherently
suspicious think about it it would be a
bit of a red flag if someone in your
neighborhood offer children candy every
11 days but never on Halloween it would
give you pause for thought and even if
the state government does investigate
special districts may try to blow them
off when that Kentucky auditor started
asking his state's districts about
they're making their information
available to the public he got some
pretty unhelpful responses here's one
direct quote by the way we didn't take
any liberties with these quote this
contains information the public is not
entitled to know this is a good one we
don't want to fill this out because
there are too many crackpots in the
world and my favorite well we just
rather the public contact us directly to
gain information so we know who's asking
you you get the sense their preferred
mode of contact would be an email to
fake email address at fuck off gov and
and by the way if after hearing that
some Kentuckians wanted to shut a
district down they might not be able to
because as that auditor wrote many types
of districts may continue to exist
because there is not a process for them
to be dissolved there's no way to break
them up they're like styrofoam packing
peanuts or the enduring friendship of
Jimmy Fallon and Justin Timberlake
they'll be with us until the end of time
now to be fair some states are pushing
to reform special districts California
for instance has made them far more
transparent in recent years and a
special districts Association in San
Diego even launched a competition for
school children to create a one-minute
video
educating the public about what's so
special about special districts the
deadline was Tuesday and it had a $1,500
top prize and the reason I know that is
we entered with some local school kids
and this is the results your districts
what's so special about the special
districts of small government that
collect taxes to handle one specific
service like fight fire or provide water
or buy fireworks or smoke cigars special
districts are special because they can
receive little oversight they sometimes
got ghost governments I used to be
afraid of those but now alfrid girls
special districts can also be very easy
to create sometimes the only people
voting for them are two people in a
crowd in the middle of nowhere maybe two
people in the trailer in an empty field
sounds like my younger brother you know
it's true duckling
you won't wanted sometimes special
chicks aren't so special though like
when the mayor of a village in a county
with for mosquito spring districts came
down with the West Nile virus
come on that would barely be acceptable
if your tongue we're near the actual
Nile everything this thing's so little
about you don't even realize that's not
enough he's been perhaps the most
specific about the district don't party
this to get rid of him they're all is it
possible to do this dry like Wolverine
it is super bad for you just drive over
II though obviously they would never
meet because that's crossing universes
so to recap special districts save your
money and do whatever they want with it
with little to no consequences what I
grew up I want to be a special district
yeah
you