racism you know the problem that crash
failed to solve and specifically we're
going to discuss school segregation
which it turns out is still a big
problem racial segregation is on the
rise the number of schools where 1% are
less that the student population is
white has more than doubled in the last
20 years that's true even as our society
has grown more diverse nearly 7,000
schools have the same racial makeup as
the audience of your average Tyler Perry
movie and that one white guy is Leonard
Maltin and he has to be there it's his
job boo Ahmadiyya Halloween three stars
now at this point if you are in a city
like New York you're probably thinking
Oh splendid
I know where this is going a story
vilifying the backwards and racist
American South let me just grab a
handful of kale chips that I can munch
on while feeling superior well hold on
there is something you should probably
know according to the UCLA Civil Rights
Project the south is the least
segregated region for black students and
in fact New York State is now the most
segregated system in America
in large part due to New York City oh
shit liberal right New Yorkers twist
anything you will racist the whole time
put back those persons you bought
yourselves as a trip from fairway you
don't deserve them anymore and look it
would still be problematic even if these
schools were roughly equivalent
academically as that would still be a
violation of the principle of Brown
versus Board of Education that separate
educational facilities are inherently
unequal but in practice they are very
rarely equal in any way black and Latino
children are more likely to attend
schools with inexperienced teachers
which are then less likely to offer a
college prep curriculum on top of which
because race and class are inextricably
linked those students are six times as
likely to be in high poverty schools and
while there are teachers and students
working incredibly hard in those places
they are often doing so with fewer
resources as one student learned during
a school exchange program once a year we
do what's called a school swap where
students that go to County High School's
attend a school in the city for one day
and then students in the city attend a
school in the county for one day I went
in and the first thing that I noticed
actually was all this stuff around her
I'm talking about stuff that looked like
it cost lots of money the teacher come
in they can get right on topic they have
multiple computers that they can use
it's like wow and then I related back to
my school well we don't have all that
okay I get what that program was trying
to do but it still seems cruel giving
students a glimpse of what other kids
are getting at least on a plane they
cover first class with a curb and sure
that might still bake cookies and waft
the smell down the aisle but that's just
a with you so how is it possible that
our nation schools are by some measures
more segregated now than they have been
in over four decades well it turns out
places like New York haven't so much
resegregate 'add as never really
bothered integrating in the first place
because the 1964 Civil Rights Act was
very carefully crafted by northern
lawmakers it targeted the kind of
segregation by law which existed in the
south so you couldn't have a school that
was officially designated
whites-only but it exempted the
so-called racial imbalance of northern
schools so if a New York school was all
white because it was drawing from an
all-white area even if that area had
been kept that way due to a host of
explicitly racist housing policies that
was somehow fine and if you're thinking
that is some hypocritical bullshit you
are not alone Malcolm X was pointing
this out in New York at the time you
don't have to go to Mississippi to find
a segregated school system we have it
right here in New York City it shows
that the problems that there are the
white liberals have been pointing the
finger at this southern segregationist
and condemning them for exists right
here in New York City yeah of course
racism exists in New York have you never
seen West Side Story it is a musical
about love transcending the obstacle of
one person being Porto Rican it'll never
work
and for what it's worth when on rare
occasions northern cities were forced to
desegregate things got just as ugly as
they did down south listen to one Boston
man described his memories of being sent
to a school in a white neighborhood so
my first day of school was when we
walked got out the school bus was right
under step in white paint
niggers go back home to Africa you got
all these whites out there but Rock you
know with you no signs calling us niggas
you know go back home you know the whole
bit and then did somebody saying kids
you see in class so now you're like so
what's up with that yeah he's got a
point there they shall go home to Africa
and then sit beside you in class
I do hope the kids who heard that had
the opportunity to go oh you want to
borrow a pencil well I'm sorry I must
have left mine in Kenya this morning I
could just get space
of the general paranoia surrounding this
issue back then just watch this trailer
for a movie called halls of anger a
handful of white students are
transferred to an all-black school you
know there's gonna be trouble vanilla
ice cream and I'm gonna take me a big
lick okay
that is clearly horrible but on a side
note using the terms chocolate and
vanilla is actually the best possible
argument for bringing races closer
together because what happens when you
combine chocolate and vanilla I'll tell
you what happens fucking fudgie the
whale happens and it is superb and even
though the path to integration was rough
and the burden often felt
disproportionately on african-american
communities there were still clear
benefits because bringing in white
children also brought in resources to an
almost comical extent immediately when
the decision was made that white kids
would now be bused into West Charlotte
it was like a community joke like
overnight a gravel parking lot was paved
the athletic facilities in terms of the
football stadium basketball gymnasiums
ax was upgraded it was like overnight
someone had written a check for a
million dollars exactly funding tends to
follow white people around the way white
people follow the band fish around it's
a different show every time man last
time I was rolling cuz I snorted money
off a communal didgeridoo different show
every time man
Batman school was in Charlotte North
Carolina a city which became a model for
how desegregation could be effective by
the end of the 1980s just 1 percent of
Latino children and 3 percent of black
children were attending schools
considered racially isolated that is 90%
or more minority and this was such a
point of pride that when President
Reagan visited and tried to talk shit
about Charlotte's system it didn't go
down too well they favored busing that
takes innocent children out of the
neighborhood school and makes them pawns
in a social experiment that nobody wants
we found out it failed I don't call that
compassion Reagan got no reaction from
the crowd on that bond I took great
offense to that and I stopped across the
floor and said a few choice expletives
about the president and cut out the TV
oh that is some courtly southern
aggression I'm guessing his choice
expertise or heavens to Betsy that
really fried my grits and sir you are a
scoundrel without valor without Weller
I'll say
unfortunately what happened next in
Charlotte is basically the story of
desegregation in a nutshell because in
1997 a white parent got upset when his
daughter lost out in a lottery for a
magnet school which had reserved some
seats for black children and even though
she was still assigned to one of the top
ten elementary schools in the state he
filed a lawsuit I really believe that my
daughter's constitutional rights were
violated and as a concerned parent that
a responsible parent I hope I believed
it was my job to look after her
well-being okay sure but she was already
in a top-ten school and I do get making
sure that your kid has a good education
is one of the most important jobs a
parent can do it's right up there with
lying about not having a favorite child
because every parent has a favorite
child and it's Dylan it's not you it's
not any of your siblings it's Dylan just
ask your parents they like Dylan he does
his own laundry but but that man
selfishness had a huge impact a federal
judge ruled in his favor vacating the
district's desegregation plan and
basically blowing up the whole thing and
tragically Charlotte then experienced
Swift re-segregation as by 2010 those 1
and 3 percent figures for Latinos and
blacks had grown to 44 and 47 percent
and I know it is tempting to be angry at
that one parent especially because and
this is true before the verdict even
came down he moved his family to
California which is the constitutional
challenge equivalent of farting in a
crowded elevator just as you're stepping
off of it
but to be fair this wasn't an isolated
incident all over the country
desegregation plans were struck down
thanks in part to Supreme Court rulings
making it easier to challenge them and
the prevailing narrative became that
desegregate desegregation imposed to
higher cost on students for a benefit
that was no longer necessary it's an
attitude that's best summed up by this
Louisiana State Senator do you think
that you have to bus children all over a
bus on long distance so you can say you
sit in a seat next to someone diverse
different from yourself the Justice
Department now they achieved their goal
who can say we're not desegregated yeah
when african-american president we have
an african-american mayor here in Baton
Rouge what a majority white in the
parish we've been through all that and
there it is the idea that because
President Obama was elected systemic
racism was pretty much solved which is
absolutely absurd because racism is not
one of those things that just disappears
on its own in due time it's not like
chicken pox or Chewbacca mom and I know
I know I have just restarted the clock
on that one and I am genuinely sorry so
the only solution here is to be
proactive because remember if you just
assign kids to their neighborhood
schools and their neighborhoods are
segregated you will have a segregated
school and clearly there are some
parents who it seems would resist just
about anything that might result in
integration just listen to how these
parents in st. Louis reacted to the idea
of students from a mostly black
community being added to their schools
so of this district send my son to a
better school when this one goes down he
one sis here please a song I deserve -
now I have to worry about my children
getting fat or taking a drugs or getting
robbed because that's the issue oh that
is not subtle
she's just a homies and a baggy pants
away from full dog whistle bingo and
look those parents are all extreme
examples but even if for a moment you
give everyone the benefit of the doubt
and you assume that all complaints about
bus schedules or class sizes are
actually just about buses or class sizes
the hard truth is you don't have to be
intentionally racist to do things that
have racist effects in the 60s if you
had insisted on separate lunch counters
not because you hated black people but
just because you loved your son so much
you wanted him to get his lunch quicker
the end result would have been exactly
the same and while I get the impulse to
seize every tiny advantage you can for
your kid I get that segregated schools
cause devastating harm to actual
children and not just to their education
but to their very sense of self-worth
you don't have support at all
we have lack of books resources anything
you can think of but when we go in
contact with these white children or a
Southside Caucasian they don't know how
to act because they believe that they're
better than us and we don't know how to
act because we believe that they're
better than us and that is heartbreaking
because classrooms should teach children
about the importance of self-esteem not
rip it from them because that is what
prom is for and and there can be lasting
positive impacts to integration not
because the mere act of having a white
classmate is somehow magic it's not
unless of course that kid has round
glasses a scar on his forehead and sits
alone on parents visiting day but but
getting to attend a good middle-class
school can be transformative Berkeley
professor Rucker johnson studied black
siblings where one went to a
desegregated school and the other didn't
and not only did those exposed to more
years of desegregation fare better but
their kids did too and that is not all
blacks who attended desegregated
elementary schools were more likely to
graduate and
92% less likely to be incarcerated as
adults
what is more Johnson found that the
narrowing of the achievement gap and the
increased success of black Americans did
not have any negative effect on whites
on any metric so it was good for black
people and have no effect on white
people whatsoever it's like this
canister of black and sassy cream shine
I am pretty sure I can make that joke I
am pretty sure that's okay hold on hold
on hold on uh which writer pitched in
shit shit
that doesn't help the point is for white
children a lack of experience with
people of other races can have serious
downsides just watch one young girl take
a racial bias test show me the good
child why is she the good child can I
think to a fight me okay show me the bad
child why is she the bad child
she's a lot darker what do you think
shocking to you I just think it's
because she's not exposed exactly and
that is why it is important to expose
kids to other races at a young age you
don't want your child playing guess who
at a birthday party and asking is this
person bad to rule out anyone who isn't
white and what and what and while yes
you can absolutely teach kids about
racism in the abstract if your school is
overwhelmingly white important nuances
can get lost as this second grader found
after making a bold choice for a school
project have a dream today I have a
dream that my four little children
they live in an Asian Sean is portraying
a historical figure assigned by his
teacher
well monitor King jr. he said mom I want
to wear suit because that's what he wore
and a black tie and I have to wear a
white shirt and he said I'm also I want
to play you know do my face and black
they thought it was inappropriate and it
would be disrespectful to black people
but I say that it's not I like bad
people okay first Wow second it is
obviously not that kids fault II didn't
know any better and finally if Martin
Luther King jr. could see that clip I
legitimately don't know whether he'd be
thrilled or horrified he might actually
be both he'd be like wow I really made a
difference to a point so so the benefits
of truly diverse schools are obvious the
problem is often just our willingness to
do it at all and to their credit some
school districts including Charlotte and
now looking for ways to fix things and
there are models small and large around
the country for what can work at Boston
as long had a voluntary program to send
kids from the city to schools in the
suburbs it's tiny but it's wildly
popular and Louisville has created a
complicated school assignment formula
that has resulted in more integrated
schools it is not perfect and they've
had to tweak it a lot but it is worth
knowing that under that program 90% of
kindergarten families still received
their first choice of schools which is
impressive cuz I doubt 90% of those
families even received their first
choice of kindergartner I mean she's
great she's great she she draws on a lot
of things but she's great she's she's
fine she's absolutely fine she's no
Dylan of course
because as we all know Dylan is the best
and everyone should be invested in those
sorts of solutions because because while
this always gets framed as an issue
about parents and their children it's
actually about adults and everybody
because kids grow up and those little
doctors soldiers police officers and
superheroes asking you for candy
tomorrow night well in a decade or so
they might be actual doctors soldiers
police officers and assistant directors
of human resources and there are massive
and multiple benefits for all of us if
they interacted a lot more from an early
age and I know this seems like a lot to
ask but in the words of a small white
child dressed as a dead civil rights
leader I have a dream
you