our main story tonight and I cannot
believe I'm saying this is Donald Trump
and I say that I said that knowing that
every time his name is said out loud
he has a shattering orgasm and look look
we have mostly ignored Trump on this
show but he is now won three states has
been endorsed by Chris Christie and
polls shall him leading most Super
Tuesday states which is a big deal since
1988 every candidate who's won the most
states on Super Tuesday went on to
become their party's nominee so at this
point Donald Trump is America's back
mold it may have seemed harmless a year
ago but now that it's gotten frightening
ly bigger it is no longer wise to ignore
it and I do understand why Trump
supporters might like him he's
unpredictable and entertaining just look
how he went after Marco Rubio on Friday
did you ever see a guy sweat like this
it's Rubio
that's what it
that's objectively funny just as it was
funny when a few years ago he tweeted I
would like to extend my best wishes to
all even the haters and losers on this
special date September the 11th he
wished haters and losers are happy 9/11
there is a part of me that even likes
this guy it's a part of me I hate but it
is a part of me and if you are someone
who's sick of the party establishment he
might seem like a protest candidate with
some attractive qualities we like him he
tells it like it is he says what he
means I honestly believe he's telling
the truth
he's funding his own campaign nobody
owns him he's aggressive and he's strong
and he's bold I think he's an incredible
businessman if he runs the country like
he runs his organization we buddy in
good shape Donald Trump can seem
appealing until you take a closer look
much like the lunch buffet at a strip
club or the NFL or having a pet
chimpanzee sure it seems fun but someday
Coco's going to tear your fucking limbs
off because let's look at each of those
qualities those people list it first he
tells it like it is
does he because the website politifact
checks 77 of his statements and rated 76
percent of them as varying degrees of
false and I've witnessed this firsthand
he once attacked my old boss by tweeting
if Jon Stewart is so above it all and
legit why did he change his name from
Jonathan Leibovitz he should be proud of
his heritage and then two years later
rose I never attacked dopey Jon Stewart
for his phony last name would never do
that and then just last year he claimed
falsely to have turned down an invite to
appear on this very boring show and and
who's he trying to impress with that lie
our show's guests include sloths
and puppies
well basically a petting zoo with a desk
but but when we pointed out that he had
never been invited this is how he
responded all of a sudden I see people
saying that John Oliver and of Saint
John Oliver and I checked with my people
he asked me to be in the show four or
five times and I don't even hardly know
who it was I wouldn't know what he looks
like what look first for us I wouldn't
expect him to know who I was although
for his inevitable angry tweet about
this segment I'll tell him what I look
like I look like a nearsighted parrot
who works at a bank but but secondly
secondly it was genuinely destabilizing
to be on the receiving end of a lie that
confidence I even checked to make sure
that no one had even accidentally
invited him and of course they hadn't
and and I'm not even sure he knows he's
lying I think he just doesn't care about
what the truth is Donald Trump used the
truth like this Lima views the Supreme
Court vacancy I don't care about that in
any way please Koff I have a banana so
so let's move on let's move on to his
next selling point that he is truly
independent and not beholden to anyone
or as he puts it I'm self-funding my
campaign I tell the truth
and it'll be spent so far probably 2025
million dollars okay let's break that
down first I'm rich therefore I tell the
truth has the same internal logic as I'm
a vegan therefore I know karate
there is no cause and effect between
those two and the correlation usually
goes the other way and while it is true
that he hasn't taken corporate money the
implication that he has personally spent
twenty to twenty five million dollars is
a bit of a stretch because what he's
actually done is loaned his own campaign
seventeen and a half million dollars and
has just personally given just two
hundred and fifty thousand dollars and
that's important because up until the
convention he can pay himself back for
the loan with campaign funds and if you
don't think there's a significant
difference between a gift and a loan try
and giving your spouse an anniversary
loan and see how that goes
and even he himself sometimes admits
that his campaign is by no means
completely self-funded I'm self-funding
my campaign other than the little tiny
ones where they send in you know women
sending we had a woman seven dollars and
fifty nine cents what do you do how can
you send the money back you know it's a
nice it's cute it's beautiful they feel
invested in your campaign he makes it
sound like women a stuffing grimy dollar
bills in envelopes writing Donald Trump
on the front and he's just too kind to
send them back but he's taken in seven
and a half million dollars in individual
contributions and if he didn't want it
maybe shouldn't have had to donate
button's on his website because money
isn't unsolicited when you have to ask
for someone's credit card expiration
date to receive it okay so how about the
claim that he is tough well again I'm
not sure about that because for a tough
guy he has incredibly thin skin back in
1988 spy magazine called him a short
fingered Vulgarian and ever since the
editor Graydon Carter says he receives
envelopes from Trump always with the
photo on which he circled his hand to
highlight the length of his fingers
usually with a note reading see not so
short and look look his fingers seem
fine but the very fact he's so sensitive
about them is absolutely hilarious as is
the fact that those notes were
apparently written in gold sharpie which
is so quintessentially Donald Trump
something that gives the passing
appearance of wealth but is actually
just a cheap tool now now Trump chose
signature
his signature Tuttle often involves
lawsuits he loves to threaten to sue
people like he did with Rosie O'Donnell
she said I was bankrupt
I never went bankrupt so probably I'll
sue her because it would be fun I'd like
to take some money out of her fat-ass
pockets
look-look-look of course of course he
needs to take Rosie O'Donnell to court
to take money out of her pockets because
his tiny tiny fingers are too short to
reach into her wallet but he never sent
her he never sued Rosie O'Donnell in
fact he's repeatedly threatened people
with lawsuits and not followed through
including the rapper Mac Miller lawrence
O'Donnell Vanity Fair and an activist
who launched a petition for Macy's to
drop Trump's products I'll sue you is
Trump's version of bazinga it doesn't
really mean anything but he says it all
the time but perhaps Trump's biggest
selling point as a candidate is his
success and where could people get that
idea from I'm really rich I actually
think I have the best temperament people
love me and you know what I've been very
successful everybody loves me I went to
an Ivy League school
I'm very highly educated I know words I
had the best words oh please literally
the biggest word in the sentence I have
the best words is the word words well
it's worth noting well yes he has made
more money than most of us will make in
a lifetime not only did he get a
multi-million dollar inheritance from
his father but he's also lost a huge
amount and this is where we need to be
careful because as we've learned he will
he will threaten to sue your fat ass
pockets with his cocktail sausage
fingers if you talk about his company's
bankruptcies so I will just let his own
daughter describe the state of his
finances at one point in his life I
remember once my father and I were
walking down Fifth Avenue and there was
a homeless person sitting
sitting right outside of Trump Tower and
I remember my father pointing to him and
saying you know that guy has eight
billion dollars more than me because he
was in such extreme debt at that point
you know and that really shows you the
indomitable spirit of Donald Trump to
fall to his lowest point and in that
very moment still find a way to be kind
of a dick to a homeless guy now now his
campaign claims his current worth is in
excess of ten billion dollars and
they've written it in all caps so it
must be true but others have disputed
that figure in fact a book won't
suggested that Trump might be worth a
mere hundred and fifty to two hundred
and fifty million dollars which Trump
protested by suing the writer for five
billion dollars which is a pretty
roundabout way of getting half the way
to ten billion and you should know for
the record Trump lost that lawsuit twice
but I am glad that he sued if only
because during the deposition he
explained that his estimate of his net
worth fluctuates based on and I quote
feelings even my own feelings and that
can change rapidly from day to day think
about that he claimed that his net worth
changes depending on his mood which
makes absolutely no sense partly because
he always seems to be in the same mood
specifically smug yet gassy and I'm
interestingly
interestingly a significant portion of
his self valuation is intangible his
brand is what he values very much and
his disclosure form that he's released
it's about three billion dollars that's
what he values his brand as exactly he
values his own name at three billion
dollars and I'm not saying a name can't
have value it's why people will pay a
hundred twenty dollars for a plain white
t-shirt that is designed by Kanye West I
don't want just any white t-shirts they
want one designed by a bored sociopath
with a finger free anus but but three
billion dollars seems a bit high
especially because while Trump has said
if I put my name on something you know
it's gonna be good over the years his
name has been on some things that have
arguably been very uncooked including
Trump shuttle which no longer exists
Trump vodka which was discontinued Trump
magazine which folded trunk world
magazine which also folded Trump
University over which he's being sued
and of course the travel booking site go
Trump com whose grief existence was I
imagine a real thorn in the side of
anyone hoping got rom-com featured a
single thing worth masturbating to and
that's not even mentioning this when it
comes to great steaks I've just raised
the stakes Trump steaks are the world's
greatest steaks and I mean that in every
sense of the word and the sharper image
is the only store where you can buy them
and not only can you not buy them steaks
anymore but why did he sell them at the
sharper image that is a weird choice I
will take a massage chair an indoor
waterfall and eight and a half pounds of
the finest meat in America
and sure every business executive is
bound to have a few missteps but Trump's
lack of sound financial instincts is
perhaps best exemplified by the business
that he put his name on back in 2006
just before the entire housing market
collapsed I think it's a great time to
start a mortgage company we're gonna
have a great company it's Trump mortgage
and Trump mortgage calm and it's gonna
be a terrific company yeah it wasn't in
fact in fact starting a mortgage company
in 2006 with one of the worst decisions
you could possibly make but I guess you
can convince yourself it was a good idea
when you say 30 words and five of them
are great great terrific Trump and Trump
and you might say well never mind side
business is what he really is is a
builder but a building with Trump
written on it is not necessarily owned
by him he may have just licensed his
name to them something he claims is
actually better than ownership you don't
put up money you don't put up anything
spoken like a true builder and some of
those licensed buildings sell his
reputation hard like the sales video for
the Trump Ocean Resort in northern
Mexico I'm very very proud of the fact
that when I build I have investors that
follow me all over people ask me what is
Trump stand for more than anything else
and if I use one word it's always
quality right but it's easy to throw
around the word quality have you ever
stayed at a quality in the pillows are
stuffed with hair they fished out of the
bathtub drain he was never the Builder
for that project which was later
abandoned leaving would-be condo buyers
like William Flint who lost a hundred
and sixty eight thousand dollars feeling
understandably betrayed Donald Trump was
an expert in in these types of projects
or so we thought in a deposition for a
lawsuit regarding the property Trump's
son Donald Trump jr. conceded that the
Trump brand could lead people to think a
project was a solid investment there's
one of the things that you've learned
through this process is of the Trump
mean bring stability
and our viability to the project I don't
have a bring stability availability but
I imagine certain people feel that and
that might actually be the most honest
slogan for the Trump campaign Trump 2016
I don't know if it brings stability or
viability but I imagine certain people
feel that not only not only good
investors in that property sue Donald
Trump they also did in Trump Tower
tamper another project that never got
off the ground
and in both cases Trump
characteristically deflected blame onto
the developers and you would think those
investors will be facing it up
impossible legal battle given Trump's
tough talk when I get sued I take it
right oil tits take it all the way you
know what happens if you settle suits
you get sued more it's true I don't
settle anything I don't settle guess
what
he settled both those cases but the
problem is even when you can do monster
we prove Trump to be wrong it somehow
never seems to matter
you can hold his feet to the fire but
he'll just stand there on the stumps
bragging about his fireproof thought
skin and that may be because he has
spent decades turning his own name into
a brand synonymous with success and
quality and he's made himself the mascot
for that brand like Ronald McDonald or
Chef Boyardee and that is who we have
seen in the apprentice or WrestleMania
or home alone - but if he's actually
going to be the Republican nominee it's
time to stop thinking of the mascot and
start thinking of the man because a
candidate for president needs a coherent
set of policies whatever you think about
Marco Rubio and Ted Cruz at least you
basically know where they stand but
Trump's opinions have been wildly
inconsistent
he's been pro-choice and pro-life for
and against assault weapon bans in favor
of both bringing in suing refugees and
deporting them out of the country and
that inconsistency can be troubling just
this morning for instance he was asked
about the fact that David Duke former
Grand Wizard of the Ku Klux Klan had
told supporters to vote for him and this
was his answer will you unequivocally
condemn David Duke and say that you
don't want his vote or that of other
white supremacists in this election
what you see you understand I don't know
anything about David Duke okay I don't
know anything about what you're even
talking about with white supremacy or
white supremacists honestly I don't know
David Duke I don't believe I've ever met
him I pretty sure I didn't meet him and
I just don't know anything about him
really that's your best answer there
because you definitely know who he is
partly because you called him a bigot
and a racist in the past but that's not
even the fucking point the point is with
an answer like that you are either
racist or you are pretending to be and
at some point there is no difference
there and sure he disavowed David Juke
later in the day but the scary thing is
we have no way of knowing which of his
inconsistent views he will hold in
office will he stand by a statement that
vaccines are linked to autism or his
belief that Mexico is sending us rapists
oh and what about that plan he had to
defeat Isis we're fighting a very
politically correct war well we see the
other thing is with the terrorists you
have to take out their families when you
get these terrorists you have to take
out their families they care about their
lives don't kid yourself what they say
they don't care about the less you have
to take out their families that is the
frontrunner for the Republican
nomination advocating a war crime and he
might say he was joking or he's changed
his mind about any of these things and
private individuals are allowed to
change their minds we all do it but when
he's sworn in as president on January
20th 2017 on that day his opinions are
going to matter and you will remember
that date because it's the one that time
travelers from the future will come back
to to try and stop the whole thing from
happening
I get that the character of Donald Trump
is entertaining and that he says things
that people want to hear and I know his
very name is powerful just listen to
this one supporter explain what it means
to her I was a little girl well I didn't
even know what Trump Towers were but I
knew that he was a wealthy successful
man somehow like there was even as a
very young kid the word Trump sort of
meant riched
it meant success she's not even wrong
Trump does sound rich it's almost
onomatopoeic Trump is the sound produced
when a mouthy servant is slapped across
the face with a water thousand dollar
bills Trump it's the sound of a cork
popping on a couple's champagne over
Surrey the data renovations in the wine
cellar were finally completed the very
name Trump is the cornerstone of his
brand if only there were a way to
uncouple that magical word from the man
he really is well guess what there is
because it turns out the name Trump was
not always his family's name one
biographer found that a prescient
ancestor had changed it from and this is
true drunk yes King drunk and drugged is
much less magical it's the sound
produced when a morbidly obese pigeon
flies into the window of the foreclosed
old lazy drunk it's the sound of a
bottle of store-brand root beer falling
off the shelf in a gas station mini-mart
and it may seem weird to bring up his
ancestral name but to quote Donald Trump
he should be proud of his heritage
because drug is much more reflective of
who he actually is so if you are
thinking of voting for Donald Trump the
charismatic guy promising to make
America great again stop and take a
moment to imagine how you would feel if
you just met a guy named Donald Trump a
litigious serial liar with a string of
broken business ventures and the support
of a former Klan leader who he can't
decide whether or not to condemn would
you think he would make a good president
or is the spell now somewhat broken and
that is why tonight I'm asking America
to make donald drumpf again hashtag
like Donald Trump forget paperwork to
trademark the names run and incidentally
when we own it I will have the best word
and if you go to Donald J Trump calm
which we own you can download a drum for
native Chrome extension which will
replace the word Trump with drums
wherever it appears in your browser and
you can also buy these make of Donald
drunk again hats which we are selling at
cost meaning we've chosen not to make a
profit a fact which will probably
irritate mr. Trump more than anything
else I've said tonight and if you're
thinking well that's all great but I
wish there was a new campaign anthem for
Donald Trump well here it is now here it
is right now because listen we cannot
keep your employment is by the magic of
his name we need to see him through
fresh eyes so please don't think you'll
miss Donald Trump I'll think of
something
don't pump them cuz he's tough he's a
baby with even smaller fingers don't
vote because he's a builder he's more of
a shitty lifestyle brand
I await your motion to the morning
took place will be signed in gold
sharpie
goodnight