let the most dangerous thing in Led
Zeppelin's name and I will remind you
the other thing was Zeppelin now we've
heard a lot about lead over the last
year due to the horrific events in Flint
Michigan Flint's tap water was laced
with dangerous levels of lead the state
knew about it and did nothing there are
200 children under the age of six in
Flint with elevated blood levels 9,000
children have been exposed
yes Flint has become a city whose very
name evokes disaster like Benghazi or
Waco or Smurf Village never forget never
forget what happened there never forget
Flint was a perfect storm of
incompetence from start to finish and
the crisis began when the city switched
water sources a decision which was
commemorated gusli here's the plan it's
a little weird to see people make a
toast as they essentially drink poison
because under those circumstances you'd
usually expect to hear something like
I'll see you all in Hell or the mother
ship is coming and soon we will all
ascend that new water source corroded
the city's pipes and leach led into the
drinking water and with all the
bureaucratic cluster fury involved
politicians in Washington were lining up
to be vocally outraged we've got
children that have been harmed and yet
we're sitting here equivocating over
words that mayor mayor may not establish
blame the safety and well-being of our
citizens is not a Republican or a
Democrat or an independent issue it's a
human issue we're not some third-world
country where you get a hundred thousand
people who get poisoned poisoned for
long periods of time that's right
because there is only one poison that
thousands of Americans should consume
and that is Mountain Dew Code Red
oh great the most delicious way of
contracting Reds poisoning that is
horrific so we all care about lead in
Flint now which is great
unfortunately the problem is not just in
Flint a USA Today Network report found
lead contamination in almost 2,000
additional water systems spanning all 50
states and we can't just act like it's
not there the way we all pretend that
the public swimming pool is not 3% child
you're in and that's generous by the way
and if you're thinking well what we
should just rip out every lead pipe in
the country it's not quite as easy as
that there are an estimated seven point
three million lead service lines around
the country and we don't even know where
many of them are and if we did a partial
solution that could increase rather than
decrease lead in water but perhaps more
importantly even if we did replace all
lead pipes that still wouldn't come
close to stopping lead poisoning as one
led activists reassuringly puts it kids
are not gonna get poisoned from a water
fountain at their school they're not
they're gonna get poisoned from paint in
their homes okay okay I like how that
starts off sounding reassuring will ends
up even more terrifying
it's like saying look that boa
constrictor isn't gonna bite you it's
not it's just not it's gonna crush you
to death with its body
and then swallow you whole because
that's what it does but she is right
the biggest threat of lead poisoning to
children does not come from water it
comes from ingesting lead paint dust
there are an estimated 2.1 million homes
all around the country that contain both
a lead dust hazard and a child under six
and the CDC estimates over half a
million children have elevated blood
lead levels and that's terrible
ladies almost as much of a scourge in
young children's homes as frozen
merchandise why do you need three Olaf's
and a singing Elsa Mackenzie let it go
go
hashtag let let it go go and if you're
thinking at this point what what how big
a deal is a little lead dust anyway it's
a big King deal how potent is led a
child can be poisoned by only 10
milligrams of pure lead to give you an
idea of what a small amount that is this
spoonful contains about four thousand
milligrams today we know just ingesting
small amounts of lead dust can lead to
brain damage and even death okay well
first maybe don't say death in that
jolly tone of voice over the photo of a
baby but but second it is true that
there is no safe level of lead it's one
of those things so dangerous you
shouldn't even let a little bit of it
inside you much like heroin or Jeremy
Piven even even low level exposure can
lead to irreversible damage like lower
IQs antisocial behavior and reduced
attention span and the dangers are so
severe that 20 years ago
Sesame Street even produced a video to
teach kids how to deal with lead in
their holes let's go everybody from the
car wash your hands before you eat wash
your hands before you eat stay away from
peeling paint stay away from peeling hey
enough I've had it
who do you people think you are anyway
the lead police
it's a close call but as police songs go
the possibility of being poisoned by
lead is still less terrifying than every
breath you take every breath I take
you'll be watching me that's a crime
you're stalking me Gordon you're a
stalker that video was made 20 years ago
and it's enough to make you wonder well
if lead paint is so dangerous why the
fuck is there still so much of it in
houses where kids live and that's a good
question many countries around the world
actually bans the use of lead paint in
the 1920s so we knew it was dangerous
but instead of joining them America
decided to put LED basically everywhere
and humble LED also plays its part in
preserving and protecting old and new
buildings in the form of white LED for
wooden structures and red LED for field
weight humble that it's a naturally
occurring element not Meryl Streep's
Oscar speech and also if we're assigning
personality traits to metals why stop
with humble led how about passionate
zinc free spirited copper and extremely
racist tin and and it wasn't it wasn't
just newsreels
promoting Lent the the lead industry
reassured us it was safe releasing
things like this coloring book inviting
you to the Dutch boys LED party which
sounds like the worst sex club in all of
Amsterdam and even when the government
finally got serious about banning LED in
the 70s and 80s the LED industry did not
go down without a ridiculous fight here
is the head of a led industry trade
group pushing back against the evidence
that led was dangerous the fact of the
matter is if you look at a total
national profile we have never been
healthier we have never lived longer
there must be something that that we're
doing right what he's basically saying
it can't be bad I turned out fine which
is the number-one argument made by
people who did not turn out fine it's
like when your uncle says hey I'm my
first beer at 10:00 and I turned out
okay
but did your uncle stone did you though
because your dinner last night was 23
croutons dipped in frosting and that is
not turned out fine behavior make a
change uncle and and by the way there
was already plenty of hard evidence
showing that childhood LED exposure was
harmful to you in large part to a study
by this man dr. Herbert Needleman
in the late 1970s dr. noodleman studied
the baby teeth of healthy school
children in two Boston suburbs when we
looked at the data we found the children
who had highlander teeth but who had
never been identified as having any
problems with lead at lower IQ scores
poor language function and for your
attention that's right it's time you
knew children there is no tooth fairy
your baby teeth were all taken away by
dr. Herbert Needleman we told you the
fairy thing because we knew that would
creep you out but you should be thanking
that man because thanks to studies like
his America started regulating and
removing lead from our environment in
the 1970s resulting in a graph of child
blood lead levels in this country that
looks like this now lead paint was
banned here and leaded gasoline was
phased out all through here so getting
rid of lead in paint and gas was a major
public health victory you know that
18-year old intern in your office who
thinks he's so damn smart well he
probably is because he was born after
America's lead epidemic you've got lucky
soy yet now go get my coffee
but even though we drastically cut back
on the amount of new lead that we put
into the world we were still left with
all the lead that was already there in
our pipes and on our walls and while we
all agreed it was a problem the cost of
getting rid of it all was surprisingly
high in 2000 the estimated cost for
testing for and then totally removing
lead from old housing stock nationwide
was sixteen point six billion dollars
per year every year for the next decade
which is the sort of figure that turns
the government into parents with a sick
family dog hey I know we said we'd do
anything to make this better but we just
got an estimate from the vet and you
know that in doggy heaven every meal is
hot dogs
don't you think bandit would like to go
live there I do I do and look nobody
expected the government to pick up that
full tab that same report even ran an
estimate of what it would cost if the
government used interim controls like
sealing lead paint in or periodic
cleanings and only did that in homes
where families with low incomes lived
and that cost came out to just two
hundred and thirty million dollars per
year which sounded lower and therefore
better unfortunately and amazingly we
have never funded it at that level for
instance the main program to abate lead
paint in housing HUDs
lead hazard control program has never
been appropriated funding above one
hundred and seventy six million it's
been steadily going down since 2003 and
this year we've allocated just a hundred
and ten million dollars that is just a
little more than Americans spent to go
see right along to a movie which
incidentally the New York Post described
us as funny as lead poisoning it's
amazing
and look that reduction is by no means
because we were done removing lead from
housing because remember there are still
millions of homes with lead paint
hazards in them and according to heart
they were only able to fund around half
the applications for lead abatement
grants they received last year meaning
many Americans still live in homes with
LED in them and sadly it is often the
group's least able to do anything about
it
people in the lower socio-economic
levels go into older housing less well
taken care of housing housing where
there may be absentee landlords and as a
result are more liable to have lead
paint that is not been abated has not
been taken off the walls of course and
if you're in that situation you probably
can't shop around for a new apartment so
most people with lead problems are stuck
in homes they can't leave trying their
best to avoid danger which may sound
familiar because it's the plot of
everything horror movie ever made and
the crazy thing is while LED abatement
is expensive its cost effective for
instance some studies show a correlation
between decreasing LED levels and a
falling crime and when you combine that
with lower medical bills and greater
economic activity one study found that
each dollar spent on lead paint hazard
control would bring back at least
seventeen dollars in societal benefits
which is great although the cost savings
still do rank a distant third on my list
of reasons to not poison children number
one and two still being it's poison and
their king children
and you would think that our members of
Congress would be on board with doing
more to fight lead poisoning after all
you remember how angry they were about
all those kids who got poisoned in Flint
right we've got children that have been
harmed it's a human issue it's an
American issue that affects Americans
lives we're not some third-world country
where you get a hundred thousand people
who get poisoned poisoned they seem so
concerned concerned which which is what
which is what makes it but that's what
makes is so frustrating that last year
all of those men voted for a bill that
would have reduced the already low
funding for hunt led abatement programs
by thirty five million dollars amounting
to a thirty two percent cut and the
truth is if you cut funding like that
a whole lot more children might get
poisoned poisoned now the good news is
those cuts didn't go through the bad
news is the funding stayed flat and by
the way the other two primary agencies
that work on lead related issues have
had funding problems in recent years as
well which makes no sense because I
thought poisoned children was something
we were all justifiably outraged by this
problem was obvious enough twenty years
ago for Sesame Street to feel the need
to address it and since we very much
still have this problem it's clearly
time to address it again
hi Elmo hi Rosita I can't believe that
it has been two decades since Sesame
Street taught kids how to avoid lead
dust you two do not look like you've
aged a day
oh well thank you mr. Oliver I'm
moisturize oh very nice Elmo's been
hitting a gym oh whoa there well I can
see your lips well you both look great
but unfortunately I'm here to say a lot
of places still contain lead paint what
can we do about that mr. Oliver well
it's a good question we need to care
more than we currently do so that we
spend enough money on containing it have
some money
take it down oh that's nice whoa how
much yeah how much have you got in there
Elmo
how much is it one dollar and that's 76
cents okay that's a start
no no no no no no no no no helmet you
did not you didn't actually do it
because because we're gonna need a lot
more of that money probably hundreds of
millions of dollars every year I yeah
yeah we really do not have time for that
but but that the problem here is people
are worried that lead is too expensive a
problem to fix
that's ridiculous oh hey Oscar
yeah how can anyone say it's too
expensive huh
aren't they aware that according to a
study in Environmental Health
Perspectives
every dollar we spend on lead paint
hazard control produces returns of at
least seventy to one
Wow that is an astonishing level of
economic insight coming from someone who
lives in a trash can
hey the scan is rent-controlled I've had
it since the 60s okay but asking I know
I know it's cost-effective but people
just aren't willing to do it I guess it
just seems too hard yeah that does make
sense Elmo things do tend to get done if
you just decide you want to do them can
you think of another example where
that's true one pair too tight my shoes
I can never do it right then I decided
to practice it note it hide it you see
you just have to have a vested interest
in the outcome and you'd be amazed of
what you can do
rasca you take a verse oh yes my
trashcan is messy people stop and they
stare i suppose i could clean it
the problem is I don't care
well that is unsurprisingly negative
Oscar but you know what that's actually
a fair representation of our
institutional problems so there you go
ah you mean I helped you prove your
point yes Oscar you actually did let is
still all around us our pipes our walls
and our hair we should do more to
contain it but first we all have to care
that's our show thank you sir
so much
you know
you