I would like to talk to you about an
exciting opportunity
I just need 30 minutes of your time to
explain it but it has the potential to
transform your life I'm talking about
multi-level marketing companies or MLM
companies like Mary Kay
Rodan and fields a new skin and way and
Herbalife they sell different products
but generally MLMs have two main things
in common first you don't see them on
store shelves you buy them through
distributors like a friends family and
co-workers and secondly those
distributors are always looking for more
people to join them and they have a
pretty attractive message why over life
because you get to be your own boss earn
extra money
work from home raise your own children
you can name your own hours make
part-time or full-time money paying the
bills share this video with ten people
that you care about that you love that's
your door that you admire 20 people 30
people come on what are you waiting for
hundred people share with everybody they
want what we have we got it okay hold on
I'm supposed to share that with ten
people I love adore and admire
that's a tough ask let's see there are
the judges on this season of Project
Runway that's three oh this Tim Gunn
that's obviously four if you count Tim
Gunn twice that's five but I'm still
five short and I am out now and before
you brush this industry off you should
know collectively it did around thirty
six billion dollars in retail sales last
year in the u.s. you probably know
someone who is considering joining an
MLM or who already has and is posting
about it ten times a day on Facebook or
Instagram and if you do know someone
like that or have considered signing up
yourself this story is important because
let me explain how the system is
supposed to work generally distributors
have two main ways to make money sell
the product itself whether it's a makeup
vitamins or health shakes and earn money
on those sales and and this is key
recruit other people into the company
and get money based on their sales and
the sales of people they recruit in turn
just look at Vemma a few years ago a
hidden-camera court had then distributor
for that company walking a prospective
recruits through just how easy it can be
let's say you send the three friends
enter a new and I would help my friend
send a picture and get there Samantha
there's nine people there right and we
got nine people and I've lived me to
soccer that they go so it kind of gets
their money back
wait you kind of get your money back
that's as reassuring as hearing a doctor
say he kind of knows where your appendix
is oh it's probably somewhere near the
spleen and if you are thinking well hold
on that business structure sounds
familiar
isn't that a pyramid scheme well there
was a journalist waiting outside to ask
the exact same question it's not an
illegal pyramid scheme it's a direct
selling network marking company does it
shape like a pyramid the business is
shaped like a pyramid yes but you're
saying it's not an illegal pyramid it's
not in the illegal pyramid scheme oh I
get it
so it's not a pyramid it's just pyramid
shaped you know like a Dorito or an
angry bird or just a pile of bullshit
but let's put that pyramid question
aside for a moment because from the
outside these companies do have the
trappings of legitimacy many have high
profile celebrity endorses vemma had
noted science experts Jenny McCarthy
AdvoCare has esteemed ball thrower Drew
Brees and an MLM called max
international had this guy after more
than a year of due diligence gene and I
joined max international as home-based
distributors and media spokespersons Oh
to be a fly on the wall while Gina and
Chuck were poring over the numbers
during that year long due diligence
session Gina with an adding machine
chuck randomly kicking stuff it'll be
like watching Lennon and McCartney right
sergeant pepper still for many MLMs the
biggest celebrity is their founder who
can enjoy cult-like status just look at
JR Ridinger
CEO of market America at company
conferences the guy makes quite an
entrance
[Music]
Oh
Junko
[Music]
okay fourth string wedding chapel Elvis
calm the down and that's just his
walk-on once he gets going he puts on a
real show demonstrating how you can pump
money dramatizing the rat race by sweat
aliy running around in a giant wheel and
screaming at the gravestone of joe
nobody who never fulfilled his true
potential job the more man the dreams
you told me about we can actually do
them now we don't have to wait man it
works and I'm doing it and I want to
help you do it because it's so good Joe
this is amazing we can we can have
vacations and sailboats and we can have
multiple homes and you can give your
wife the the jewelry that she deserves
Ben you're gonna be a hero come on now
let's do it get out go get out before
it's too late get up holy shit all I can
say is thank goodness funerals don't
have a speak now or forever hold your
peace section because he would be at
every cemetery delivering motivational
speeches she lived a good life cue your
grandmother died a loser come back to
life Ethel you can still have that yacht
come back to life and the dangling of
vast lifestyle improvements is at the
heart of the MLM pitch their materials
feature flashy cars and luxury travel
that you can achieve and just watch a
distributor from youngevity walk you
through a future dream scenario in
exquisite detail in two years this is
what's gonna happen to you you are gonna
you're gonna drive to your work you're
gonna walk into your boss's office
you're gonna sit down and you're gonna
quit your job
[Music]
you're gonna explain that that little
pyramid scheme thing that you almost got
terminated for last year you're now an
entrepreneur and you're gonna be doing
that full-time whoa fuck oh fuck oh fuck
did you just say pyramid scheme and then
almost got terminated and then you're
going to go out to the parking lot
you're gonna get into your silver
Mercedes that youngevity has paid for
and you're gonna drive home oh no wait
actually first you're gonna drive to the
bank I'm sorry I hate to dwell on this
but you definitely said pyramid skating
back then but I'm sorry now we're
suddenly going to the bank and you're
gonna walk into the bank and you're
gonna deposit your coding bonus and the
lady's gonna say will that be checking
or savings and you're gonna say yeah I
don't really care I get these all the
time and then the lady's gonna say ha ha
that's fantastic but I actually need to
know which account this goes into and
you're going to say makes no difference
to me and she's going to say but I can't
deposit this unless you specify which
account its policy and you're going to
say it's all gravy
and she's going to say how about
checking and you're going to say I'm
loving it and she's going to say do I
need to get security and you're gonna
say the account ending in 842 for please
now youngevity told us that that woman's
claims are not authorized by the company
and are against youngevity policy which
forbids income claims although that
video was taken at one of their official
events and the woman Denise Chennault is
featured with her husband on the company
website with the words Denise and Tom
Chennault are youngevity oh come on you
don't let someone embody your company if
you don't agree with them if Flo turned
out to run a dogfighting ring
progressive would wipe her off their
website immediately and by the way you
know that's coming you can see it in her
eyes there
dead dogs dancing in there but but you
cannot deny the picture that she paints
is enticing who doesn't want to tell
their boss to go fuck themselves half my
staff would do it right now if they
could but MLMs hold out the hope that if
you work hard you can take control of
your life start your own business and
help your family but how real is the
opportunity well let's take a look at
just one of these companies in-depth
Herbalife you saw its pitch earlier it
was the one that you were supposed to
send to ten twenty a hundred people
it sells nutritional supplements like
shakes and vitamins and it's one of the
biggest MLMs around with net sales of
4.5 billion dollars last year it has a
celebrities who talk up its benefits
from superstar athletes like Cristiano
Ronaldo to pretty much the last person
you are expecting to see in this piece
well first of all you have a great
product that makes all the difference
we got sorry buddy you're a product of
the product well I am a product of the
product it has every combination of
things that I like it's a very good
product delivered by really good people
yes that is Madeleine Albright talking
to Herbalife CEO claiming she's a
product of the product so forget
studying at Columbia and Johns Hopkins
if you want to be like the first female
Secretary of State just chug a couple of
vanilla adjacent you tree shakes a day
and thank her in the morning oh and
about those products in its early days
Herbalife was accused of overstating
their health benefits claiming in the
80s that one product helped to relieve
everything from venereal disease to
tumors to bedwetting and back then their
founder Mark Hughes was asked by a
Senate subcommittee to answer experts
who'd called his diet products into
question and this was his response I
think if they're so expert in weight
loss why were they so fat yesterday it
seems to me then I'm not trying to make
any jokes but I do think that they ought
to use our product first he seems great
but but second why would anyone in the
80s take Herbalife to lose weight they
had cocaine
come to think of it we also have come
cane the point is cocaine is an
effective weight loss option it's not
where I thought I was going with this
but it is where we have ended up now to
be fair that was thirty years ago and a
lot has changed at the company since
then although when ABC News filmed some
Herbalife distributors just two years
ago they found some claims that seemed
to echo the company's past this
Herbalife distributor in New York City
told us the story of a woman who
overcame an inoperable brain tumor
thanks to Herbalife whatever the front
of it and helped her a lot new recruits
were told
Herbalife products help to treat heart
disease 24 years ago I had
heart failure nothing worked and even
helped one woman get pregnant well that
is obviously bullshit nutritional shakes
cannot help you get pregnant there are
only three liquids that can do that a
glass of merlot the honey smooth music
of Sharda and good old-fashioned Jews
and people people might be making claims
like that because they are desperate to
move excess product you think broadly
speaking under upper life system
distributors can get bonuses and massive
discounts on products based on how much
they buy which can be a huge incentive
to buy in bulk for instance let's say
you're selling
Herbalife's disgusting creamy chicken
soup powder for 1335 a box the cheaper
you can buy it from Herbalife the more
profit you could make but to stay
qualified for those higher discounts you
have to keep buying product and it might
not be easy to sell that extra soup
because a it's a little pricey and B we
actually tried it and it tastes like the
wood shavings inside a gerbil cage and
as one former top distributor will tell
you if you are just accumulating product
that can lead to a problem common enough
to have a special name we'd call it
garage qualified they would stack as
much product as they can in their garage
and at some point they would realize
that they have to quit so people buy
product more than they can then they can
sell it sits in a garage what happens
there's got to be an end point here at
some point when they run out of money
there's an end point exactly
so other life may be an industry leader
in worthless crap people stick in their
garage along with of course the PT
Cruiser the car that looks like a sporty
version of a hearse and and as a
distributor it is not easy to figure out
exactly how you are going to make money
just watch this Herbalife video from a
few years ago explaining one narrow part
of their insanely convoluted
compensation plan okay here we go
take a look at this example now when e
places a four thousand buying point
order at 40
two percent this counts as personal
volume for you but since this qualifies
e to supervisor with a one-month
qualification that volume now becomes
encumbered for everyone in the upline
remember each upline distributor needs
to accumulate 1000 unencumbered volume
points if they want to qualify for
supervisor as well it's simple and if
you accumulate 10,000 unencumbered
volume points those are grouped into an
unencumbered batch which qualifies
benedict cumberbatch for one
unencumbered cucumber cummerbund and
well yes that is absolute nonsense
it makes exactly as much sense as
everything that came before it in fact
to hear another former Herbalife
distributor tell it your main focus in
the business might be less on products
than on the people below you you don't
make money from selling products you
make a little not much not enough to pay
the bills that are racking up you make
money from signing people up of course
it's like that famous salesmanship motto
from Glengarry Glen Ross abst CE OS TOS
always be selling the concept or selling
to other sales people and at this point
that's pyramid scheme question that we
set aside earlier has to be addressed
because in broad terms
if distributors earnings come primarily
from selling products to actual
customers outside of the company that is
probably a legitimate business but if
those earnings come primarily from
selling product to the distributors
you've recruited below you and their
sales of product to the distributors
they've recruited below them or within
the company that may be a pyramid scheme
and any business that is set up that way
has a big problem for a reason that and
I will warn you does involve math almost
all of these schemes tell you that you
can make money by just recruiting three
or four five let's say five then you let
the five do they're five that gives you
twenty five what they don't show you is
that you could only do that 13 cycles
and you would exceed the population of
the earth
it's true within 14 cycles you run out
of people and that is assuming that
everyone on earth wants to be a protein
shake distributor and I can think of at
least a few people who have better
things to do Alan Alda
for instance or Malala yousufzai or
Morten Harket lead singer of AHA the guy
is still swimming in take on me money he
doesn't need this shit and an Herbalife
CEO Michael Johnson has an interesting
way of deflecting that whole pyramid
scheme question I go back to any company
I started in Disney as a director then I
went to be executive vice president and
then president of the international
entity of the company so I moved up six
or seven levels and at the top was
sitting the CEO of the company Michael
Eisner is that a pyramid is that any
different than what we're doing here yes
it is completely different Disney was a
corporate ladder those were all salaried
positions with benefits the company
wasn't banking on you personally filling
your garage with cases of unsold DVDs of
The Lion King - Simba's pride but but
Johnson could have made a stronger non
pyramid case in that interview if he
could have just shown how much money
distributors get from selling product to
actual retail customers but conveniently
Herbalife didn't keep records of those
figures now unfortunately for them the
FTC recently finished a multi-year
investigation into the company and filed
a blistering complaint walking right up
to the line of outright calling it a
pyramid scheme they alleged Herbalife's
compensation program doesn't incentivize
retail sales but rather the recruiting
of additional participants who fuel the
enterprise by making wholesale purchases
of product which sounds like you know
how pyramid schemes work and when people
pointed this out the FTC chair made an
amazing statement he is
that he had all the hallmarks or pyramid
scheme isn't that right our focus isn't
on the label the word appeared pyramid
does not appear in our complaint that is
true they were not determined not to
have been a pyramid think about what she
just said they're not determined not to
be a pyramid how is that not a huge
warning sign if the FDA announced we
have not determined cotton candy not to
be clown pubes you would never risk
eating that shit ever again now now who
knows why the FTC stopped short
perhaps it ensured Herbalife agrees to a
settlement in which they neither
admitted nor denied wrongdoing but did
pay two hundred million dollars and
agree to significant new changes but the
contents of this complaint are
mind-blowing at the FTC claims that the
overwhelming majority of Herbalife
distributors who pursue the business
opportunity make little or no money and
a substantial percentage lose money in
fact the FTC even stated Herbalife is
going to have to start operating
legitimately which implies they hadn't
been up till then and yet amazingly
Michael Johnson characterized this as a
victory hey we've got great news we've
reached an agreement with the US Federal
Trade Commission that ensures that our
mission to improve people's lives will
continue to thrive I have to tell you
this is really good news and it comes at
a time when our business is growing
bigger and better than ever before oh
you didn't just didn't just polish that
turd he put it in a bottle and convinced
people that they can make a fortune
selling nutritional turds in their spare
time but look whether Herbalife is a
pyramid not a pyramid or not not a
pyramid it is true that Herbalife is
growing and a lot of that growth has
come from Latino communities where
Herbalife has been aggressively
expanding for years they even bought a
sponsorship on the hit telenovela La Fea
must bear it's very subtle to just see
if you can spot it Mira look it's called
Herbalife this is going to help you have
more
energy and it's also going to help you
face all the problems you have believe
me
really I drink it every day and besides
it's delicious if that is happening on
the show I can't imagine the real drama
happening in the commercials
mr. Geico lizard I want to say 15% on
car insurance but how can i when you are
sleeping with my wife
and the fact a large percentage of our
lives business comes from Latinos is a
point of pride for Michael Johnson we
call it your Bligh family and we're not
ashamed of that very proud of that
the Latino the the blood if you will but
you know if it's in this company and it
feels great oh I love the blood of a
Latino community I just want to bathe in
it I want to bathe in your blood Latinos
how's this sales pitch going I feel like
it's going away no but to those supply
that Latino blood it can feel less than
great as this community meeting of those
who feel burned by Herbalife shows este
negocio y Ageha per day la cantidad de
de inc we don't mil dlares en wave a
message oh / d diamond dlares her
husband continuously reminds her about
the eight thousand dollars that she owes
to them el producto 7 C so C note ed a
CEA's tar Tabas Devender lo por lo que
todo con process una gran Pierre de yeah
sabia que yo no tena su dinero y esta
viendo el dia y cuando el es que paso
lingua nagging an sia y dijo tu tienes
que me Terra gente Abajo de T para que
tu puedes ver una ganancia le dije sabes
que dicen day to take evoke a steady yo
no voy a estar ferony DN mass so yo
Purdy grammarian drove after tea for me
you know what now might be a good time
to point out when someone says their
blood is in me and it feels great that
is what a fing vent is s
and friends of yours may say well that's
just herbal life my MLM is different but
there are echoes of what you've seen
across this industry for instance
Herbalife is far from the only company
that has made bold product claims
regarding health when I started my body
fat was 37.5 and now it's right around
1617 the pain and the lethargy that go
along with fibromyalgia is gone three
days into the experience I was feeling
25 years younger when I found out they
had a pet formulation of liquid myself
that's when I knew I had something very
exclusive after putting rembrandt on
liquid bile cell pet for three months he
started walking again
okay first of all obviously good boy
Rembrandt my second are you sure he
didn't just summon the energy to walk
because he was desperate to get away
from the eyedropper of liquid nonsense
you were shoving in your pets mouths and
just like Herbalife MLMs can often have
Scientology like levels for you to
ascend through with USANA
you may have gone from sharer to
believer to builder to achiever and
beyond and at Kyani you pass through a
series of ranks with the names of
gemstones as a one distributor explained
at a company conference I want to talk
about a millionaire mindset because if
you got involved in Kyani to become a
Jade you're selling yourself short if
you got involved in Kyani become a
diamonds you're not thinking big enough
yet if you haven't already visualized
yourself a double black diamonds
you need to kick yourself in the rear
now double black diamond is technically
a skiing term for particularly dangerous
slopes and I'm thinking maybe you
shouldn't choose a term that basically
says if you even try this you'll go
downhill fast and may end up in a king
ditch and the garag qualified issue is
not exclusive to Herbalife either it's
come up with multiple other MLM
including Mary Kay I saw with my own two
eyes the warehousing of the product
meaning they had basements full of it or
closets full of it or garages full of it
take a look at this inventory from a
consultant who is
the company she agreed to show us boxes
of product she said she bought to keep
her status Wow
so it seems some distributors may have
been more customer than salesperson
that's what finding out Jamie Lee Curtis
was actually the one eating all the
active ear
I eat 146 containers a day and I shit
like a machine gun and Mary Kay an
Herbalife will tell you that stockpiling
is uncommon and you can return unsold
products for a refund but you should
know those refunds can be partial or may
involve resigning the point is MMS may
present themselves as a great
opportunity but your chance of success
is actually remote just look at the
income disclosure statements kyani's
shows that just under 40 percent of
active distributors received a check for
$10 or more meaning that most didn't
even make that and new skins
says around 18 percent of active
distributors earned Commission checks
which is actually worse than it sounds
because active distributors represent
only around 36 percent of total
distributors so if you do the math which
they conveniently didn't that would mean
that 93 percent of all new skin
distributors receive zero Commission's
from the company in an average month so
even if you have never heard of Nu Skin
before it may be paying you just as much
as it does 93 percent of all its
distributors now MLM Zwilling 6 those
percentages are misleading they will
tell you that many of their distributors
aren't even in the business to make
money they just went to all that trouble
of signing up to get discounts on their
amazing Rhino ejaculate or as they call
it soup Belle don't they'll say
individual distributors like that Vemma
guy and those are herbal life reps don't
speak for them and that their claims are
against company policies and violators
get disciplined and most importantly
they will all insist they are not
pyramids and no one claims that any more
spectacular manner than JR Ridinger
who has an airtight case based on
spelling the word pyramid backwards
we're actually the anti pyramid
the reverse pyramid the dimmer ripe we
are in a devil ray he sounds like a cult
leader about to demand his followers
drink poison and it frankly doesn't help
that he looks like Jim Jones to a
genuinely creepy degree but it is hard
for the FTC to investigate these
companies the industry is large and
opaque and pursuing a case is a long
arduous process
they've only brought around two dozen
pyramid scheme cases against MLM in the
last four decades and MLMs have
surprising lobbying strength there's
actually a direct selling caucus in
Congress with more than 40 bipartisan
members including jason Chaffetz who
worked at Nu Skin for more than a decade
as for Herbalife it has gone to
remarkable lengths to protect its name
in Washington its recruited two former
top FTC officials to work for the
company and it's willing to be
incredibly petty as well because
remember that clip of Herbalife victims
that is from an upcoming documentary
called betting on zero and when it
played at a DC Film Festival earlier
this year the screening had 173 empty
seats because an Herbalife lobbying firm
reportedly bought them out and that's
not just petty it's stupid if you don't
want people to see a movie you don't
need to buy out seats just put up
posters saying starring Shia LaBeouf
dumb job dog
nobody's there but even if the
government did suddenly decide to crack
down on this industry which seems
unlikely many MLMs have been expanding
overseas here is a video from India via
changing people's lay you are the brand
we are growing every day let's mash you
up 1 million 1 billion one region
they are lucky Gandhi isn't alive to
hear that song because it would really
test his belief in nonviolent protests
you know what kid everybody pick up a
rock and meet me at herbalife
headquarters that song was unforgivable
just look online and you can find videos
of gigantic Herbalife events around the
world
here is one in South Africa here is one
in Mongolia here's one in Venezuela
here's one in Malaysia and here is
Michael Johnson in Mexico doing this
[Music]
okay I don't say this lightly
but that is douchebaggery at a double
black diamond level so the point is what
can we do
because good hard-working people are
going to keep getting caught up in these
companies there has to be a way to tell
the world about the dangers of MLMs
and I think I might know the perfect
distribution network and that is why
tonight we are starting our own pyramid
scheme hashtag this is a pyramid scheme
because if someone you know is thinking
about joining an MLM this is a huge
opportunity and let me show you how it
works
[Music]
[Applause]
I want to tell you about a fun
to share with friends and family the
product is this entire video about why
MLM czar King awful let me break it down
for you by sharing this you can be an
independent distributor for a leading
web video about the dangers of MLM you
can do this full-time or part-time and
give your family the lifestyle they
deserve which is frankly not getting
caught up in this bullshit you need
scientific proof that it works we told a
dog we were going to produce this video
and look the dog is walking now was it
able to walk before sorry we don't keep
those records here is how it works
simply watch this video and then forward
it to five people and then instruct them
to send it to another five people and so
on and so on and so on within 14 cycles
every single person on earth will have
seen this to the point that we will need
to start fucking to create more people
to watch it also if every single person
on earth is watching this video hello
Beyonce look I'm a really big fan
and like MLM we would like to direct a
message to Latinos in particular so we
will be uploading two versions of this
segment to YouTube with one in Spanish
but because I do not speak Spanish it
will be subtitled and this before this
portion will be performed by Jaime Camil
from Jane the Virgin hola hola I like
one hola
, faster um you are clearly more
attractive version of me in every way on
you honey yes yes yes I am so please
share this video to stop people getting
involved with these schemes because MLMs
are hurting people and we need to spread
the word about their dangers send this
to 20 people 30 people a hundred people
what are you waiting for this system
will work and it is not a dimmer right
it's an anti dimmer right this is a
pyramids right right
this is a bear
[Applause]
Oh
see you next week good night
you