I would like to talk to you about drugs
and I know I know
I already sound like a middle school
health teacher about to show you a video
like this the pattern is generally the
same take a lack of responsibility the
inability to make right choices add to
it ignorant and indifference and top it
off with a desire for escapism and kicks
the sum total is then conceivably found
in the Benny's the reefer the pop needle
yes the port needle now now now you may
laugh but that Filmworks think about it
when was the last time that you saw a
pot neither exactly exactly
but unfortunately America is now in the
midst of a new drug crisis and it seems
that no one is safe from it
Laura Charlie's owner who asked us not
to use her last name says Charlie had to
be rushed to the vet you can't see the
suspect throw the drugs over the fence
in the video but that's Charlie and what
she's eating is a full bag of heroin
you can't process the fact that your dog
ate heroin yeah and if she can't process
it imagine how it must have felt for her
dog when it kicked in who's a good boy
I'm a good boy I'm a really good boy I'm
the best boy
[Applause]
even that light-hearted local news story
had some chilling context Garret Bishop
runs the bar can play where it happened
he says it highlights a much bigger
problem
this whole heroin problem around here is
is ridiculous you know we find needles
we find everything around here and it's
it's getting to the point to where I
can't let my employees go outside okay
that is terrifying although honestly
rampant heroin abuse near a doggy
daycare center is the first case that
McGruff the Crime Dog is actually
qualified to solve well the thing is
that that is symptomatic of the fact
that America is facing an epidemic of
addiction to opioids like heroin and
prescription painkillers as of 2015 an
estimated 2.6 million Americans were
addicted to them and they're now
involved in almost 30,000 overdose
deaths a year in the US and the
prevalence of this problem astonishes
some people just listen to Donald Trump
up in New Hampshire they said the
biggest single problem they have up here
is heroin and I said how does heroin
work with these beautiful lakes and
trees and all of the beautiful it
doesn't yeah it does though it does
heroin works basically everywhere
because it's heroin it's not a cellphone
heroin has full coverage
so so tonight we're going to look at one
of the major causes of this crisis
prescription painkillers which are
chemical cousins of heroin around 75% of
heroin users started with a prescription
opioids drugs like oxycontin vicodin and
percocet which some take recreationally
and others takers prescribed by a doctor
but however it starts it can get out of
hand fast so how many if we start from
this side have moved from prescription
drugs to heroin everybody and every so
much more cheaper once people became
dependent on painkillers
they said they do almost anything to get
them and one time I I was hurting so bad
that I ended up punching a 4x4 and
breaking all three of these fingers in
this bone to get pain meds for my doctor
I do that several times so you'd hire
yourself in order to go to adult this
affects ninety pulled out of my head for
prescriptions at the time that's how I
get a prescription you updated with like
groups of people where they taking like
that to their wrists protons easily I
mean how many people do know someone
that's died of overdose everybody this
is happening everywhere the odds are
right now you probably know someone who
is struggling or who has died from an
opioid addiction some towns have been
devastated just two months ago in and
around Huntington West Virginia
twenty-eight overdoses occurred in one
five-hour span and given their risks
it's kind of amazing how freely doctors
have prescribed them because there are a
lot in circulation we have currently
nearly 250 million prescriptions for
opioids written every year that's enough
for every adult in America to have a
bottle of pills and then some holy shit
and those bottles aren't necessarily
sitting on a shelf unused like that
bottle of wine that you are saving for a
special occasion but now serves as a
reminder that you haven't had a single
event in four years
that was deserving you're getting fancy
drunk look see these these pills are
getting used or falling into the hands
of others from from those who are
already addicted to just bored teenagers
so how has this happened because
interestingly as recently as the early
90s doctors were excessively wary of
prescribing opioids back then there was
a thing called OPA phobia
a lot of health care professionals did
not want to prescribe opiates at all
because they thought you give the
slightest amount you turn your patients
into addicts and so even people with
stage four cancer weren't being giving
obvious they were left to suffer yes
OPA phobia which is not to be confused
with Oprah phobia which is the
irrational fear of screaming talk-show
hosts giving you a brand new Pontiac
sedan Oprah I can't afford the taxes on
this yeah haven't thought it through now
obviously that level of undertreating
pain was a huge problem in itself and to
their credit pain care advocates work to
dispel some dangerous myths but in doing
so they made a key mistake as you will
see right at the end of this clip today
the federal government said in a report
that about half of all surgery patients
suffer needlessly because doctors and
hospitals don't pay enough attention to
painkiller health secretary Louis
Sullivan talked about myths the pain
builds character myth he said that
infants don't feel pain another myth
that elderly patients have a higher
tolerance for pain or that painkillers
are addictive all myths ok ok ok
first of course babies feel pain how the
did we ever think otherwise but more
importantly the fact that painkillers
are addictive was not a myth it's like a
book of Greek mythology featuring the
stories of Zeus Sisyphus Oedipus and
Yanni come on that last one is very real
and it cannot be dismissed and look a
nuanced discussion between the medical
community about the complexities of pain
treatment is clearly important the
problem is that discussion became
dominated by the pharmaceutical industry
who started amplifying the message that
opioids should not just be used for
acute pain like that from cancer or
surgery but for
all sorts of pain like arthritis and
back aches which makes sense as a motive
coming from the pharma industry end of
life pain care is a narrow business it's
hard to make a lot of money off of the
product exclusively marketed to people
who are close to death honestly I don't
know how Fox News even does it I have no
idea it's a mystery
volume I guess but I don't know and
within the pharma industry the loudest
voice was Purdue in 1996 they released
the blockbuster drug oxycontin and they
marketed it to doctors aggressively
giving out swag like a fishing hats
swing music CDs bearing the slogan swing
in the right direction with oxycontin
and oxytocin
we didn't get hold of one of those you
have clearly never watched this show
before because yes here he is and yes he
is my new best friend and yes his name
is Harold and I've got a sight Purdue
this is the perfect choice of mascots
because much like a gorilla
oxycontin might seem appealing but if
you're not careful it will tear your
life apart
won't you Harold yes he will Purdue also
distributed inspirational videos like I
got my life back
featuring 7 patients whose lives were
turned around by the magic of oxycontin
since I've been on this new pain
medication I have not missed one day of
work and my boss really appreciates that
Lauren is there every day so I'm able to
be very productive and one of the things
that's really dear to my heart and which
I'm especially excited about is just the
fact that I'm able to spend time with my
grandchildren
it's amazing just to be able to keep up
with them and not have to always
constantly tell them grandma can't play
now
can't do their screams hurt and grimace
back hurts that's genuinely sweet and is
also a powerful message although I will
note it makes time with your grandkids
more fun could apply to literally any
drug hey kids
grandpa's gonna take you to the park oh
no I'm gonna take on the swings I'm
gonna push you real high and then we're
gonna stay up all night I'm gonna come
up with inventions and you're gonna
write them down and you're gonna write
them down fast we're having quality time
and it wasn't just it wasn't just
uplifting stories other platoon video
sought to reassure patients who might
have been nervous about taking such a
strong drug less than 1% of patients
taking opioids actually become addicted
less than 1% and I know it may seem like
they are pulling that number out of
their ass but they actually pulled it
out of the letters to the editor section
of the New England Journal of Medicine
seriously this is it that paragraph is
the whole thing
it wasn't peer-reviewed and it was only
about short-term use of opioids in
hospitals but it became the main source
for that 1% claim and letters pages are
not a solid source for information just
this month
a Pennsylvania newspaper published a
letter featuring a man's question about
Hillary Clinton's fitness for office at
because and I quote what if that time of
the month comes to which the obvious
answer is 1 she's 68 and too cute maybe
even if doctors started noticing that a
lot more than 1% of their patients were
getting addicted Purdue had a ready
answer what if they're not because they
had doctors on their payroll like Alan
Spanos who were happy to explain the
helpful new concept of pseudo addiction
I'll let him tell you about it pseudo
addiction is when a patient is looking
like a drug addict because they're
pursuing pain relief so pseudo addiction
is relief seeking behavior mistaken as
drug addiction wow that is so convenient
that is like Chipotle going have you
heard of this fascinating new thing
called pseudo diarrhea it looks a lot
like diarrhea but it's not diarrhea and
the cure may actually be more tacos and
produce overall message of a quick easy
cure for pain was very appealing
especially for primary care doctors who
might only have 15 minutes to treat a
patient so it is no wonder that by the
year 2000 doctors were writing nearly 6
million oxycontin prescriptions per year
and its sales were more than even viagra
and remember that was a drug that had
the distinct advantage of being sold by
Bob Dole the red-hot late 90s it boy
however evidence started piling up that
it was far riskier than promised with
headlines like oxycontin abuse is
increasing and oxycontin abuse called a
plague or as I'm sure Perdue would call
it a pseudo plague and even the stars of
Purdue's I got my life back video we're
not immune from this trend because a
later investigation discovered two out
of the seven of them died as active
opioid abusers and that grandmother you
saw earlier became addicted and nearly
lost everything I lost my house
I have lost cause I've lost I lost a lot
a lot I I lost a lot to keep um behind
taking that drug when I did lose my dog
mm-hmm and I not lost my medal by
insurance although as I said if I was to
go to the mailbox once a month and I
would find a bottle of oxycontin in it
I'd probably still be on it and I'd
probably be B then think about that
losing her health insurance might have
saved her life that is an irony so deep
it would vaporize Alanis Morissette into
a cloud of King Steve now by now I'm
guessing you are pretty angry at Purdue
so you may be glad to hear them in 2007
they admitted some responsibility in a
lawsuit so big it actually led to the
evening news good evening
the maker of a hugely popular painkiller
has some pain of its own tonight the
company and its top officers will pay
634 million dollars in fines for lying
to the public Wow
you know they've done if they had to pay
over six hundred million dollars for
misleading marketing because you get a
lot of leeway on that that's why Duncan
doughnuts is not yet being sued for
saying America runs on Dunkin when we
all know their real slogan should be
sometimes you can't find a Starbucks
look it wasn't just Purdue pushing the
envelope Cephalon paid a four hundred
and forty four million dollar settlement
for over marketing drugs and iNSYS has
been investigated for some of its
practices surrounding a drug they made
containing fentanyl and opioids which
can be a hundred times more powerful
than morphine their drug is only
approved for cancer patients but
interest is accused of not just pushing
it for non cancer patients but even
helping convince insurance companies to
pay for it and to do that according to
want ex-employee they used a
particularly shady technique if you
don't have cancer and breakthrough
cancer pain no insurance company is
gonna pay for this medication so if you
call up and you tell them that the
patient doesn't have cancer it's
automatically denied so instead what
were you doing they would always ask
does the patient have cancer uh-huh
that's what we would say so you do a huh
you're right say yes but I'm not saying
yes right I would just say uh-huh
isn't that a yes well that's what they
did think um but I wasn't blatantly
saying yes Oh God except everybody knows
aha means yes if you go to thesaurus
calm and type in aha
literally the first word that comes up
is yes
followed by options such as absolutely
definitely unquestionably and yep look
at at this point I should say that
Purdue and Cephalon owner told us that
those practices were in the past and
iNSYS has denied wrongdoing and didn't
respond to any of our questions not even
with a not our but at a certain point
the question has to become less what did
we do wrong and more what do we do now
because these drugs are still the most
effective solution for certain types of
pain and many patients need them so we
can't get rid of them but we have to be
much more careful about how they're
prescribed and to their credit the CDC
issued voluntary guidelines this year
suggesting doctors use non-opioid
therapies when possible and if and when
one is needed to start patients with a
lower dose and is sure to supply a
technique that they call start low and
go slow which does sound good but also
sounds like how your creepiest
highschool friends described cunnilingus
dude start low go slow and afterwards
take her to friendlies chicks love root
beer floats dude they'll often dude
those slow though once loaded
well yeah look what while all that
sounds great
unfortunately not all areas of the
country have access to alternative pain
treatments it's easy to say use some
non-opioid alternative but in a lot of
rural areas patients don't have access
to things like physical therapy and
mindfulness meditation and insurance
companies won't pay for and that is a
big problem because even in a rural area
alternative pain treatments should be at
least as easy to find as waffle houses
which like heroin are both hazardous to
your health and dangerously addictive
and to put it mildly it does not seem
that the pharmaceutical industry is
expecting any major reversals in opioid
sales any time soon in fact they are now
marketing extra drugs to fight one of
opioid side-effects constipation
[Music]
if you need an opioid to manage your
chronic pain you may be so constipated
it feels like everyone can go except you
[Music]
you know painkillers are powerful if
people use them despite the sound of
this I defect being jealous of a dog's
butthole
and that commercial ads during the Super
Bowl this year which means a it is a big
business and B I can only assume there
was a reverse commercial during the
Puppy Bowl featuring a jealous dog and a
shitting man but we cannot just work to
prevent future addicts we're going to
need to do more to help the millions
that already exist which means more
investment in treatment programs as well
as increasing the availability of drugs
like nilachal naloxone are commonly used
in a nasal spray to rescue people from
overdoses because as this firehouse
makes clear it is a tool that they use
with depressing frequency so every
single firefighter in the Revere Fire
Department knows how to use this has
been trained on this yes yes and has
used it yes from the chief down we tend
to have more overdoses than we do fire
fires so it's a piece of equipment that
we can't go without now just like we
have the hose it's true firefighters
might be more likely to use a nasal
spray than a hose which is really going
to cut those hot firefighter calendars
because something about an overdose
reversing nasal spray isn't quite as
sexy it's still sexy which is not quite
as sexy it is still sexy though just not
quite but still and that's not the point
the point is there is no one simple
answer here
not all opioid addicts will respond to
the same treatment and not all people in
pain will find relief from alternative
therapies this is going to take a
massive effort and a significant
investment it won't be cheap it won't be
quick and it won't be easy and it is
hard not to be angry at the drug
companies like Purdue whose promise of
cheap quick easy pain solutions helped
put us in this fucking mess because
while they may not be solely responsible
if you were to ask me if they best
significant blame for reckless greedy
behavior
which contributed to this massive public
health crisis I might not say yes
exactly but I would definitely say aha