Puerto Rico the island that for decades
has been marketed to us as a beautiful
vacation spot this is the Commonwealth
of Puerto Rico a land of song and
laughter coconut milk that delicious
Puerto Rican rum this is really living
its the revival of an old coconut mask
festival at Luisa just 45 minutes from
San Juan and how'd you like to see this
the morning after wait wait where were
we did that 1950s narrator just make a
sex joke why if you've got the moxie you
can every crazy masked stranger on the
island ha ha ha but what oh Rico is an
island of three and a half million
people and they are currently facing a
horror even greater than a demonic
Slipknot coconut Mars Porto Rico is in
desperate financial trouble Puerto Rico
is facing a 70 billion dollar public
debt amid a tenure economic crisis and
they thought it was real considering the
state of our economy the name okay so
the debt is not payable Gaetano say this
is not politics this is math that is bad
because this is math is one of the most
dread inducing sentences in the English
language even when it's uttered at the
start of an actual math class as for
voting statements go it's right up there
with it'll never grow back and mommy
whiskers has been napping for a really
really long time Warren Rico is
currently around seventy billion dollars
in debt and it is wreaking havoc on the
island the poverty rate is a staggering
45% last year alone over 80,000 people
left for the mainland u.s. worker Rico
has already shut down more than 150
schools in the last few years the
cash-strapped government has
dramatically hiked sales taxes from 7
percent to 11 and a half percent far
higher than any in the United States yes
right now
Puerto Rico is like the last Tower
Records everything's overpriced
everyone's being laid off and they're
still
weirdly large number of Ricky Martin CDs
and remember Americans have a personal
stake here
Puerto Ricans are American citizens and
they and their descendants include some
of our finest judges both of our laws
and our idols they're some of our top
athletes and our top Guzman's and just
this week does this week lin-manuel
Miranda the son of Puerto Rican parents
won the Pulitzer Prize for Hamilton the
Broadway smash he created and stars in
and last month he made a heartfelt plea
to Congress on Puerto Rico's behalf if I
can leave you with anything today
our island is in crisis and if I can
help in any way if I can get more
eyeballs to this crisis it's a fixable
problem I'm urging Congress if Hamilton
tickets will help I'm happy to do that
too
Wow that that is incredible because I'm
amazed even he can get tickets it is it
is easier for a meerkat to get into
Harvard Law School than it is to get
into that show and and quick sidenote
here Congress should take him up on that
the show is amazing have you seen that
clip from when he performed a
work-in-progress version of the opening
song at the White House but word got
around this said this kid is insane man
took up a collection just to send into
the main lab get your education don't
forget from whence you came and the
world is gonna know
Alexander Hamilton it's so good it's so
good we all want a Rico for that man so
how did we get to the point when members
of Congress are being offered Broadway
tickets to save Puerto Rico well much of
it has to do with the fact that as we
have talked about before here Puerto
Rico is not a state but rather as a 1901
Supreme Court case stated it is a
territory that is foreign to the United
States in a domestic sense which sounds
like what a liquor store clerk says to
try and sell surplus cases of Miller
High Life oh you're looking for a
quality foreign beer I'd call this
foreign in a domestic sense and look we
don't need to settle tonight the
question of Puerto Rican statehood that
is a complicated issue on which many
Puerto Ricans themselves disagree but
one thing is for sure because it's a
territory many laws that apply to the
states have loopholes concerning Puerto
Rico and as you will see time and time
again in this piece
those little legal quirks have had
massive consequences some good but many
utterly devastating and let's start with
a quirk many Puerto Ricans like
something called section 936 it gave tax
breaks to encourage businesses that
would otherwise have moved overseas to
move to Puerto Rico and it worked in the
1970s the US government helped attract
business to Puerto Rico by granting
generous tax breaks that led to a
booming manufacturing sector
particularly pharmaceutical companies at
its peak the island was home to 89 drug
manufacturing plants all of a sudden
Puerto Rico was a pharmaceutical
paradise at its peak the small city of
barceloneta
even housed 14 pharmaceutical and other
plants including one that produced
viagra and that viagra plant was such a
source of pride that the town's mayor
has said we're responsible for a lot of
good moments
I'm one step away from outright changing
the town's motto to barceloneta you're
welcome for that boner now unfortunately
for Puerto Rico Congress got rid of
those tax breaks to offset a tax cut on
the mainland phasing them out completely
by 2006 and between that and the u.s.
recession Puerto Rico lost over half its
manufacturing jobs putting its economy
into a flaccid state that no amount of
Viagra could fix and to pay its bills
the government started issuing tons of
municipal bonds and a municipal bond is
basically an IOU puerto rico borrows
money from someone promising to pay it
back later with interest and for years
people lined up to buy those bonds
because thanks to some other quirks in
the law they were very attractive
Congress decided bonds from Puerto Rico
would be triple tax exempt those who buy
them don't have to pay federal state or
local taxes on the bonds the money you
earned on them was triple tax-exempt
anywhere in the US and triple is the
best you can have like triple fudge
brownies because double fudge is shit
and quadruple fudge doesn't even exist
because what would the fourth fudge spin
now now Wall Street loves those tax
breaks as well as the fact that thanks
to yet another legal quirk that they
themselves lobby for they could stash
tons of bonds in funds without putting
Puerto Rico in the name you might even
own Puerto Rican bonds and not even know
it Oppenheimer's Maryland municipal fund
for instance is made up of 50.4% Puerto
Rico bonds which is insane
because if you are more than half
something that is what you should be
caught even Taco Bell makes sure their
ground beef is less than 50% squirrel
lips
and that's because as we all know the
rest is a combination of raccoon dicks
and weasel knees and yet Puerto Rico
even went a step further to entice Wall
Street's writing into its constitution
language suggesting that certain
bondholders would be paid first ahead of
anything else including funding basic
government services which is pretty
fucked up the u.s. owes 1.2 trillion
dollars to China but if you called 9-1-1
you would not expect them to say oh I'm
sorry we chose to send our firetruck
money to Beijing
have you tried blowing on the fire
really hard and his provisions like that
that kept the money flowing in and as
their former governor puts it Porto Rico
got hooked
they were extremely attractive in the
marketplace and Puerto Rico actually got
addicted I would say to it and and so it
was a lot easier to just go out and
Barrow as opposed to making tough
decisions yeah and that is absolutely
true but you were the governor for many
of those years so hearing you complain
about addiction is like hearing Keith
Richards complain about the Rolling
Stones drug problem it was you key
you're the only rolling stone whose
blood was a controlled substance it was
you and there was wrong walk work here
which made Puerto Rico at timebomb
because unlike States Puerto Rico cannot
authorize what's called chapter 9
bankruptcy which is huge because think
about that if you are massively in debt
and you can't declare bankruptcy you are
stuck and this happened because of a
tiny amendment to a law in 1984 and the
crazy thing is no one can say why it was
written it's interesting to note that
chapter 9 applied to Puerto Rico from
1933 to 1984 and then mysteriously for
some reason where Rico was exempt from
Chapter 9 a provision was stuck into a
larger bill with no explanation or
debate there is no legislative history
to explain why Puerto Rico was singled
out he's right so the next time you're
obnoxious friend tells you
everything happens for a reason you can
simply say no dan not the 1984 provision
exempting Puerto Rico from bankruptcy
protection so shut the up look we've
even tried out we even tried you tried
to find out ourselves why that amendment
got attached
we knew strong Thurmond had proposed it
so we asked an archivist at the library
where his papers are kept to go through
the relevant papers and they came up
with nothing which might actually be the
best case scenario there because usually
when it comes to Strom Thurmond the
answer to the question where did this
come from
is either his testicles or fervent
racism so so at this point with massive
debt and that it's promised to pay a
head of government services and no
access to bankruptcy Puerto Rico was
fucked but wait because we're only
getting started here because four years
ago in an attempt to turn things around
they embarked on a disastrous plan to
lure in wealthy individuals and small
businesses by among other things
exempting them from capital gains taxes
which you have to admit is pretty good
rich people bait it's right up there
with tiny dogs in bags and big dumb
round ice cubes the colder when they're
round you know the government even
created a video to sell mainlanders on
moving featuring a businessman talking
in spectacularly condescending tones
about how unexpectedly civilized life in
Puerto Rico is what we found first of
all was a thriving business community
solid like the United States in terms of
family I must say I was skeptical at
first but in the end the island has
everything you might need great
possibilities I visited schools and Wow
top level in English I saw living
alternatives up to our standards
I felt safe there's so many little
treasures you want to explore
complemented with all the comforts the
necessities you and your family are
accustomed to oh that level of colonial
town makes me cringe and I'm King
English yeah the buildings had roofs the
cars had wheels on them but wait they
also had indoor plumbing and the printed
word but while those tax breaks were
part of a plan to create 50,000 jobs in
18 months a study later found they only
directly created fifty eight hundred
that's 12 percent if an ER doctor told
you congratulations we got 12 percent of
the GI Joe out of your rectum you would
not consider that a job well done and
while those who relocated have gotten
out of paying around 420 million dollars
in taxes Puerto Ricans have been
suffering the effects of savage
government cuts including hospitals
literally struggling to keep the lights
on puto Rico sad problem has gotten so
dire the Power Authority cut off the
hospital that's behind on its bill the
Electric Power Authority did at least
wait until surgeries were done for the
day today before pulling the plug oh
that's nice they waited till surgeries
were done I guess it's only the people
on life support that have to worry about
the switch to bicycle power generators
pedal faster Luis we're losing him and
with working conditions like those is it
any wonder that apparently at least one
doctor a day leaves Puerto Rico that is
an attrition rate rivaling that of
Grey's Anatomy how have so many of you
died you work in a hospital
and the truly tragic thing here is
Federico may soon need those doctors
more than ever health officials are
worried as they expect the Zika virus to
infect one in five people in Puerto Rico
the island of Puerto Rico has already
seen 450 confirmed cases of the virus
that's been linked to severe birth
defects so hold on on top of debt
industrial collapse school closures and
a sudden influx of tax dodging arseholes
now Puerto Rico has to worry about
deadly mosquitoes it's like the island
is being hit with all the plagues that
God felt were to Finke for the Bible and
this is clearly a moment where Puerto
Rico could rightly cry out to its
creditors for mercy however a lot of its
creditors and now hedge funds who
traditionally thrive on this kind of
chaos hedge funds often invest in debt
ridden economies buying up bonds at low
prices and looking to flip them for
quick profits and Puerto Rico is their
latest target the strategy has earned
them a reputation among critics as
so-called vulture funds it's true as
much as 30 percent of Puerto Rican debt
is now held by vulture funds and if you
are alone in the desert and sea vultures
perched above you your first thought is
never all thank God the vultures are
coming to help
and these vulture funds have lived up to
their name with a group of them
producing a report last year titled for
Puerto Rico there's a better way
suggesting budget cuts like cutting
excess Medicare Medicaid benefits and
reducing the number of teachers on the
island so shaving money out of medicine
and education is your better way well at
least have the intellectual honesty to
then change the title of your report to
hey Puerto Rico q pay me
now the good news here is Congress is
currently considering a bipartisan bill
that would give Puerto Rico some
breathing room to negotiate with
creditors and the details are still
being worked out but if this is done
well it could be a real help to Puerto
Rico unfortunately there is now a
coordinated campaign to kill it
who will bail out Puerto Rico Washington
says you will retirement accounts
crushed a bailout on the backs of savers
and seniors tell Congress stop the
Washington bailout of Puerto Rico okay
everything you just saw was bullshit
first it's not a bailout no one is
suggesting a cash infusion second that
ad wasn't paid for by savers and seniors
but by the center for individual freedom
who spent nearly 2 million dollars on
ads like that they are a dark money
group so it's impossible to say where
that money came from hedge funds hedge
funds go for the money
it's it's impossible to say which funds
impossible even even these sad old
people featured in that ad of bullshit
because they're all stock footage models
and if you let the stock footage of the
man with the moustache play out he's not
even sad because he starts keep smiling
that's amazing you can you can make him
react to anything looker hey stock
footage man you've been used in a
manipulative attack ad oh don't be sad
let's get some ice cream oh you know
what bad news they're out of ice cream
but they have cake pound cake though
with strawberries Oh stock footage man
you're America's greatest living actor
and this is not to say that regular
bondholders have not been hurt in fact
some Puerto Rican bondholders may have
got the worst of this thanks to one more
quirk because some of the bonds were
underwritten by the investment bank UBS
which sold them to one of its own
divisions essentially selling them to
itself ups then offloaded those bonds on
to Puerto Rican customers even though
its own sales force felt they were so
risky they came up with a list of 22
reasons not to sell them and
22 is a lot of reasons to ignore if a
waiter at Bennigan's says she has 22
reasons she doesn't feel comfortable
selling you the Cobb salad you listen to
her and you go across the street to off
King sizzler
now now UBS says they did nothing wrong
and technically they're right I mean
sure
UBS should never have been able to sell
those bonds to themselves it's actually
illegal to do that under the Investment
Company Act of 1940 but and I think you
know what's coming by now that doesn't
apply in Puerto Rico because apparently
no laws apply to businessmen down there
I would not be surprised if in Puerto
Rico hedge fund managers somehow have
the ability to fly due to some bullshit
exemption to the law of gravity Strom
Thurmond wrote up in the 1980s look the
point is 3.5 million Americans are
facing a dire crisis right now and the
clock is ticking
their next debt payment is due on May
1st and in the short term they need
relief from hedge fund lawsuits and an
opportunity to try to restructure their
debt and in the long term we need to
stop treating Puerto Rico like it's just
a tax haven or a place to have
terrifying sex with a stranger in a
coconut mask and instead we have to
start treating it like an island of
American citizens whose fate is
interwoven with ours and look there are
certainly better voices than mine to
speak on behalf of Puerto Rico luckily
there is someone with Puerto Rican
parents and an amazing voice and he is
here tonight please welcome
yeah my family's from Puerto Rico the
tropical destination where you can spend
your Washington's the spot where you
vacation a Commonwealth with not a lot
of wealth and not quite nation 70
billion dollar topic of conversation
hoping the god John Oliver's comical
dissertation resonates with the Congress
that got us in this situation along with
suicidal tax incentive declarations yet
will pay your bonds first close the
hospital the patients this is an island
a hundred miles across a hurricane has
come in and we're running up a loss we
got here through a million misguided
loopholes that giveth and take away
businesses and poop in our soup bowls
they crapped in y'all's they crapped in
mine and somewhere down the line Strom
Thurmond's goes busted a cap and a
chance to cap to nine the great debate
over statehood has to wait that's Rose
and Jack on the Titanic asking when's
our next date the ship is sinking we
have to stay in patient and matters then
we'll figure out our facebook
relationship status will they or won't
they its friends is Rachel and Ross we
have to help our island just a hundred
miles across
to recap 3.5 million American civilians
are on the hook for billions pulcher
funds are circling and lobbying for
payout there's nothing left to tax or
cut we're stuck we need a way out
allow them to restructure there's no
structure for what happens if you let
this crisis play out renee is less than
a day out it's nonpartisan the hard part
is in convincing Congress but political
matters so their heart is in the fight
for relief not a bailout just relief a
belief that you can pass legislation to
ease our grief Paul Ryan who comes in
Hamilton at your house how does he do
with Pelosi how where my Hamilton blouse
your citizens are suffering stop the
bleeding stop the loss how Puerto Rico
it's just a hundred miles across
thank you
it sounds like a boring keys