cars the muse for America's greatest
songs from the complete works of Bruce
Springsteen to Tim McGraw's ode to the
American truck if you like it up loud in
your heel very proud and you know
talking about a nation true rock yeah
that song is untrue 'king believable I
mean sure it doesn't really make sense
that they're just driving around in an
empty lot but it looks like they're
having fun so who gives a flying truck
but America's Auto obsession isn't just
a hobby 86% of American workers get to
work by automobile and the remaining 14%
presumably commute by public
transportation walking or in the case of
that one weird guy in your office named
Nathaniel penny farthing bicycle get
down from there
stop it and if you don't have a car
holding down a job can be a tremendous
challenge just watch one woman describe
her daily commute via public
transportation
I normally still get the kids out on
their bus on time it's just a matter of
not whether I'll make my bus this is the
first bust and then I take two trains
and another bus normally it takes me
roughly hour and a half to two hours on
an average day if I were to drive to
work it takes me maybe 10 or 15 minutes
so how commute would be 10 minutes with
a car but without one she is literally
the length of the movie the imitation
game away from her job which is to say
to wasted hours that feel like forever
but but cars are obviously expensive
which is why many people have to take
out loans to buy them some from places
like this
everyone has approved EDD buyers auto
sales regardless of your credit even if
this is my trade-in
approved even if I'm self-employed
I'll even if we have to repossessions
over closure and a bankruptcy everyone
is approved okay listen I do not mean to
be judgy here but don't approve the
clown he's a clown genetically speaking
he is programmed for murder
now now that is targeting people with
bad credit who are only eligible for
what are called subprime lungs and
nearly a quarter of all car loans are
now of the high-risk subprime variety in
fact so many are being issued they
recently reached a ten-year high and if
the phrase a boom in subprime loans is
making your eye twitch with flashbacks
to the mortgage crisis just wait we will
get there but first let me take you on a
tour of the subprime auto loan industry
and we'll start with so-called buy here
pay here dealers who do their own
lending they've been around for years
and their ads make it all look very
simple how can we get you financed when
others can't two reasons first we are
the bank we don't have to send you or
your deal anywhere the second reason we
can get you financed is because we don't
even look at your credit score of course
in fact we don't even know what a credit
score is what is a good one pg-13 640 on
the verbal 710 on math 3 under par is
that a good credit score we've got no
idea and that's why you should trust us
and look theoretically theoretically it
is a good thing that car dealers lend
money to people who can't get financing
elsewhere but in practice these
dealerships can trap people with few
options into paying vastly more than a
car is worth it's just one of the many
ways in which when you are poor
everything can be more expensive the
average interest rate they buy here pay
here a lot is 19 percent with some
paying up to twenty nine percent and
that that interest is on top of mock-ups
and add-ons that can inflate the price
of the car so just look at Arlene Jones
she went into a Chicago dealership
trusting that they would help her when
she first got to the quick auto lot she
told the salesman she had an upper limit
on price I told myself I can't afford no
car over three thousand dollars she says
he was very reassuring like don't worry
about he's a man do it in the end
Arlene borrowed eight thousand six
hundred dollars at twenty four point
nine percent interest over three years
if she had paid off the loan she would
have spent more than thirteen thousand
dollars on a car that was only worth
about three thousand holy shit that is
outrageous the only way to acceptable to
sell someone a three thousand dollar car
for thirteen thousand dollars is if you
slip a mint-condition
x-men issue one into the glove
compartment at that point you're being
generous but it's no wonder that buy
here pay here loans had an average
default rate last year of nearly one in
three with most customers who default
doing so just seven months after taking
out the loan and just think about that
seven months is not a lot of time if you
put a seven-month-old baby in front of
the screen right now it would not
understand anything I'm saying it
wouldn't even know if I was making fun
of it I'll show you go ahead get a baby
right now and put it in front of the
screen here we go hey hey dummy hey you
don't know that I'm locking into stupid
wittle thanks do you know you don't know
you don't you who knows about that but
not you you don't mind at all see seven
months is not long enough to do anything
now put the kid to bed you're a terrible
parent
but the problem is the problem is even
if you're just a few days late on a
payment the dealership can repossess
your car and when they do sometimes it
is with little regard for what's inside
when the mother went to pick up her
three children at a daycare she left her
nine-month-old in the car but when she
came out there was no baby and no car I
wish you reap all car you check the car
for you take it that's really just don't
you know take my money baby yes exactly
don't take a baby is a good general rule
for everyone whether you are
repossessing a car
choosing a prom date or making a
selection in the NFL Draft
don't take a baby you don't take a baby
I don't care what they did in a combine
and and increasingly it is not difficult
for buy here pay here dealerships to
repossess your car because many now
install a special device which goes off
when your payment is due every five
seconds the device is actually beeping
at them as their way all the way taking
the kids to school all the way to work
informing them that they need to make
their payment contact or lender however
if they don't then the device at
midnight most lenders choose midnight as
their time of shut off device will not
allow that car to start okay
setting aside the horror of the fact
that they can shut your car off that
beeping sound is unbelievably annoying
anyone with a smoke detector knows it
only takes about 30 minutes of incessant
beeping before you've completely lost
your mind
I'll push the button I unscrew the top
and I smash the whole thing with the
breadmaker and it's still making that
sound so the only reasonable option is
now to set my house on fire
and once they have repossessed your car
these dealers don't have to refund your
down payment and they might decide you
still owe the money because the car is
now worth less than they sold it to you
for so you can easily end up with no car
and thousands of dollars in debt
meanwhile the dealer can turn around and
sell your car to someone else so the
truth is they can make money either way
and the same car can get sold this way
over and over again and to prove that
let me take you on a magical journey
because a few years ago the LA Times
tracked the sales of one car from a
Kansas City buy here pay here deal it
was a 2003 Kia Optima much like this one
it had a Blue Book value of five
thousand three hundred and fifty dollars
but in April of 2008 it was sold for
nearly eleven thousand dollars or double
its Blue Book value the original buyer
complained of mechanical problems and
refused to make payments so the car was
repossessed and sold again in August
before being repossessed again four
months later and was then resold after
just three weeks before being
repossessed again from a mother of three
who without transportation lost her job
at Walmart it was then resold again in
May 2009 to an owner who complained of
transmission trouble so the dealer took
it back and resold it just four weeks
later after which it was you'll never
guess repossessed again from an owner
who later filed for bankruptcy thanks in
part to payments he owed on this
piece-of-shit demon car but wait we are
not done it was sold again that December
and was repossessed just five months
later before being resold in May and it
was then surprise surprise
repossessed again even though the owner
a mother of four claimed she made every
payment and then according to the LA
Times it was sold one last time before
being repossessed just one month later
that one car changed hands eight times
in three years each time at a price
double or even triple it's Blue Book
value at which point you almost feel bad
for the car which presumably needed two
sessions of therapy a week just to be
able to start it's crappy engine
now now back that is where the LA Times
left it but we felt so emotionally
involved we actually tracked that car
down and discovered that since then it
has been sold again repossessed again
and then sold yet again and when we
caught the last listed owner she said it
had been stolen and I really hope
whoever did that drove it straight off a
cliff although I am guessing even then
some sleazy lobster wound up selling it
to a poor unsuspecting fish now
now after see that you may be glad to
hear that buy here pay here lending has
lost market share in recent years
unfortunately that is only because it
seems everyone is getting into subprime
auto lending now there is a surprising
amount of competition to give car loans
to people with poor credit so much so
people who've recently declared
bankruptcy are being actively targeted
through the mail just listen to one
bankruptcy lawyer describe what he's
seen these are all car loan
solicitations high interest Cartland
solicitation sent to my bankrupt coins
people have already filed bankruptcy
here's one that looks like a cheque and
it's made out to $21,000 I guess it's
going to be a used car and with a
signature and everything sent to one of
my clients here's one that looks like
some kind of an official certificate
they encourage you to apply for car loan
even if you suffered bankruptcy car
repossession foreclosure or all the
above that is a slightly weird tone of
voice to use there he sounds almost
excited about a bankruptcy a car
repossession and a foreclosure
he's like the doctor saying wow you have
herpes HPV and gonorrhea most people
only get one
and and this feeding frenzy over
subprime customers now includes big
lenders like Santander and GM financial
they are both expanded their subprime
auto financing and there are newer
players like Scopus and Exeter who
specialize in subprime lending and you
might be wondering why the fuck is
everyone in such a hurry to lend money
to people with bad credit I mean sure in
the mortgage crisis they were doing that
so that they could bundle those high
interest loans together and sell them on
Wall Street but there's absolutely no
way that that is happening that is
happening again that is exactly what is
happening right now and people have
actually been worried about this for a
while now
is there a new bubble that's about to
burst in the auto sector does this
concern you at all though that it could
possibly become a repeat of the home
loan boom do you see similarities
between the housing crisis and what's
going on now with used car loans is
there concern now that there's going to
be another subprime crisis except it's
not going to be mortgages it's going to
be car loans yes there is concern that
this could be the subprime mortgage
crisis but with cars and normally if you
add the phrase but with cars to any
historical event it sounds a lot more
fun like the assassination of Abraham
Lincoln but with cars sadly this is the
exception to that rule now before you
panic experts say there are important
differences here subprime auto loans are
a much smaller part of the overall
economy than subprime mortgages were so
even if they do go bust this wouldn't
necessarily be the Big Short all over
again so much as the director video
version with Brad Garrett instead of
Brad Pitt and instead of Ryan Gosling an
actual Gosling names Ryan and Wall
Street firms insist that they have
learned their lesson and have set things
up in such a way that tons of loans can
default and investors will still be fine
but there are trouble signs for instance
standards for some of the loans being
sold as investments can be shockingly
lacs we've seen deals come to market
with very low FICO scores and in some
cases no credit scores at all yeah loans
which is amazing so some people joke you
know you really just need a pulse
right now to get a you know subprime
auto loan so that's a good joke so solid
setup hard punchline potentially
devastating effect on the American
economy top shelf comedy there it's the
rule of three is what it is and behind
closed doors some in the lending
industry openly acknowledge conditions
are deteriorating in fact when we sent
hidden cameras to a debt buyers
conference in Vegas a few months ago we
stumbled on Ken chilsen the head of the
National Alliance of buy here pay here
dealers he sees trouble brewing because
he thinks in attempting to keep pace
with the big players who've entered the
subprime industry his own dealers have
been forced to issue longer term loans
with less money down at higher cost to
clients who are therefore at greater
risk of default and these broader
lending trends are clearly terrible news
for borrowers but to hear him tell it
it's a great opportunity for those who
buy bad debts and collect on them these
people have negative equity all the way
through and they're not going to be able
to hold their life
you know the customer you know how to
collab you gotta be the last cookie
what's holding today wow that is both
inspirational and profoundly upsetting
it's like if the song I believe I can
fly merged with the rest of our Kelly's
life now listen listen the news the news
don't Google that listen the news the
news that used car dealers are predatory
is clearly not new but it seems these
days market pressures are forcing them
to be more aggressive and take more
risks to the point where we may be
getting cloaks to an industry that looks
like this how do you can't afford a car
no problem just come right on down today
to crazy Johnny
crazy Johnny but don't take it from me
take it from my cousin crazy Jame
crazy Johnny bring you got it ah I love
the smell of Beals in the morning I got
a question for the people at home do you
have bad credit we don't care
have you filed for bankruptcy we don't
care is your credit so bad that giving
you a high interest loan will basically
trap your own Mountains at which there's
no reasonable hope of this game we don't
give up we've got a beautiful offer for
you right now man this here is a free
free free free free free pre-owned 2003
Jimmy Jimmy you're gonna tell the people
when it comes to I will that comes fully
loaded with four tires coming to one
engine and beeping device which emits a
sound that will haunt your dream does it
come with anything else it does man if
you check the back seat this car has up
in baby in it
there is an actual baby in this car
right now I have serious personal
reservations about the situation this
time
what don't focus on that look this car
is worth $2,000 but will let you have it
for zero down and just two hundred a
month for the next seven years
spats nearly severed $1,000 $17,000 no
no don't don't do the actual math on
that you won't think of it I don't like
this act now and this Cole effect every
financial decision you make for the best
part of the next decade and that is a
crazy jolly profit crazy and the crazy
thing is this piece-of-shit car is
actually an opportunity for Wall Street
to but don't listen to me listen to our
accountant crazy Walter come on out here
well it's true if you set aside the
human misery this loner has the
potential to cause as part of an over
collateralized security this can be sold
as as a as a on time as a high-yield
investment but has disturbing echos of
the mortgage passing crazy
and he's so easy for us to get you in
this car why it is almost gripping it
truly feels like it should be a criminal
activity and yet somehow it isn't let's
receive that you so much for joining us