let us dive right in this week with the
2016 election or as it's increasingly
known America's fuck tastic circa to
dismay now the big news this week
surrounded Donald Trump a punch line
that is quickly becoming a nightmare
look like like if you said take my wife
please
and then she was actually kidnapped by
Isis this week revealed a somewhat
startling statistic a new report from
USA Today found Trump and his businesses
have been involved in at least 3,500
lawsuits over three decades 3,500
lawsuits that is unprecedented for a
presidential nominee in fact if each
lawsuit involving Trump were the basis
of an episode of law and order they
could sustain all 456 episodes of the
original or 389 episodes of Law &amp; Order
SVU or 195 episodes of Law &amp; Order
criminal intent and all 22 episodes of
Law &amp; Order LA as well as every episode
of the practice Ally McBeal la law
Boston Legal Night Court The Good Wife
Matlock jag Perry Mason Judging Amy the
Guardian the public defender Owen
Marshall counselor at law Harry's Law
Courthouse suits family law sweet
justice 1970 ones the DA 2004 sturdy a
reasonable doubts damages shark the
defenders the Paper Chase headcases Judd
for the defense and all three episodes
of NBC's first years and at that point
you're still missing one lawsuit but
you've also basically run out of
television shows about lawyers meaning
Trump's lawsuits exceed the limits of
the fucking genre well
lately there have been some new
developments with Trump related
litigation after he complained about a
judge presiding over two particular
cases against him I have a judge who is
a hater of Donald Trump a hater he's a
hater his name is Gonzalo Curiel
and he is not doing the right thing the
judge who happens to be we believe
Mexican which is great I think that's
fine oh are you doing
you think that's fine great news people
of Mexican descent Donald Trump thinks
it's fine for you to be a human being
existing on this planet now for the
record the judge in question was born in
Indiana but that's not the point because
as he later clarified it was the judge
his Mexican heritage that made him unfit
to judge Trump you're invoking his race
when talking about whether now he can do
his job I'm building a wall okay I'm
building a wall I'm trying to keep
business out of Mexico Mexico is fine
there's nothing but he's a messenger
he's a Mexican heritage and he's very
proud of it as I am where I come from
what worry where exactly are you from
I just you look what you came out of a
clogged drain at the wonka factory no
that's great I think that's fine but
think about think about what he's
implying it
the judge is unfit to do his job because
of his ethnic background and just this
morning Trump took it a step further
what if he was a Muslim though you've
had been very tough on temporary Muslim
immigration banned if were a Muslim
judge would you also feel like they
wouldn't be able to treat you fair well
fairly because of that policy of you
it's possible yes yeah that would be
possible absolutely I would say that was
the dictionary definition of bigotry
except after this campaign the
definition of bigotry might just become
C trump comma Donald's now as it happens
the judge he initially insulted is
overseen cases involving the
controversial Trump University and he
ordered a cache of documents to be
released this week which was very
exciting to us because we actually
looked into his University when we did
our big piece on Trump back in February
and it wound up on this very long list
of awful Donald Trump stories that we
literally didn't have time to delve into
even in a 22 minute piece but once we
started reading through these new
documents we figured oh fuck it let's
take some time to talk about it now
because Trump University is kind of
amazing back when it opened Trump made
some big claims at Trump University we
teach success that's what it's all about
success it's going to happen to you if
you don't learn from the people that
we're going to be putting forward and
these are all people they're handpicked
by me then you're just not going to make
it in terms of the world of success the
world of success it sounds like what
Donald Trump calls his bedroom welcome
to the world of success please enjoy a
mint and a nondisclosure agreement
unfortunately Trump University ran into
problems in several states starting with
the name itself we started looking at
Trump University and discovered that it
was a classic bait-and-switch scheme it
was a scam starting with the fact that
it was not a university
holy-shit Trump University wasn't even a
university which is enough to make you
wonder what the fuck was in Trump steaks
oh god it was possible it
it was possum you monsters but the name
was just the beginning because remember
how he had hand-picked instructors well
according to his own depositions he did
not personally select instructors for
live seminars and was unable to recall
the names of key faculty members and
it's probably good that he didn't
hand-picked them himself that would be
dangerous
anything Trump's tiny fingers touch turn
into an ex-wife or an abandoned casino
and and it doesn't stop there according
to the sworn testimony by several former
employees many instructors and mentors
had no experience buying or selling real
estate in fact one had worked as a
salesman for Lowe's and another had been
manager for Buffalo Wild Wings or as I
call it B dubs dubs even a former member
of Trump's own sales staff testified
that it was among other things a joke a
facade and was just selling false hopes
and lies and to be fair every University
has sold some of its students false
hopes and lies it's just most of the
time they call it a theater arts degree
these these new documents also included
several revealing play books of sales
tactics for instance the room
temperature was to be no more than 68
degrees which is partly to keep students
alert and partly because professor Wild
Wings doesn't want the ranch sauce
getting all gamey
there are also instructs on how to sell
and upsell students or as the play books
call them buyers on expensive courses
with typos riddled tips like if a client
is adamant about knowing a price simply
say our course range anywhere from
twenty nine dollars to thirty five
thousand dollars and if prospects seemed
at all where II there was advice for
dealing with that you must be very
aggressive one passage from the playbook
reads if they complain about the price
remind them that Trump is the best you
might laugh but that is the same
technique that Trump has been using to
run for president and apparently it
fucking works these play books are rife
with sleazy salesmanship
for instance employees were told to
substitute the words thank you with
congratulations so that the potential
customer ends up thanking you which is
pretty obnoxious if I started this show
every week with welcome to last week
tonight congratulations on joining us
you would quite rightly turn it off and
I know what you think you what what
about people who simply didn't have the
money
Trump you didn't really have a problem
with that a set of play books for the
sales team coach them on how to market
the courses even to single mothers with
three children who quote may need money
for food money instructed the playbook
is never a reason for not enrolling in
Trump University if they really believe
in you and your product they will find
the money you are not doing any favor by
letting someone use light
of money as an excuse lack of money is
not an excuse is not what single parents
need to hear it's what Donald Trump
needs to hear when a fifth company of
his inevitably Falls for chapter 11
bankruptcy and as you might expect some
of the customers on the other end of
that hard sell wound up feeling duped
like Carmen Mendez who put a $35,000
course on her credit cards and was left
disappointed I thought that I'm going to
be a millionaire because Donald Trump is
a millionaire and they were offering
their course for people to get bridge
this is the closest Mendez got to Trump
during the course a picture of her with
a picture of Donald Trump oh that's not
a one-off because another former student
said we were told that we would get to
have our pictures taken with Donald
Trump it ended up being a cardboard
cutout of mr. Trump which is actually a
perfect metaphor for Trump University
you're expecting the real thing but in
the end all you get is a tacky
two-dimensional facade with Donald
Trump's face slapped on it but perhaps
the most suspicious thing of all is that
the play books even include specific
instructions on what to do if an
attorney general shows up and believe it
or not the answer is not kick over a
table as a distraction and get the fuck
out of there no apparently you contact
April immediately and it also reminds
you you do not have to show them any
personal information unless they have a
warrant which is suspicious advice for a
university employee I'm pretty sure
Harvard doesn't tell its new professors
welcome here's a gun and a cyanide
capsule in case the first show up don't
let them take you alive
now daughter Zoltan has broadly denied
the claims in the lawsuits and his
attorneys have gathered statements from
satisfied customers in fact to hear
Trump tell it the school was very good
value 98 percent of the people that took
the courses we have report cards from
everybody they report carted on the
course ninety-eight percent of the
people that took the courses 98 percent
approve the courses they thought they
were terrific okay first there is
something instantly fishy about 98
percent the only things that have that
level of unanimous approval are
dictators Pixar movies and Neapolitan
ice cream yeah it's got chocolate for
the chocoholic
vanilla for the borings and strawberry
for the perverts in fact according to
plaintiffs the reason those numbers are
so high is because the surveys were not
anonymous and were filled out when
participants were still expecting to
receive future benefits from the program
such as assistance or mentoring from the
instructor they were evaluating so
listen to why one former student gave
you a good review that he now regrets I
really look at it like this is is say
you go to a really nice restaurant and a
really expensive restaurant you eat this
really gorgeous dinner and the chef
comes out near the end of your meal and
ask you how you like the meal and you
really really loved it but then you by
the time you go home you realize that
you've gotten food poisoning and you're
really really sick what do you think
about Trump University I felt like I've
been poisoned I just feel like I was
just duped and poisoned and ripped off
the only thing worse than that is having
that same feeling and then realizing oh
shit he's got three years 364 days left
in his first term but but perhaps the
most valuable lesson to come out of
Trump University is the one that it is
currently giving all of us in what's
behind Trump's campaign strategy because
the PlayBook tells his sales people you
don't sell product benefits or solutions
you sell feelings and that is what is
happening now crowds at a trump rally
may not be able to point to a concrete
benefit or solution he offers but they
know how he makes them feel and that is
jacked up and ready to
boo any name that sounds vaguely Latino
so if you are planning to vote for Trump
in November I'd like to direct you to a
quote from the top of Trump University's
old homepage take the risk but before
you do learn what you're getting
yourself into Donald I could not have
said it better myself
so thank you or should I say
congratulations