we are finally in an election year so
for our main story tonight let's look at
voting the cornerstone of American
democracy the unshakable principle that
everyone should have an equal vote even
idiots even this guy go now I know it's
painful but his vote should count as
much as yours it should count as much as
the presence that's what America is all
about
now in recent years some states have
made voting easier for instance three
states now hold their elections almost
entirely by mail and 30 states plus DC
now let you register to vote online
sadly others have gone in the opposite
direction
because depending on who you are and
where you live you may face new
obstacles to voting this November thanks
to among other things the Supreme
Court's decision to weaken the Voting
Rights Acts for instance since 2011
seven states have curtailed early voting
and 13 have added requirements the
voters show some kind of ID at the polls
and the lawmakers pushing those voter ID
laws claimed they are just simple
common-sense measures it is common sense
that you would use picture ID to protect
the integrity of the voting process it's
an ID
everyone has an ID the people that are
homeless the people that go to vote they
get sick they go to the hospital they
buy they buy stuff they need IDs I'm
proud that North Carolina has joined the
34 other states to enact a common-sense
voter ID law that that isn't going to
impact a significant amount of North
Carolinians oh it's not going to impact
a significant number of North
Carolinians well that's fine although by
that standard
you could also say we're going to
incinerate everyone named Warren that's
that's not a significant number of
people but you are going to have a
pretty justifiably upset Warren Beatty
on your hands
that lore is significant to him because
not everyone actually does have ID in
Texas alone at least half a million
registered voters do not have the form
of ID necessary to vote North Carolina
and Wisconsin have roughly three hundred
thousand voters a piece with neither a
driver's license nor a state ID and in
Virginia an estimated two hundred
thousand voters may not have one and if
you think about it
you probably know at least one person
who doesn't have an ID
whether it's your grandma who had her
license taken away you'll recluse uncle
who rollerblades everywhere or your
cousin who lost his license after his
third DUI come on Jace you can't fool a
breathalyzer by whispering the word
sober into it and even if you try to
obtain an ID just in order to vote it
can be difficult
let's thought a Pennsylvania woman went
through when her state's ID law was in
effect 68 year old Doris Clark was
turned down three times applying for her
Pennsylvania voter ID card and every
time she says the state wanted another
document original birth certificate
original Social Security card
then she needed her husband's death
certificate when a clerk demanded proof
of her married name you feel like why am
I going through all these things I'm not
Ben land wife bin Laden's wife that is a
strange way to frame it why not say
Osama bin Laden was a mullah al Siddarth
husband or see hamsa bars husband or
career Sabah's husband hashtag Osama bin
Laden hashtag feminism and yet and yet
none of these difficulties seem to
trouble legislators like Wisconsin's
Joel Kleefisch who argued for a strict
ID law by pointing out his state's photo
ID requirement to buy sudafed I find it
frustrating that so many of the same
people who today are telling us that a
photo ID is just - gosh darn much to
maintain the integrity of the ballot and
those same people two sessions ago
made sure those same people many of the
same people in this room made sure two
sessions ago that you had to have a
photo ID to buy stuffy nose medicine
okay okay a couple of things there first
that bill was designed to help curtail
Wisconsin's meth problem and and second
voting is a right if you take it away
you ruin democracy if you take away
someone's sudafed the only thing you'll
ruin is their sleeve and in some parts
of the country the offices that issue
IDs are hardly ever open in 2012 a study
found that in Wisconsin Alabama and
Mississippi fewer than half of all ID
issuing offices in the state to open
five days a week and in Sauk City
Wisconsin just a few districts over from
where that business casual Kevin Smith
lives the ID office is only open on the
fifth Wednesday of every month and only
four months in 2016
even have five Wednesday's oh but don't
worry
there's a rhyme March June August
November have five Wednesday's but
remember if you come on days not those
you sell theft King clothes every first
longer English guy
gets taught that there she's also
mentioned that studies have shown these
restrictions tend to disproportionately
impact african-american and Latino
voters in Texas for instance experts
found that african-american voters were
nearly twice as likely to lack voter ID
and Latinos were nearly two-and-a-half
times as likely it's just one of those
things that white people seem to be more
likely to have like a sunburn or an
Oscar nomination so so what why are we
doing this well if you listen to the
legislators who help pass these laws
they'll say that they are necessary to
prevent fraud here is a co-sponsor of
Texas's bonds are ideal or debbie riddle
the very freedom of our nation is based
on the integrity of our ballot box and
if things are so lacks that that
fraudulent voting can can occur that
means your vote can be stolen and simply
showing an identification it's not too
much to ask are you sure about that
though don't eat fish on the subway is
not too much to ask never start a
facebook status with that moment when is
not too much to ask requiring ID can
actually be asking a lot and as for
fraudulent elections well let's look at
that for a moment because while American
history is littered with vote buying
vote tampering and ballot box stuffing
voter ID doesn't prevent those crimes
the only crime it prevents is voter
impersonation one person showing up to
the polls pretending to be someone
they're not which is a pretty stupid
crime because you have to stand in line
at a polling place and risk five years
in prison and a ten thousand dollar fine
all to cast one probably not
consequential extra vote in terms of
pointless crimes it's right up there
with forging a Bed Bath and Beyond
coupons it's a lot of trouble with low
reward and yet people insist that this
happens a lot without photo ID what do
you fear could happen well without photo
ID I mean let's be clear I don't want
dead people voting in the state of South
Carolina I've said that from the very
beginning and it
already say there is evidence that dead
people voting is a real problem
according to a statewide investigation
by South Carolina's Department of Motor
Vehicles in January
it found that 953 ballots were cast by
voters who were deceased now that's true
the DMV
did say that and the study called such a
stir that one lawmaker stated we must
have certainty in South Carolina that
zombies aren't voting and look he's
right he's right no one wants that
except possibly for upstart candidate
Philip rose but but when the state law
enforcement division investigated the
DMV's claims it found no real basis for
them in fact of the prior elections 207
suspicious ballots 92 of them were cases
where someone had the same name as a
deceased boat so usually a father and
son 56 of them were cases where the
Social Security number of a living voter
was mistakenly matched with a dead
person
32 was simply scanner errors one person
requested an absentee ballots completed
it and then died while it was in the
mail and and most of the others were an
array of random clerical errors
altogether the investigation found five
ballots that could not be accounted for
this is an election where more than 1.3
million votes were cast these voter ID
laws are the biggest overreaction to a
manageable problem since Sleeping
Beauty's father ordered all the spinning
wheels in the lands to be burnt this is
the Quarian economy we need those wheels
why don't you just watch your daughter
for literally one day in her keep life
the truth here is voter impersonation
fraud is incredibly rare one researcher
who tracked it closely found that from
2000 to 2014 there were 31 possible
incidents in the entire country out of
over a billion ballots cast photo voter
fraud is a problem the way that deadly
knife play from crabs is a problem I'm
not saying it doesn't exist there are
cases where it has happened but let's
not overreact to one stabby crap look
but these laws do actually tend to make
a little more sense whenever you see
someone slip up and suggest other
reasons for why they may support them
voter ID which is gonna allow Governor
Romney to win the state of Pennsylvania
done do you think all the attention
drawn to voter ID affected last year's
elections uh
yeah I think a little bit I think we
probably had a better election think
about this week Kaido Bhama by five
percent which was big yeah a lot of
people are cited that he he won he beat
McCain by ten percent he beat Romney by
five percent I think that probably photo
ID had a helped a bit in that you know
you're saying the thing that everyone
knows but you're not supposed to say out
loud
that's like writing I'm desperate to
bone on an online dating profile or a
band calling their reunion tour we ran
out of money but but perhaps the most
galling thing here is that there there
are actual cases of voter impersonation
caught on camera and you will never
believe where they happen this is state
representative Debbie riddle she
authored the bill that would require
voters to show a photo ID clerk brain
develops a record vote it's all about
integrity record vote but the integrity
of one person one vote doesn't apply at
the legislature we found many lawmakers
vote more than once
take a look Riddle votes turns around
votes again for state Rep temple three
one and watch them out on the screen
Elkins goes to vote for merit but
Hancock is faster
Elkins heads back to his desk but before
he can vote Joe Crabb turns around and
beats him to it holy shit
literally competing to press other
people's voting buttons and remember
this is Texas which has the strictest ID
laws in the country and apparently this
process is called ghost voting and it
happens in state legislatures all over
the country and sometimes they involve
literal ghost votes one lawmaker in
Texas died and was a recorded voting
three times
later that day which is clearly
ridiculous a real ghost wouldn't waste
its time voting on bills
it will be out terrorizing a young
family in their new house or trying
desperately to bang Demi Moore on a
pottery wheel one last time and and
debbie riddle is not the only voter ID
proponent who has done this remember
Wisconsin's Joel Kleefisch
I mean there is there is no way that he
got caught doing it right a cell phone
video posted online shows clay fish
placing a vote for an absent
Assemblymember clay fish says the online
video is an attempt at character
assassination no no no that's not
character assassination it's unedited
footage of something you obviously did
if anything that is character
auto-erotic asphyxiation I normal
lawmakers in Tennessee are so shameless
about this they've got the whole thing
down to a fine art it's such a common
practice in the house in fact that many
lawmakers have sticks they use to reach
each other's voting buttons look
if you are going to pervert democracy
could you at least do it with a less
creepy stick that looks like what an
evil leprechaun would use to beat a
child and yet whenever legislators like
debbie riddle i asked about this actual
voter impersonation they say they've
done nothing wrong and only acting out
of necessity we have a lot of votes we
have a lot of amendments and there's
times when we don't break for lunch and
we don't write for dinner
we don't have bathroom breaks okay well
quick suggestion have you considered
getting some extra long voting sticks
they tend to help you know what at this
point I would like to propose something
any politician who has ever supported
and unnecessary voter ID law should be
forced to obtain a new ID every single
time they want to pass a bill just to
make sure they are who they say they are
and yes they might say well John that's
ridiculous there is no real reason to
make us do that and it's so cumbersome
it could prevent us from engaging in the
democratic process to which I would say
welcome to the King Club