Det
it's the reason Nicolas Cage has made so
many great choices in recent years and
presumably it's the fuel he uses to
power performances like this one from
his recent movie the trust holy shit he
delivered that line like a child on PCP
opening birthday presents which he
clearly hopes are full of more PCP now
American households collectively owe
over 12 trillion dollars in debt and
right now 436 billion of that debt is
seriously delinquent meaning it's 90 or
more days past jus and it is not good
when anything is that late if your baby
were three months overdue you'll
effectively just be giving birth to a
floppy toddler and look clearly if you
have debts you should pay them if you
can
but many people can find themselves in
debt for no direct fault of their own
take Bob Wine cough a few years ago he
was in intensive care over breathing
trouble and after four days of treatment
the hospital told his wife that their
insurance was not going to cover the
costs she said uh the bill is up to
eighty thousand dollars already and she
said mrs. wine cough I hope you realize
that you're responsible for this bill I
was just hysterical I thought what am I
gonna do I've worked my whole life is
this how my life is gonna end that's
terrible because some debts are
completely unavoidable this isn't
someone spending 80 thousand dollars on
this Versace coat that looks like a
banana to Rorschach test
look this is someone spending eighty
thousand dollars to breathe but the fact
that so many people have money trouble
is not really surprising what may
surprise you is the extent to which
seriously delinquent debts have now
given birth to an entire debt buying
industry when most consumers get a call
and say I'm calling your
Bank of America debt you assume that
it's someone a Bank of America but what
happens is Bank America's sold off that
debt for pennies on the dollar years ago
and it's been bought and sold and bought
and sold bought and sold most of the big
banks do it and not just banks but
payday loans book club membership gym
fees auto loans every year billions of
dollars of this debt is sold off cheap
it's true debt buying companies like
these that you've probably never heard
of have amassed a huge amount of
Americans debt in fact the largest
encore Capital Group which has these
subsidiaries tell investors that one in
five consumers either owes the money now
or has owed the money in the past which
is incredible because that means
statistically one member of Evanescence
owes or has old encore money and I think
we all know who that would be it would
be guitarist and backing vocalist Troy
McCall horn huh but as you will see
almost every step of how this industry
is allowed to operate is problematic and
let's start at the very beginning let's
say you have a thousand dollar credit
card debt that you can't pay at a
certain point your bank might write off
the full thousand dollars on its taxes
and then to make just a little extra
money sell it off to a debt buyer for a
tiny fraction of the cost maybe $50 and
that debt buyer can then come after you
for the full original amount and if it
can't collect potentially it can then we
sell that debt for a fraction of what it
paid to someone else who can still come
after you for the original amount or
sell it for a fraction of what it paid
and so on and so on and so on now you
might think the information changing
hands would include a lot of verifiable
information but you would be wrong it's
I think helpful I understand that when I
talk about debt that's being bought and
sold here we're really just talking
about an Excel spreadsheet the
spreadsheet will have debtors name
social security number address balance
date that the account was opened maybe
one or two other fields but that's
basically about it that's right the
information about your debt may be
solved in an Excel spreadsheet which is
troubling for two reasons first nothing
good happens in Excel
most of us go into a cold sweat if we
just open it by accident oh god oh no
please no let me go back in time and fix
this
oh and second in many states there is
little obligation on the part of the
debt seller to provide additional
documentation many leaked contracts have
explicitly stated the debts are being
sold as is and with all faults which are
we attempt to see in a major business
transaction they'd even be troubling in
the context of an OkCupid profile as is
with all thoughts sometimes I masturbate
to little mermaid hey hey it's the fish
half that does it for me now as for debt
buyers they aren't always scrupulous
about checking their information before
collecting which is why it is not
surprising to see incidents like this I
opened the door and a envelope was
thrown at me and the guy said you've
been served and left supposedly it was a
debt that I owed it was right under
$5,000 what it was with a company I
never had a card with it's humiliating
it's intimidating it it provokes a lot
of anxiety humiliating intimidating and
provokes anxiety but to be honest I've
had a similar experience but at least
afterwards I got to brag that I finally
lost my virginity it was it was it was
some years after that but it's not it's
not just it's not just being sued for a
debt you don't recognize buyers can end
up harassing you over debt that is part
passed the statute of limitations or
that you've discharged through
bankruptcy or that you've paid you may
have seen stories like this on local
news because it's got a fun name it is
called zombie debt that's debt that you
thought was dead but starts to take on a
whole new life much like a zombie buried
old debt coming back to life it's called
zombie debt we're not talking about the
kind of zombies that terrorize humans
each week on The Walking Dead old debt
thought to be settled and buried coming
out of the grave if not to eat your
brain then certainly to give you a
headache yep zombies off
but the comparison is actually quite apt
because just like on The Walking Dead
zombie debt comes back from the grave is
incredibly hard to deal with and seems
to disproportionately impact minorities
so so once once a company has bought
your debt whether the information is
accurate or not they are going to try to
collect on it and they can either do
that themselves or assign it to a
collection agency and while many
collectors work within the bounds of the
law some behave like this team give me
my money back
I want my money or I'll kill you I wake
up every neighbor in your entire you
won't be a man or your iPad or telephone
like a little bitty Mouse we're gonna
how your daughter Esther if you're in
here whoa whoa that is not just
horrifying it's stupid how are you gonna
put handcuffs on a dog
they don't have wrists the cuffs are
just gonna slip straight off their doggy
paws your plan is silly and some debt
collectors won't just stop at calling
you listen to an employee of an upstate
New York debt buyer explain one of his
tactics to a hidden camera one of the
things that I like to move in $1,000
which is pretty nasty though is that
I'll find out where somebody works and
then I'll find out who the owner their
company is you can find out their number
and call them at home I love that I call
the boss at home that's my favorite
thing to do that's your favorite thing
that is the weirdest favorite thing I've
ever heard and I am including whiskers
on kittens and ground paper packages
tied up with string that's a parcel bomb
she's describing a parcel bomb also
what's wrong with the rest of the kitten
you creep now tactics like the ones that
man described are illegal but debt
buyers have been caught operating in
flagrant disregard for the law just look
at william scott and associates
federal prosecutors allege in a criminal
trial that will start next month but
they lied to debtors telling them they
were part of a government task force set
up to investigate for
Lord and using this letterhead featuring
a clip art image of scales and the logo
of for some reason the State Department
and they even gave their employees
aliases like senior investigate or ace
Rogers and Joe Steele which sound like
the stage names of understudy
Chippendales sorry ace sorry Joe
everyone's here again tonight please put
your shirts on and leave and look the
debt buying industry will tell you that
all these abuses are outliers and that
most debt buyers work within the law but
one way they do that is that they sue
people a lot debt buyers are among the
heaviest individual users of our state
court systems in fact in some cities
like Newark st. Louis and Chicago and
this is true debt buyers have been found
to file more cases than any other type
of plaintiff and if you're wondering how
the lawyers representing debt buyers
possibly have time to review all those
cases they often don't when one New
Jersey collection firm was sued they
found that one attorney reviewed up to a
thousand cases a day reviewing one case
for just four seconds and look there are
definitely things that you can review in
under four seconds Lay's biscuits and
gravy flavored potato chips for instance
one two three awful there you go
or your mother's new boyfriend one
Mississippi two missing up my real dad
but for judging whether you have enough
information to sue someone should really
take a little longer than that and it
turns out there is a strategy behind
filing so many lawsuits these companies
Bank on consumers ignoring the lawsuits
which means they're automatically
responsible for the debt they're dealing
with ninety to ninety-five percent of
these lawsuits going unanswered it's
true they go unanswered meaning people
don't turn up to their court dates and
the debt buyers win by default and the
phrase by default makes any situation
sound less legitimate hi I want you to
meet Carson he's my boyfriend by default
oh hi Carson I have a lot of questions
then and if they win in many states they
then have the power to garnish your
wages directly and given all of this it
is hardly surprising that the debt
collection industry of which debt buyers
are a major part can claim a dubious
honor we receive more complaints about
this industry than any other and last
year alone consumers filed over two
hundred and eighty thousand complaints
with federal authorities related to debt
collection Wow there aren't even two
hundred and eighty thousand complaints
on the Yelp page for Hitler's bunker
although though I'd actually like to add
one more
why is there a Yelp page for this one
star one star for you now regulators and
prosecutors have taken some successful
actions against big players in the debt
industry and some states have tightened
their laws concerning debt buyers but
others like these have all loosened
regulation just look at Arkansas where
in 2013
representative John vines proposed HB
2028 which he claimed didn't do much at
all what it does is it defines the term
credit card which is apparently not been
defined throughout our many UCC
provisions so all this does is define
credit card and other terms that are
germane to credit card and credit card
usage 2028 now I know that sounds like
the
most boring man describing the world's
most boring bill boringly but that's not
all it did because that bill actually
defines the legal term creditor to
include debt buyers and established a
presumption of correctness of the
information in favor of the debt buyer
that is a very friendly deal for them or
anyone like a bank that would want to
sell to them and it's worth noting that
representative vines his wife works for
a bank and I'd say he should have
disclosed that but there was really no
need to because the legislature was too
busy creepily joking about it and it is
considered a pro consumer bill or
neither not neutral is up for the
banking what would it pull I don't I
don't know that it's going to have any
effect on the consumer it's more just
clarify the terms of usage
I think presently used in the industry
represented Williams if it's not good
for banking I suggest that
representative representative Ines not
go home tonight well I would suggest the
same way I want to make sure that he's
taking care of the bankers always Oh
always tell you what if I don't take
care of the bankers I'm gonna be taking
care of myself in the shower for the
rest of the week y'all know what I mean
five give me five I'll take another five
let's make it a twenty now by the way
that that bill passed the Arkansas House
eighty three to zero but perhaps what's
most concerning about all of this is
that in some states there is a
shockingly low barrier of entry into
this industry in these states you can
purchase debt with no license and in
these states you can collect on debt
with no license essentially that means
there are places in this country where
you need to fill out less paperwork to
start collecting money from people's
pockets than you do to collect fish from
a king lake now the debt buyers trade
group DBA international claims the
industry is working to regulate itself
in fact it's developed a code of ethics
it calls the gold standard of the
industry it actually has an annual
conference in Las Vegas which does make
sense as Vegas as we know is the gold
standard of shitty places
anyone can go to their conference though
I frankly wouldn't recommend it it's
pretty bleak and the reason I know that
is we sent people with a hidden camera
and the footage they brought back was
fascinating not fascinating like a good
book more fascinating like a rat
carrying a wedding ring across some
train tracks there's a story there and
it's a king sad one but right from the
start of the conference there was a
defensive tone one seminar was actually
titled debt buyers are the good guys how
to convince the court although their
argument for that seemed shaky at best
what we're doing unbeknownst the most of
the world is we're helping the economy
we're securing monies from sources that
wouldn't ordinarily have been paying
them we're helping people who are
struggling with that to try to
restructure that and get their lives
back in order oh yeah they're really
helping people get their ducks in a row
but only in the window of a Chinese
restaurant since then this good guy
conference also featured a free
shoeshine booth for a business promising
to liquidate your bankrupt and deceased
debt which is exactly what it sounds
like because their business includes
collecting on a debt after the debtor
passes away and that is the sleaziest
way of making money
imaginable other than a petting zoo
attendant charging 10 bucks extra to let
you get to second base with a goat and
whenever the Lord did come up speakers
could be surprisingly glib for instance
some debt buyers try to collect on out
of Statutes debt which is debt that has
grown so old you can no longer be sued
over it and that is something that some
states now require debt buyers notify
you about in letters that they sent but
watch the contempt with which one
speaker dismisses those warnings who's
gonna leave notice can these words
flatter the unsophisticated consumer I
don't know do you think you think we're
good is it really going to impact your
collection I'd be curious to know you
know but all those disclaimers you want
on the letter have the peasant really
negatively impacted collections and I
should only want your nobody on sedation
inside with it and I know it doesn't but
I had opposed these plaintiffs in these
lawsuits they only read a letter Oh Q
not no good guy business model has ever
been based on the logic of oh don't
worry about people's legal rights I'm
pretty sure half these unsophisticated
morons can't read right guys right am i
right though guys look it is pretty
clear by now debt buying is a grimy
business and badly needs more oversight
because as it stands any idiot can get
into it and I can prove that to you
because I'm an idiot and we started a
debt buying company and it was
disturbingly easy let me explain
back in April we spent $50 to
incorporate a debt acquisition company
online in Mississippi and incidentally
over the internet is the best way to
experience Mississippi we called it we
called it central asset recovery
professionals or cop after the
bottom-feeding fish I became chairman of
the board and Karp set up this very
bland website and dipped our toes into
the debt market and with little more to
go on than that website we were soon
offered a portfolio of nearly fifteen
million dollars of out of statute
medical debt from Texas and a cost of
less than half a cent on the dollar
which is less than 60 grand for that
amount carp would be sent to the
personal information including names
current addresses and Social Security
numbers of nearly nine thousand people
so we bought it which is absolutely
terrifying because it means if I wanted
to I could legally have carp take
possession of that list and have
employees start calling people turning
their lives upside down over medical
debts they no longer had to pay there
would be absolutely nothing wrong with
that except for the fact that absolutely
everything is wrong
with that and that is why we actually
decided to go another way
because we thought well instead of
collecting on the money
why not forgive it because on one hand
it's obviously the right thing to do but
much more importantly we'd be staging
the largest one-time giveaway in
television show history because as best
we can tell the most anyone has ever
given away on a TV show at one time to
date was this
[Applause]
yeah
that giveaway was worth nearly eight
million dollars but we bought nearly
twice that in medical debt so instead of
having the file center carp we had the
seller send it directly to a nonprofit
organization which specializes in
forgiving medical debt with no tax
consequences for the debtor and tonight
at my signal with the power vested in me
as chairman of the board of car they
will commence the debt forgiving process
so what do you say are you ready to make
television history clearly this is only
going to help the 9,000 people whose
medical debt we bought the larger issue
is we need much clearer rules and
tougher oversights to protect consumers
from potentially predatory companies
like the one that we set up but in the
meantime it seems the least we can do
with this debts that I cannot Qing
believe we are allowed to own is to give
it away so are you ready to do this you
are about to watch me give away 15
million dollars you Oprah
[Applause]
Oh time zone
you
[Applause]