[Music]
president obama a man so close to being
able to smoke again he can almost taste
those camels now his time in office is
almost done and while he's achieved a
great many things tonight we're gonna
look at one of his in arguable failures
i have ordered the prison at Guantanamo
Bay closed by early next year make no
mistake we will close Guantanamo prison
I still want to close Guantanamo as
president I have tried to close Gitmo I
will continue to push to close Gitmo
it's time to close Gitmo today the
department is submitting to Congress our
plan for finally closing the facility at
Guantanamo once and for all
yes Guantanamo Bay it's a bombers one
that got away which is a little odd
considering it a place where literally
no one can get away so why has the
president been unable to close Gitmo
well for a start most people don't want
him to according to a recent poll 52% of
Americans believe it should remain open
and there are others who believe we
should actually be using it more in my
opinion the only problem with Guantanamo
Bay is there are too many empty beds and
cells there right now we should be
sending more terrorists there for
further interrogation to keep this
country safe as far as I'm concerned
every last one of them can rot in hell
but as long as they don't do that and
they can rot in Guantanamo Bay now now
he's basically saying there let's use
Guantanamo Bay like hell's waiting room
and that is problematic for two reasons
first it's arguably unconstitutional and
second hell's waiting room is already
the slogan of Henry Kissinger's bedroom
that's a fact
that's just a fact and look I can see I
can see the reasons that Guantanamo is
appealing you get to keep potentially
dangerous people locked up and far away
but tonight I would like to argue that
there are even better reasons for
closing it forever
and let's just start with the practical
ones it's very expensive
Guantanamo cost four hundred and forty
five million dollars to run last year
which means we're currently spending
over seven million dollars per prisoner
per year but the costs obviously go way
beyond that
last year a UN Human Rights Council
conducted a review of the US and Gitmo
was some
thing of a feature Iceland recommends
the closure of the Guantanamo prison and
illegal detentions in Guantanamo Bay
immediately close the Guantanamo Bay
facility and do all its best in order to
close down the Guantanamo facilities
improve living conditions in prisoners
in particular in Guam or investigate
torture allegation extrajudicial
execution on other violations of human
rights committed in Guantanamo yeah you
were right that is Iran Sudan Libya and
others lecturing us about human rights
abuses which is yet a little
hypocritical maybe don't tell us to eat
healthy when you have a quinoa purrito
in your mouth but but it does seem like
this is one of the few things the entire
world agrees on it's basically
Guantanamo is fucked up and yeah you
know what Kevin can wait yep we can let
the man wait so how did we get here
well Guantanamo's origins are basically
a series of weird circumstances and ad
hoc decisions for start we don't own it
it's a rental in in 1903 we struck a
deal with Cuba to lease the land for a
naval base and ever since we have mailed
them a check every year for four
thousand and eighty five dollars in rent
although as Fidel Castro once told a
film crew they've just been accumulating
in his desk quiere decir que estas
chicas Dago y'know not americano so por
La Ventana Guantanamo for one Tanna just
think about that we've barely been
talking to Cuba we disagree with their
politics and yet every year we send them
checks for hilariously small amounts of
money
we're basically Cuba's grandparents and
this this unique arrangement means that
Guantanamo went on Mo's legally both
America and not America or as one White
House official once called it the legal
equivalent of outer space which is a bit
of an exaggeration to be honest some
laws do apply up in space there's the
law of physics for example and the law
of attraction yes of course you didn't
really think Neil and Buzz did not con
the moon right
oh they move they move to my friends
don't move
good deal with it deal with that and
this legal limbo has been useful to us
in the past
George HW Bush used want Animoto
involuntarily detained Haitian refugees
seeking asylum and Bill Clinton not only
continued that for a while he later used
it to hold Cuban refugees so the use of
Gitmo to store people was one of those
dicey legal workarounds in the 90s it
was right up there with Vanilla Ice's
explanation of why he didn't ripoff
queen it's not the same baseline like it
goes ding-ding-ding-ding
ding-ding-ding-ding
that's way there's those awesome
ding-ding-ding-ding-ding the baby that
makes sense you've got a rock-solid case
there vanilla no problem man now now
stashing those refugees at Gitmo
attracted significant criticism at the
time but when the war on terror began we
started doing the exact same thing with
terror suspects
even though right from the start Donald
Rumsfeld admitted it was far from the
perfect solution trouble every time
we've tried to use Guantanamo Bay in the
past told people for other reasons why
use it why is it the best place I kiley
characterized Montano MoBay Cuba as the
least worst place we could have selected
the least worst place that is a rousing
endorsement from the worst worst
Secretary of Defense of all time but but
there was an obvious problem with using
Guantanamo in the war on terror and
people were pointing it out at the time
how do you avoid the prospect of the US
military in fact being jailers for an
indeterminate period of time of people
who have not been charged what are you
what are you gonna do about it it is
certainly the the not the first choice
of the Department of Defense to be in
the business of detaining people for
long periods of time yeah it might not
have been his first choice but it was
inevitable could a war on terror isn't a
traditional war where there's an
exchange of prisoners
at the end we were never going to accept
a formal surrender from the president of
terror who I can only assume is Willem
Dafoe and and and now that brings us to
here here right now nearly a decade and
a half later and we're all so accustomed
to the very existence of Guantanamo that
news crews tore it like it's a million
dollar listing this is a typical cell in
camp five it meets all American
Correctional Association standards this
is about 95 square feet of living space
with about 80 feet of unencumbered space
one of the other amenities available to
the detainees is a library of books
magazines and videogames the book that
we have the most in different languages
would be the Harry Potter series inmates
are also given art classes the results
of which are on display he's making it
sound like the world's least Jewish
summer camp who's doing birth right next
year
nobody is although even the current
luxuries the prisoners get tend to carry
a chilling reminder of where they are
all prisoners use toiletries which
happen to have the brand names maximum
security oh come on a prison calling
it's deodorant maximum security is a
little on the nose if we like a Holiday
Inn Express calling it's complimentary
lotion tearful masturbation
look that hit home a little too close to
some of you and before you think that
those library books provided an escape
for the inmates just listen to shocker
Armour who was released last October
after being held without charge for
nearly 14 years he found one particular
book less an escape and more a reminder
of where he was you know they got they
got an island in Harry Potter he says as
become well there's no happiness they do
you know they just suck all your
feelings out of you and you don't you
don't have no feeling anymore and truly
that's how I felt all the time is this
is as becan this is not from this world
you know because that's what they tried
you know they want to make you feeling
this Wow that is the saddest allusion to
Harry Potter I have ever heard and I say
that as a man who is often described as
Harry Potter if he aged like a president
and that's the point here no amount of
sugarcoating can cover up the reality of
what we have done at Guantanamo Bay
because in the early years interrogation
techniques included physical beatings
short shackling where a prisoners arms
and legs are shackled together for long
periods and hours and sometimes days of
repeated loud music which is horrendous
although sometimes that last technique
backfired because that same Harry Potter
loving inmate grew up loving American
rock music and would annoy the guards by
singing along and just listen to him
describe the one song that gave him the
most consolation I mean I'm sure I'm
sure everybody would love him here
because I used to sing here a lot I used
to because the words I thought the words
are fits me the words makes me feel like
yeah it's me again which is a Whitesnake
it's here I go again
the god the worst goes here I go again
on my own going down the only Road I
never known like a drifter I was born to
walk alone because I know what it means
to walk alone in only street of dreams
and here I go again and it's true
because it's just dreams dreams that I
will be home when they dreams that I'll
be free dreams that contentment will be
closed you know you are miserable when
you are finding solace in a king
Whitesnake song that is a group whose
second most inspirational lyrics are
probably I know you ain't a bad girl
honey no matter what the neighbors say
it's just you wear those skin tight
dresses with your g-string tunes to a
pure poetry purest poetry but we justify
Gitmo and everything we did inside it
because we were constantly reminded of
one thing these are not mere innocence
these are among the worst of the worst
they are bad guys these are the worst of
the worst these are the people who are
the bomb makers the bodyguards of Asama
bin Laden the financers the the plotters
the people who have been sent out to be
assassins to be a suicide bombers these
are the worst of the worst now the worst
of the worst is a big claim I can think
of at least one person who fits that
category and who is not in there and
that's because apparently he stills
working for the Today Show but who knows
but but what but while some detainees
some detainees like Khalid Sheikh
Mohammed have clearly earned that title
others have not because think about it
if they were really all so terrible it's
a little shocking that we've released
seven hundred and ten detainees over the
years and leaked documents have since
revealed that out of 212 Afghans who
were there almost half were in the
assessments of US forces either entirely
innocent mere Taliban conscripts or had
been transferred to Guantanamo with no
reason for doing so on file and some of
the evidence against detainees was
surprisingly flimsy one I guess piece of
evidence that they would use to
determine I thought this was fascinating
Casio watches well
it's kind of a little bit arbitrary but
anybody who was wearing this particular
brand of Casio watch which was handed
out by al-qaeda to their fighters
because it was used as a timer for
setting off devices so anybody who
happened to have this very popular watch
on was immediately picked up and a lot
of them ended up in Guantanamo Bay
that's true if someone was caught
wearing this Casio watch that could be
used as crucial evidence and
incidentally that makes this the only
time in history anyone has actively
sought out a man wearing a Casio watch
ah look this is not to say that everyone
in Guantanamo is or was innocent and
there is justifiable concern that
whenever we release someone they might
go on to fight against us in fact the
government claims that nearly 6% of
those released under President Obama
have been confirmed to have reengaged in
insurgent or terrorist activities and
for those released by the Bush
administration it's been 21% and while
some argue those numbers are inflated
even if they are they are not zero and
that is why politicians like Dick Cheney
have taken a hard-line position that we
should not let anyone go I'm more
concerned with bad guys who got out and
released than I am with a few that in
fact were innocent you're okay with that
margin for I have no problem as long as
we achieve our objective yeah but that
is not reassuring the only objectives
Dick Cheney has ever achieved have been
somehow serving as president
unofficially and managing to exist
without the need for a working heart so
so there are clearly sharp divisions
about what we should do with the
remaining population and you should know
there's actually not that many left
there are currently just 61 detainees
down there that's less than the number
of people in our audience right now some
of whom are arguably worse people than
some of the detainees at you know they
note they
they know it and it's an odd thing to
clap and and you might think well why
doesn't the president just put them on
trial figure out which ones are guilty
and then he can decide whether or not to
close it well it's just not that simple
because the 61 detainees fall into three
groups ten of them including Khalid
Sheikh Mohammed are having their cases
handled by a military commission that is
a legal process that we've basically
invented from scratch and it's so flawed
that of its eight convictions so far
four have been fully reversed on appeal
now another 20 of them are actually
slated for release but are waiting for
the State Department the intelligence
agencies and the Department of Defense
to agree on a country to send them to
and that leaves us with the trickiest
group the remaining 31 detainees who
have not been charged with a crime but
who are also not cleared to be released
and they are the real problem here
because even the president doesn't quite
know what to do with them there's gonna
be a certain irreducible number that are
gonna be really hard cases because you
know we know they've done something
wrong and they are still dangerous but
it's difficult to mount the evidence in
a traditional article 3 court more so
we're gonna have to wrestle with it now
think about what he just said that is
the president a man who has taught
constitutional law suggesting that for
some detainees there is no clear path
toward a trial or an exit now it's a
group that the administration is called
the irreducible minimum which sounds
like the name of a band that was going
to call itself absolute zero but got
into a fight about it with their
pretentious theremin player and if
you're wondering why the president says
it's difficult to announce the evidence
what he means there is in some cases
there's not enough of it and in others
it was obtained through torture and
there is a good reason that that is
inadmissible because people often say
anything to make torture stop if you
gave me a purple nurple for just 10
seconds I would look you in the eye and
swear that my favorite cereal is grape
nuts and and I'm fairly sure that that
cereals original name was good-morning
idiot to eat some cat litter
so the point is how does the president
who has spent nearly a decade promising
to close Gitmo plan to do that well it
turns out it all depends on what your
definition of the word close is closing
Guantanamo at this stage in the Obama
administration view is really moving
Guantanamo to US soil
the idea is to pick up the last
detainees and move them to military
detention in the United States what we
call wanton mo North yes Guantanamo
North or as I'm sure it will be called
once they build a wholefoods their Gitmo
no and and look moving Guantanamo is not
closing it but even that is not going to
happen there's been relentless
congressional opposition to moving any
detainees to US soil and the people in
charge of Gitmo seem to be settling in
for the long haul and the reason we know
that is because a legal document from
last month showed the commander the
current commander there proposes
renovating their infirmary as it will be
beneficial to the continued care of the
aging population so there might well be
detainees that we scooped up as young
men who we think are guilty but who will
never get a trial and they will be there
until they die and at this point we all
have to ask ourselves are we ok with
that
and remember it does seem that more than
half of us are but I would argue that
any potential risk in putting detainees
on trial losing that case and having to
release them is worth it for a few
important reasons first as it stands we
are ceding so much moral high-ground
that Vladimir Putin feels comfortable
saying things like this what then you
heard him say once said that they would
close Guantanamo and what is it closed
no today there's still people there
walking in shackles that is just
medieval without a trial these people
stay in prison well just imagine it's
incredible can you imagine if we did
that here I can't wrap my head around it
if I am befuddled by their behavior
luckily here in Russia the people I do
not like just disappear for reasons
nobody will ever know and nobody needs
to worry about but won't animal it blows
my mind what might make a while
supporters of Guantanamo argue that
closing it would be a sign of weakness I
would argue it's an act of strength just
listen to Lawrence Wilkins wilkinson :
Powell's former chief of staff what do
we do with them do we leave them there
forever as an American citizen who is
not a coward I'd be willing to release
every one of them tomorrow morning
and face them on the battlefield again
if necessary but we got a lot of cowards
in this country these days exactly when
you see a bumper sticker that says
freedom isn't free this is what that
means standing up for our highest ideals
even when it requires accepting a
certain amount of risk and when that
bumper sticker was displayed above a
pair of red white and blue truck nuts
it's a good reminder that doing
something like that takes balls and and
there is actually one final thing to
consider here the concept of Guantanamo
represents an opportunity to operate
outside the boundaries of the law and
that is way too tempting a proposition
to have at the government's disposal
because while you might be someone who
trusts President Obama's judgment
remember he's on his way out now meaning
that the keys to Azkaban will be handed
over to whoever succeeds him and there
is still a possibility it's going to be
this guy we're going to keep as you know
Gitmo we're keeping that open and we're
gonna load it up with bad dudes we're
gonna load it up with a lot of bad dudes
out there that's the point if we don't
shut it down future President Trump
could theoretically throw anyone he
doesn't like into Guantanamo and you
might say well come on he'd have to come
up with some pretext and it couldn't be
an American citizen but I would like to
put it to you that I've been shit
talking this guy for the better part of
a year and I own a pink a/c
we need to shut this shit down now
[Applause]
you