presidential primaries and caucuses the
electoral foreplay that we've been
engaging in since February which will
culminate in the mass balloon
ejaculations of this summer's
conventions both parties nearly have
their nominee and it looks like America
will be choosing between Donald Trump
America's walking talking brush fire and
in all likelihood Hillary Clinton the
woman who exhibits either too much or
too little of every human quality
depending on who you ask which is not to
say that the Democrats primary process
is over as we saw in Nevada last weekend
it is very much still raging this is
ridiculous this whole process has been
screwed up emotions ran high at the
Democratic state convention in Las Vegas
after Hillary Clinton took more delicate
ones and Bernie Sanders Saturday
holy shit usually when a crowd is that
angry in Vegas it's because they just
realize there are no elephants in Cirque
de Soleil just a bunch of terrifying
nightmare perverts but but it is not
just Nevada that is caused frustration
over how delegates are assigned
throughout this process thanks to an odd
quirk in the democrat system there have
been news reports like this we're
putting up right now a graphic Bernie
Sanders wins 56 to 44 percent in Wyoming
the delegates rewarded Hillary Clinton
11 Bernie Sanders 7 why does the
Democratic Party even have voting booths
know why this system is so rigged oh
please we have voting booths for the
same reason that Friendly's has
Restaurant booths so that we can have
relative privacy while we choose from a
deeply unappetizing menu and it is not
just the Democrats when Donald Trump won
Louisiana beating Ted Cruz by more than
3%
he was upset to discover the Cruz could
potentially get as many as 10 more
delegates or as he put it I end up
winning Louisiana and then when
everything is done I find out I get less
delegates than this guy that got his ass
kicked ok give me a break the thing is I
get why he's annoyed and there is no
clear a piece of evidence that our
system is broken
no more thoroughly dead canary in the
coalmine than when Donald Trump is
actually making sense because when you
see results like that the process does
feel counterintuitive so so tonight we
thought we'd ask why do the parties
operate this way because for many years
they didn't until 50 years ago most
states didn't even have primaries and
candidates were chosen by party insiders
at the convention but in 1968 that
system broke down when the Democratic
Party leadership picked Hubert Humphrey
despite the fact he hadn't even competed
in a primary Democrats were pissed off
and the convention was chaos a lot of
pushing the man being pushed watch it
they're going to knock that over
man is a delegate they're asking for
silence there's a priest in here dozens
of reporters and the man who got
involved in it all it's very calmly
smoking a cigarette oh oh he's not just
smoking any cigarette he's smoking a
Chesterfield Chesterfield once you've
turned democracy into a riot
you deserve a Chesterfield now in the
years that followed that mess both
parties reformed their processes to give
their rank-and-file members more of a
say but many of the details were left up
to state leaders which might help
explain why we have such an erratic
clusterfuck every four years almost
every part of this process is difficult
to defend for instance while most states
hold primaries in all of these states
one or both parties hold caucuses which
as I'm sure you know is a process
whereby you typically have to turn up to
a certain place at a certain time like a
school gymnasium at 7:00 p.m.
attend a party meeting that can take
hours and then vote which can be
prohibited because if you work at night
we can't get a babysitter or you don't
have transportation you can be frozen
out and that is probably why while
Republican primary turnout in 2012 with
19 percent their turnout for caucuses
averaged just three percent which is
terrible if you have three percent
turnout at an orgy it's basically just
you masturbating next to a table full of
uneaten snacks so generally generally
you are lucky if you live in a state
that has a primary unless you're a
Democrat in Washington state where
things get a little more complicated in
Washington State we have both caucuses
and presidential primaries will you
actually cast a ballot in private but
Democrats have never liked the primary
and they've ignored it from day one it's
true the Democrats presidential primary
in Washington doesn't count they have
won and it's this Tuesday but all the
pledged delegates were decided in their
caucus months ago so you know you're
awful friend who says he doesn't vote
because he doesn't feel like his vote
counts if he's a Washington Democrat
participating in the primary he's right
he's still awful but he is right and
then there's the problem of how the
delegates get divided up which is key
because remember you're not directly
voting for a candidate you're voting to
help determine the delegates who will
attend the National Party convention and
vote for a candidate on your behalf and
some states have even more steps in
between just look at what led up to last
weekend's events in Nevada they had a
caucus back in February which Hillary
Clinton won but that caucus only
determined 23 out of their 35 regular
delegates as for the remaining 12 those
were decided by delegates at the state
convention who were chosen by the
delegates at County conventions in April
who were chosen in those February court
visit caucuses which remember Hillary
won now unfortunately for her at those
County conventions more Bernie
supporters showed up so they had an
advantage going into the state
convention although by that time Hillary
supporters had realized what was
happening and have managed to mobilize
their turnout putting numbers in that
room basically even at which point both
sides began fighting to disqualify one
another's delegates over technicalities
such as failing to register as Democrats
by May the first a deadline set after it
had already passed at the convention by
the credentials committee and at this
point whoever you support you probably
feel like this exactly I just don't know
if there's a better servation
of this entire primary process so far
than that sound now for the record
PolitiFact looked into the charges of
rigging in Nevada and found no clear
evidence the state party hijacked the
process and you can disagree with that
as I am sure Bernie supporters will in
the comments section below this video
alongside hurtful remarks about my
personal appearance like oh look it's
British Milhouse or he looks like
someone who says my parents are my best
friends but who's also an orphan or did
someone just Benjamin Button Henry
Kissinger all of which statements
PolitiFact also rates as true but but
the larger point felissa fact made
regarding Nevada though I think everyone
can agree with is the arcane party
structures don't reflect how most people
assume presidential selection works and
that in itself is a huge problem any
competition should have clear rules you
don't get to the end of a football game
and say okay who founds the most eggs
wait what
that's what we were supposed to be doing
why didn't someone tell me that at the
start I only have five eggs and look
this this patchwork of convoluted
systems would be annoying enough but
each party also has its own way of
potentially putting its thumb on the
scale for Democrats its super-delegates
about 15% of the total delegates to this
summer's Democratic convention are
unpledged these are elected officials
former presidents and assorted party
bigwigs called super-delegates they can
vote for whichever candidate they want
regardless of who won in their state or
district okay so the delegates are super
in the way the kids on my super sweet 16
are super they are party obsessed widely
resented and untethered from all
responsibility now the theory behind
super-delegates was that the party
leaders could step in if they didn't
like the way things were heading which
is what makes it so weird that whenever
debbie Wasserman Schultz the chair of
the DNC is asked about them she insists
that super-delegates would never do that
look we have party activists elected
officials and other leaders that are a
part of our process but who have never
determined the outcome of our nominee
yeah but if they're not going to make a
difference then why take the risk of
having them at all
you're basically keeping rat poison in a
jar next to the sugar saying hey it
hasn't been a problem yet
that might technically be true but is
this really the best system you can
think of meanwhile Republicans have
their own way of diluting the power of
primary votes in many states delegates
are only required to reflect their
state's choice in the first round of
convention voting after that they become
unbound delegates and can vote for
whomever they want and Pennsylvania
takes this even further out of their 71
delegates 54 are completely unbound even
on the first ballot
and while these delegates are elected by
voters those voters may not know what
they're actually voting for if you're a
GOP voters you well know which candidate
you are choosing when you step into the
voting booth but when it comes to
choosing delegates to the presidential
convention there's no way for you to
know which ones support which candidates
because it's simply not listed like your
vote but who are you voting for you have
no idea ah makes no sense
listen if don't see with the Stars
had a system where instead of voting
directly for Paige Vanzant or ginger Zee
you had to vote for Doug or Karen to
vote on your behalf
neither of whom will tell you which
dancer they prefer there will be riots
in the streets and it gets one step
crazier because this year North Dakota
Republicans just said fuck it and had
neither a caucus nor a primary the party
just chose 28 Delegates themselves and
and in explaining why primaries aren't
that important one of those delegates
kind of gave the whole game away in
previous years we've used primaries to
probably get us some kind of an
indication of the preference of the
population but the delegates at the
convention choose a nominee not the
voters in the primaries so basically
he's treating the more than 27 million
people who voted so far in the
Republican primaries like a parent
treats a kid with a toy lawnmower oh
great job Billy you did it all your own
now step aside daddy's coming through
and look to be fair to both parties
they're basically private clubs they can
set their own rules in theory they could
give the nomination to whichever
candidate comes first alphabetically or
whichever one can squeeze a frog the
hardest without crushing it but if you
play by a system of complex opaque rules
that almost nobody understands and that
you could use your advantage even if you
don't you are going to alienate voters
this is a system which clearly needs
wholesale reform the problem is once the
system produces a winner the
conversation tends to just move on and
if you need any more proof of that just
listen to Trump earlier this month
you've been hearing me say it's a rigged
system but now I don't say it anymore
because I want okay strong you know now
I don't care I don't care okay it's
quick nobody wants to change the weird
rules if they win you think the
producers of the Martian are complaining
about the rules by which the Golden
Globes actually gave them Best Motion
Picture comedy or musical no of course
not they're just busy writing another
movie as side-splitting Lee hilarious as
Matt Damon potato farming in space for
two hours it would clearly behoove both
parties to take a long hard look at this
because they actually got lucky this
time
whether you like these two candidates or
not it does seem the party nominees will
coincidentally be the people with the
most votes Trump currently has a lead of
nearly four million over his closest
competitor and Hillary leads Sanders by
over three million and Sanders
supporters might argue that doesn't
include all caucus votes but when the
Washington Post estimated the rest they
found that she would still lead by two
point nine million votes and even if you
multiply all those estimated caucus
votes by seven to account for lower
turnout even if you give Bernie a bonus
of 10,000 extra votes in every state
that's voted so far and even if you tack
on an extra hundred thousand votes just
for shits and giggles she's still
comfortably ahead and I know Bernie
supporters I can hear you typing right
now
I can hear you typing that I look like
an angry toucan funded by ciliary but
that doesn't make that any less true but
the problem is there is no gap there's
no guarantee that the candidate with the
most votes will win next time and if
they don't all the floors we just
documented will be exposed yet again
because unfortunately we only get angry
about the primary process during the
primary process when it's impacting the
candidate that we care about but the
middle of the game is the worst possible
time to change the rules so if everyone
is as angry as they say they are right
now let's together
pick a date early next year to actually
write an email to the chair of each
party and remind them politely to fix
this I proposed February 2nd now that
will be easy to remember because it's
Groundhog Day which does seem
appropriate because unless this primary
process is fixed we are all destined to
live through the same nightmare scenario
over and over again until the end of
King time
you