the 2016 election or as it's commonly
known a horrifying glimpse at Satan's
Pinterest boards 2016 this week was the
Democratic National Convention and after
the bizarre Republican circus that
preceded it all they really had to do
was not appear like a complete disaster
and yet somehow
good evening their party's chairman off
the program an apparent Russian email
hack and now a revolt among Bernie
Sanders supporters welcome to day one of
the Democratic National Convention that
was day one day one
the DNC got off to the roughest start
that I've seen since Fox fives 2011
coverage of the San Diego Boat Show good
morning everybody I'm hanging out with
my friend John Fox 5 Morning News starts
look over there and it starts right now
that is basically what happened on day 1
of the DNC in a nutshell because because
before debbie Wasserman Schultz could
even gavel in the convention a leaked
email scandal had forced her to resign
and Bernie Sanders supporters gave her a
rough reception when she met with her
own States delegation oh I'm sorry
disruptive borderline unhinged and
getting ready to cop a vote that is
literally the only Florida that we know
that the only way that could be anymore
Florida is if one of the Bernie
delegates was an aging heavily armed
racist alligator now luckily for the
Democrats things gradually got back on
track thanks to a series of stirring
speeches beginning with the first lady
today
I wake up every morning in a house that
was built by slaves
and and I've watched my daughter's two
beautiful intelligent black young women
playing with their dogs on the White
House lawn now whatever your party
affiliation that is a truly moving
speech the only thing I would say to the
audience is maybe don't start your round
of applause directly following the
phrase built by slaves oh yeah they did
a lovely job they had to they had to do
a good job they they had to that's why
lovely now the next day it was Bill
Clinton's turn to fire up the crowd
retelling his relationship with Hillary
seemingly in real-time
and then Wednesday on Wednesday Joe
Biden spoke assuming the role of
America's motivational cattle-prod
we are America second to none and we own
the finish line don't forget it god
bless you all
may God protect our troops come on
come on girl once he has left the White
House Biden is going to be the most
inspiring soul cycle instructor ever
come on pedal you own the finish line
Kaitlin come on people like the wind
Biden was actually the warm-up man for
the president who like many speakers
throughout the week occasionally lapsed
into a tone of actual disbelief at what
America might be considering doing this
election people outside of the United
States do not understand what's going on
in this election
they really don't that's actually true
the rest of the world does not
understand Trump's candidacy any more
than they understand the menu at Guy
Fieri's American kitchen is this a
donkey saucer is it made from actual
donkey why do you do this to yourself
Wow Wow but the emotional highlight of
the convention was undoubtedly a speech
by Kaiser Khan a lawyer immigrant and
father of a fallen Muslim American
soldier Donald Trump you're asking
Americans to trust you with their future
let me ask you have you even read the
United States Constitution
I will
I will gladly lend you
oh shit that is an American founding
document being inspirationally used as a
middle finger I did not know that was
technically possible and here's the
thing it wasn't even the most
devastating part of mr. Karnes speech
have you ever been to Arlington Cemetery
go look at the graves of brave Patriots
who died defending United States of
America you will see all faiths genders
and ethnicities you have sacrificed
nothing and no one
Wow that engendered in me a level of
emotion that I did not think was
possible after 16 months of this
depressing campaign and 39 years on
earth as a British person and yet the
true theories however incredible the
surrogate speeches are conventions are
really judged by the performances of the
two people on the party's ticket so how
did they fare well let's start with Tim
Kaine a human sweater vest he's he's
basically the portrait of a vice
president that came with the frame his
speech his speech is exactly as boring
as you would expect with the exception
of his almost impressively bad Trump
impression it's gonna be great believe
me
we're going to build a wall and make
Mexico pay for it believe me we're going
to destroy Isis so fast believe me what
the fuck was that that doesn't sound
like him at all how is this man going to
win an election if he couldn't even win
a game of cranium I don't know is it
Jackie Gleason Brad Garrett kicked him
just mold whoever it is out of clay we
have no chance here and as for Hillary
Clinton on the night of her historic
nomination she stood before the nation
in full pitbull cosplay had she had a
genuinely stupid amount of balloons
dropped on her head and in between
delivered a speech focusing on the
actual job requirements of being
president I sweat the details of policy
whether we're talking about
the exact level of lead in the drinking
water in Flint Michigan the number of
mental health facilities in Iowa or the
cost of your prescription drugs
because it's not just a detail if it's
your kid if it's your family it's a big
deal
it was kind of interesting approach
instead of soaring rhetoric the bulk of
her speech was basically I'm gonna
micromanage the shit out of this office
I'm gonna get granular as fuck now drop
the balloons and I will count them all
I'm all about the details it was
definitely a restrained speech to close
a convention especially when you compare
it to the week before when Donald Trump
essentially opened his mouth and exhaled
a swarm of locusts but but now that both
conventions are behind us maybe we
should try and take stock of what they
have taught us about the current state
of our two political parties the DNC
showed the Democrats to be a coalition
of constantly squabbling if
fundamentally like-minded Katy Perry
fans and as for the RNC it showed that
the Republican Party doesn't seem to
currently exist because to all intents
and purposes we didn't really get a
Republican convention this year make
sure there was a Cleveland based
gathering of delegates featuring all of
Donald Trump's favorite family members
and Tiffani and celebrities whose most
notable upcoming projects include the
Emmy Awards in memoriam reel probably
but but almost everything that you would
expect from a GOP convention was absent
many prominent Republicans chose to skip
it as did both living Republican former
presidents and for the party of Reagan
the tongue was unusually and
relentlessly negative not only have our
citizens endured domestic disaster but
they've lived through one international
humiliation after another one after
another what is he even talking about
only one major international humiliation
from recent history comes to mind and
it's the ones standing behind that
podium and this left this letter
Democrats wide open to pick up the
mantle of people who actually like
living here don't let anyone ever tell
you that this country isn't great that
somehow we need to make it great again
because this right now is the greatest
country on Earth
yes the greatest country on Earth you
hear that Denmark
you got yourself yeah I don't care what
the world's happiness index s Michelle
Obama told me that we're number one and
her arms make me feel safe
so unusually the DNC felt like the more
patriotic occasion it featured America's
greatest actress dressed up like a
plastic tablecloth from the fourth of
July and General John Allen's screaming
at people to our enemies we will pursue
you as only America can you will fear us
and to Isis and others we will defeat
you
who who are you shouting at Isis is not
watching the DNC they're watching
Braxton Family Values
it's Thursday fool but but that is think
about it that is a retired four-star
Marine general threatening vaguely
defined enemies while a crowd wave signs
reading USA that is not something you
expect to see and a Democratic
convention not because Democrats aren't
patriotic but because Republicans have
always done that louder and longer this
whole two weeks felt topsy-turvy it's
frankly no wonder that commentators felt
a little confused if you were a Martian
and you came down and looked at these
two conventions and somebody asked you
which of the two parties is the most
overtly patriotic yeah you would say the
Democratic Party okay but if you're a
Martian who landed on Earth and someone
asked you which party seemed more
patriotic you would probably say wait
that's your question
I'm literally an alien is that nothing
else you want to ask me how was your
trip for example or what was tilda
swinton like as a kid
usually I runs like usually people's
first question for me is why is your
penis made of pure glowing white light
but the reason the Republican Party
essentially forgot to celebrate America
this year might be because they were too
busy celebrating Donald Trump's claims
that he would fix whatever Donald Trump
thinks is wrong with America nobody
knows the system better than me
which is why I alone can fix it when I
take the oath of office next year I will
restore law and order to our country I
am your voice now now I am your voice is
actually a fair claim he does speak for
some people although he would kind of
hope that they would then react the way
most people do when they hear their own
voice which is to say oh shit I don't
actually sound like that do I
that is King a horrified the RNC taught
us that a party which used to be
organized around a set of shared
principles is currently organized around
one man and given that that is the case
his judgment is pretty much the only
thing that is important when considering
who to vote for in November so to that
end I would like to show you something
he said recently and before I do he has
clearly said countless awful things
throughout this campaign any of which
would disqualify any other candidate
just this week he declined yet again to
release his tax returns lies about
getting a letter from the NFL agreeing
with him that the debate shouldn't clash
with football games called Angela Merkel
and moron implied that Brazil brought
the Zika virus on themselves and
encouraged a foreign powers hack of his
political rival now two of those didn't
happen but you're not sure which two and
that's kind of the point isn't it
because Trump hasn't said one crazy
thing he said thousands of crazy things
each of which blunts the effect of the
others it's the bed of nails principle
if you step on one nail it hurts you if
you step on a thousand nails no single
one stands out and you're fine that is
how Donald Trump has managed to say
pretty much anything in this campaign
seemingly without consequences and yet
even with that caveat his response when
asked about that speech from Kizza Khan
stands out I saw him he was you know
very emotional and probably looked like
a nice guy to me his wife
if you look at his wife she was standing
there she had nothing to say she
probably maybe she wasn't allowed to
have anything to say you tell me but
plenty of people have written that she
she was extremely quiet and it looked
like she had nothing to say okay for a
start his wife has explained that she
chose not to speak because she gets too
upset when she sees images of her dead
son's face you King asshole but I'm
sorry I'm sorry
please continue he said you have
sacrificed nothing and no one
well that sounds who wrote that did
Hilary's script Grider's write it how
would you answer that father what
sacrifice have you made of your country
I think I made a lot of sacrifices I
work very very hard I've created
thousands and thousands of jobs tens of
thousands of jobs built great structures
I've done I've had I've had tremendous
success I think those are sacrifices oh
sure I think they're sacrifices no no
they are absolutely not
they are self-serving half-truths from a
self-serving half man who has somehow
convinced half the country that
sacrifice is the same thing as success
honestly the main takeaway from these
two weeks is that incredibly we may be
on the brink of electing such a damaged
sociopathic narcissist that the simple
presidential duty of comforting the
families of fallen soldiers may actually
be beyond his capabilities and I
genuinely did not think that that was a
part of the job that someone could be
bad at and now this and finally this
week some more highlights from the
Democratic National Convention
to hell with Trump's American Nightmare
we believe in the American dream
the right-wing has thrown everything at
Hillary not only the kitchen sink
not only the stove but the refrigerator
and the toaster stood by for the macro
issues and those macaroni and cheese
issues
put down your pokemons go for just a
second we're naming Donald Trump to our
Dirty Dozen list dirty dangerous denying
Donald shade boy by Gary campaign this
campaign but she wants to throw no she
knows death row she won't stay through
and it's true I haven't really gotten
the bolo tie look to catch on she was
the first person to call me when my
second child was born I heard no it says
about my family
the Hillary on oh she loves HGTV and she
can devour buffalo wings whether on a
car plane or train
it's healing time is hope time is
Hildred time is healing time is hope
time is Hildreth time it's healing time
is hope it's Kendra time it's healing
time
is home time it several time is healing
time it's her time
you better listen to me I said she won't
stay cool