once the envy of all employees who work
in open-plan offices I would take asking
beaded curtain just so I don't have to
directly observe Carol clipper nails do
it at home Carol what this year one
particular wall has gotten a lot of our
attention I will build a great great
wall on our southern border at the Trump
walk beautiful walk I will build the
greatest wall that you've ever seen they
ever put my name on I want a gorgeous
wall the Trump wall will that be a
beautiful one yes Donald Trump wants to
build a wall on the US Mexican border
and based on his tone he also wants to
fuck that wall the wall is such it's
such a fixture of his speeches of so
popular among his supporters one man
even wore a spandex wall costume at one
of his rallies and I mean that's kind of
incredible the only group of people more
excited about barriers are high school
health teachers oh that's right cool
guys and cool girls when you're horny
there is nothing better than a good
dental dam it feels exactly the same it
doesn't it really doesn't
the border wall is one of the few policy
proposals Trump has talked about in
detail so instead of mocking or
dismissing it out of hands tonight let's
take a series proposal by a serious
presidential candidate seriously and
first let's put aside the potential
racism and xenophobia involved here we
can come back to that later and instead
let's focus on the practicality of
whether and how it can actually be done
and let's start with the cost when Trump
first started talking about this he said
it would cost a lot but not a lot a lot
let's say the world costs 4 billion you
know they say 10 billion that means 4
billion if you know what you're doing ok
so so so he's saying he could build a
wall at 40% of what it would cost others
which I would say is an insane magic
trick if I thought his tiny fingers
could wrap all the way around the magic
right so actual poker actual actual
photo but but since then his estimate
has grown the rule is going to call 6 or
7 billion world's probably 8 billion
dollars a war gets built it's gonna cost
10 billion dollars to build a wall get a
lot of money to walk the walls gonna
cause 10 billion dollars maybe 12
depending okay
so we've gone from 4 to 12 billion
dollars Donald Trump's margin of error
is the entire GDP of Moldova but but
still fair enough with where we're now
at 12 billion dollars but but to truly
know the real cost we're gonna need to
know what the wall is going to be made
from now if only Donald Trump could
explain that to me like I'm a child so
you're going to build the wall what's it
going to be made out of
hey that's a good question lift him up
here bring him up gonna be made of
hardened concrete and it's gonna be made
out of rebar and steel okay first first
Trump is holding that child less like a
human being and more like a cat he just
gave a bastard but but second second to
be fair rebar and steel okay that is a
clear answer I appreciate that now now
the amount we would need would depend on
the height of the wall unfortunately
Trump has been unclear on that
suggesting numbers ranging from 35 to 90
feet so let's work with his lowest
estimate at a 35 foot tall wall which
Trump has said we would need around a
thousand miles off now according to one
estimator and construction economists
that would cost 10 billion dollars for
the concrete panels and 5 to 6 billion
for steel columns including labor plus
another billion for concrete 30 for the
columns and a concrete foundation so
that's at least 16 billion dollars
we're already four billion over his
largest budget and we've only just
gotten started here because those
materials are heavy and you're gonna
have to transport them into many areas
that are currently inaccessible to
construction vehicles so that same
expert estimates another two billion
dollars to build roads so that 20 ton
trucks can deliver those materials and
that's not even getting into another 30%
or so for engineering design and
management so now we're up to around
twenty five billion dollars anywhere
from two to six times Trump's estimates
but wait cuz we're still not done all of
that is just building a wall the
Congressional Budget Office estimated
for a similar project that wall
maintenance costs would exceed the
initial construction costs within seven
years so it's a big dumb thing that only
gets more expensive over time it's like
getting a pet walrus you think it's
stupid now
what until you learn want a bucket of
sea cucumbers costs
you've not prepared for that but but
whatever the cost is Trump claims he has
got a way to pay for it
Mexico is going to pay for the war
they're going to pay for the war Mexico
is going to pay for the war Mexico is
going to pay for the wall and they're
gonna be happy about it of course they
are of course that people love it when
you make them pay for shit they don't
want that's why everyone is so happy
when their cable company bundles
together cable internet and landline all
land thank you oh and look lucky me
that'll come in handy when I need to
call my cell phone because I can't find
it and that's about it but but is Mexico
going to pay for the wall because the
current Mexican Treasury Secretary has
said Mexico under no circumstance is
going to pay for the wall that mr. Trump
is proposing and two former Mexican
presidents were even clearer Mexican
people we are not going to pay any
single cent for such a stupid wall as
you can I'm not gonna pay for that in
war he should take
I think I think the best part of that
clip is the fact that he even took the
extra effort to swear in English hey
this may be my second language but I
want to make absolutely sure you firs
understand it but but when Trump was
asked about these comments he responded
with characteristic diplomacy the wall
just got ten feet taller believe me he's
got ten feet tall come on things don't
get bigger just because you're angry if
that were true Alec Baldwin would be a
hundred feet tall by now now to be fair
to be fair here Trump has thought
through how he will get Mexico to foot
the bill we have right now a 58 billion
dollar trade deficit with Mexico that's
why the wall gets built by the way
that's why they're gonna pay for it okay
I see I think Mexico will pay because we
have a trade deficit I understand
unfortunately that's literally not how
anything works because well yes we did
by fifty eight billion dollars more in
goods and services from Mexico than they
did from us last year that money doesn't
belong to the Mexican government it's
earned by Mexican businesses it's not
lying around in some centralized scrooge
mcduck money bin labels dumb Americans
money do not spend on border fence but
look let's put all this aside and let's
say we did find the money where would we
put a border wall now your instinct says
on the border but even that is actually
more difficult than it sounds and we
know this because in 2006 George W Bush
signed these secure Fence Act which
called for the construction of 700 miles
of fencing along the border a project
which incidentally then senators Barack
Obama and Hillary Clinton voted for
which is terrible although keep in mind
that millions of you voted for Taylor
Hicks in 2006 so we don't be quite so
quick to judge so Patrol
yeah that Thanks that fits ran into a
lot of problems though for instance in
large stretches of Texas the border
consists of the Rio Grande and typically
you can't build a wall along the river
as a 1970 treaty prohibits building
anything that may cause obstruction of
normal flow of the river and for that
and other reasons some stretches of the
border fence were built considerably
inland and as towns like Brownsville
Texas have learned that can be a problem
this here is the Rio Grande River
it's cuts all the way you can see it
makes a natural Crescent there this is
Mexico all back here here's where the
walls built so all of this golf course
is now stuck in between Mexico and this
border fence it's true
that golf course was stuck between the
u.s. border fence and Mexico in a space
that like the case of Diablo Pajarito
occurred over isn't really American but
sure as shit isn't Mexican and the
ridiculousness of this situation was not
lost on the people who played there you
realize when you're golfing here that
you're in them you're not really in the
United States or Mexico here I don't
care where I have them as long as a mama
golf course you think it's helping with
security now
stupid okay I think that woman just said
in two words what I'm taking 20 minutes
to say in this piece does the fence help
no stupid and look Texas became a real
problem for constructing that fence
because in Texas unlike in other states
there is no federally owned buffer along
the Mexican border meaning the land is
mostly owned by private citizens like
the loop family who owned a ranch in
Texas and discovered that three-quarters
of their land would suddenly be on the
other side of the fence
when Homeland Security asked the loops
to sign away rights to their land for
the fence they said no way I said that
I'm not signing anything at this point
nothing it's just not possible so the
government used the power of eminent
domain and condemned their property Wow
and the loops were not alone hundreds of
property owners were sued by the federal
government so the fence could be built
perhaps the only silver lining here
might be that historically in America
when the federal government takes your
land and treats you terribly you at
least get an offensive football team
named after you so I guess one day we
can all look forward to the Washington
loops hey it's a sign of respect they're
respecting their heritage why can't you
understand that and the fences damage
didn't stop there because Michael
Chertoff then Secretary of Homeland
Security signed a document giving his
department the authority to waive 36
laws to build the fence including the
Endangered Species Act the Safe Drinking
Water Act and the Native American graves
protection and repatriation Act he even
welded parts of the fence himself
wearing an American Eagle facemask and
he looks like a member of Daft Punk
if Daft Punk played nothing but Lee
Greenwood covers and that Native
American grave laws came in horrifyingly
handy as this Native American leader
explains fragments of human remains were
found in heavy equipment tracks on the
Christian ranch archaeological site a
site now crossed by barrier barriers and
the border road imagine a bulldozer in
your family graveyard I mean say what
you will but I think imagine
a bulldozer in your family graveyard is
definitely the worst verse of John
Lennon's Imagine it's not my favorite it
is not my favorite and by waiving the
protections for wildlife the fence has
posed dangers to the survival in the
u.s. of everything from Jaguars to
pronghorns to pygmy owls and look how
shocked they look by that fact although
although I will admit they do
permanently look like you've just
murdered their entire families but put
look look Trump might well argue having
a wall is worth all of this because it
will act as a fortress to stop people
and drugs flowing across the border but
let's look at that because the most
recent authoritative estimate suggests
nearly half of the unauthorized migrants
in the u.s. entered legally through a
port of entry like an airport or a
border crossing usually with visas that
they then overstayed a wall can't stop
that it's like wearing a condom to
protect against head lice you could do
that but that's not really how you keep
the thing you're worried about from
happening which is not to say that there
are not some people crossing the border
where a war would be but would a wall
really stop them what the Border Patrol
says and I've spoken to a lot of their
people is look first of all if you build
a 30-foot wall all it's going to do is
create a market for 31-foot ladders of
course of course that's right and I by
the way remember when you're looking for
a 31-foot ladder avoid Werner climbing a
Werner ladder is like dousing yourself
in cooking grease and climbing a pile of
tetanus do yourself a favor and get into
Walt ladder and I'm not being paid to
say that I'm just a fan fan a very happy
customer
and ladders are not the walls only
weakness
watch as Donald Trump inadvertently
stumbles his way into a key realization
so you take precast plank it comes 30
feet along 40 feet along 50 feet long
there's no ladder going over that if
they ever get up there they're in
trouble cuz there's no way to get down
maybe you're up yeah this may be a rope
yes yes your brilliant plan has been
undone by mankind's third invention and
as for stopping drugs walls and fences
have not posed much of a challenge to
cartels in Mexico police have discovered
a tunnel believed to have been used to
smuggle drugs into the u.s. using this
makeshift cannon they were shooting
packages small packages of marijuana
across the border these men were
actually using a catapult to launch
drugs across the border other smugglers
have kept it a bit simpler than that
they just get somebody with a really
good arm
who throws it over the fence like a
football okay okay well I will say if
they're looking for a new recruit
I know Peyton Manning is currently
between jobs but but let's face it for
many people efficacy is beside the point
this wall is about making us feel safer
and here is where the racism and
xenophobia that we put aside at the top
of this piece really needs to be brought
back because while other politicians
have supported barriers at the border
Donald Trump has been uncommonly clear
about who we need to be protected from
when Mexico sends its people they're not
sending their best they're bringing
drugs they're bringing crime they're
rapists and some I assume are good
people
Trump Trump sounds like an angry
villager running through the town square
yelling werewolves Run For Your Lives
though some I assume are good werewolves
but they're here to kill you with maybe
a few exceptions but mostly werewolves
run run
we're werewolves love me and I love
werewolves but they're here to kill all
of us
but but about that because while yes
individual undocumented immigrants have
committed horrible crimes so obviously
have American citizens and in fact
researchers consistently find that
immigrants are less not more crime prone
than their native-born counterparts the
crime rates among immigrants once here
are relatively tiny digits which is
something Donald Trump should frankly
understand given that he has ten of them
attached take these minuscule wrists
this is one reason to say that the idea
of the war is not still comforting for
some people or as one man who actually
lives near the border puts it this was
put up to illustrate to Joe whoever up
in Dubuque or someplace they see a
picture of this and their overstuffed
butts and an overstuffed chair looking
at a to big TV think oh yeah that'll
stop them well of course it doesn't this
guy is amazing shitting on the fat cat
out of touch metropolis that is Dubuque
Iowa but but even if it does make the
people of Dubuque feel safer given
everything we've seen is it worth it
because remember we calculated earlier
that this could conservatively cost
twenty five billion dollars excluding
the cost of both maintenance and the
land under it that works out to around
seventy seven dollars per person and
here is where I would like to make a
counterproposal to Donald Trump's wall
plan if the main thing is going to get
us is a warmed sense of satisfaction
inside I suggest instead of building
that wall we use the money to buy every
man woman and child in America a Parma
waffle iron these beauties retail at
seventy-five dollars a piece so we still
have nearly a billion dollars left over
and just to be clear this isn't one per
household this is one per person you
have five people in your family you got
five waffle irons coming your
not only is this cost-effective unless
you are a really sick fuck this waffle
iron plan would not kill a single pygmy
owl and look I know what you're thinking
John this is a stupid idea but is it is
it really yes
obviously it is but is it significantly
stupider than Donald Trump's war because
this waffle iron plan will cost less
it'll do nearly as much to keep out
immigrants and drugs it won't harm our
relationship with our third largest
trading partner if it is racist it's
only toward Belgians and and and unlike
Donald Trump's wall this makes King
waffles some come on America let's ask
ourselves what kind of country do we
want to wake up to one that spends
brilliant on an impossible impractical
symbol of fear or one that smells like
breakfast
exactly