welcome to unforgotten realms live hey
ray so that's that's enough so let me
explain what we're gonna be doing today
so today is the character creation now
we cut this out of the stream because we
have to either rush through it or it
takes up a long time so what we're gonna
be doing today is we're going to be
making the characters that we're going
to be playing every Saturday so the
today's Friday you guys will be you'll
be able to watch it tomorrow
we'll be doing like the introduction to
the quest so everybody will know that
the campaign they'll get to talk to NPCs
and whatever before they go out and on
Saturday they can jump right into the
show so this is pretty important if you
care about nerdy stuff not important if
all you care about is us talking about
jokes and things like that so no joke
yes you're not less joke yeah we're not
allowed to be funny this is actually
like a funny show um so we're just gonna
go right into it so we have these cards
made by coos tournament booster here
look at that they're really pretty
Oh everybody give man already yeah okay
yeah you're not we're gonna actually
here's my hand oh yeah we have virtual
hands that's why I did this okay so the
first campaign you guys are going to be
doing are you are going to be going on a
quest for the good old Miss 'van to
steal a key from some elves that's it
that's all you're going to be doing this
has been we'll have more details on the
quest once you guys have made your
characters but you guys are a group
under the leadership of Roman who are a
band of thieves so that is your
characters motif in some way you guys
Roman is the leader of a band of thieves
and you guys are going to be hired by
Nyssa VIN to go steal a key from some
elves okay all right so today for races
you can be either a gnome or a dwarf
however you can't all be the same race
so I got there gonna be there goes down
we got it which by only yeah
well you can either be so what I mean is
we can only have three dwarves and three
gnomes so you can't be all domes or all
dwarves ah some sort of mix today so
there's that so each race has a special
passive if you pick a dwarf you're going
to start with more shopping money and
one of your treasure items will roll
over to next week's game okay if you
pick a gnome you're going to only get to
pick two class abilities but you'll get
to start with four random treasure cards
now treasure cards are basically
abilities that they're bait they're
basically a weaker class abilities
sometimes they're passive sometimes
they're actives sometimes they're
weapons that could be all sorts of
things so if you go with dwarf you're
going to have more control over the neck
the shopping portion of the game if you
go gnome you're going to get a lot of
crazy shit but have a character
abilities hat if I'm a dwarf - I control
item I would start with next week yes
forget the pick you get to pick so one
of your treasure card items you'll roll
over onto the next night how do we are
how we gonna do this
Roman is the leader so romantic well
Roman Donnelly I mean stealing cards now
hey hey hey put because this card's back
real exactly derpy I don't even know
where you guys gonna put the cards looks
like it's done it on section yeah well
let's have the you know what here let me
know Roman do it Roman no Roman pick
okay we should get well wish you got a
proper table will here I'll get it I'll
put ours on your night for arguments
yeah I'll get your dice okay I get a C
for Co okay we'll get a J for Justin
perfect okay I'll get a B for dead bones
yep I like it B's for bones from oh I go
by my slash easier all right well as
leader
okay I've selected so no who's our next
though Roman it's your call on these
orders you're the leader for this week
uh clearly we're going in alphabetical
order by last name so we shouldn't Kobe
ass dead dead bones
well no I didn't say this was the order
this is just how Rob wrote them out okay
I did once your last name is bones uh
Koh ingested I'm unfamiliar with what
your last names are ours also Justin
Justin Justin its Justin Justin Justin
and Co your last name star ain't no
Beauty funny
just like aardvark okay you like
guaranteed to go first I couldn't win
exhale pick pick erase here dead bones
dead boots now go be no okay
yeah always go small like you're kidding
me ready so sneak also for treasure
cards so so here's a so here's the thing
about cards and abilities
this is a ever evolving game for anyone
watching what what this is this is like
our version of Dungeons &amp; Dragons that
we're going to do live for you every
week and the gate the game doesn't
necessarily need to be insanely balanced
because if these guys break the game
I'll just change the cars for next week
so by all means if you guys think
something's way stronger that means I'll
either have to buff something buff other
things or nerf it so just whatever
preference what we do is we make no
really shitty so indiscipline gets to
play gnomes or just terrible
what's that question Roman nah man okay
so I get for treasure cards are those
reusable yes
treasure cards are reusable and let's
the card states they're not reusable
they're like they're like super items
okay okay wait wait so no Koga Oh No
co-star yeah just no scar so just after
noon I'm gonna go tour okay you're gonna
give Hall choice money money over
everybody take and oh just so kinda
taking them to look at you know I want
to so we're gonna have three gnomes and
a dwarf so you guys want to think so so
you guys can have character names but it
would be really confusing for the stream
if we're trying to use both character
names and names so we won't ever use
these names these will be like for
documentation of The Legend of X
character right but we'll just call each
other our normal names but you should
think of a name for your character I
need to know excellent I have a name
sub-basins before I pick my name okay
come on yeah yeah that's true
so each race also
as a sub race which would give you
another passive and these are these are
not limited I will just give you guys
each a different card for them there are
two types of gnomes you can be and there
are two types of dwarves
so for gnomes you can be a tinker and
that will let you take two additional
treasure cards and trade them in for a
random treasure card and if used in
combat you can also still use the
treasure so this means that if you have
crappy treasure cards or you just want
to roll the dice and get something else
you can get under the treasure card it
is possible to get duplicates of the
same treasure card so that's like you
can have multiples of the same item
potentially like passives and stuff and
it can get ridiculous key gnomes let you
use the treasure cards of other allies
which are really good in groups of
gnomes which you guys kind of are I
think we should all be in Rouen we don't
even take it I'll do it for you here we
go seriously there's a keen for you to
take alone what we'll do just in a
second do any of you want to be the oka
no where do all you guys just want to be
Keynes together I'll be in me I'll be
the oka noma you'll be special
alright let's take the Keen yeah you can
take the King yeah Rome would you be
totaling things to and fro my god so
many treasures it's so easy
okay so Justin you have a choice you can
either be a tall dwarf which is
effectively just a human right he's just
mints that's what a human would be and
that would allow you to use your move as
a basic attack which could potentially
let you to attack twice each turn but if
you pick that you have to own two
weapons which means you'll have to spend
more of your money to be able to do this
because if you don't have two weapons
you can't really do a wield okay um you
could it could not attack with weapon
and then punch yes for one sure for one
yeah this is a clarification are you
sure you mean is not it is not called
Wharf and that's able like
phone-a-friend and it's a door that
shows up no it's not a telephone friend
guard no it says call dwarf I'm saying
let's see code know I'm a called like a
call girl yeah I'm a mellow but the work
of the night oh that's why you so much
extra money yeah oh man that totally
does look like a see you're right I just
read the cards cuz I know what it looks
like yeah well to fix that these are
the final designs for the cards they're
just like what we have right now we plan
on doing like lots of character artwork
and stuff on the cars I'm making them
really freaking cool but you know that
takes a lot of time so we'll get there
though
and so the so the other one you'll be
just in is adrenaline and this makes it
so any time a character is defeated by
you or your party you can use an
additional basic attack on a target
adjacent to you even if it's not
creating your turn so this one basically
allows you if you're killing lots of
small little guys to just free attack
free attack free attack free attack over
and over and over again I like that I'm
gonna go with that I'm a he'll door
that's pretty beastly yeah Jesus
let's go ham alright so there are four
classes you can be this week and you
guys have basically seen these classes
but there are slight changes Solaria
when we improve these cards out so we
can better see them boo boo the guy that
did the D&amp;D car you don't like this to
be higher and for this yeah so the
gnomes are only gonna be picking two
abilities and Justin you're going to be
picking three of these okay I'll kind of
talk about these cards in one second for
you but basically the abilities are the
same from the last time for anyone
watching on youtube if you want to look
at these cards we have them on our
website for you to look at at the
buffalo is calm and we'll also have them
in our subreddit discussion on the
buffalo wizard subreddit for you guys to
check out because I know sometimes it's
hard to read all these cards in the
video so we got the warrior the sorcerer
the bard and the lumberjack you'll see
the cards all has these little gems if
it has if it's a purple gem with the
lightning bolt that means it's just
classified as a spell sometimes that
matters and if you see the exclamation
mark that's the indicator that means
that you can use it at any time so even
if it's not your turn interrupt yeah
it's it's the interrupt tool yes icon
system this is amazing I already say we
got gems and shit yeah and in this way
and then the stamina cost is at the
bottom right which is the number so it's
very you guys are allowed to be the same
class if you want but Roman it's again
it's your call decide who's going to be
picking class
is what you want to do okay but we could
all be we could all be asset class it'd
all be the same potentially so remember
your campaign is not necessarily based
on stealth but your job is going to be
to be stealing a key and you're going to
be taking it from elves who are going to
be much stronger than you so while it's
not fully stealth there's got to be some
level of sneakiness or infiltration to
be able to effectively get this key or
you guys have to be badass warriors
there's no one between you got to either
be a team of sneaks or a team of kill
everyone if one got three sneaks in a
tank I mean you could do that but what's
going to happen is the tank is going to
stand there and die and get captured or
you know not maybe not die but just get
you know get knocked unconscious and get
captured and and this needs to get by
that I guess that could be your tack
today it's a distraction I mean we got
we got this big lumbering dwarf I mean
it makes sense right I mean maybe the
universe
I mean Roman how like how long you
you're the you're the lead on this case
oh you have a lot of decision powers
they get to define their characters but
you get to kind of define like when did
you hire these guys who's the new
recruit
who's the newest team member monning
roman uh news team under is clearly
justin is very eager to impress he's
yeah like all days like come on come on
boss can can I go to mission she's a bit
inadequate really uh is this your like
is this your first time working with the
dwarf like were you trying to get a
fourth gnome and you're like yeah gotta
think what we can get to get this job
done you know as what I say there's
other thieving guilds and they kept like
hiring dwarves and we had to strict no
dwarf policy and it was just becoming a
problem and we're like you know what
fine we're lower the barriers ritalin
towards it so essentially Justin you're
representing your opposition you're
racist future well Wow okay I just make
sure you know and you know nobody what
do you look like we're in a Dorf you
know odd well we clearly went through
this during the interview process but we
picked you because you were you were a
stout fellow you just kept you would not
shut up about how like oh I'm like way
better than those called Ross twice as
long as I like you just look like a boy
you're get tossed Wharf just like yeah
it's Vic that's what we were thinking
warrior I mean you may be trying to lap
kind of you know cross speck maybe
dabble a little bit in some other arts
but you know I'm just saying you come in
as a warrior
kind of excite you to fill that role I'm
kind of your meat shields and I'm the
guy you're gonna throw in front but yeah
you get it done you're gonna take the
hits alright well well what does anybody
actually is anybody know what class they
want to be right off the bat is it blog
like on a person I do like worried I
will say so that watch out Arsenal
towards everything that is warrior
so yeah I'm leaning towards sorcerer
okay what do you think Roman I'm leaning
towards sorcerer I gotta say the whole
two abilities is making of of what a
right of Blink you mean no no no those
abilities oh no yes yeah because without
knowing what kind of goodies we have in
our pocket yeah see with into it two
abilities is going to be rough too
because you could use something like
something like the blink sorcerer that
gives you a completely separate turn or
any of things that give you like that
amplifier boss get pretty oh my god
Ralph so rare Frost's not gonna pants at
that what are you kidding me is nothing
else it's not a class skill which means
I it's a free yeah cute or I use that's
a pretty good gnome one good that's a
pretty good Ramon because it means you
can use ray of frost for one stamina and
then use one of your treasure cards each
turn yeah that's a really strong one for
another Bard
you're gonna go bard again there are
yeah yeah well me again I don't know
what you're talking about Rob haven't
you played for what that game never
happens yeah you guys who you guys
should be these are this like we've been
playing with these general cards I think
sorcerer was pretty new because I think
era was the latest abilities last time
yeah I think you had a couple like these
are these should all be pretty familiar
ability to anyone who's kind of watch
this stuff before they've only had
slight changes so all right I'm gonna go
sorcerer you just
or what abilities you want to go with
Roman Co what are your sorceress
specializations uh fog and blinking
that's what I'm all about
perfect he's like Sneaky's like castle
fog need teleports out yeah that's you
that's that means you're gonna be really
reliant on weapon damage a KO to do any
torch sort of damage you have to keep
that in mind unless he's got a combo
with this fog with his sorcerer buddy
yeah that's true
okay so that one and rolling fog okay Oh
cuz I wasn't goin trout on that one oops
wait a minute you want man you know
here's the thing I understand that I
these lookin I'm planning Liggett chugga
you guys can start selecting abilities
and if you want to change around at
least allies sure yeah yeah yeah okay
cool my friend ray a frost is coming
like their chant way that's I mean if
there's okay what else you think Roman
uh how do I not do in large now so
here's so I'll tell you one thing so
rolling fog is interesting because it
affects everyone but the sorcerer but I
but if but if in the case of two
Sorcerer's with two rolling fogs I know
you're really not gonna pick this I
would make it so they can play nice
together right hmm I would do something
that's good duality it yeah because it
cuz cuz if you if it's two sorcerers and
they're both using the fog yeah sure
okay a little large oh yeah and Laurence
really oh I thought you said I'm good I
thought you said I'm gonna go large and
I was like okay what are you gonna pick
okay look I'm gonna be a support
sorcerer as a leader also that might
mean I get to hang in the back and not
really good my hands dirty
I'm just saying no connection alright
what do you think of Justin now these
guys are really light on damage so far
and like they're gonna be at the mercy
of tragic treasure cards so you really
probably well I don't know or you can go
sneak like yeah I was kind of torn
between warrior and lumberjack I'm like
on both sides right here you guys kind
of already have a
or utility-based team maybe it's better
to you know goes out right horse I don't
know this is this is why by the way I
didn't want to stream this stuff because
well it's not that it's boring it's that
it's time-consuming you know what I mean
and the problem is you don't want to do
like an hour of this and then into a
three to four hour adventure it's just
it's not enough you know yes like you
just give you tires yeah yeah yeah we
got a build man builder carriages uh
permits the only thing again oh well
hope dead bones is going bard for sure
huh let's do dead bones then we'll see
you remembered what gasps don't you owe
me first okay I'm cool with that show to
bilities wisely so I'm always thinking
we're going to stealth because we're
like a Thieves Guild right we're part of
the thetour Thieves team it's some some
sort of your romance thieves team that's
why I'm working on that only on the team
name right now that's why I'm going with
charm and disguise I'm a silver-tongued
devil Oh smooth talk oh you have to help
you better have your phone ready for
selfies cuz every time you use it I want
to see a cell I will make sure that I
take the best selfies for charms ever
okay yeah and what do these guys
disguise yeah yeah yeah this is a good
build I got I think I'll squints same
squits
charged with character charm can be
pretty good offensively now I'll tell
you this charm will not really work on
like really tough guys or bosses wait
tough guys won't be attracted to a
pretty okay no no they what a combo this
so if if you combo what I mean is like
you know like for example the boss any
any major boss charmers are gonna work
it's only gonna really work on ads and
stuff but I it can be it could be pretty
powerful and the thing is with charm is
term doesn't necessarily wear off even
after combat of it you know it doesn't
necessarily wear off but the problem is
if you don't if you like like let's say
you charm like you know some other dwarf
and you know you just he's just
following you around at some point it
could break and then it you know it's a
the best the best example and it's only
going to help Roman it's like minstrels
charming of things it's like you're
charming I love
until a certain amount of time goes by
when he breaks so you know he's got a
roll a number and then he breaks so you
could keep them from an encounter to an
encounter
we got a pet and I just wanted music
can't break yeah and I would let you
charm multiple people but it's one of
those if you charming people it's gonna
break more you know okay these yeah but
I mean hey if you just keep rolling hi
cool I mean that's the dice mm-hmm
remember it's charm not enslave I mean
it's a kind of same thing buddy
all right absolutely not the same thing
cat not chill description when I get to
10th level and I a multi-class then
turns into Chen right it's like the
tenth level version come online there's
no level not rare in this game life
that's not red flames handbook no levels
buddy this is all you get I want to use
that as a level three spell all right
what do you think Justin all right so
here's what I'm thinking you know we've
got these three gnomes they're all
sneaky they're into their tech stuff
they're into all that and they've got
this big your dwarf who's gonna just
stand around and when things go wrong
he'll take the image form some muscle so
you're gonna take okay yeah ah so you're
gonna tank yeah so that's in it so
that's basically this is this one's fun
because you basically can at any time
you can use it also as a movement
basically to do damage which can be
really really helpful and it combos
really nicely I don't what was your
second ability gonna be Jason I was also
gonna go with blockade I'm thinking it
combos very nicely because if you
blockade you can basically literally
just be a wall it is pretty boring
though Justin but I see I figured I
would almost be like a uh-oh you got a
third ability hey you're not a 98 a
third ability yeah oh yeah well that's
why I so I figure yeah so I'm gonna take
blockade as my third ability just just
so everyone knows it's not the most
important one okay wait it's up there
that's my third did you double blockade
oh no no no I still get to pick another
ability I think double pick abilities no
you can I got double charms as a diamond
chant no and I was thinking I don't
consider that in the future game design
it's just
fun - uh sorry - me to take the card
it's it's fun to pick up and throw
people and Tasha just it's great it's
been buffed a lot - like I changed it so
it does five damage which is really high
when you're looking at all the other
damage numbers yeah you can pick up one
guy throw it another guy and effectively
have done ten damage which would go
really nice with your other ability
he'll dwarf because if you can kill a
guy with a toss then you can smack a guy
in the face right next to you right yeah
yeah and then there's stun next to room
so it's got a little bit of FCC the
other choice is like if you want
something damage e is something like
whirlwind because whirlwind lets you
move around do damage and again like if
we're talking about dealing with lots of
little like I've made this first
campaign pretty balanced there's times
where you fight lots of little guys
there's times where you fight really big
want single guys there's times where you
fight mixes it's got a little bit of
everything so you'd want a little bit of
everything but hmm because ruins would
kind of proc with a adrenaline right
whirlwind is probably yes so basically
if you killed something on the whirlwind
you can immediately get a take attack
and you're constantly getting to move in
between the turns now because this game
is now four players you basically are
going to it's ten damage right because
it's Romans turn your turn KO's turn
dead bones turn the mobs turn and then
it ends so it's going to do 10 damage AE
so it's that is the most possible damage
the tosser can also be useful useful
because you can also throw allies which
can be very useful in specific
situations that has that utility aspect
where as what and the other thing with
whirlwind is you you then become
confused which is one of those bullshit
roles where you're rolling I'm like a
you hit yourself in the face this card
alright that's why it does so much
because it's really one of those you use
it and you might be screwed for a little
bit maybe not maybe you could screw
maybe yeah yeah I think I'm ready I'm
leaning towards the toss I like the
tosser get throw those gnomes yeah you
just tossed gnomes around it'll be a
good time all right so now we're gonna
do your no trade force yeah this is big
so bad I'm super
no idea what these are me anything
it could be like you get a pet elephant
oh my girls okay Justin here we go ruin
your trip Rob can one of them be an
elven Q that we need let's gonna bust
over no it cannot be a question okay so
there are two stream just roll credits
so the first one you get Roman is all
spill a cost one less and your picture
so that's one less oh yes you get fee
right the frost thrown my
congratulations on winning the lottery
yeah you get to spam rain frost every
turn for free your your second treasure
Roman is spell word armor which will
make you take less damage if you roll oh
cool
so you can notice you know block rings
your third one is a book of curse
fellows when using this book a random
spell is selected you must pay the
stamina cost and must complete the cast
or the book will be destroyed this is a
random spell Roman any spell in the game
even of even of classes that aren't
necessarily out yet even classes I I
didn't necessarily put in this week
there are six complete classes so
classes the dates random spells are open
oh sure hope don't come across some
beggar and finally you get blade turn
which you are me first
alright Roman is very very is very
strong don't want me the fucking leader
come on no are you with this shit Co
your first treasure is blunderbuss which
is a weapon so it's a ranged weapon that
does three damage in a 2x2 radius so
that's like four squares I could do
damage now yeah hey I also need you crap
on it just it also means you could
suspect buying the weapon with your gold
yeah you also have a book of Christos
has ratchet you also have a crystal
catalyst which will summon forth ten gem
links to aid you in battle and it will
destroy this treasure cards a one-time
gem Ling's
deal one damage they have one health but
you get to control
ten oh man okay oh so they start and
they last forever so as long as the gem
Ling's survived combat they keep
following you they but they are what
like you if they get hit by anything
they explode in a little crystal spark
so Wow so the combat armor what damage
to other gem leads by chance what game
actually yeah oh so you said they
explode in a spark any that ventures
that just crap oh no no it's just
graphic they just explode okay okay I
would have put it on the card Roman are
they worth anything uh no there's no
experience for anything like oh you also
delaford Wow Wow on our sorcs oh there's
not that many treasure cards yeah uh no
there's uh that's quite a few how many
are how many in this deck 18 K oh wow
yeah like we're gonna make more as the
week's go on I just want to make sure I
had enough so you guys can see a lot of
variety this week alright so here we go
dead bones first you're getting a
crystal catalyst elf well and you're
getting a work blade which is a melee
weapon and any time you use the melee
weapon you may have a free teleport yes
rogue what no a healing totem I'll bet
you can drop it on the ground it'll hear
stamina on your turn to everyone around
you it only heals allies so you don't
have to worry about monsters and stuff
wow yeah and finally you have a spell
board armor to reduce spell damage
all right great hey just wear your
trainer cards oh yeah don't know so now
now we're at the store portion and
Justin you may buy treasure you'll
notice these treasure cards all have
numbers that is 500 gold
the gnomes here are going to be getting
a thousand gold you guys will each have
a thousand gold to spend and you got to
keep in mind that you probably want to
buy some armor you probably want to make
sure you have a weapon and then you can
spend your money as is on other things
this week we have assortment of some
melee weapons and some range weapons we
have some general armors and then we
have some potions and you can may but
you may stock up on these potions room
and if you just want to spend all your
money buying five quickness
lick sirs by all means just go ahead and
buy quickness elixirs you guys could buy
whatever you want
in addition to that you may also buy
these treasures oh we can buy Buddhist
treasures ready these are the treasures
that the merchants will be selling this
week one oh cool let's do that thing two
three that thing four five so we have
another war played on their blunderbuss
and the spell word armor and mu little
bones which prevents death once that's
pretty good no matter what it is it'll
prevent the death and a ring of fire
which is a line attack that deals damage
basically a cost for stamina because it
does for damage and they can do it in a
wave Wow now one thing to note is if
someone buys a treasure I pull out
another card to put down and no you may
not stack there is there really is you
have total so there is a kind of a
problem Roman and this is just something
cuz me and Co having maxed it your
Kingfisher cloth and your spell ward
armor are both armor you have to keep
this in mind so you see I can't actually
we're both that we don't have like the
item things wait can you not sell one to
the shop now and get money equivalent
and buy potions with it no you can't
sell things like that he can keep it and
then I could give it once the adventure
starts you give it to Jess or something
like that but basically Roman you
already have two armors so you're gonna
have so you're not going to buy leather
chain or plate obviously because you
have these is there a limit down many
items we can have um not necessarily but
if you get ridiculous and start picking
up every single acts that kobolds
dropped then I mean I mean caught like
buying now buying no there is no limit
we just a thousand
you only have aprons when these
responsive may because our I'm sorry
Kari
uh Justin because you were the dwarf you
may purchase first right great ah I'm
gonna take the steel longsword okay to
go with that is there only one of those
in the shop um I hadn't decided um I'm
gonna go with the items no cuz I don't
really want to restrict you guys on
weapon types and stuff it's earned
treasures
so now you have 1500 gold left Justin
now all right ah now see I'm not really
crazy about any of these treasures and I
want to buy some treasure well you can
just wait somebody else could buy if you
want I don't care whatever you want to
do does anybody want to buy any of these
treasures I do it early what do you want
to buy by the spell wall the spell wall
armor yep are you sure okay cuz cuz
Roman has one but that's his oh yeah oh
yeah because IM ellis cose I'm gonna
open Noma yeah he's not keen you can't
do the thing we do how does that by the
way can we do that it doesn't work with
armor no it works with very specific
items and will work with armor and
weapons oh crap I totally forgot I could
yeah yeah it's gonna be using a sword
Rome it's gonna work I can use your warp
wait how does it have no it won't work
for things like work blade this is it
because it won't work with armor or
weapons and we don't have like icons on
the cards just yet so so far on the
board you guys can use book of curse
spells you can tell us if you can use
you could use a bath totem you could be
catalyst you could use his totem but you
could use his totem but that can still
only be one totem so I can't really use
a forum you could use the catalyst for
someone sure yeah you guys really don't
have any of their reusable treasures to
use like Ring of Fire is like one that
gets exchanged around right sure okay so
put like a little two arrows thing yeah
no we need we need two more more icons
and stuff but it's still good to work
and work in progress oh we're doing so
do you still not advise that or what
let's let's do this alright alright Co
um it's just Rowan has an armor and you
know he's gonna want to use the
kingfishers cloth over here I can show
you is I'm I'm rolling an armor Co so
that's you can't have it but you can use
it throughout the adventure for the yes
so low learner
as a team we all you know we're all in
this way out so can we can do that then
we can just yeah
what's our treasure it's a man literally
just straight up so like oh yeah you
wouldn't want to do it right now cuz
we're just looking at the cards but like
once we get to like in-game yeah you'd
be like I need some armor and you'd have
it right wrestle these are the things
Romans gonna have on him and so you can
know okay your Romans gonna blend you
the armor give you the armor so you can
use it so I wouldn't buy this spell
blade because Romans not gonna use it I
think a longer fee of torque you know
what I'm gonna buy the amulet you're
gonna be honest yeah I feel like I'm I
stand the most risk to die here yeah yes
ooh what anyone was doing oh it's the
Super Bowl whoa so good basically say
basically if you roll 20 it does point
average I'll buy that uh I'm actually
you scout - yeah you got the gun we do
my babies are they good I guess he's his
eye he can be our range dude whatever
you guys oh yeah yeah why don't I argued
about you just you're fine I just like
arguing okay well heli what do you do we
have keep in mind you already have a
range weapon as well so that means if
you if you're gonna use that one
somebody should keep in mind use the
blunderbuss and/or also because how is
the oken oma if you guys get shitty
treasures you can just trade them out
here could we just bought a blunderbuss
- did you buy a bunker bliss - but
you're gonna have to blunderbuss you
shouldn't mix them together I go that's
what your plan is
who's moving these cards I don't know
give me give me uh here random oh you
can't you hazy bill you know you can't
use now would be baby now that's a neat
ability ah that's why I was gonna do
that
I wasn't you could you can do it in-game
like if you want bright right on
Saturday if you want to do it go for it
just remember balls oh that's not gonna
have what I want though because now I
don't want the blunderbuss so I figured
I'd buy another junk treasure and then
trade them in for a new but now I can't
I have to spend that money now basically
is what you're saying and then do that
at the beginning of the game I'm okay so
you can you can do it once we're done
shopping
once you're done shopping and we're like
doing the little roleplay thing you can
do it and we'll I'll give you a hard
shell he'll you wanna if you want to buy
a treasure just to have another treasure
oh you can I'll wait until rails is done
then unless you guys want me to buy one
to open up another slot there's another
healing totem by the way how much gold
do you think you have I just want to let
you guys know but 800 gold well yeah oh
yeah thousand you have balls oh yeah you
had 800 because you got the armor
there's a loners feet
no no no no no Roman work for free
that's not how it works there's no gold
once you get in game to be trading
around like that we don't have money we
don't we don't bother but there's no
trader out or we buy it on credit yeah
you you can if you guys want to do some
sort of trade you can but it's not it's
a rental Oh Oh Lorenzo has to go back to
the thieves a depository Justin so dead
bones you have anything you want to buy
it uh here's what I don't here's my
don't question does just play armor
affects stealth Rose um not yet so
already we did I I was talking to Co
because we were quickly doing these
cards and I was like man I really need
to put penalties on like play armor for
that type of stuff but I didn't so no it
does so for now no for now no it is a
very fact no nice ablator
keep in mind that you have yeah but
that's like it's not actual originally
for some magic and I don't know how much
you guys gonna be very grateful by the
way that ko went o kinoma so you can
trade out these shitty treasures that
you don't want yeah I got the spell
armors cool but if we're not fighting a
lot of magic dudes it's kind of useless
right uh yeah uh well yeah yeah Elmer's
like do abilities count as spells I
guess no I you know asked that that I
call yeah yeah so it's kind of MA and
mobs in a I would focus the same way so
much money do I have left
after what did you buy have you bought
just the plate armor seals 500 more gold
all right I want however many of that is
in regrowth potions okay that's that's
two and then you're just gonna be
wasting a hundred gold okay yeah this
there's no hundred gold items right now
yeah I'm gonna try it tree branch is
anyone buying any more treasure you want
anybody my my
you throw away treasures so that one
opens up for you yeah okay
formation you would want to buy a
blender busco when you want to buy
something that might not be a throw away
but I'm going to immediately throw it
away okay I'm gonna take both Bond
blunderbusses given to you and say give
me a random I just I'm just saying you
know it is possible to put both your
bowler plus away and draw another
blunderbuss right or my understand that
guy or you suck play I know that Hawk
could be nice okay just double the
damage of a normal blunderbuss but if
that happens I will use the shit out of
it he's got to blunder bliss man all
right here's another traitor for you
guys it is a blade turn it's pretty good
that's all right no it's good no I mean
the Vince if you get this blue you guys
have picks three gnomes okay there's
only it's not like we're on 100 trigger
cards right now you you look at me
treasure cards are in your god a minute
okay you're gonna see a lot of
duplicates this week right I'll take the
blade turn and some plate armor and then
I'm Adam muddy
yeah plate Bros fleet brooms leap room
okay so I think Roman has 500 yeah
that's way Roman assisted on a grand
yeah Roma still a thousand that's really
good probably you should get this like
yeah Wow get that so I can use it to the
Ruby allows you to move a second turn
you're not allowed to use this move as
like some other special anything you can
only be used to as a move
Roman get that's how I can use it why
would you want to use it cuz we can
because I can give what I don't
understand what about it like what
combos it that you're like so excited
for it be using it then Romans turned in
him using it oh oh yes yes because yes
that is one of those items if you bought
it Roman basically you in dead filter W
yes that bows we can always escape you
two will be the fastest comes Steven
team were used where practice we're like
we're room well I machine okay
um wait some whatever home air just
called yeah
okay and that's everybody done shopping
whoa whoa whoa whoa
Roma's not done yet mm-hmm you get some
plate yes I'm gonna get some plate might
want it actually I think you guys saw
every single treasurer card really then
I just put that over yeah you guys have
gone and seen them enough of them well
spoil everything for you yeah all right
here's my no no more trips records
before Saturday so I have free Raya
Frost yeah that's too damaged so that
your so your problem right now Roman is
uh you're gonna want to you probably
want a range weapon like oh yeah yeah
now I think not huh well no so rare
Frost is range in the I mean he could
use it as a melee right cuz he can even
spam Bailey stun but I mean he have his
ability to move basically he's got the
ultimate kiting build right now so he's
got things that negate spell damage he's
got a thing that will gate one melee
he's got double move bad news yeah uh
yeah I get the short bow okay yeah yes
I'm the getting close to stabbing guy
then no pretentious yeah that's how you
get in close
so now just in with your ability um
you're allowed to keep one treasure next
week ah but you're not allowed to do
anything Chiti like have these guys
passed you a treasure okay and as to be
a treasure item that you've either you
personally got or you've been using
throughout most the inventor so if Roman
gives you the book of curse spells and
you used throughout the adventure you
can roll it but you guys cannot do the
bullshit of a pages CNAs Ruby yeah and
this baby this is way room overpower you
have an anyways we have I will let you
know that if anything is really really
broken you can expect next week it has
been changed and you're getting that
variant of the changed are you doing
okay if some reason ever have to
outright remove something then you're
just gonna get something random and play
doesn't become a legendary let's say
yeah is there a chance for like things
to become enchanted but you just got a
plain sword what a visit we break in
here we get to
Lu we find a wizard who else is like hey
bro thanks for help me out zap boom you
got a sewer on fire
congratulations it has to be a treasure
card it can't be just like a random
might not like this OH
this week's normal items are just actual
things in future weeks we'll have
hundred gold items that are like rope
watch your McCullough they'll probably
want to be hundred gold they'll be like
50 gold so you can stock up on like
little random tiny things to use
throughout the adventure could be it
rolling past rope to each other
I've known because they're not treasure
cards allowed to reuse treasure cards
yes it is but it's already so
overpowered by letting you guys do the
Ruby attack there's only two of us
there's my letter you know Robby twins
and and co I remembered why you don't
want to re-roll now because there will
be more treasure cards which means it's
less likely you get things you must be
seeing so I wouldn't reroll any of your
junk treasures till we start the game
okay and then go ahead cuz they'll be
more do you remember to do that yeah
well you can make it no - because I'm
for sure chat I'll be going to
blunderbuss is I'm sure probably telling
you you're like a traveling you know
range with nerds like oh just like maybe
get resolved early because you really
pull one out shoot pull another nut
shoot every turn you know just
constantly switching yep
oh the Okinawa passive is also keep in
mind it's a great desperation thing in
the sense that you can use it on your
turn and then use the item so you could
keep selling all your treasures and then
use the treasure as they come if you
really wanted to yeah
so until I get that the one the under
one yeah so keep that in mind if you
just want to go full spend all your
money on a boss fight or something that
is something you could do yeah
Rob the team name yet then you could
wish you could use my Ruby
okay um so yeah have you guys started to
think of like what you want to do for
characters and stuff everybody started
it has anybody been thinking about that
I got a name and I would name me like
our perp like our character you might
like the character itself okay I guess I
got a base idea I'm here I'm I'm the
super-ego right tres bulb Roman why
don't you come out and meet this event
first okay why don't you come out and
talk to mr. first date no way hey there
Roman or Nesmith let's go again
so what what do you what do you look
like this week Roman as your leader of
the Keene bandits what hat you thinking
of equipment yeah you get it you get a
hand mine look we got a new guy on the
team so it's all business it's a three
just full-on helmet okay yeah good good
good
okay who's your second in command then
ah second in command is uh my close
friend dead bones okay come on oh come
on oh dead bones Oh see oh there is oh
hey dings hit about what's going on
we're really let me go a little bit over
here you're looking good man so you're
gonna stay okay I got a stand right here
that's good right well tell ya what are
you going for were you thinking
character wise this week that's odd dude
that's a gut so so much stuff let me
just think
uh hmm all right yeah no I'm feeling up
you have like two Donis goggles goggles
for squeaks yeah you're that squink
sniffing no wrong hey yeah I know
just look I you know I about personal
space okay just don't company all right
I didn't hear you to hear his character
names either those are paying attention
memo is hard to like my character name
is you me you me you were girl how are
you gonna be a girl Roman are you gonna
give you a lady now yeah nice I like you
that's awesome
I'm not a girl though because I'm a cool
surgery so you're gonna be did you when
did you buy plate armor why are you
waking your plate helmet if you're not
even gonna be in the fine that's the
hell are you it's decorative
what do you got I
okay okay uh mr. Koh you want to come up
that box when you move back over here
yeah I can okay Klein no come to thorium
please you can talk to me over here come
on it's particularly a circle we're in
the same here me yeah I can hear you
just fine go dumb all right so go what
do you think of your character well my
name is gracias cross oh cool that's a
good variation from you're not doing
words for thanks every week you can have
it this week oh why not
it's ooh the gagaga buddies I like it
yeah I mean you know yeah well not
really buddies only one of them's
wearing them I mean I can't really fight
look Roman if I put them over my hex you
wouldn't know what I'm doing that's
that's that's that's how he talks Roman
if he doesn't you know actually I have
goggles over you can't tell what's good
Mel doesn't move his eyes does not go
around when he does my head I know this
and at no point has it not creeped me
out okay but then what are the goggles
or how the goggles I do nothing Oh
references
Oh mr. right where you going it's
Deadlands what's your Richard character
name again squeaks squeaks so yeah
silver chunk well maybe not silver
anymore like bronze tongue squeaks he's
not the best at it but he tries to be so
we have you me
squeaks gracias and we're basing our
dwarf Justin where's Lana
I do guy get out here hey hey my god
Justin oh yeah
Amador yeah I said okay okay yeah and I
my name is uh bumbly wumbly we're bumbly
type-c bumbly the dork that's what
you're really gonna go with so that's
really good at the door right yes that's
a terrible name
that's really it's it's fine I'm a new
guy I'm new gay yeah it's like wait is
it a name or a nickname then I mean you
said like which way you gonna go with
this is it a name or nickname you know
what I'm so eager that I let the guys
name me now you coming to the Thieves
Guild you leave behind your original
name and late you have to have hear of
the first door if ever I'm so excited if
I what's my name what's my name
you just give you that you can doubt you
can name him Roman we should we should
name him yeah oh yeah that's right Roman
do you like bumbly he just said that you
can name it we should name him you can
do anything you want anything anything
at all okay well we got a call to do you
go pick a name you can't pick anything
me I won't let you name him like
shithead now you that won't be
acceptable but if it's play what why are
you taking that off the table it has to
be it has to be okay
elvish I think it's a call really but I
mean look at them yeah look at him
we call him dwarf no okay you can call
them dwarf if you really wanted to hey
here's the here's what we're gonna do
he's dwarf number three for you why are
you calling him to work number three
don't ask about the first two
it's a long story then alright you can
just reserve those they seem really the
first semester is so excited is that try
harder is that the thing with your group
you always have one Patsy you bring
along it is always something not known
the little rabbits he did even ask for a
cut of the treasure it's amazing where
the best vagueness depends on dose man
we're gonna get out of here no we're
good we're good look you know what's
going on look at the size of them I mean
yeah look oh wait can you see Sir sighs
shit run what I'm out of here
oh I was resting I'm standing on a stool
it's fine
get-get back here I gotta tell you damn
quest McGarry kid over here hey all
right
is what's up I'm gonna I'm a I'll be
right back okay oh God
I'll be right back I'm gonna hang up my
hat you know okay here we go
much better it was so warm in here you
don't get to my eyes you kind of lovely
bald yeah okay you're right now I really
look like this have been with us touched
me in a bad way I guess what all right
okay where's where's your dwarf so I can
tell you guys you're adventuring or if
it's not wearing pants and we don't
really need the dwarf here just hide
ourselves it's just night so here's the
deal
okay um I need a key stolen it's a small
little elven town man I don't remember
the name it's not really important you
guys are gonna remember it anyway I'm
gonna give you a map and you guys are
gonna go find it now the thing with this
elf town is they are not going to let
dwarves or gnomes anywhere near it like
a hundred percent you guys are going to
be able to get anywhere near this elf
town if you just try to walk in the game
the best way in is to either you know
sneak through the main gate use some
sort of disguise or go the long way
around
go through the back inches of the
entrance of the cave now inside the cave
there's going to be probably coal bowls
and stuff but outside of that it's fine
you know you guys I'm sure you can
either sneak past with coal Bowl to deal
with it yeah I mean it's pretty simple I
just need to steal key um you know if
you get if you get lost
uh I think I got like a friend his name
is a jolt bill bot yeah jolt bill bottom
the PCV means he'll bill bother you can
help oh I'll jolts of real oh do we just
let it yell for him like I jumped no no
he's got a little Canio he's get he's
known he's a geek he's keen so he's just
not you too yeah we wait we might be
related to the soft rig like no uh ways
Joel - no I got no it's the baseball
trick it's just all Top Gun
yeah do you feel like you do anything
with you sure I don't know sure make
sure you know what I'm talking about
yeah okay so the exact key by the way
you got a steel is called the the
ancient key
some so that's what's called okay it's
the temple of the Fallen sons that's
where you're going
bunch of elves they're like special
assassin II mages very dangerous do not
do not fight any of them alone if you
fight them you will probably wait wait
you mean alone like blog ass alone or
one by one alone no no I mean like you
guys so we can't fight them I mean you
can but you don't you'd probably lose I
don't like their superpower yeah they
just basically I think if they get
alerted to your attention that you're
trying to get this stupid key you either
they're gonna send in someone really
mean and nasty her name is uh mom when
Wow good one yeah her name is Gwen Sun
sword that's it Gwen it's Sun sword
that's that's her name going at Sun
sword and she comes in she's gonna be a
real hassle for you guys you're not
gonna want to deal with that um so but
it's not a curiosity one what what kid
but why can't you get it um I mean you
got like all these magic powers that you
can blink um come on wait why can't you
do this what's what's it what do you
need us for me yeah I mean yo here hey
hey we're trying to get a job here guys
slut man I'm a rich wealthy wizard I
don't do the dirty work anymore I just
hired little mercenaries like I guess I
could go to it but you know I mean this
is a perilous job that's why I'm gonna
pay you ten thousand gold this gold will
roll over to the next adventure I'm
gonna pay you 10,000 gold split up
anyway Roman chooses in the next venture
so close man eyes closed about this but
I don't I don't like pompous ass wizard
gnomes whatever hell you are look I got
I got it again look it's a job it's for
a lot of gold doesn't sound that bad
apparently if these guys get a loan or
something they get all mad I don't I
don't understand I just I got it it's
not that they get mad when they get a
loan I'm just saying like you wouldn't
want to fight them
I mean we're gnomes they're elves I mean
you don't know me look at me like ticket
like a rule book or something so we can
keep this straight should we not get
away
feed them after midnight or something
when we rely right Oh what if we give
cover them with water
what happened yes they mune the sunlight
does your dwarf talk he's just been
standing there
he's a little simple really tidbits hey
dwarf what got his helmet he's super
happy go over there
Hey okay what's up go to sleep this
wicked just just ghost you don't need to
listen listen
right Wow I'm Thomas hamon slate or
remember you break it you bought it
alright chill out relax alright good job
right go back over there
alright keep an eye on whatever the hell
you got gracias okay okay
geez jacket my mom so yeah it see I mean
I'm not gonna do mean job you know hey
uh what's your name again row see this
is why we're not doing character me but
just call you it's over to Roman this is
you know we've done business before
haven't we haven't haven't you always
have and I always giving you good easy
jobs that just revolve around you know
killing few people and stealing it's
just a good job it's just I'm just
warning you you probably don't want to
fight the elves and if you do have to
fight the elves for the love of God
don't don't don't kill him just just
don't kill him what happens if you get
what a lot of the week it's a question
Oh in what context are you saying you
can get the weapon they don't melt there
anything that's that's fine but just
don't kill them what happens they both
apply no just just just don't kill them
if you kill them you will piss it's like
it's like shooting a police you know
what is are you like five stars
yeah no yeah will you saw a lot stars if
you have a good rating if you attack any
of them good police or them guards you
know it's gonna piss them all off
they're gonna come after you so don't
actually kill any unless you want to I
3x Anders Denham kill one um like an
oopsie make sure you know you make make
sure well if you accidentally kill
someone make sure you have someone to
blame on it that's so we blame you Oh
dead boats will leave a note I don't
know don't play D oh wait oh yeah we can
play the dwarf it's fine
yeah yeah exactly hey you're gonna buy
him one of your party members
uh I said it works I cannot but really
cares guys my name is Miss 'van your
name is you okay no that is my name you
cannot have my name so your names I see
you're miss 'van no I disagree this guy
no I'm me what's up guy no this is the
guy we need to talk to no no we're
talking this guy for the job
yeah yeah no okay what's the job yeah
that's up you know I could prank on in
this event that kills elves oh how he
kill elves do you cover water oh hey
everybody it's me discipline oh yes see
that's what a real wizard can do okay oh
that's whatever that's what a real
wizard could do we can transform all
right I add you're really not okay with
this right now
it's vengeance I can do that to you guys
so just do we have any more questions
this is the point of the game in which
you try to prod me for tips and I tell
you tips
oh oh oh yeah cuz throw water at him
Larry got that tip uh what right hmm
what why my door for number three but do
we go show her about it nobody cares
what's up is like a life and fauna will
we be dealing with on the edge um yeah
so it's a it's a pretty deep forest
before you get to the city um you're
gonna be fighting lots of elephants
which are basically half elephant half
Elks but twice the size of both all
right cool wait how many mermaid we're a
slice of which at both of them together
so they're they're like really really
big elephants carrots Worf right just
make sure he doesn't hurt himself right
sure something there's gonna be there's
gonna be some kobolds that good but you
know kobolds you you could be ever mess
with kobolds
there yeah yeah oh you you have mister
uh Justin yeah an ox action at what Cole
bolts are not our rocks and we drew a
circle on with the cobalt a through T's
like kill ago Paul I'm like I have the
high score is good I mean
are pretty peaceful so as long as you
know piss them off that's fine but yeah
thank you I'm sure you could you know
defeat the money right right follow-up
question what we get those wit get what
the cobalt work yeah um you know I don't
think I don't think I know I have no
idea so you're this big highfalutin
wizard you even know happens a couple
gets work I don't walk around here okay
I don't go around twisting like Nibin
step by step I don't know what sweat
all right go around throwing water at
things okay that's not what I do I don't
go around throwing water and on the fire
wizard so that's what we did at dwarf
number three when we met him yeah
especially I saw it happen this turned
it off as AK world followed us I don't
think it's the reason the water is the
reason you follow me I don't think
that's I mean those throw water and opal
they're gonna follow us it's just
circumstantial evidence use that what
happened it kobolds follow people who
throw water on them right that's since
mr. Dewey so if we throw water on an elf
it becomes a cobalt uh yeah I don't
twice the size of a cobalt yeah and with
like the power of an elk it's like
whatever the need is what a beaver I
don't the beaver
what the hell's a beaver I don't know I
paid was her guide you don't get we're
sorry it's yeah it's like a rat with the
UM you know like a slappy tail
I swear yeah wait what kind of looks
like dams just imagined to the beard on
his butt yeah it's a dwarf but the beard
goes on his butt that's basically what
they look like
yep so I'd say that's an accurate
statement huh it's nothing terrifying I
think it's a you can do what this thing
does but better yeah we can trade up do
you guys actually have any actual
questions that pertain to the getting of
the key it's a pretty simple what's the
key for that no I can't tell you see us
we all ask him oh hey hey girls listen
ten thousand gold pieces I don't need to
tell you what it it what its it gonna be
for what does it look like what does it
look like one of theirs keys I'll make
sure the gap um no he draws do you know
what the key looks like no is it a
traditional you're thinking what I'm
thinking oh hey I don't know get my
three throwing I remember is going back
to me hold on I need to get my hat go
let's go ready clunk it's good over the
head let's go get the key real quick oh
my god you're so nice arts great you
better not be just get your keys my my
goddamn door if you bring me my goddamn
keys yeah Kate woof give him the key ego
ten ten thousand gold lieutenant Ilia
please ten million a chain why do I have
to work with goddamn idiots this is just
my keys okay I know exactly what it
looks like okay it looks like a little
Sun you know what it glows orange it
comes about I brought about that yeah
glows orange did you find an orange
glowing key and that really hot don't
you cover a qian tang and come back here
i'm gonna know i mean sexually uh guys
guys guys that's me no specific once
right kim eyes open all right guys make
sure he doesn't get in the flower okay
some pink much hey how's it going this
event this is not gonna work hey how's
it going there dwarf key 10 million
Goliad is just a key okay oh dang shit
dwarf stop giving him keys wait what I
mean I would have done it first good
thing he's done my house keeps trying to
this off hey hey come on get going yeah
my house with Lily believe now mail
everything I got one less question got
one this question was your question let
me say we get you wet
yeah yeah I have to go in the bathroom
wait come back wait you lasted so uh hey
it's get the hell out of here go stand
over the equipment ready yeah jackass
that's the wrong way yeah keep walking
keep walking here you go eating
that's fine huh
why do we find these people from I don't
know what I just quit this but it's
horrible at all right
he was right here and then he then he
did this know we cope Naoko Oh bleh Oh
God
see it's terrible we should probably
should probably leave okay all right no
we're packing up we're getting out of
here really a mess with this ice house
is creepy we're tired of it I mean
you're tired of it all right Collins are
going I am though you don't say let's
get going that's what I say let's get
going haha that's good no that's not
what you say that's why you Ryder
no besides the horses need to go and do
I swear God I I'm gonna count to three
any butters going oh one two three
Oh young guys the phone's go and I'm
gonna go to sleep
hey bones hmm
I don't know how to get out of
dissidence house you guys are assholes
all right let's just come on follow me
let's get going
okay thank you I'm so I'm so confused
all right so guess that is the start of
the euros live campaign that we'll be
doing this week it's going to start
tomorrow 3:00 p.m. Eastern and if you
have watching this at a later time then
you're probably can watch it the next
episode already on YouTube so we hope to
see you guys all there it'll be at
twitch TV slash co-star there also be a
thing everywhere on the subreddit and
the Buffalo is his website they'll be
links in the description so please go
check out all the cool stuff we have
ready for you guys and we hope to see
you guys all there for the first show
this summer of run arose live yay all
right let's get going
you