everyone welcome back to UM Ron Rome's
live so this week we're gonna be doing
something way different than last week
so last week Roman was leader of a band
of thieves this week dead bones is going
to be our protagonist and you guys are
going to be a group of elves who are
defending a town and one of the patrols
has come back to tell you that there was
a large amount of porks we are orcs and
we put a pea in front of it so now
they're made another pig's three yeah
perfect it's the best race at least one
of them advance race we can currently
talk about so last week was a lot last
week you guys had a lot of problems in
combat and that was a little bit because
I made you way underpowered a little bit
because uh because yeah it was just a
little you guys probably were less
powerful than you needed to be to
probably get through encounters but it
was good though because um you guys
managed to dodge one of the hardest
fights in the game with those those
elves by sneaking past it which I felt
was that was probably one of my favorite
parts in the campaign because you guys
were a group of thieves and you actually
snuck past stuff which was cool see but
this week it's you guys are elves and so
you're going to be either badass wizards
and magicians and like combinations and
it's going to be a lot more fighting and
killing and I think this week when you
get to the the final encounter it should
be more or less something that you can
realistically be and not just a bunch of
gnomes versus a giant dog and the whole
rooms on fire what if the boss this week
is just a bunch of gnomes we're okay
they kick alright so we should win it's
the same no man is like reverse Vader
first are we gonna get a dog yeah you
guys just sit in the town and those come
in to be Chum they blow up your town and
go get away it's fun um so this week
you're all gonna be elves and elves are
special in that you pick your class you
pick your three abilities and then you
get to pick two other abilities from any
of this classes that can be selected
today
as long as they are spells you can tell
something that's a spell if it has the
little purple gem so you have to make
sure you do this in the right order like
if you want some warrior abilities
none of the warrior abilities or spells
so you have to be a warrior pick three
abilities and then pick another class
it's kind of important you pick it in
the right order or you won't really be
able to do what you're trying to do
until I do what you want to do there if
you do what you're trying to do there we
go putting the elf before his name just
I don't planning it so there's two
different types of elves you could be
though and this is really going to
determine what you want to do you can
either be the type of elf where anytime
an ally so anyone at any four of you
roles are critical you can use another
spell ability even if that turn yes I
know chant that and I spelled it wrong
so this is really good because if any
time you guys were critical if you were
all noble born you would all get one
free spell so it so it makes rolling 20s
way more substantial for the group well
yes
is this any twenty role so I want to
check for traps
I roll twenty many we start firing off
spells I'm going to limit it so you
could only possibly do one role per turn
so you can't do like like you're trying
to like and chain it you can't chain it
twenty Roman rules 20s so I'm going to
make it so it can only possibly be one
rule so we should probably say like the
first rule of the turn and maybe that
might be have to be something I need to
corporate in the card but it's gonna be
pretty loose you know sometimes I'm
going to forget and there's gonna be
five rolls maybe six rolls on an entire
round of combat so I don't know why I
gave you guys old noble board I was
hitting myself all we do is just key to
shoot at each other who me and then with
dodge and then we rolled it was the the
spell blade is the other class you can
be and this one so this one's going to
be pretty pretty important if you're
going to use more of a weapon I this one
can work uh use a melee should say or
range attack man I need someone to
proofread these in the future
Oh Oh actually counts on a range attack
- oh that each edge is maily or range
attack on adjacent target
oh I guess not tell me like it should
only be Amalia thing yeah yeah this yeah
yeah making sense it's a spell blade
yeah that's his range attack well you
got some dude right up in your grill I
mean you know you can use your you can
hit it with your bow sure yeah yeah you
could hit him with your bow sure you
ever do one damage just like your fists
remember well I do - those - yeah oh
yeah yeah I guess I guess of your staff
so but you would really want to only
pick this if you're going to be the type
of caster or if you're going to be a
type of warrior who you're gonna be up
close using a melee weapon anyway and
your spells are kind of just secondary
because then you could just use either
get a bunch of utility spells and focus
on just doing melee damage and but
always get free attacks anytime you have
to do a utility spell or get like a
cheap spell like the type of thing like
the flare or the ray of frost that
sorcerers have to do a lot of damage
because if you know you had like Justin
sword from the last game that did five
damage and then you had flare you could
obit you could basically flare someone
in the face for five damage and then
swing for ten swing for another 510 you
should really try to be thinking about
how can I do
five plus damage a turn last week I had
you guys pretty gimped and nobody
besides Justin could ever really do more
than 5 damage a turn but this week I'm
pretty sure that all of you guys are
going to be able to do like that 5 to 10
damage almost every turn they're not
unless it's just bad rolls and stuff and
or you're just doing a lot of utility
based stuff yeah now before we get into
classes Justin you didn't have you you
were dwarfed less like the only dwarf
and so you have your dwarven inheritance
but you know having treasures did you
know I got robbed
you got a of all your treasures so we're
going to give you a random treasure and
we're going to give it now because it
might determine what you need like they
might determine some of your choices
here anyway no treasure is going to be a
weapon and it's going to be just a
really crappy melee weapon it does to
range but if you roll a critical it'll
kill a target or do 15 damage this was
actually paid by a fan like when we
grabbed from the reddit I really liked
it
yeah because you know what if I get a if
I get my one you know melee attack of
return yes my skill so it could just be
instant yeah it might actually be okay
for spell blade yeah it might wake you
up that way I think I like that that did
change my decision
cool well done yeah because even if you
got a sec a different weapon you could
just have that in your pocket for
anytime somebody's close to you and it's
to range remember it's not it's not
necessarily just a melee attack right
it's to range so you don't you could do
it a little bit more than that so nice
it's a melee weapon with two kind of
like a flail type of thing FLI sword so
what you guys thinking for your sub
brace noble born or spell blades I'm
going noble born this will affect your
character member noble borns are gonna
be way more pretentious you know they're
gonna be pompous they're gonna be like
hahaha
going Noble born kills go noble born
Justin you think in spell blade then
because of that treasure card I am yeah
the Church of cards oldsman okay dead
bones and Roman remember dead bones you
are the leader for this hmm so I was
born to be Noble born Arango spell blood
oh we're gonna get most oh nice cool
that's this I like this so we're already
gonna have maybe two more male eccentric
guys into caster that takes the 5%
damage boosts mmm-hmm five percent
look at me I'm so terrible show
technically had more than that what
should that Roman because it's has a
chance Oh is he actually adds anybody's
yeah yeah so I got 20% right 20 percent
of math what six percent if I stop now
that works
oh if you proc your thing yeah yeah then
then you guys get to cast spells as well
oh yay time his Russell go kill
something oh yeah oh yeah that's it
that's it that's any time Justin rolls a
critical on a morals late swing
basically the party's gonna have a huge
turnaround Scott he's gonna kill us
something easy to kill something or D at
least do a big chunk of damage if you
guys are not gonna get free spells all
right so who is pretty solidified in
what they want
a bill that would want to go first on
looking at spells there's three new
classes a week we have sort Bart and
warrior returning and then we have three
very heavy spell classes and these spell
classes have really heavy stamina costs
lots of damage that comes from them the
only thing to take note other than some
other type of sand stuff is fireball
says seven it should be ten and that
might sound like a lot like whoa ten
damage but it's three stamina you got to
remember Justin used to do five damage
for no stamina cost just yeah I'm
swinging my weapon each turn so it's got
a really heavy cost but we have some new
caster based items that you'll
definitely be able to buy at the store
to help with that we have a staff that
will reduce stamina cost by one as well
as we have an armor that would reduce
stamina by one and we have a one that
can reduce stamina by one
now you can't combined all three mostly
because you don't have the gold and if
you get if you get something like a
staff to use your spell I'll just let
you guys do what you want this week if
there's a really balanced that usual
deal with it later but if you get the
staff and the cloth robes for example it
will reduce your spells by two now you
can't really get two staffs that wow I
guess if you're really one of the dual
wield two staffs you can just do it over
getting staffs and a robes but I'm
making your character walk around naked
if you do that oh wait wait wait we have
robes and we're naked no no I mean if
you didn't get robes and you've just
decided to pick two stabs cuz you're
even a leafy underwear because
technically there's no benefit to the
rope all right I'm gonna put imma put
increases your stamina by one on the
robes that way you're going to get
penalized if you pick up two staffs and
run around naked I'm just letting you
know
but yeah so these so if you get these do
spellcaster-type items you could turn
some of these classes that have really
really high stamina costs into more
reasonable costs to just be a
full-fledged spell caster but your cost
will be you won't have a real
auto-attack so things like spell blades
and stuff won't be really as effective
for you this is a melee weapon and you
won't get and you won't be able to get
some of the armor no he's just
I know okay this is a great one you
can't buy that now yeah no and you won't
and you won't get armor which armor is a
big amount of stamina now what we're
going to do for stamina this week is
last week I gave you guys I believe 20
stamina plus your whatchamacallit this
week I'm going to give you 15 plus
whatever your rule right now oh oh
really
yep if you get a 20 you can have 12 plus
20 stamina so who's rolling oh oh dude
not me Coco all right oh God
and if it's a one you lose all used to
fix so Co you will have 21 stamina this
week oh he's very nervous I'm going for
it dear old Justin terrified all right
oh well nice so you will have 25 wait
wait - 10 27
yeah 27 yeah I mean you go alright
bastard
oh look one of us is gonna get the one
it's gotta be me right we'll have 20 and
uh Devils your leaders good I mean show
them your leader hit points
oh right there you'll hello my god so
wow that uh yeah you guys we did its
Meier than last week but it's what I
have again 27 I'll check the video no 27
good twice oh that's the farthest one
cuz uh if I may I was gonna go uh I was
gonna go caster real heavy there you go
real heavy ko asking permission you
don't need to expert oh no I'm Justin I
was asking permission to be the first to
choose misspell Oh
Oh Devlin's is that okay yeah no it's
gonna go Justin ko Roman me okay whoa
you're gonna rest okay hey um
so which class is gonna be your starting
class before you pick your extra spells
Justin all right ah you gotta keep in
mind if you're basically if basically if
you want anything from Bart or anything
from warrior because Bart only has that
one spell yeah pick them first so leave
you know I'm I'm gonna start wizard then
cuz I'm not going anything from either
then okay so what I'm a wizard what do
you think of Wizards just whiz
has very little utility there just five
really different spell like damage
spells and you get to pick three of them
so you're gonna have a large variety of
ways to do single target AE and remember
that fireball does ten the card just
says seven
okay well I'm gonna go with fireball
okay that's for sure let's see I'm
thinking Blizzard was it looking nice
yeah
Blizzard has one of the new icons on the
card it has that little silver hand that
means you can only use it once per
combat okay what kind of it leaves that
little like it leaves the cloud there
until it gets busted up somehow a base
yeah so basically somebody does
something that could interrupt the cloud
like some sort of gust went wind yet
yeah you could mess up the cloud and
then it would get ruined yeah gotcha
okay also to keep in mind and this is
very important because lots of these
have these area things which are just
grids so a 3x3 would just be nine
squares they will hit allies so you have
to keep that in mind to be careful
fireball can be kind of scary because
when it critical is it's going to do 20
damage and if your allies are all
surrounded it's gonna blow up in their
face and hit them for 22 now with any
rule like that I typically give you guys
a chance to dodge yeah but you'll have
to keep that in mind for some of these
spells there's a lot of different like
wizard has a lot of these areas and line
attacks and you've got to be careful
that's why they're so powerful because
you can hit your friends with them so
the spell would be something like arcane
missles which you basically just pick as
many targets as you want and shoot
little one damage missiles like in that
gem lord encounter you will have been
ridiculous you would have been like
goodbye gem Ling's and just popped seven
at once yeah yeah alright I'll leave
that up for someone else I'm gonna take
ice blast well I'm all about ice blast I
like it okay the soul ice blast is
really good for just you know white
killing everything around you yeah
that's like my panic panic button so
what's your second
what's your other two spells that you
want to grab from another class what are
you thinking all right I'm gonna take
blink okay like that's a like that's a
cherry pick one just the boy I get free
turns out and I and blink was like my
instant getter on I really got you know
aa life dream Life Drain no like drain
life train is really powerful because if
you get the stamina cost reductions that
it's effectively healing you for more
because it gets for damage and you'll
get healed for for as long as it lands
even though it will cost three so you'll
always be getting one health but if you
pick up the the cloth armor and a staff
then suddenly you know you can you can
get healed for three each turn and but
it doesn't really do a whole lot of
damage so yeah it's really this if you
need to substan yourself for its yeah
it's like that say act to life that got
another panic button that's a panic
button yeah all right that's why that's
what guy that's a full damage build Wow
yeah Justin's gonna be a big deeps and
if anything gets close you're gonna pop
them with your your blades Shiva popping
pop don't win a damaged meters it's like
out so uh
KO's going next what do you think it go
Kabul Kabbalist sores have a little
wobble Kemalist I take kabalists
Kemalist would be the actual
pronunciation but alright what's what's
your first spell lifedrain I knew that
was gonna be popular with you guys we'll
see how strong it is because it doesn't
really do a whole lot of damage but uh
I've like just any form of healing is
probably really strong on this game ten
range though I flanked it of darkness
blanket of darkness so blanket of diet
darkness is another fog type ability but
this one makes people lose their mind
and so basically anyone in this is going
to do a roll and if they roll a one they
just go permanently mental I'll probably
be more lenient on you guys as you're
very intelligent elves but a bunch of
porks or whatever Yuri longed to in the
in the world there's going to be a lot
of confusion and we're messing things up
wouldn't you argue that well we're on
the intelligence bactrim they're so
stupid that it wouldn't really change
much
you know well it would make them more
likely to attack or run in fear type of
thing well it would make somebody's
their mine
they might just waste their turns and
stuff I'm going to make so anyone who
goes crazy they're gonna start doing fun
things so and Raven's claw yeah that's a
good one too that's a fun one for just
duty so that one can do a lot of things
if you read of the card it's not just
that it can do damage in a little radius
but you can also grab and hold people
think of it like that hand from Zelda
that would just come in and grab players
and take them to the beginning of the
dungeon it's that type of thing so you
can grab you could use it to grab people
instead of doing damage or you could use
it just to like toss someone around grab
you steal loot steal sir I guess you
you're gonna have to push my limits to
really use them to those full
effectiveness and so two more spells
from another class call earth Lord call
or earth Lord so this is one of these
pet abilities and basically what you're
going to do is you're going to make a
minion your out of dirt in stone you're
just going to summon it up at your turn
and you're gonna be like minion go kill
that thing and then his only purpose in
life is going to be to charge at that
thing and start attacking it until
either he dies or it dies and if he
kills that guy you don't you don't
control him in any way you're only or
you're only thing you get to say is
you're gonna go kill that thing you're
gonna go do this one thing and he's
gonna go do it until he either dies or
fulfills his goal when he fulfills this
goal he's just gonna and turn back into
mud and dirt and stone again on the
ground right but he's like a persistent
effect so there can be just you could
just earth Lord earth or earth or there
could be five of them and then you're
just all doing 15 damage they can just
stack and stack and stack and stack if
you want so another thing to note that
you guys should know is the pet gem now
the petram didn't have any real purpose
before it just was indicating that
summoned pets pets take pet you
generally control pets on your turn but
anytime a pet is attacked you either
take the standard damage yourself or the
pet is destroyed this is kind of
important to know because for something
like an earth Lord you know if the if he
just dot if those earth words just died
cuz I don't say how much health they had
because anything that hits them is going
to kill them that wouldn't be that
useful you know you spend your turn
casting at North Lord he goes out he
does three damage dies that's not worth
it but you can take hits for them so you
know if they're fighting like a little
weak things it's like your authority
attack for to damage you can be like
I'll take that you take that earth Lord
stays alive it's think of it like you're
spending your energy to keep it's
conjure like going anytime it gets hit
you're you're spending your mental it
you're becoming more exhausted to keep
it alive and then your last ability kill
summon frost elemental that cool so
frost elemental is going to reduce your
max stamina what did you ruin your
stamina you have 21 yeah so if you
summon one you're only going to have 11
stamina so that's that you should keep
that in mind when you're thinking about
armor because if you want to be a
technically KO you could you have just
enough stamina
unlike Roman to have to frost elementals
but you would only have one stamina and
it has it has the gem icon too so they
work the same way anytime a frost
elemental takes damage you either take
it yourself or it dies now you'll notice
it doesn't have a range and almost every
spell has a range you basically got to
put your hand in some water to conjure
this thing you got to find a pool of
water and you're going to summon it and
if you lose your frost elemental you're
going to need another big body of liquid
I guess of any source I guess you can
use anything but has to be a big big
pool liquid to summon this puppy the
frost elementals going to be able to use
the rare frost from the stork class and
the ice bolt from the Third's class each
turn just for free so you can basically
just have this army of dudes around you
that just summon real spells or
basically stun things and then just like
the earth Lord they can get kinda out of
control as time goes on in combat I have
a question about that
so your your maximum stamina goes down
when you summon one and then it dies you
get that stamina back okay and then you
lose it again when you summon it under
yeah so think of it see it'll just
reduce it and then the thief dies you'll
get that stamina back so if in combat so
you have 21 if you summoned it you would
have 11 stamina
and then if it died you'd still have
eleven stamina but your max would just
go back up to 21 understood okay and
then I think that's oh that's it for you
one to do for five all right cell Roman
what are you thinking because I know you
and Cole both wanted to do
they're just up are you gonna both be
pet buddies or you have a new idea okay
so the terrible role for the stamina
really kind of wrecked my idea idea how
little yep I was like uh um I'd already
I already accepted that I was going to
go Kabbalist cuz Co was gonna go there
just and then Co goes capitalist so I
think basically me and Co just like mine
screwed with each other until that's
either of us are really happy with what
we have that's my phone I told you guys
to talk about like cuz I before this
that we started I was like now you guys
to talk about it there's just some what
ideas you want to bounce off each other
and Romanenko both want to do the exact
same characters and then how you guys
are just gonna do neither of you are
gonna do it just you know it would be
these separate hybrid II I'd rather have
nothing yeah yeah no class no you know
two spells the pages are gonna be flare
and and large it'll just make big flares
you'd want to flare and double down yes
no that's that's how you'd want to do it
flare double but it's not about yeah
maybe I'll be poor could be barred that
could be barred and do that but yeah I'm
not gonna actually do that I mean
because flare could you could double
down like I know the reason why you're
one of the frost elementals cuz you
wanted a friend well you could just
double town coast frost I was ready to
happen yourself there's my oh oh
actually have two of them Oh double the
number of frost elemental not even think
about I was thinking just like that's
the size huh double downs not enlarge
sometimes like double you wait family
table something you can just help tell
me where you want to double I am sure ah
see that's we just fucked with Romans
class choice again damn it that's it
that's interesting like you could do
double down cult-like
like I said with the balance of the
stuff if ever solids overpowered one
week I'm too
gonna let you guys roll with a little
down fireball but yeah you can
definitely double down basically
anything for any damage
the thing is multiple that down is it
makes you have to roll twice for every
attack because you roll to do doubles
you roll to do the attack and that has
to land and then you gotta roll to
double down and if you fail to double
down you fail the roll you fail the
attack since that's an interrupt can use
on other people's skills yes because if
you failed up Lenny's their skill fail
no but it would definitely on yours
though okay yeah I wouldn't make it so
you're gonna screw over your friends or
you're gonna use it against enemies for
some reason but on yours it definitely
yeah I guess I could just make it so the
normal spell just goes off I guess it
just doesn't get doubled mm-hmm if
you're all wanted yep new holds of one
it if it rolls of one yeah but that's a
one you that's whatever like a double
down roll is gonna be a 50-50 like
that's generally it's gonna how it work
the only time it's going to be more than
a 50-50 is if you're trying to double
something ridiculous like what is double
the mountain yeah you're just like hey
Rob I want to double like something
ridiculous would be something like
trying to double a frost element thought
it's summoned because God would that be
strong just oh just have this free frost
elemental that would be really
ridiculous hang out at a pool all day
just yeah this you see how that works
I'll just be like alright that caused
your stamina you like okay we want to
rest like alright it's gonna take 20
minutes of you guys sitting around here
hopefully no porks come by we try to
summon that's all you gonna say and they
all melt alright um I'm gonna go
Kabbalist okay double Kabbalist double
Kappa life training ball sorc you are
working a life straight yeah okay with
you here for you guys
ravenclaw okay Raven your site near site
so near site is really really good at
the start of combat basically you could
save it and sometimes you'll probably
want to save it especially if you don't
know what things do because you're going
to make it so you reduce their range
down to one and it's an interrupt and
unlike most interrupts there's no real
penalty so if you just want to go your
site near second your site new your site
nice right on everything in the in thing
every
in combat I'm going to let you and
enemies if they want to get rid of this
near site because you're basically
blinding their eyes that I got to spend
a turn getting rid of that the that's
going to cost them a turn so it's in
some ways it's like a stun it's not
going to really stun melee guys but it's
going to stun to anything that ever uses
range which can be a really big deal so
um then I'm going to take wind blast
okay so when wind blast deals nine
damage and it knocks people back but you
can also use it as an interrupt to get
out of a way of an attack you're still
going to pay that the cost for it and
you won't be able to use your move on
the next turn but it's still really
powerful because you get to be like you
know just blast the wind and now I'm on
this side of the room it's lit it gives
you an it gives you kind of like a
guaranteed dodge it gives you like moat
like you know how sometimes like well
sometimes they give you guys dodges this
is something that you have more control
over you could dodge basically anything
you want to um okay question about the
air sprites do they spawn what can makes
can I spawn them up to ten units away
yes you control where they spawn and
once you've spawned them they're mine so
you're going to summon for air sprites
and I'm going to play for them for you
and they're just mindless attack the
nearest enemy target they'll never talk
to you and will never attacked allies
these things don't have like minds of
their own so not going to be affected
like things like fog or something that
can't really be charmed they're wispy
they are they pieces of errors in log
yeah they're just pieces of air essence
and but they will not listen to you in
any way they are not necessarily your
friends like once enemies are gone
they're just going to hang out until
they just kind of dissipate type of
thing okay would we still say there are
allies they can they create you want so
can they crit can they anyone he wants
no can they get in again yes they can
definitely critical but love but I but
as I established last week when I have
to do multiple roles for small little
minions I only do one die but okay but
it will be yes you could get in Krita
whatever that's got cool free spells
it's cramping alright so then will do
will do air sprites is it wrong but I'm
sad they don't stun you know what Roman
I
in the card but then I was like man I
don't want to have to calculate all
these stun roles and what stunned what's
not stunned evident chain stun it was it
was something I almost tried to do
though it's okay it's okay
I'm happy with this all right dead bones
you're the you're the last one here huh
so by a tonight my character decision
was completely based on the fact that I
forgot I was the leader this week you
leave this week yeah so I'm thinking I
have to go something I thought complete
change what I was gonna do but now I
think I got a good one well you you're
on a team of like I really built casters
just join there's gonna be fast cuz I
feel like a dragon bit uh no no no no
dead bones there no no you you never
have to rush scared agree the reason why
what I already have it I know it I know
but what I'm saying is is a like these
videos are okay to be like okay we can
we can be already stabbed with the fans
that like a if we want to take our time
to properly make our characters right
they wouldn't want us to rush through it
and that's why we don't do it on stream
and that's why we did on this video so
don't ever feel like you have to rush
this stuff we can see it until I can
nerd out as much as we want here okay
cool alright well I'm gonna be going
warrior okay thanks I'm going to get
blockade chivalry and tosser seems
familiar for some reason and Nelda Lee
before hold on before there was one
thing I wanted to bring up cuz Justin
never used it um and I think it was just
cuz you guys didn't know when somebody
uses block a blockade you guys can
control whoever is blocking as your move
you can move them right you can move
that shift you can shift them yeah okay
yeah no you can move them the full five
spaces oh you can just like push forward
you can bring out lock tips yes pretty
yeah you so basically you can use your
move for them on them oh but that's an
important thing to remember because I
don't there could have been ways you
used it and I think it was just cuz in
order for a blockade to really work
everyone in the group has to kind of
remember that they were never up
together at most times like Justin Lee
usually the front we were got kind of at
the back so wouldn't really yeah it
would never got ya if it was a snake
fight yeah I see what you're going for
already alright what are your other two
abilities are going for linking for a
flare blink and flare
okay so you're going to be spamming
flares kinda I am the defect during
spamming flares well just like
teleporting around to block it link lock
link block chiller II I don't actually
but whatever tosser yeah yeah we did you
like it surely no I didn't get you look
okay did did I do that I did okay yeah
chivalry yeah
okay so last week uh last week Deb
Justin got a treasure for playing at
dwarf I'm also gonna you guys still are
still have only a thousand gold but I'm
going to be giving five hundred gold to
the person I thought had the best RP
moment and 500 gold toward the person
that chat thought that had the best
therapy moment well people chat definite
least their favorite was Phillipe he was
lost everybody loved him he had just fan
art at the but and Philippe was
definitely caused because of chose
actions so we're gonna give the fan
favorite for last week to Co and my
favorite RP event and this is something
chat did not like but I just loved it is
the fact that Roman decided to surrender
which in this type of game I just never
see happen people either like die
fighting or like they get into the video
game mentality but Roman just got to a
point where he's like no I give up
anybody got up in his hands and knees
and surrendered which was so hilarious
because that then just played out that
he still got to escape like I can
visibly see it as if it was like a movie
you know just like the I gives up and
the dead pose because that explosion
comes by just like I need that gem is
like oh you should have room I love that
so we're gonna be giving Roman an extra
500 gold so everybody got something
besides dead bones that's cuz you wanna
but I'm the leader
you went anti-party like all you need
this you don't see tell them about the
new loop thing right what part of neelu
thing we're gonna get it every time he
kills oh well well that all I could talk
about on Saturday uh last week we didn't
really get to do a lot of treasure cards
from looting on bosses and so and a lot
of people wanted to do supportive things
for the stream like being able to sort
poor people and we have some ideas for
that but you guys will just see it
Saturday
and there'll be lots more like treasure
along the adventure or treasure because
there's not going to be a lot of
treasure cards this
week because there's no gnomes you guys
don't really have a lot of money so who
knows already what they want to spend
their money I will add you I guess I
should reveal these treasure cards so
yeah let's let's see that first let's
see what we we have new treasure cards
in the mix uh not really
there's there's only there's only a
couple but we didn't see many last week
anyway so there's only a couple there's
work blade
there's a spell word armor spell word
armor I believe has changed and now also
increases your stamina and anytime
oh yeah this one's oh that's pretty good
any time you were hit by a spell by the
opponent you get a copy of that spell
and you can cast it once so think of it
like if you get hit by any spell and
it's a spell and you're going to ask me
Rob what's that a spell I'll be like yes
you then get to cast it once so
sometimes it'll be wrong but what no no
it's every time you get hit by a well if
you fight anything that's a wizard and
hey and you get hit by a fireball I'm
gonna give you a copy of fireball you
get a gag once I could run into a
blizzard you gave to people you could
run into a blizzard and get a copy of
blizzard hey I probably would not make
hay I probably would not keep giving you
copies of blizzard if you just purposely
stand in the blizzard but I'll give you
one if you do it I want to move out and
then back in oh god not another fucking
Ruby yeah there's a a catalyst oh and a
nebula bones the crystal catalyst last
week you guys use them use them on the
fucking jet learning count
aliens and it was not a good place to
use these things mind you these things
will be your allies and now that we have
the pet system if you want to take kids
for gem Lane so they don't blow up by
all means and you should be able to
control them maybe this needs to be
changed they work more like air spirit
sprites so I just have them all just
attack whatever's nearest um but at the
st. but at the same time they will be
your allies as long as you don't fight
another gem Lord and then use it I guess
the gem board which all that come on I
mean come on oh man I want to spell worn
armor fuck I'm on the leaders sorry I'm
sorry Ted phones are I'm sorry Justin
here's the leaders this is gonna
stablish a Soviet resentment just so you
know think about this way just a mine
makes more sense because I can blink in
front of spells and take them
yeah well the yeah I I think it makes
more sense if you think about Justin
because he's going to be using shiver
Lee so anytime you guys would get a hit
by a spell he could purposely jump in
front of it take it for you and then you
guys get a spell oh sure I'm still gonna
resent him for anybody cuz you know
officer whatever that's that's the start
of my characters I hear at the shop you
bought it so do what okay so we there
was a point where there was supposed to
be a wiggly wrench and some reason who
said it wrong so I purposely made a rig
early wench as well card and it doesn't
do anything
it's well you little does can that be
its hanyan it's a it's a crap treasure
man it's if you super-bright something
he just breaks it no no no no it's a
week it's a wriggly wench so it's gonna
be a wrench name wig wrigley and she
falls you around she's not useful
she doesn't participate in combat do
something I get you you get a wench
to follow you around it's it's gonna
have nothing other than RP benefits so
all now I'm considering so initially
read it as a wrench and I was like oh so
now like a person it's a pretty it's a
person her name's Wrigley and she is a
wench not only just a person it's a wet
wood what I have like a wench on hand I
don't know
very like I don't know lucrative gonna
think a long-term here just Justin
there's a lot of dudes where we are it
also lets you destroy your treasure
cards whatever you want which man's nice
you can kind of get a cursed treasure
you know there you go see now you're
thinking oh crap we're to get cursed
treasure you sure take in the woods are
you is anyone buying anything
uh nah the treasures I have a question
you talked about dual wielding staffs
hmm yes well what is your questions
about Google buildings uh so can I do
wheel stabs and get my cloth robes
oh did so you'd have my money you have a
minus three you have the money for that
um
I'll let you do it if you really want to
if you also losses yes if I'm dual
wielding stabs do so I would have a
skill in dual wielding so whatever
you'll attack with those steps
no no um no so the reason why you
wouldn't be able to do it is because you
need a hand free to cast spells you
always need one hand free to cast spells
huh
so you'd have to have one of your staffs
in your back which means you want to be
in that bonus room and so you could do a
wheel staffs but not if you get the
cloth robes as well
well like well no you could do a wheel
staffs but then you'd have to cast then
you would be able to cast spells yeah
that's how I cast them as you can to
will staff so not what do you do it okay
now why do you have no cos spells for
this adventure ugh it's really nice
besides I got used to it all right
ah I'm gonna buy the Ruby then oh yeah
just Ruby's the best yeah I cannot have
his Ruby come on good treasure and then
I'm gonna buy the stage this one's this
one's family this was actually one of
the newer ones another another fan made
this one I thought it was wrong so this
is this is a one-time use essentially
but you reveal it to someone and they
get stuck in the mirror okay
Aiko hey hold up it's fine you can have
it right um if this mirror breaks so
when your backpack this thing's going to
come out of it and that's the only thing
you can do you can trap one person in a
mirror and once they're in the mirror
the only thing left to do with this
treasure is basically accidentally break
it or purposely break it to release
someone you could trap anyone you want
they're just stuck in the mirror that
one time so sewed up with coke the only
gold did I have you know did we have you
have 1500 yeah so I will let you know
that if you try to use this that gets
really really big things you're gonna
have to roll 20 break but if you're just
if you're just doing it on normal things
or things that aren't really like super
bossy like that's fine or hard or maybe
if they're weakened
like hey if you weaken a boss and then
you want to put in the mirror that's
fine but treated like Pokemon okay
the structure it is you know the less
likely the mirrors going
work on it but if they're weak and you
want to keep them in the mirror because
you rather do that by all means the
treasure card okay fact which is always
fun especially all these new spells no
kiddin um also take a staff in the cloth
armor hologram so that'll be Roman done
boo boo boo uh what do you think dead
bones you have 500 gold left here and
that spell worn armor also completely
changed what I was going to do you you
really kind of need a weapon here see I
was Hebrews I was gonna have whip and I
was gonna go plate armor but now got
that I'm just gonna get fucking mace oh
yeah yep yeah so the new thing with mace
is you could choose such make it's done
rather than doing damage all types of CC
are like diminishing returns the general
idea is you can stun some you can do
different types of CC maybe once or
twice on an enemy and it's really not
going to work unless you're rolling
really high and that's just the type of
dr we'll use for not permanently
stunning things for entire combats I
have a question yep can I wear two sets
of rooms no no I don't want I don't want
to stab hey you know what you want you
get uh suck you just man what should I
know no oh my guess is you rose to the
staff reduce the scooping time well now
I want resumed items come cold what you
don't want alright I could take okay
every but it's still really almost so
here's what I'm gonna do with all these
costs reduction things I'm gonna make it
so you cannot reduce something to 0 yeah
yeah I'm not because I generally only
make things 1 or 3 you've never seen it
a two already and I can put that on the
card I can just be you can't produce
anything to zero and that doesn't mess
electricity Romans doing so yeah that's
it's it's just I don't really want to
get into that realm of completely free
cost spells or anything like that I I
just wanted for the sake of I don't want
two ropes yeah I don't know I can't
understand that Roman did you want to
would you like your staff and robes or
did you want to be naked with two staffs
that's your call by the way it's I mean
you had your eyes set on it
in there so I wasn't sure well I mean to
be fair I was also imagining like
spitting around to staff that's pretty
badass
fire I have no idea how spells are gonna
be cast but I'm sure I figure out a way
um like there's like dual wielding isn't
something you get just for having two
weapons I think there's I think it's
like a dwarf racial hold work yeah I
think certain classes will be able to do
that type of double attacks and so
there's certain passives you get that
lets you attack twice and that's kind of
dual willed but not just because you
have two weapons now so I'll stay with
this rope and so I think Justin's broke
Devlin's broke oh you got a thousand
bucks buddy you're the last shopper here
yeah I'm going to buy uh cloth robes and
a staff yeah I just it's it's pretty
much if you're going to be a heavy
caster you're gonna always rock that
it's just the same yeah I was trying to
think it through was like oh I got the
leather or the studded armor that's like
five cast difference and then I get that
I'm also sexy so uh if I was if I hadn't
oops sorry good Oh knows the fight still
the fights went way too long that it was
just like nag you can't oh you were
gonna get the wand yeah because of the
one we're going to make a ten range that
way it's at least makes a little bit of
sense but you're gonna get that if you
can get the mirror well no I had it
armor Oh gals are also consented order
too if I hadn't got the mirror I was
probably going to get a bunch of
quickness elixirs hmm well one thing I
mean you could if you wanted like you
don't need to get a - to like - stamina
on a spell is pretty it's not bad you
know what I mean I love spam and I
remember 21 yeah yeah um you didn't do
to eat crap on the rolls really really
bad we had was five or six and eight and
then a 12 out of 12 then I'm actually
you know maybe instead of cloth robes
you instead it because we'll think about
it like this I think that just I'll be
less about to die if I get a water
elemental frost element well and also
think about it like this like in order
for something like
studded armor to be worse than your
cloth robes you effectively need to have
casted 10 spells 505 well because you're
in a cast spells at two per wait why was
my math night off I think it's kind of a
wash actually they get to wash because
if I get this then I'll have 31 stamina
right but all my spells are going to
cost two so that means if they're going
to drain my stamina the same rate if I
use the same number as if I have the
cloth robes yeah because yeah so to wash
doesn't fucking matter like it's like if
I had that I would could he as in
elegantly kill blinds more attractive
and people for trash man yeah yeah dude
Saint ko well someone has chills it's
like a good thing and there's that point
I think I'll just try it cuz it doesn't
matter yeah I mean like like what what's
the map on that shouldn't it be like you
have to cast ten spells for it to be
worth it because this one gives you ten
and it's only a one cost reduction like
if you're not casting more than ten
spells in a fight it's actually it's not
really worth it yeah I feel like I feel
like I want to keep it only because of
Blink yeah the the I think I think the
the biggest thing the reason why you
have to consider it is because of the
life tap ability and you you have that
to KO because that makes it so you're
effectively gaining more stamina like
that's a big deal but like you said
because you're gonna rock a frost that
amounts mental to would be at 11 health
that the whole idea you you use life tap
yeah good job ko you regained half your
life like you could get knocked out in a
turn without some armor so I think
that's smart
alright so there's a patrol on his way
back dead bones and he's going to be
coming to tell you guys the report on
what's going on in town but I don't know
if you want to meet with any of your
your your fellow soldiers your fight
desserts your conjurer fellow wizards
yeah you know theta squad
I'll get you elf ears is that that's
what you wanted for sex if I want elf
ears in a wig elf ears yeah if you guys
have happened
sinem I keep going with that hat Justin
okay okay how's this playing with that
before
Devlin's what's your name by the way
what do you what are you gonna go on
character name the swings how fuck had
it uh Carol Carol is that your first and
last name is it just first name Carissa
first name okay cool last name are you a
boy character what do you know it's a
girl it's a girl
okay cool it's a lady lady lady elf like
Brienne yeah that's kind of what I was
going like Brienne of Tarth okay who's
gonna be who's gonna be your trusted you
know second command who defends to
offend your town you know I don't have
one
you don't have notices that this is the
theta squad this is this so these are
all trails the alpha squad we didn't we
lost the alpha squad but beta squad we
couldn't find baseboards Epsilon squad
we couldn't find epsilon squad so we got
fucking theta squad they're all casters
and one of them's I'm pretty sure it'll
touched in the head buttons whatever
okay they can just come out whenever
ordered like find themselves coming at
him well Roman what is you're gonna be
your character name then Templeton
faster reporting for service sir yep
sobbing I didn't I forgot to do my voice
shit all right whatever
well you can still do your voice that's
fine I can great this is the setup for
Saturday right yes this is when you were
you're establishing the characters right
if you're gonna totally got in character
buta if you got to change things now's
when you change it okay cool
can I help you sir madam madam madam
sorry are you a girl - Roman no okay
you're a very pretty girl it's the hair
in the Hat robust it looks I don't
understand you should have a little
flower see I am NOT a girl whatever just
go get your um what's the other one
called Justin what's gonna be your name
what's name Oh is my name can't remember
you know that one ah I'm going to be how
would it be the write-up ml Mar el Mar
okay L know MA
llamar I was going it's going good
el martes Amanda just I'm gonna go all
Professor Oak you are you a boy or a
girl Oh
check you see this my problem with every
boy doesn't want to tell and sometimes
you understand why you can't figure this
out Oh extremely feminine and I'm used
to the males looking a lot stronger yeah
all right okay you're all like you're
all growing dresses for one thing that's
well I think one of you is now in Coe
what's your character gonna be my name
is de nada
I don't know I don't know are you a girl
nah what is with you guys
unisex names this week is that just an
elf trope are we just gonna make it in
order to be an elf you have to have a
name that's kind of way as a pretty
adronis right okay
my name is extremely masculine wasn't
him again Templeton implement Templeton
Templeton Templeton Templeton what
Templeton barring stir bear bear rings
two bearing stir nice a with me Baron
Baron King in stir fuck bearing stir
what this guy's Elmer L mark and I are
gonna de your Dennard antenna does it
get like this is why during the campaign
we'll just call each other room and just
this is we go hard remember Nate
yeah uh yeah but maybe if we had like a
little indicator at the bottom of the
screen man yeah we're evergreens
what are you sorry is a bunch though
fuck is a scream what is your title by
the way dead bones are you a lord or you
lookin man oh no no I'm uh I'm uh mm
yeah let's go a cap the cap is not too
highfalutin hey captain works captain
Carroll oh yeah I am works on so you
don't have you don't have any like
lieutenants or anything these are all
just
recruits not new recruits this is the
we've run out of actual people that we
want to use oh all right so our Roman
Justin uh Coe or any of you guys are you
new Wizards are you I don't know but it
was it for many many years
well you visit runs in my family oh you
really doesn't look like a wizard
he's a very wizard like do you see the
staff yeah the robe yeah but it says
here on your document that your
kabalists a capitalist novelist
Kabbalist florist catalyst okay whatever
you say I don't I really I just
addressed yep whatever say it with me
man in a dress all this catalyst go
stand behind damn Elmar just go you
believe this is in charge what's your
name hey Roman that's why we only use
yeah I just use real names these
actually our excuse me what bearing stir
I don't if you talk to me Oh Justin
hello Justin hi Justin yes ha ha ha fuck
the names hello Justin hey dead bones
good okay you're looking so here are
very robes yes yeah this is and he's got
a plate I don't have a dagger yeah I see
that I'm like a I'm like a shifty
shadows I got I thought that's what
what's with the two robes I'm cold
you're cold I have low blood temperature
oh dude sick robes
thank you see oh man I thought about two
L's I don't thing I could pull it off
but dude nice yeah device he's got to I
spells so you know it's when you're
casting uh-oh where - he's a silly
wizard is it chilly verily wizard got it
heard of those things I am Elmore the
chill like normally we'd have like an
ice mage or a frost wizard but you're
just you're chilly wizard sir do you
wait a bit long
music like waily waily and papers
where's the other one hey hey Elmer hey
I'm not joining this Ray what applause
okay uh here lies your uh your men don't
seem to respect you much fynbos yeah I
figured that much
oh it's cold what did you do do not play
chilly Willie's with him he's really
good
I don't oh I don't even care - jet boots
captain dead bones it's terrible well
total honks what there's over 50 ports
in the caves
I think they plan to attack the village
did you say 50 over 50 you're even
you'll be I've counted them myself I'm
really good at counting you how did you
get that close to count them I mean this
thud I that's why I said there's over 50
I saw at least 50 and then you ran oh I
came back to report the news to you you
wouldn't believe it
hmm they're dead who's dead the doctor I
just saw them five minutes ago he's
lying
wait the porks a dead weight the porks
are not dead they're coming to a temple
a village with squatting from and from
your squad my squad yes I've been with
you for the last three years
really yes a bit along your side
patrolling the towns guarding the towers
are you a boy or a girl
well um dead bones yes I have a pamphlet
for you it helps you identify boys and
girls ha ha ha this this will be very
helpful all you have to do is ask if
they want to play chili willies ah no
clever he also has a pamphlet about how
to say his name it's really fuckable do
you have a gun a fair I'm going to call
you Tempe ster Tempe so we got is we got
this Goff Eco wizard
we got a commander who has no respect of
his troops we
got chilly really or chilly really with
surgically really was easy I mean of
chilly willie feeling really the
champion of Willie's and then we gotta
get this other wizard who's this pompous
nobleman who insists on his greatness
good Capleton barrister Templeton
Erick's you normally don't give what
characters last names but I like it
Roman I like it it's good so this will
be the campaign that we'll be playing
this week tomorrow so I hope you guys
have are really excited last week was
really really fun we're trying a lot of
new things we're having everyone play
really different characters it's going
to be a lot more action II type of
campaign this week just to mix it up
we're hoping to just do lots and lots of
different things explore everything that
works and everything that doesn't works
and there's always going to be little
kinks like I know you guys are seeing
typos left and right I'm terrible at
spelling and this is going to be
something we're always changing and
upgrading and yeah you guys have just
been so passionate and so supportive of
this already we're really excited
all the guys including me we were just
like yeah can it be Saturday already
because we really just want to do this
all over again and yeah um I hope we go
see you guys tomorrow yeah yeah oh yeah
it's a voice in the sky we're barbecuing
the porks if they want something not it
you can't be dead I'm come down they're
not