all right hey guys welcome back to
upfront roms live we're doing the behind
the scenes for the second campaign pork
hunters so a couple things to talk about
this week this stream was hard I tried
so the this last that last week I was
working on getting Dwarfs vs. zombies
out I'm I have a video I think maybe
even later today earlier today or
sometime today about tours for zombies
and about all that stuff but I kind of
over worked myself that week I launched
it on Friday night the night before this
and I still had some you roams prep work
to do so I didn't really get to bed
until 10:00 a.m. so I did the show with
about three hours of sleep so so if a
couple things felt off in my execution
that was very much my fault the one
thing I did not take care of this week
very well was myself and I kind of paid
for it because the day after I had the
source of back Sunday Monday Tuesday of
this week I'm recording this on actually
Thursday so all the episodes are already
out and I want to do behind the scenes
but I've been so busy and I had pulled
my back I've never had a back injury
this bad
like the type where you know you just
don't you can't get out of bed type of
thing and I was so worried but this week
I've only really focused on doing this I
I had some other stuff that I wanted to
do this week I decided okay I can't do
that this week I'll just push it back
and we'll just focus on this week's show
and this week's shows turning out to be
very really exciting but we're inside
but last week so anyway last week again
I was I was really tired things didn't
go flawlessly because of my mental
exhaustion if the show felt a little
stale and more combat II it was because
I was relying more on what I had written
and less of impromptu I got my second
wind about the time we were going to
well I was pretty intricate the entire
time because I've kind of developed this
ability to just go on like just turn
just beyond exciting energy as much as I
can
even if I'm completely exhausted but I
got that second wind and stuff I wanted
to do in the second half when they got
into the pork cave but uh but overall
I'm going to try to never let that
happen I mean if a week comes up and
there's a bunch of stuff that's not
ready I think I will either delay the
show and start at like 5:00 or 6:00
Eastern Time or even later and just be
like sorry Europeans not this week
watched on YouTube or I will even just
push the show back a week this is
something that's really hard because
this is the type of show where basically
you gotta think of it like this so I
mean so here's how it works
if we do a show on Saturday and then on
the Sunday I'll talk to all the guys
about euros live we'll get some opinions
in the last show I'll do some talks I'll
start doing some rudimentary planning I
need to talk to the guys and plan out
the base idea right so I need to plan
out all right this this next week we're
gonna probably be like elves or
something and they'll tell me what they
want to do with characters and stuff and
then I got to go plan the campaign and
that involves me drawing like a very
crappy version of the maps you see
because I got to pass that over to Megan
sir to get the artist but it also
requires me to start coming up with all
the major things that I want to do in a
campaign to do events that way Nick can
start doing the little animations you
guys see Nick also has to be able to do
all the little arts that goes on these
tiles so anything that I want to add new
this week I need to kind of get to Nick
as fast as I can because on average he's
gonna end up doing 15 plus little
five-second animations and they're
they're not the biggest like fanciest
animations but it's really hard when you
only have you know a very short amount
of time to get all of this work done so
me me him and Megan are all just kind of
like powering through this each week to
be able to put on the show we do and you
guys shouldn't be worried about Oh Rob
don't overwork yourself I know I'm I
know I know last week I kind of did but
I can kind of tell when I'm getting to
my limits I know that we're gonna need
to take a break I would say every four
to six shows and I know that we're only
to be able to do this for maybe nine
months a year so I think probably like I
said we still have to talk so these
aren't much final but I think we'll
probably do something like take
September off take January off and take
April off type of thing and that'll give
us the space we need to regroup because
the thing is you guys always have these
suggestions for like what I can do with
the Puppet Pals and do this and then
this and there's no time let you know
what I mean like at this point like all
the time to make the Puppet Pals program
and do all the puppet stuff and get all
that free pre work done has been used up
and so we're gonna need that time to
really be able to focus on doing this
more now mind you all the stuff that I
have to do I can pretty much do in about
two to three days which is what I need
to do because I still have
responsibilities for LOM and DBC but
also this fall me and this event are
working on the unforgotten quest game
which some of you probably don't know
about but a couple years ago there
actually used to be a show called on
Forgotten Realms and it was a cartoon I
would make and then I kick started to
gain from it and that whole project
maybe maybe you know or maybe you don't
know but it's been kind of like just
it's gone on a roller coaster for
emotion of what's gonna happen with it
but it's still something that I really
want to get done and finished and do
well and now that we have you mom's live
it's a great platform to take everything
we're doing here and put it in a game
because generally it's all the same type
of stuff it's just my comedy and my
stories and now I get to share it with
like a lot of other great people and so
doing a game off that is really for me
like that like if you haven't figured it
out I love designing games
I love making games I've now created
this show that allows me to do a type of
cartoony fun that one fur on drums was
but at the same time I get to make
classes in games and parts of a game
each week I like somehow built this
weird like combination of all the things
I like and all the things I feel I'm
personally good at into a show but I'm
gonna completely off track that I'm just
kind of talking about everything but
don't worry too much about me over
exhausting myself I know we're gonna
take a break here
at the end of this month take a week off
and that'll be the time we need to let
us get a week ahead I won't actually
take a break I'm not saying you're a
critic seller I'll take a critic in
September but I don't let us get that
week ahead so things are no longer
stressful so now I'm a campaign ahead we
have a lot of stuff ahead and that'll
let us give us a lot of breathing room
for you know if we need to take some
just days off and more time to polish
and stuff but big improvements to like
all our systems and how we do the show
and people like talk about oh you should
add music and all this stuff those are
things that I'll need the longer breaks
for they'll need breaks for when I can
actually take time to get breathers and
actually do the research and development
people don't always think about that but
sometimes when you're building things
like this show you need time to just you
know figure it out like you know coming
into tabletop simulator and figuring out
how you're gonna do tiles how you're
gonna do spacing how you're gonna do
this game how you're gonna record it
like can you do something like Puppet
Pals okay can we do something like that
like this is it this is the type of time
that you guys don't only see because
it's always hard for people to like wrap
their mind around how long it takes
something to takes people to just get to
the point where you can start producing
the content so all the little changes
that you guys have with just do this
just do this most of it are great
suggestions and I would love to even at
least try but I'm kind of limited in
what I can do right now and some of you
will offer to help I have had lots of
programmers and artists and all these
people offer to help but you also have
to understand that it takes time to be
able to start delegating and to build
that trusting relationship with with
artists and programmers and stuff and
right now in the middle of summer I have
no time to sit down and talk to people I
already do a lot of that each week
between talking to my guys talking to
the artists I work with talking to all
just everyone that trying to bring in
new people would just be more of a
burden than anything else so I greatly
appreciate anyone in their offers for
doing this stuff and I'm not saying
don't offer your talents I'm just saying
at this time like I don't have time to
even consider any
thing I know that like I always want to
be very community focused like the the
t-shirts the teachers for blender bros
went fantastic
they're gone now you can't have one
because we're only doing like quick week
sales people have asked are you do a
t-shirt every week and the answer is no
but maybe because if we have these cool
designs that we really like and that we
would just want to collect I kind of
like the idea of just having them for me
personally this just like memorabilia of
t-shirts that I can wear that are just
the dirty of Forgotten Realms references
and stuff like that they're just cool
designs that's that's cool to me so they
don't really even need to do well like
if we have these cool shirts and they
sell like 20 of them that's that's fine
because I know I'm gonna I would get one
I know Co would get one and with and
with websites as easy as spring tea
it really isn't a burden for us to do
that so we don't know we don't know the
donation goals i buffed this week and
some of you seem to think that they were
coming in slower but they weren't if
you're really thinking about it like
last week that donates the first the
first the first battle we went into was
50 100 and 150 and this week it was 400
400 800 and and that 800 came in in one
round so that's like just just the 800
alone is that's almost like over double
right 50 150 50 100 150 that's 300 yeah
that's so it's almost triple the amount
right the diligence came in same good
came in fast but that's really good
because that means that I don't
necessarily need to rely on always doing
like four or five or six or seven or
however many combat events I need to do
each week I can factor in more role play
which is important to me because a lot
of the fun that you guys love comes from
both the combination of the in combat
and under combat scenes and outer combat
scenes fundamentally really can't have
donation goals it's one of these weeks
I'll probably try them and I kind of do
in the sense that I let you guys force
and counters on them but
we'll kind of see the show did really
really well it did a little bit better
than last week
honestly if the show keeps doing this or
even like 60% of what we're doing plus
if we're selling you know on average 50
t-shirts a week I'm excited because it
means that not only are the show able to
do everything I expected it to do but
more it's gonna already have started to
have do little tiny things with some
people I've already started to work
towards other goals in the future for
things like expanding this show and just
Buffalo wizard stuff so that's awesome
I hope it does too well a lot of you are
like worried because people are like oh
but people are gonna burn out and not
have enough money well and one thing you
need to understand is we need to build a
show that's based around people giving
like two bucks five bucks ten bucks each
week because while I'm we I greatly
appreciate these we've had some really
big donations we've had some people that
have put over like 500 bucks in a show
or a thousand books on show and trust me
I greatly appreciate anyone who could
support us that much that is crazy but
at the same time it's important for me
that the show has enough to be supported
off not just by these big big donations
that let us keep the goal get to keep
the goals that we're trying to make but
by these smaller donations because
smaller donations means that you know if
one of the fans who was major supporting
us but maybe he just grows old
maybe he runs into some personal finance
issues it doesn't cause a show to suffer
so I want to keep building a fan base
that is consistent enough that we just
have enough people donating you know
just 2 bucks or five bucks or 10 bucks
just unless is like thank yous for the
show just if you were to go see somebody
performing on the street you're like hey
you know what I like that chick you did
with the sword on the head and you gave
them a couple bucks that if we can build
that but on the internet then this show
will be very stable and it'll be very
dependable income and it will give give
me personally a massive opportunity but
all the guys I'm working with really big
opportunities to keep doing the type of
stuff we're doing so don't worry too
much
with
all that stuff we this week again we
basically sold every donation goal we
were going for I think one wasn't sold
but Minh to really used it unless the
guys were losing like I think it was the
the revived the elves one in the third
fight and so that one kind of made sense
because that wasn't was kind of like a
strategical when chat should use it like
if things get really scary type of thing
the final ones and all the enrage events
I completely messed up I you play I used
some of the event stuff I didn't use it
all because I just kind of didn't know
what to do the guys were kicking my ass
anyway so I couldn't even use them all
if I wanted to somebody was good the way
it worked out that was just a little bit
of like I had that enraged goal at five
thousand I'm actually curious because
people could have actually probably hit
that which is the scariest thing in my
mind I put that up because last week's
of rage gold you guys weren't supposed
to hit and you hit it and this weeks I
was like okay I'm gonna put 5,000 and I
think I'm just going to go back to two I
think then I'm gonna keep the prices
generally the same these enraging
counters aren't really supposed to
happen they're really supposed to be if
you guys want to just really make it the
hardest possible encounter but I but
after this week I've noticed that you
guys like a good mix of positive and
negative effects and not so much these
enrage effects you like both a positive
and negative but what you really like
it's just things that dramatically
change the battle you don't like things
that are just alright adds one more
level to combat you like things that
really kind of not just add a combat
mechanic but a story element as well so
for example something like you know the
the whisper snake getting hydro pump or
the responding 10 fire sprites is
nowhere near as interesting as just in
getting a third coat and I know that's a
little bit because it's also a positive
but I also know that that's a big deal
this week I have some ones that you're
gonna look at and you're gonna be like
ah they should be they you should look
at them and they should be more cool I'm
also trying one that is really
interesting that it's it's it's a new
way of doing it and we'll see
it works but I'll talk about it next
week in the behind the scenes one thing
I'm gonna have I don't know if I'm gonna
100% have it because I only have
tomorrow to work on it I'm going to try
to install an overflow mechanic in
donations that I control and the idea is
sometimes these donations get more than
what they need or there's gonna be times
when donations don't make it right and
any time those two events happen I'm
gonna have it go to a visible fund on
the screen that I control and I'll tell
you right now I will only ever use them
on negative things but what will happen
is like if from an event to event
there's some overflow stuff I will pour
it into things like negative things that
I think are gonna happen and and stuff
like that just trigger those events and
so we can so so because cuz there's
there's this weird idea that's hilarious
that you can waste your contributions to
the show that's always funny to me
because you guys aren't really
purchasing anything I mean in some ways
you you think you are cuz you're you're
you're purchasing these in diem events
but really all you're doing is just
supporting the show and saying now I
want my support to go this way or that
way it really doesn't matter we'll talk
about that stuff later at the end of the
day as long as you guys walk away you're
like you know I was a really fun show if
you're the type of person where you
putting your money into a show and
something bad could happen with that
money would really upset you because of
the money you put into it I would
suggest you wait on supporting it until
you're no you no longer have those type
of feelings because really in your mind
all I want to do is create a fun way for
you guys to support rather than just
having a big button that does nothing
and then expect you guys to reach it I
wanted this a fun way so that you guys
could feel like you're getting involved
in the game and you could be like yeah I
booked I put ten bucks towards Justin's
coke because I'm a coke guy myself like
I like that it just adds another level
of talking and support and you guys
feeling like your contributions are
actually affecting the game and I want
that feeling because I want you guys to
feel more attached to this whole project
so if you ever feel like you're getting
burned from some donations like The Cove
wolves were going to eventually talk
about
just just just hold off I would rather
you guys not feet I don't want you guys
to ever feel like you're getting burned
by the show treating you poorly because
as long as you walk away from the show
when it was fun anyway cool all right so
let's talk about the elves so uh we had
four characters this week and these guys
are still growing especially as role
players right now they have a lot of
work to go they're really funny guys but
you're going to see them improve greatly
over the next couple months year however
long we still do this hopefully forever
but you're gonna see them grow a lot as
players and trying to do things one of
the things that people didn't really get
was a CO was trying to be a grumpy Gus
character and we didn't really establish
that very well with the audience of what
he was trying to do we did this better
in today's character creation video I
think comes up before this I don't know
but uh we do this better and talking
about what each players want to be but
some of you guys were upset because you
thought that Coe was gonna be the same
loveable go hug kobolds guy that he was
last week and it's important to remember
that we can't do that if the characters
are always the same personality traits
that they are every from week to week to
week if they're if they always just play
who they are the show would get really
stale because you wouldn't be seeing a
dynamic range of characters and stories
you would just be seeing co-star 3.0 you
know Roman's 6 now they all have you
know personality traits that are tied to
them right like justin is a lovable
idiot and Denbo dead bones is like you
know a sarcastic british man I know he's
not British but but to us Americans you
know I'm sorry you're all British but um
and Roman plays that the number muncher
min/max er type thing and Co is very
much a lovable idiot and they can't
always get away from just some of their
ideas and how they play the game but at
the same time it's important that they
they try to play different characters to
create different stories and some weeks
is going to work and some weeks it's not
gonna work some weeks are gonna have
characters that aren't as strong but as
long as we generally have a couple
characters that kind of stand
no it's okay if every week Roman is into
the the winner right it's okay if every
week you know Justin isn't being picked
on type of thing so you should always
try to think about the characters in in
that sense you should try to think about
not you know hey it's Justin its whoever
they're trying to play as is generally
that's what we try to have come out so
we have this town this town for the most
part just had plenty of people in it
there was no real like plot associated
with anything like this little girl
these son clerics or anything like that
I left it completely up to improv if
they decide to walk around the town or
do anything I always like I always try
to storylines I want to tell all right
and I'll have them down but if they're
just random characters unless there's
details that are important like oh I
want this character I have this trait I
don't put anything for them if ever I
like let's say they got in a bar fight
what I would have done is I would have
pulled up my spell blade template and I
would have just brought in some
impromptu characters to kind of wing and
then that's kind of just how I would
have gone about it but again I don't
necessarily want to go and just make
this massive document because that's a
whole huge amount of time being like
this character's name is James Whipple I
also like improving it because that just
gives me the ability to wing stuff and
being able to wing stuff often creates
some of the most memorable moments like
Phillippe wasn't supposed to be a
memorable moment and the porks were not
supposed to be passive so we'll get into
that so I have Romans brother and
interesting enough Romans brother was
not supposed to be in this campaign he
was completely improved from the get-go
I was slightly worried that dead bones
would be having trouble leading the
group and so I needed a reason for them
to fight the porks other than dead bone
says because right from the get-go dead
bones commanded no respect at character
creation he commanded no respect so I
needed some a second person in the party
to be on board with going and killing
force in our port killing adventure
other than there seems to be porks
nearby
what's funny from this is because the
porks never kidnapped the little boy
because the porks never actually
attacked anyone there might have been a
mix there might have been like a
conflict where we might have said in
character creation they're attacking and
then in here we they said they didn't
attacking you can always chop those up
to things like you know one person said
something but there's no proof of it
type of thing it's the same thing with
like elves don't sleep it's kind of
funny dead bones is an elf he starts in
a bed but I thought I almost don't sleep
butts but nisman's said help sleep
what's the what's the truth well I was
dead was dead bones sleeping did he say
he was sleeping you see the type of elf
asleep maybe the certain types elves
asleep these are the type of things
where we're not going to be very
consistent about but it's it's fantastic
because it allow us to create these
really jokey role-playing moments for
example in this first fight over here
kotas coast being a complete goofball
decides he's thirsty and needs some ale
and a pizza well there's a new card I
don't think I have it up but there's a
new card that I've made that's an RP
item that I think you guys will see in
this first the character creation video
that is just elven pizza I've now put
this as canon in some way and I plan on
doing that a lot as these guys do their
jokey dumb things I'm gonna figure out a
way to take their jokey stupid little
things and somehow turn it into a
legitimate role play thing half serious
like enough it's so serious enough that
you could take it serious without the
fact that it was something really dumb
like coach says he's gonna get pizza so
I've made elven pasta bread okay that's
this item the elvish name for Calvin
pass the bread is pizza just little tiny
things that like that that I can make it
so even when they are kind of breaking
this fourth wall I can go back and just
patch it up no no no it's this walls not
broken look I fixed it I really like
doing that from because from a comedy
standpoint it kind of allows you to
basically do whatever you want whatever
you think would be funny but still
always have it so it never breaks the
world so if ever that feels like there's
a conflict of things all it means is
that I need to come in
you know later and be like
and here's the actual logic of the world
and then we as the guys need to then
once we actually have established this
is real then treat it like it's real
treated like okay this is real type of
thing so there was not much in this town
I think dead bones got a potion they
kind of argued a little bit and then
Romans brother ran off because I needed
to get them to go save his brother who
doesn't really need saving as we find
out and then we get to this first
encounter which was ridiculous this is
this first encounter really told me that
I needed this overflow system because
both of the fires both of the negative
donations should not have gone through
the only reason they went through is
because they these guys dragged the
combat so long and then I you know if
the chat gets the donation amount I
can't end the combat these guys were
never close to killing him it's not like
I had to heal them or anything but at
the same time he really didn't get out
of control until ad started being a big
deal these little fires were not
supposed to spawn fire sprites but I but
when Roman put out the fire I was like
I'm gonna punish him for that and he
started spotting fire sprites
it was a terrible idea cuz it just
created so many extra guys that
shouldn't have been dealt with this is
that three hours of sleep and me not
thinking through my decision of making
these fires right roma tries to put out
a fire like a goofball I'm like oh yeah
Roman you did such a good job then now
only two fire sprites spawn that would
not have been there it was just
decoration he decided to put him out so
I decided to make a cannon music camera
should have been a very fast one but
that's the thing is I can't actually
decide if I count as fast or not I've
realized that we're only gonna ever be
able to do four or five combat events
this week it's like per week there's
this that is what's gonna happen my I
had planned these campaigns were they're
gonna do like ten different combat
events in five different roleplay events
in between there's no way these guys are
gonna always be slowpokes and sometimes
these things just gonna take way longer
walking through a cave of ports took 30
fucking minutes more than 30 minutes it
was like almost 40 minutes so there's
just I have to take that into
and my dreams of doing a five-hour show
there's no way I already talked to all
the guys and if we can do it and I think
we're this generally this is gonna be
six to eight hour show and then
sometimes it's just gonna go long
because we're gonna want to really be
satisfied with getting a good story so
let me let me think so this event was
pretty funny I know they decapitated a
guy Justin yet again first encounter
roles of one criticals is one of his out
or the last week he wrote a 22 kill s we
got a one with his doleful probe blade
which literally says in the card that
just instantly kills a lesser enemy I
think these guys only had like nine
health I think all they had but they had
really powerful spells to help attack
and I don't think they got to use
anything like these guys have like Raya
Frost's in something and that the other
thing is this encounter was completely
skippable I designed it so much that
they could just skip it if they're like
yeah we don't want to find a fire
elemental
so each week I generally take the leader
aside from the group and I give them a
little bit of information I don't tell
them about the campaign specifics but I
tell them about how different things in
the world act and what gets created
I don't think dead bones do anything
about this I think he just knew that
there would be an enemy that's already
subdued and if he wanted he could not
assist and just push forward which was
to be honest if they had done it you
guys would have seen a completely
different show because it would have
meant that we had another hour plus and
we would have done something way
different over down here but the way it
went they fought it they fought it
poorly this was the actual the hardest
encounter in the game for them but it
worked out because as we'll see in this
event as you've probably saw on this
adventure their party kind of started
out shitty and then just got better and
better and more serious and serious and
by the end of it there was a lot of
respect going everywhere except for
Romans character who just kind of ended
up being the butt of the joke
his brother kind of saved him and
everything it was pretty funny when
Roman activated this Goblin luckily
Roman punched him in the face and it
didn't actually have to get activated
I was full-on ready to do a dual
encounter even with them being low
because of the way the whisper snake was
designed
so after they finished this guy and they
already knew this goblin was here I
think I was Mable to see ya I managed to
steal some treasure and get the Goblin
over here this whole encounter was
designed so I'm one of these guys on the
rocks so I can spawn in the whisper
snake whisper snake is probably one of
my favorite mechanics already I really
like the idea of mine controlling people
to force them to go anti-party it'll be
something I probably do not a lot but it
is a reoccurring theme because making
someone go anti-party produces a way for
me to deal lots of damage to a party
without actually having to do it myself
it also makes it so these guys get to
play an tea party which is fun for them
which they get in the enjoyment out of
it makes it so you know for someone like
Roman he trances his main maxing set
where he's like I'm gonna do the worst
possible thing I could do to my group
but he but he'd you know he does it for
me
I love the whispers snake I'm definitely
going to have more whisper snakes in the
future just just right just like they're
fantastic as just a little mechanic I
liked it that they didn't really do
damage like that was just a ton of fun I
think in the future like having like to
whisper snakes can get really really
crazy funny enough again this week are
pretty enough for this event it was the
exact same thing as the previous one
where people were way more interested in
dead bones getting a mace than they were
in doing something like giving this guy
hydro pump and giving this guy in
spawning goblins I kind of felt like
these events came a little too slow for
me so I decided to tweak the donations a
little bit so that these events can come
quick but at the same time I also did
like the rate at which all these events
occurred all the events occurred but
they didn't occur so fast that ran out
the get-go you got a guy hydro pumping
and you got you know one two three four
five goblins if anything that goblins
were kind of fun because after they had
dealt with the whisper snake then the
goblins came out and then it was like a
whole new separate encounter of fighting
these goblins who you knew they were
already really scary because all these
goblins were designed to do was take
treasure run that's all they were
designed to do just take treasure and
run
we also get to see some of the you know
I don't wanna use the word racism I'm
going to look out and find out another
word because racism is not the word that
I want to use for this but the goblin
racism that elves apparently all share
because they just stomp this shit and
made sure that each one of these
confidence was dead dead one of the
things we had talked about in some of
our meetings was goblin is this race
that everyone hates like universally
like nobody likes the goblins at all
they're just everything just the the
biggest bully Don they get picked on
take a race and so it was really funny
for them to remember that and remember
and be all elves and be like no we're
killing them because to me
I was almost thought that was that a
character that they would just
straight-up murder these little thieves
but then I was like oh no these are
prestigious elves you've got some noble
boys you know some spell blades now they
treat these guys like they're animals
they're they're not people
oops dead bones is mace I really liked
doing this it's really fun if you've
already seen the other video
what's interesting design a new type of
card that is like an artifact card one
where there could only be one of it in
the world there's other doctors a second
coat as well but it's a winter coat it's
not as it was not as legendary type of
thing but I like the idea of this being
a surge I like the idea of renaming it
to not to be like was his name like
Carell I like it to be cover out
lieutenant
Carol's surge a base of surge or
something and then making an artifact
card so it only has one thing like my
whole thing with stories is you guys
aren't going to see the same characters
from week to week to week to week
I plan on revisiting things like based
on this story we're gonna revisit this
world and it's gonna be like this exact
setting but it's going to be different
and it's the type of thing where I want
to be like really like if I don't know
if any of you are fans of law and order
one order loves to do this thing where
like five years later they will have
something that references a case that
did five years ago and I really enjoyed
those types of callbacks and that's the
type of thing I like to I wanted to I
want to do these subtle nods from
campaign to campaign you know build the
world of these races and characters and
how they act and
how they do things but at the same time
I don't want it to be like just the
following of the same character from
week to week it's so much more fun if we
get to build new characters and tell new
stories because it allows us to kind of
quickly populate this world of like
interesting people because what's really
cool is eventually we will have so many
of these characters but then that can do
a campaign where the intermingle where I
take a couple characters from here and a
couple characters in here and have these
guys revisit their character or maybe
not even their character maybe Co is
gonna play one of Romans characters type
of thing intermingle these characters to
do an adventure that may have be
associated with other things that are
happening in the world like this is
really really it's growing you guys are
watching it grow type of show which
again is like one of these things I'm
talking about like II I don't really
know what this is don't you know this
hasn't been done I don't know what this
is it really hasn't been done type of
thing like there's a lot of community
influenced like some of you already know
but like when I'm doing treasure cards
almost every week now when I just have
to go add treasure cards I'm kind of
looking at forums and my twitter and my
email and stuff and I'm looking at
people's ideas I'll tell you this right
now if ever you're trying to make a cool
card or idea I think this week we're
gonna actually have a thread on our
reddit on the Buffalo Wizard subreddit
so if you want to make a card with the
the guys of the year rums wiki who are
fan like it in the fan support is crazy
the guys are the you realms wiki have
made this wiki that it's at the point
where this week I actually went to the
wiki for reference on something already
it's already that detailed but they have
a card creator which is really cool like
COEs actually shared a lot of the art
assets Coe went and shared a lot of
fonts so they're gonna be able to update
it to make basically these exact cards
we plan on doing this stuff on the
website but they already got it there
now so I know you guys are like I've had
a lot of requests for like hey can we
have your maps can we have the stuff
these are all little pieces of a puzzle
that I'm working towards making so you
guys can have all this but like I said
this is really this cool world that's
not just being built by me it's it's
kind of being built by me and and the
guys and the community but it's all but
it's all kind of control
can all be the same like unforgotten
realms world you would expect where I
get to interject my humor and the
stories I want to tell but I'm
completely open to the idea of letting
all of my players bend it and letting
the community bend it but no four-car
it's the most important thing you could
do did I do that thing where I said the
most important thing you do and then
didn't say what I need to do the most
important thing you need is a name most
the time when you submit me a card the
text on it of what it does will not be
valuable in any way to me it might be if
it's a really cool idea and I think it's
something I could use but even way the
I'll almost universally have to change
it in the wording and I'll have to go
back and do a traitor ages to the
wording in the future as I kind of like
try to consolidate the way card lingo
works but the name is the most important
thing if you just name your thing like
shadow blade dude I've seen 15 cards
name Shadowblade very much try to come
up with a cool name and I don't even
care if it identifies with your username
on the Internet if I think it's a cool
username and it kind of fits with the
item you were trying to making I'm more
likely to use it so if you if you want
to make a card that you can just put
your little personal touch in I there's
no promise I'm gonna look at it but I'm
already but I look at people's cards
because right now I have no real
interest of just constantly putting more
and more myself in this project when I
can well I I do but I do it when I when
I want to write when there's something
that I'm like oh this is really this be
really cool I would do it but I really
like being able to do that with other
people's work I really like being able
to take your guy's ideas and kind of
molding them into something that fits in
the world because it's really just like
a few it's a weird fusion of like
community and the creation that we
really have never been able to do in any
art form that I can really think of may
I'm sure that's been done before but
with with the internet so anyway I was a
complete detour but yeah yeah yeah so
that's so this so making these type of
cards for the guys are really cool it
really gives their character personality
I need to make sure that I don't
accidentally Auto include these type of
treasure cards automatically in the
treasure deck I need to make it so if
I'm gonna pass them down in the future
it's something that I purposely put in
the deck or
know what's gonna happen because now I
admit it so at some point dead booms
loses his mace to a pirate and that has
to that has to happen and so I need to
just make sure that that can happen but
I'm more careful with it in the future
yeah they fought the goblins they fought
the whisper snake this was such a fun
accounter this might have been my
favorite encounter of this week's show
just because of the way it was built it
was just really really fun like this
week was very combat focused I want it
to be last week was very roleplay focus
and they didn't fight guys this week I
wanted to be the badass spellcasters and
it took them a while to get going but
once they got going the final pork
flight was just alright this is a true
you know
tabletop role playing some ass encounter
alright so this one is probably the most
controversial thing I've done so far and
I'm not gonna lie the feedback was
pretty mixed but it seemed like every
person I talked to about this event once
they kind of sat looked back they were
ok with it I don't really necessarily
want like I I actually liked the idea of
being able to see view guys so that I
don't have to spoil what's gonna happen
next
but it's gonna be something that I do
very carefully and it's not something
I'm gonna revisit for a couple weeks at
the very least so the idea was there is
a carriage of spell legs doing a
prisoner transport and there is a Sun
cleric named Dave who is the exact same
day which is funny that they all kept
naming other people Dave right that was
really funny in my mind because I
already had Dave written like remember
how I said you know I don't write things
like improv some things Dave was written
like I had his full name where's that
open it before I did this no wonder I
don't know what's going on this week
where is my campaign two notes
all right so let me come down to Dave
here prison transport captain Davy Dale
Singh son cleric to Commander Gweneth
son sword and it has all his abilities
here and all that type of stuff but I
had Davey Davison here because I wanted
people to think that there is a
potential this could be Philippe but
people should have known that there was
no way this could have been Philippe it
should have been very obvious to some
and I think for some of you it probably
was obvious because I had already went
and did videos about how you know if
Philippe's a cool character but if he
was to come back he'd have to come back
in a very special way and I he wouldn't
come back the next week we're never
really there's very rarely at that I
should say because I shouldn't say never
I should never ever say never it's just
kind of every time you hear me say never
it does not mean never because that is
such a there's there's no point in your
life where never should really be a
thing except with maybe like things like
murder that's just that's probably not a
I think I can be safe for that one but
for most things in life you know being
creative anytime I say never what I
really mean is I really shouldn't ever
do it right for a for a while at the
very least until society changes and it
makes more sense to do but anyway there
should never really be a time in which
Philippe comes back because that would
ruin his character guys and and like the
easiest way for me to explain it how I
was explaining to anyone who was upset
like I took time to talk to like at
least 20 fans from just Twitter and
reddit and private messages about it but
imagine if it was Philippe if it was
Philippe I would have created the
scenario in which our heroes would
attempt to kill him and Philippe wasn't
some super powerful badass he killed a
bunch of snakes he was a cool guy but
when it came to fighting else he got his
ass kicked and you know he sacrificed
himself so his friends could escape his
brand new friends it was a very you know
he was a very good character like he was
he had a good personality he you know he
only wanted to help his friends he was a
self-sacrificing was very
under character but but if you had come
out if this was actually Felipe here
right you would have had people just
beating him up
now some people would have wanted him to
escape into the forest so his memory
could live on dudes that's a shitty
fucking ending for any character story
do you I would be personally mad if I
watched the show and they did that like
the last weekend that oh my god Felipe
so good you ruined a fucking character
by letting chat just let him escape
because they want to that's that's the
type of pandering that just will ruin
this type of show there's there's no way
that's fun in any way and I mean like if
you leap they came out and started being
the character and beating everyone up
that wouldn't make any sense because how
can Felipe beat up all these elves by
himself when last week he couldn't do
anything I thought it was very obvious
it was a trap I said the beginning this
stream I might trick people do you got
to see in the intro video there was an
evil coal bulb like he had like a like
an evil or face like I thought it would
be pretty obvious that it wasn't really
pay but it wasn't and your guy's
reaction was very not mature like chat
got really vicious and toxic for a
second there over it and that was pretty
disappointing and I know a lot of you
would probably like now or look reflect
on that and they're like man I were
reacted I don't know why I just really
wanted to be Felipe and I get that and I
understand your enthusiasm and I'm to be
honest it's my fault because this type
of this type of like little joke or
entertainment that I was trying to do
came too soon you guys just weren't
ready for it
Felipe was such a big deal to you when
basically every week there's always
gonna be someone who's a Felipe there's
always gonna be some character that is
the outstanding fantastic character that
you guys like in some ways and you might
be like all but there's nobody this week
that was Felipe is like okay for you
know for some people that were and the
future weeks there will be characters
that just roll a lot of 20s and are
fantastic so I this is my fault in the
sense that you that my few fans are fans
the show's fans were not ready for this
type of idea and so while it is
something
I will probably try again it'll be a
while before I tried to trick chat even
if it was something that a lot of you
were like well it's really obvious I
knew it was coming there was there was a
little bit of a flashback from it I
don't think it ruined the show or hurt
the show in any way but I mean like the
I guys if there's a donation perk that I
can do that makes you want to scream out
and chat to boycott the show we're not
going to be able to do the type of
stories that you guys actually enjoy
because at that point I'm gonna be way
too scared to do anything other than
Pantera to you guys I don't want to just
do stuff and have just a donation each
week that's just free Felipe Chile wizzy
comes back and shoots fireballs at
everyone like that's the type of shit
that's like okay cool it's ruining all
the stories of any character we ever
made but we'll just keep using the
characters you guys love so I wouldn't
be too too down I like I don't I don't
think anything I like Benny and I'm
probably over selling how how bit how
how toxic and crazy the chat was they
were just it was one of those it's
twitch chat right twitch chat gives
everybody their natural reaction so if I
tricked you your natural reaction is
like man that's fucking bullshit and you
write in chat I understand that okay the
second year like okay well I mean it was
pretty funny it was kind of cool that
then everything's fine but twitch chat
is always acts like this reaction pipe
the the the worst part about it will
actually was code told me in our private
chat that chat wasn't happy and that
affected my mental state because you
know I thought I was doing this really
really fun cool encounter and code told
me that I told code right then and well
I told Co after the show basically hey
don't tell me that stuff anymore
if chats ever not enjoying something
tell me at the end of the show because
if you tell me in the middle of show
it's just gonna it's gonna make me doubt
myself and I'm gonna lose confidence
like and I'm not gonna be able to put on
a good show I'm gonna be like okay well
I'm scared and to be honest I was it
changed the way I was plywood change the
way I was gonna DM for the rest of the
game and and I don't really
back and reflect in hindsight decide
what I would have done but it definitely
made me more nervous I was very worried
to play this guy this character his job
was supposed to defeat everyone not kill
who's supposed to kick all the elves ass
and escape it's okay that he's going
back to the silver mine Mountains
because again I've established that we
keep sending prisoners to the silver
mine Mountains I like that because
eventually there'll be a campaign about
the silver mine Mountains and you will
know that there would be these
reoccurring characters that's why I'm
always going to name these type of
places with certain type of characters
but at the same time I wanted him to
escape so there would be this character
that I could bring back in another way
it was because because yeah I kind of
talked about it I always have systems
for if these guys lose in combat and
while there was a chance that he could
potentially kill someone that wasn't
gonna happen you know that wasn't really
what he was gonna go for he was only
gonna go for basically knockouts any
critical 20s I unless it was a very
specific scenario and which it made
sense to kill them he was just gonna be
the guy where he would just keep
knocking them out let me think
so I meant so what happened is once I
was told that jatt was not happy I don't
think I played this guy to my best of
his ability and this guy was nuts like
just looking at his abilities like like
his character sheet on on my document
here it's just kind of ridiculous what
does he got he he's a kobold so he had
the double roles he at Renton Guardian
rolling fog rheya frost summon air
spirits and wind blast so he is some
sort of fusion of two different classes
he's a sorcerer and a third gist and
we've never even put a mechanic that
lets him do that
ooh that's weird he had all these
special treasure cards one that gives
him the bonus turns one that makes his
ray of frost just wreck people one that
turns out ones the 20s which was really
important because I rolled two ones of
the encounter I needed to make sure that
because good I remember this guy was
potentially it was a 1 V 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8
9 10 11 12 13 1 versus 13 this guy
needed to be able to just truck through
people
I wanted to play fair in the sense that
for these guys I was going to go through
all of my ads okay and then target them
unless they were very threatening and
that's that's what I did and that's why
you know they got to win the way they
did because had I had a little more
health or how died made me have played
better it had better confidence I
probably would have got to knock some of
them out or maybe even all of them which
would have changed the story completely
but I'd but to be honest the way the
story went was very fun too so I don't
think it was detrimental or anything the
the last part of the adventure was
probably my favorite so it's probably
cuz we got to do role play this was a
very combat focused and me personally
I'm always gonna generally enjoy the
role play parts of it because in order
for combat to ever be exciting something
unexpected has to happen and that only
really happens when guys roll ones or
20s on really critical turns and that's
just luck right and so typically I'm
always gonna like the role play stuff a
lot more because this that's what I like
I like this the story parts way more
than I like the combat I enjoy the
combat but at the same time I enjoy the
combat to facilitate reasons to do more
roleplay but yeah overall this encounter
was fun I still like that they got to
beat it that was pretty cool
because it kind of started to create
this arc like I'm not the type of game
master in this stuff where you know I
have a plan and the plan has to go 100%
like if my character is if my players
are doing something and I'm like alpha
la I'm try to stay very impartial which
is something that is really hard to do
for a lot of people but for me I've done
so many projects like this that because
I only care about doing the thing that I
think would be the most entertaining to
the show I can completely be on the
character side or the NPC side generally
it's whatever sign I think is going to
produce the best results for the
upcoming story and at this point they
had they had dumped really poorly at
this first encounter they had done okay
on the whisper sneaky counter but they
were kind of kicking ass like they had a
lot of good 20s and a lot of they they
had a lot of luck on their side yeah
Justin there's chilli wizzy just like
oh and fireballs and missing but then
he's hitting and it's just kind of like
okay like in my mind it looks like a
Dragonball Z fight like you know what I
mean like Justin's whip and fireballs
that he's wind blasting away from a huge
explosion that's that's we that's really
cool it's like an epic epic battle so I
love that especially because we're on
such a small scale
we're not fighting gods or superheroes
or anything and we because the last
couple years of content in like the
fantasy world has really been like this
over embellishing of character power
like this this power creep and for these
characters now man they're just some
elves or some spells and they're
fighting just a kobold the kobold might
be a really powerful bad guy but not so
powerful enough that they can't overcome
him with a bunch of you know just just a
little just a little ragtag team of
elves so that was that was cool overall
I was pretty happy with us in this thing
I just it was kind of bittersweet in
from for me it was bittersweet in the
sense that I was kind of were like I had
felt I ruined part of the show by making
it a trick because I didn't have to make
it a trick I could have just made it you
know release the prisoner and I said it
was Chimaera but I thought it was more
fun and you somebody will think of
something
it was more fun somebody would think it
was not more fun this will just be
something that if I do it again if I do
this really big trick type of idea on
the on the audience it won't be for some
time so if I'm gonna get to this
encounter now this encounter is
interesting I have looked at the clock
and I decided that we probably had time
for one big combat encounter but we had
basically done roleplay up to now there
there really wasn't a lot of just
talking roleplay because the path they
chose whisper snake there was no one to
talk to in reflecting I would if I
should have had it so they could have
talked to the snake when he gone back
into the water I like if I had the
overflow event I would have made it so
the goblins in spawn I would have been
like nope you're too late chat I'm
taking that money and we'll put it
towards another donation in the future
so I could have had it so they could
have talked to the snake afterwards and
I think that was just kind of mine
just relying on what I had had written
because he's such a cool little
character that he could have just like
been like stopped combat and like you
know just you know talk to the elves and
I kind of missed the opportunity to do
that that kind of sucked like that I
could have done the same thing with a
fire elemental instead of killing him I
just kind of all had them just get
defeated and that wasn't as interesting
there's a little role played before and
after with these guys but it was just
okay it was my little thing so I got to
this encounter this one was designed to
be very which one was this this was this
was Mike number six the pork birth one
this is one where you would got to see
the poor scheming born I'll let you guys
see the porks being born but you could
already tell that there was a big event
that involved lots and lots lots of pork
spawning there was also a way if we had
done this combat event coke could have
got this cool staff then let him have
like three separate frost elementals but
I looked at the time and I was like we
don't really have a lot of time and I
want them to be able to get to the pork
boss to finish up the story so I was
like okay I'm gonna have it so these
pork such as passive and that led to a
really really funny second half here at
this point I like I said I had like the
second wind and I was just over show
game c2 area - at this point in the game
like I knew I wanted to do some roleplay
and while I had extra combat events I
could have started up I don't know if it
was from the previous event me not
wanting to do combat I think that's kind
of what it was I was kind of unsure with
myself and wanting to do these be these
be this a full-on combat event so I was
like and and just the time factor like
if this was a combat event just look at
this place
like they're gonna be fighting things
all the way through to get to the boss
so I kind of improv that and I was like
no I'm gonna have these guys be passive
and they want to give tribute I was like
okay this is going to be really funny
because I knew that by walking through
the cave as their passive I could have
lots and lots of ports follow them and
just it would create a lot of tension
and so I loved it because
all I had to do was basically just move
these guys as the guys were talking over
the screen and it created this really
funny dynamic of the characters having a
limited time to talk while the problem
they had they were trying to solve was
getting worse and worse and worse
and so that was really really cool I had
it so the characters could wake up in
this part of the dungeon if they lost
any of their other previous encounters
so that would have meant like for
example if they'd lost to the flame
spirit they would have woken up in this
cave and the game would have been way
different because I had in this in this
scenario if they were to get knocked out
I have two other encounters that could
have possibly happened that they would
have done so if they had lost at the
first encounter or at the whisper lake I
could have had you know extra encounters
bills for them to play there's so many
ways this stuff could play out I've
tried to make this modular in a way that
I can reuse encounters from week to week
or even in the same campaign so things
don't have to be dictated the way they
play out like I liked the idea of people
sneaking past something and just
completely negating an encounter and as
long as I always build it in a clever
way that I can always make sure that we
get you know at least a 5 hour show as
long as we get a show that has a good
start as a good middle has a good ending
or just has something that feels like
okay that's the story then that's pretty
happy like there's gonna be weeks where
we only do a 5 hour stream and we only
do like three combat events because
that's just the way it played out and I
think you guys need to be ready for that
because you you might be disappointed on
those weeks because you might expect
these big long shows but you have to
keep in mind that this isn't scripted in
any way and the guys we we don't have a
full-on game plan we can't just do extra
stuff cuz you know the way it plans out
like if the guys it could totally happen
one week but the guys go into an
adventure and I've made it too hard and
they keep rolling ones and they all die
and that's really unlikely and it would
have to be not only a combination of me
giving them too much they can't handle
then goofing off too much in the first
encounter and bad rolls but you have to
keep that in the back yard
because that's important that that can
happen because if you guys don't think
the characters can die then there's no
threat of death which makes it's just a
happy-go-lucky adventure you know what I
mean but it removes all of the tension
from the show it's very important to me
that characters can die and that wild
will be extremely rare in most cases
it's going to happen it's it's like it's
definitely going it's definitely going
to happen in some campaigns and so you
always have to keep that in the back of
your mind because if it's in the back of
your mind then situations can get really
tense so the brother wasn't here in the
prison you saw me spawned in that
Thailand like I said again that was
because that was completely improv I was
very I thought it was very weird that
Roman did not want to go for his brother
I think at that point Roman was just
like I'm just gonna go with this because
this was funnier but but I but at the
same time I wasn't sure if he was out of
character or not out of character I
guess Roman decided that there was just
nothing he could do to go help his
brothers who would keep going I really
love just stacking all these guys right
here to fight poor Bo because this
encounter was because I was so sleepy I
didn't really have a lot I wanted to do
with poor Bo and I was like purposely
not referencing his character sheet but
he was overall a really fun encounter he
had these elephants who honestly the one
thing that was special about them
because there was the one thing I had to
improv is the yellow folks did not have
this pickup and magic resistant thing
well sir they were magic resistant but
they didn't have like this pickup thing
and then you can't cast spells on it I
decided to include that because I was
worried that I had made the encounter
too easy like this was at the end of the
night I must have been so exhausted in
my mind like I'm really sorry guys that
I wasn't a hundred percent for this
because I felt like I kind of gave it a
way better show and played as the done
as the game master better if I had just
actually taken the sleep and not tried
to rush this out
this week won't be anywhere near as bad
like everything I'm gonna have ready
will be done the night before cuz I'm
not trying to do a completely separate
project the night before that was a
little bit of ambitious on my part but
uh poor vote hormones biggest thing was
his enrage was the ability to eat people
and that would heal his health but what
I didn't do was balances health right
portable and really had 100 stamina and
I guess that was fine for a pork Mike
you know maybe he didn't actually need
more boss maybe didn't need to be a
bullet sponge I guess the guys just did
a really good job I don't think I can
really say against them because they're
planned to just try and go for poor buh
kind of worked there was literally a
point where right before that in rage
event what I triggered it porvo had to
health and all they had to do was land
something and then I was just I was
being like no no you need a good role
than this I'm not letting you have this
I just got them I just activated an
array to start eating guys to heal but
it didn't work
they just powered through it with their
action potions and stuff and they went
for poor would just ignored everything
which I I guess I could have planned for
but at the same time I mean you know
some weeks they're just gonna win it
wouldn't really make sense of porn was
just this indestructible beast anyway so
I'm trying to think of what I could have
done better I think the one thing I did
to better is these these Kabbalist guys
I was just having them spam life trying
to heal but they had the Ravenclaw and
like those guys were using their
ravenclaw the way you can use it like
picking up characters and holding them
and studying and stuff and I really
wasn't doing that and I have done that I
made it made it so poor vogue was less
focused but uh overall I mean they have
a really good strategy I thought it was
stupid when Co did the the darkness over
here but he got a great role on it and
then it made it so I couldn't bring in
reinforcements and I was like shit with
no reinforcements to distract these guys
Porvoo was going to lose a bit like poor
the poor was not going to lose
eventually part was going to lose like
in the next turn or to these scallops
while they were scary just kept mist
like they were just charging guys and I
just I guess I was just wasn't getting
the rolls and the thing is a lot of the
story like I said it's kind of
determined on how rolls go these guys
have a lot of a lot of advantage when
they were old 20s because they would get
free spells and that was pretty
impactful a lot of parts of the game so
I don't know it was it was a great fun
campaign I really enjoyed it I think I
could have done a there's a lot of the
things I could still improve on of
bettering this show and I'm not honestly
just really excited because I feel like
I'm just continually continually
learning and there's lots of things I
can do to make this better and all the
feedback I'm getting from you guys is
nuts I'm so happy that this is something
that I can just build and keep doing and
it's fantastic so and I'm gonna keep
doing these behind the scene things as
long as you guys find them interesting
and they're cool because I like talking
about it
I like this level of communication I
have with you guys because I want you to
understand like what we're trying to do
because it's something that doesn't
really make a whole lot of sense for
some people on the internet and if this
is something I mean you're passionate
about and you can come out and just drop
five bucks on the show just on whatever
donation perk you like that would mean a
lot to us because if we bill if so long
as we can keep doing this each week and
we have just a steady supply of these
small little donations we won't have to
rely necessarily on big supporters
because that's because that's what I
want the reason why I don't want to do
anything's with with companies and
partners and and stuff like that is so I
can just focus on the actual people and
so if this project is actually supported
by just lots and lots and lots and lots
of people just giving a small amount
then
fan-fucking-tastic anyway I'm just
dragging on repeating myself over and
over I do this every week so um I hope
you guys like this I hope it was cool
I hope this week was fun this next week
is probably going to be this next week
I'm scared
less usual I don't know why I'm saying
it's gonna be the best week but uh this
guy took a lot of time and doing a lot
of fun things this week that are really
different from every show you've seen
even if you've watched man this is like
our fourth show
like if you want to count like the New
Year stream but so the only second real
well I guess the third wheel show with
counting neuron so this would be our
fourth show but it's something really
different than the normal type of stuff
we've done and the stuff we've done for
the campaign is really really cool and a
mission just to see if it works or if it
falls flat on its face I've prepared for
both but I guess we'll see anyway thanks
a lot guys and I hope you guys have a
good weekend and we'll see you the show
tomorrow