your remember your else are you a bap
are you a girl who likes girls is that
what we're gonna know if I like all
thing I'm pansexual okay like a lamp I
don't what what why is the bar on fire
hold on hold on let me explain myself
for a second this bitch it was all like
yo I don't want anything to do with you
and I was like shit man I mean come on
really
son the bar down that thing's gonna be
burning for at least 20 years or so cuz
my fire yeah I know you're right 25
years actually
uh that size of yeah that's like that's
a 20-year fire that's what Cormac thinks
it's probably 20 years not a Tony Mac
I'm gonna be cross with you if you don't
smarten up buddy I got I got flames that
can burn for 25 years and don't even
fucking try to say 20 all right fine
it's 30 years okay it's a 30 year fire
very good my shoulder they still gonna
be here look I have a job for you seven
you guys interested are you just gonna
be dick around letting burning buildings
down all day you look familiar
Erin you look you look much like a man
he used to know also named George well
not he wasn't really George but I mean
the majority line everybody has to call
George his name was like Jordan Mike
Mike Jackson um what yeah
hey you knew my father your father
really Wow he was a great man
I mean look yet he has probably a
pedophile no really in the George Klan
yeah pitiful uh-huh really yeah that's
what I heard I mean I I only oh is that
true that you Wow you could just
murdered your own father that's well I
do
are you really that far away in the
middle of this uh stunning revelation
we're gonna have mr. uh miss uppity over
here
he's gonna come out you got a car to the
bar see the fire and be like just
facepalm right away he's not really
pleased with you guys he just walks up
and he's just like what did she do Aaron
he's a known by the way so you're
actually even taller than him you got
like two were at one to two feet over
top of him and height wise what do Aaron
did you burn down the bar that's gonna
burn for at least 20 years man
look my my siblings can vouch for me
they wanna you know explain yeah I I do
this is kind of like a big temper
tantrum and he's got out of control
because he didn't get his way with this
this woman who turned out to be a male
and apparently now this buildings
burning for like 30 years or so
25 actually 25 sorry all right miss 'van
is going to walk up and try to put out
the fire that's anyone want to actually
intervene yeah what the fuck hey wizard
dude uh yeah kind of a shame about the
whole bar and everything but um yo could
I touch your rainbow staff uh once can
we roll for that can I touch his
rainbows down your way are you gonna
like do that whole thing where like you
ask permission but then before he
answers just kind of touch it anyway
yeah I'm heart it's already like in my
mouth okay go in the middle of God
killing flames are you trying to touch
it with your hands or the mouth also
trying to lick it he's aiming his staff
at the bar to cast a spell to put it out
oh my mouth okay carry on
you know you just fucking hurry up I
fucking hate gnomes wait a minute wait
did somebody let him drink apple juice
oh yeah oh no not again
you know you're not supposed to had
almost empty I don't have some apple
juice in me I'm gonna hook smash
everybody alright alright Niven hears
that he's conjuring up some apple juice
anybody wants some apple juice I would
love some oh I don't need any apple
juice I do not have any psychological
trauma we're cuddling were long and the
single get rule set here will juice you
don't need to freak out every time you
drink it all right on my shoulder make
some apple
yeah sure Co yeah you can start
fermenting your app know what I'm gonna
share with all you guys here have have
each person have all Thank You Aaron
thank you thank you it's buddy okay Wow
let's just have everybody up uh average
their friendship miss have been is just
this skill face bombing he's just he
gives Maz know he's like look so here
you go here's what I need you to do okay
this is guy his name's Bokan he's some
sort of skeleton king he likes to
collect lots of rubies he's got tons and
tons of money but all of that is paled
in comparison because he has the
location of an abandoned dragon den one
second yep cannot can i bug aaron to
bring them over into a corner where
Nyssa bin won't hear us yeah sure
alright I mean this one was mid
conversation that's slightly rude yeah
fucking fucking okay again yeah that's
fine okay all right what's that so
brother killer dude here's what I'm
thinking okay or miss ofin he called you
up apple juice right yeah what if we
steal that one of his so then that way
always have apple juice
you know what I think of forgiven you
for killing your mother see we could
work this through man we could work this
through
you ought to seal your seal at wand yes
I do
I hope I so do okay this Ivan walks up
and just gives you the goddamn wand it's
all right it's not even he doesn't even
care about this he's just like first off
I can hear you you didn't walk off that
far
you walked a couple feet second I don't
care I just need you to go find the
location of this abandoned dragon den
that's all I need
all right whatever you want as long as
you give me the wand guys guys try look
at that one
this won't delicious missive in hands
the wand to Aaron Aaron here you go you
may have the magical rainbow apple juice
summoning guanhai I want to conjure a
lady bar wench that really wants me okay
um you haven't fully mastered the one
but by all means go ahead and try the
cake
all right I'm gonna try here we go all
right you can't successfully conjure two
bottles of apple juice one of the
bottles though however one of the
bottles is actually sent inant is just
kind of like hopping but you can see
that it's a live now oh yeah you've
conjured this event is actually just
keys of like walking up he's like what
did you do look I gotta give it a name
all right um Randall what wait how did
you
you just conjured life when how did it
kill it yeah and away it is Randall how
do you kind of life is it living way
this is the beginning of something great
imagine the possibilities creating life
out of a wand gone done with this that
dude just summon fucking living
breathing bottle of apple juice I'm a TA
one thing yeah well yeah yeah yeah what
is it pause fuck yourselves
no he just he shakes his head and walks
away I swear I day that this is a really
huge moment for pansexuality
after a mental breakdown in front of his
family the next he wants to do is you
know go hit on a lady in the middle of a
Tamara so just I'm just feeling really
lonely right now I just you know my
brother and I talked it out and I sort
of got over it but I'm still feeling a
little emotional right now what's your
name uh my name is Samantha
it's very nice to meet you it's a
beautiful name it's really beautiful
um time do you get off oh well I've been
on actually working I'm actually looking
to get involved in a job
what do you hit here what are you boys
here in town for I'm looking first of
all I'm a girl oh that's that's right
well I mean the rest of you are boys the
turn I mean technically still works I
can say you know what are you guys for
mental issues I'm knocked out for him
I'm not really trying to make any
associations to gender at this point
it's just semantics really wait who the
fuck did you hook me up with the lady
warrior yeah why did you want to talk to
the bar where was the poet all no Jude
dude she she blew you cuz foxy Tsuboi
dude she blew you complete off you're
talking to lady warrior how dare you to
drink anything No all right a little
apple juice that I guess in my satchel
you had apple juice in your satchel
well I wanted fresh apple juice but I
keep some around in case bars don't have
apple juice okay that makes sense it's a
little fermented at this point but Oh
God whoa