you don't really have Hana just edit
this in but yesterday I had my stream
layout still up and I was just like you
know I could have Haunter edit those in
or I could just play it and then I'm
like started playing it and then it was
like oh my Mex that you did okay so
first off if you have if you do not
watch the stream I would very much
recommend you not watch this behind the
scenes video in the future I'm gonna
have mine behind the CTV scenes videos
come out at the end of the campaign once
it's on YouTube
so it'll generally come out on like the
Friday so I guess yeah I think that'd be
right someone's probably on the Friday
or something like that
but today this thing's different cuz
there's a lot of talk about you guys are
really excited there's a list a lot of
things if I sound tired today it is
because I am 100% exhausted so today is
for me right now today is a Sunday it's
almost 11 p.m. and you wouldn't you'd be
like Rob why are you so tired I was so
mentally exhausted and physically
exhausted yesterday that when I went to
sleep I had a really hard time sleeping
and I only got like six hours of sleep
and then I got up and I told myself I
was gonna take the day off and honestly
after this I'm gonna make missive and go
play we're gonna go play some heroes of
the storm because I've been itching to
do something relaxing but um no like
this this whole this whole project this
whole the show has been really stressful
and yesterday so so for Saturday the the
day of the first stream it was kind of a
rollercoaster of emotions we had to
start the stream late because dead bones
had his real life job was calling and
there's nothing he could do it wasn't
planned he you know he's normally always
here for these times but he needed the
extra two hours and that's gonna become
that's gonna have
a lot I mean all the guys I'm the only
one here that does doing it full times
and Co starting to get there you know
he's he but all the but all these other
guys just have day jobs and those
responsibilities kind of outweigh you
know doing a project now I'll let you
guys know because you're probably
wondering we did really really well
it's it's not I don't really want to
share specific numbers or something I
feel like it's tacky it's it's it's it's
that's not what's important but we did
we did you you can if you're wondering
like how well we did much more than I
could have ever hoped to put it in
reference like you guys remember I was
talking about like I want to make this
amount of much money and I had this
donation goal for the final boss of the
campaign and I had this bonus for it
that was so ridiculous that like but if
it went this is just like the guys would
die unless they were close to finishing
it or that would rather not die they
would think they would lose that battle
they would have to win in another way
which we'll get into I'm gonna be all
over the place again today like normally
I have a certain about a mental
fortitude but I'm just absolutely
drained so like I try to be a little
professional I'm actually able I'm
surprised I have those much energy in my
voice as I normally do because my voice
is just so tired and I just want to this
first of the day just like this but no
no no so we did we did like beyond what
I could have expected like I had some
low numbers I had some high numbers and
we kind of doubled that and that's scary
because money could be a scary thing a
lot of money too fast can sometimes be
scary it just means that I I had to talk
to all my guys talk about this because
this thing is huge I haven't had an
opportunity to do something this big and
awesome in a long time
not to diminish any of my works like
when I first started working on DBC
and they got on the Minecraft reddit I
really exploded as a content creator
when I got to participate in the mine
crack UHC I get to just explode in in
that community and a lot of people got
to see my content some of you were from
one or two of these areas when I got
when I did a the world of warcraft story
jimmy the world of warcraft story you
for a youtube contest it was like the
number-one entry fighting if I didn't
win that even though I had the most
votes cuz I got disqualified a mother
story the other day but um like every
time I've had these opportunities I felt
like I've never been ready for all the
incoming amount of work that required as
required to keep go go go go go go go
and the difference is this time I am
like what I'm trying to do for summer
with I'm trying to realms live is pretty
it's a pretty immense undertaking when
you start to consider you know DBZ this
week-long next week there's a big Coast
quest week that we're pushing out
there's a week where with Sailor Moon
and getting it finalized so we can start
releasing those episodes there's there's
a lot on my table right now and so most
people it would look you'd be like
you're taking on too many things and I
feel like that's you're absolutely right
I am taking on too many things and I
feel it's just something I kind of have
to do right now I kind of have to do to
kind of grow and this is gonna be
probably the hardest I've worked in all
my life this summer I've worked pretty
hard sometimes but this this is gonna be
really really stressful and it's it's
something where it's gonna be a lot of
pressure on me but I would not want to
do anything else this is this is
definitely what I want to do and the
opportunity to do this is not something
I'm gonna take likely or for granted
like this is this can potentially become
a massive thing I know a lot of you like
kind of like feel that way too I can
like the comments and the feedback has
just overwhelming
that the the months of work all the all
the collaboration like today you might
be wondering why are you recording this
at 10 o'clock the next day Rob when we
got off that show yesterday I mean I
talked with the guys for another four
hours before I went to bed and it was
already way way late that was like an 8
hour show plus an hour of downtime here
there and you know the the there's there
was a lot like I'll go into all that in
a second but I got off that and I was
just so tired but I was so excited I
wanted to talk these guys and shares
things and then the today I woke up and
I basically just sat down with all my
guys one by one and just started talking
about things talking about what's next
what do we do what do we do with this
money what are my plans do you what they
think about all this stuff because one
of the hard parts with with money and
something like this is you have to
everybody has to be on the same page
right you don't want people squabbling
over this type of stuff because I've had
that problem I've had that problem I've
seen what but what I can do with working
with friends and making these mistakes
where it not only destroys what you're
working on but it destroys the
friendship and I have to be so careful
going forward because these guys are
gonna go from a lot of them have just
been doing it just because you know but
one maybe one day we'll get an
opportunity well we did this is this is
this opportunity and like even if next
week we did half of what we did this
week it would have been more than I I
could have like hoped for like we were
so at our peak of what I've been told I
like just just to give you a frame of
mind I haven't got to sit down and
really go through reddits I've got to
sit down go through Twitter's my emails
packed there's so many things I just
want to read back on fans on top of that
I have my workload for this week like
I'm just overwhelmed at this point that
you know I told myself I would wake up
today and I would just do nothing I
would just sit down relax play some of
my my wizard in the Apple 3 a little bit
they do some hearthstone I would tell
myself that but there's
Platz was so overwhelmingly positive the
feedback the thinner the questions the
commentary do you guys want to make
cards you guys want to know where you
can print cards you want to know where
you can buy this game you want the
Felipe's where were you t-shirt like
it's just mind-blowing this this is this
is so much and I don't want to
disappoint and so for a while I'm not
gonna be able to shut down I don't know
what I'm gonna shut down I'm gonna burn
out I think it's gonna be after summer
I'm gonna tell you guys right now the
end of August going into September there
might be a lull in content maybe not
just maybe it'll just be you alive maybe
I'll have to take a break from something
like Lourdes maybe we'll take a break
from this well we're gonna have to take
a week break every now and then but
though they'll have to be something I
have to let go just for a little bit to
reset my mind but no I'm going to give
this everything I have up to now I've
been working at a hundred percent you
know like these these last couple weeks
these last couple months it's been every
every day go go go go go
my family will be like hey if you want
to do something I bet can't I got to
work when I could have but I I wanted
the focus on the work I wanted to give
this 100 100 percent and I kind of had
that right now my brothers you guys
might know him he's Tommy and he heeded
the moody Buddhist album last me last
year he's he went to school too in
medicine in Australia this year and he's
gonna be back in the summer for like two
weeks and I like they like well they've
had like this party well for my
brother's just my family and stuff and
they were like plenty of her Saturday
I'm like please don't do that please
don't plan on the Saturday I I just like
don't make me make that choice so they
so it's on a Monday which is who are not
a Monday it's not a Friday so yeh I can
maybe balance that in a couple hours
but no really I want to just go go go go
with this and give you guys the best I
can do like really a I've tried to kind
of I don't I have taught I tell you guys
this I don't like talking about this
stuff and I'll do these behind the
scenes stuff but future weeks is going
to be
mostly just me talking about the
campaign and not me just you know
echoing my thoughts and feelings on what
this opportunity means to me because how
you like take a second I just talk and I
don't think
okay I lost my shirt a lot that's that's
how I know that I've been doing this all
day as I'm talking to like CO and Rowan
and dead phones and all the guys just
I've just been like I'll talk about like
I was even started turning a joke so
just be like and see you know the most
important thing though with all this
stuff dead bones is that I lost my train
of thought I'm gonna have to pause I
have to go back to watch what I did
he'll kind of to make Conor do this
holler I'm sorry alright I watched it uh
you know I'm so happy
are you like I'm so happy because I've
never done this to myself and I know I
know something you'll be worried you
like Rob don't overwork yourself I gotta
tell you I'm having the time I like
doing it but I'll be better trust me
I'll be better it's it's just like
yesterday was a roller coaster
we got ddosed twice I'll tell you right
now when you put that much work in stuff
and stuff except skating heat with the
awesome Oh baby is that make you sad but
the funny thing is the first time I got
to das I was so frustrated and I was
just I wanted to cry and the second time
I got ddosed I went out and I was like
oh my god I can't believe it but then I
didn't and you know why cuz I had we'd
already we've gotten in about an hour
worth of campaign I in and I'd saw your
guys's reactions I saw me putting up
this donation event that you guys blew
through in 30 seconds and going uh-oh
I I misjudged the amount of these
donations should be by almost tenfold
like you guys were telling me about how
I should have these overflow dated like
you guys wanted to donate to the show
and you loved these these little goals
and stuff and there's there's been a lot
of debate and like people pointing out
I'll give you my point of view the one
of the things you have to keep in mind
is that the with the way it's set up it
makes it so that you guys have enough
control that the chat gets to do fun
things but
not decide the game I remember I hope
you guys haven't watched the whole thing
not just one episode because I'm gonna
start spoiling things the chat some the
decisions chat makes should always be
controlled to a certain extent because
if the chat had their way you know such
dramatic things could happen to the show
that it wouldn't be entertaining anymore
and that's a real concern
I was very I'm very I'm very not sure I
guess about the idea of positive
donations and that's just something that
was really requested we want to help the
group and the reason was because I don't
like the chat being at odds with each
other a lot of people had the ideas of
make people compete left to right and
that feels really tacky and money grabby
to me I like making the donations the
solid things and I don't necessarily
need to do them I have some ideas I'll
just try in the future because I want
you as long as you guys are excited and
you're in love with this and you know
you're gonna you're gonna throw a couple
dollars every time we do this stream 5
10 whatever your whatever disposal
income be just because you love this and
you want to participate then my goal is
really just to really give some things
that you can be like I participated into
this you know right now with the way it
was it was so low that like you guys
would just blow through a donation and
some people said oh just have it
overflow into other donations and like I
wouldn't have mattered like the like the
final goal was that $2,000 won and I
didn't think that was a thing I was like
you know if if we have a lot of hype
maybe that'll be a good time of the
night for people to really really
support the show and maybe that can
happen but that was like maybe now it's
one of those things which like no it
could be a surefire thing and I think
that's important
you guys probably noticed I had two full
boards these guys did hack then a little
bit of the game boards and that's gonna
be okay we're going to go into it one of
the big things though was how long
encounters took that was pretty
surprising see I had my understanding
was they kind of took about as long as
the encounters when we did in there in
case
and the reason like that confuses me is
because we have almost half the players
I thought they would go faster but I
think with all their little complexities
and the chatting and the with the
roleplay you know you're really only
gonna see four or five little party
adventures and I think I like that
like the story that got told Oh
yesterday on stream was fantastic it had
just it had character development it
just it had just enough just enough for
you to meet the characters know all the
traits fall in love with them and then
have either sad endings or happy endings
or frustrations or angry Enders just
endings for all the characters I I
couldn't believe how well it came
together especially because it was so
natural
and just felt so rewarding and I know
some of you like it will be mad at
hopefully people will get into that in a
second in a second I mean like half an
hour from now and like with the donation
goals i really think all i need to do is
just understand that okay these donation
goals should just be way bigger so that
more people can actually participate
another thing is I need them to come out
slower and so they're just gonna be more
expensive and that's fine because my
whole I understand it was I expected to
go through way more adventures that was
that's what was requested you guys say
they wanted more and more and more and
more and I agreed with you like I had 30
planned and there was instances like you
may have saw but what I'll show you
remember the Jim Lord encounter the
general encounter was also on the second
map because basically the way these maps
were work if you came out this way you
were gonna start in the bottom of the
map if you came out this way you were
gonna start on the left of the map and
that was designed because the animations
and all the required puppeting work
requires a lot of shared assets and one
for guys that go one way and not go the
other is kind of a problem when I do
these videos each week I'm not going to
show you events that could have happened
if they had gone right because I'm just
going to reuse those you know these
things are all designed they're special
they get animations all made up so the
can be played and the show will only get
better the more we have those banked you
know what I mean
I got this guy over here let me tell you
his name his name is Ringo and he
there's a whole storyline that you guys
didn't see but you will see it so don't
ever be disappointed if you're like man
I wish we got to see more of X because
you will
it'll just be written in a different way
and your disappointment of not being
able to see you know these characters
doing the story well I mean I'm at if
they had gone this way you never would
have met Philippe who was not a who was
completely improv right and that's
that's a really big thing okay well your
most memorable and all the fan arts
characters is drawn about a character
who is literally just an addition on to
an encounter all because some of the bad
are P because I have a lot of growing to
do I can get way better I actually want
to just go and watch the whole stream
and I haven't had time to do that
to look and see all my mistakes I'm not
perfect I'm not amazing at all the
things I'm doing right now I can be way
way way way better and I want to work
towards getting better but know when
your biggest character right is this NPC
Phillipe you guys need to realize that
everything else that I create is just a
catalyst for the stories that haven't
been written and so you should never
feel disappointed when you didn't get to
meet X character or so and so for
example if you guys remember there's a
point when Justin turns into like this
crocodile with a clock head and that was
a puppet and I are dead bones does like
when he fails his disguise that probably
felt like came out of nowhere but it's
because I told dead bones to use a
puppet for a character that was used
this week that we wouldn't get to see
like there's gonna be a we're gonna use
a lot of these assets for an improv -
right and as we develop more and more
stuff we're just gonna have a bigger
plethora of like things we can do on the
fly powerful events that we can create I
like I believe we had exactly 28
different donation events that could
spawn and I believe we did let me think
three
six to eight and then one two three so
eleven yeah that's the easy number I
know please I'm tired I'm mentally
exhausted counting till 11:00 is hard we
need eleven no not even half right Oh
God only doing more math 28 and 14 yeah
not even half which is kind of crazy so
that's what I need to do with events I
need to make them more expensive for
sure so few more people can donate and
they can come in slower so if you see
there are events being priced out and
you're like wow Rob you're really you've
up to the green here it's not that
please please I no no no no it's because
we were getting that money regardless we
were really getting that the MOT like
people would just people were just
donating out of events because they were
just like you know I really like the
show and I just wish you guys would do
good more events that I could
participate in and they were just giving
us money and that reaction is
mind-blowing it tells me that what I am
doing and why I'm making for the
community I've established is what
unanimously what they want for every guy
that doesn't was like I'm not sure about
it
they're ours that there's literally
10,000 people that are like no no you
know our happy you're gonna keep making
this movie I'm gonna come here and give
you five dollars and you're gonna make
you're gonna make that lead to Dungeons
&amp; Dragons show that you got going here
I'm like what you're cooking and so
that's that's like that that's
definitely the direction I'm gonna take
so that those events can be slowed down
they don't have to happen at the
immediately the first mob turn and if
they still do well more power to you
guys like there's nothing I can do
because it'll just expand it like and
the lovely thing is one of the big
things people talked about is like music
they love that I'm using the background
I'm totally on board with you guys only
I don't have that music I have a lot of
music if to do an hour stream but five
hours of stream that's not going to get
grating on you guys without really using
copyrighted stuff that I that I'm
actually happy with know I'd have to
work with some musicians to do that
and that requires a bigger budget but
the thing is we've done so well that if
we just keep doing this well ya know
we're gonna commission that out we're
gonna improve the crap out of this show
like if it comes to it you know we'll
hire people to make this stuff easier to
make it better like like for example I'm
the guy who programmed the Puppet Pals
program well I'm a shitty-ass programmer
right I mean I'm just a designer if
anything but like the programming part
is cracked laid it down the line and I
know some of you like I because cuz I
get I have no lot of you guys or
programmers I know some of you would
just jump and be like alright maybe me
but no no this would be something way
down the line not very recent because I
can't do overhauls behind the amount of
people who would said the word overhaul
yesterday was like you know Rob you need
to really overhaul this system it's like
there I can't overhaul things that's a
big word like I'm now setting a Content
cycle where the way I have things I'm
gonna slowly change them but not never
drastically change them like with the
donation thing people talked about
positive donations and some of them were
positive they just didn't really feel
positive like spawning Jim Ling's
the boat taught the for both times you
could spawn jailings chat we're kind of
counterproductive weren't they like the
gem Lord would have been harder if he
just didn't have gem Ling's to give
Justin for your tax if you think about
it
and the Gimli the first time just kind
of beat the crap out of all the other
kobolds and then exploded and and but no
I I think I it would be fun to do some
positive donations like that go 1 2 3
and then have you know color them like
make them hue them red if they're anti
group cue them blue if they're positive
group and sometimes the red ones will
will will be maybe a little bit more
positive and sometimes the blue ones
will be a little bit more negative but I
think it'll let us do fun things because
a lot of people just wanted you wanted
to be funky you want to be like you want
to see that donation where you're like
give room and a flamethrower and Roman
gets a flamethrower you
Oh like that's the that's the hue the
silly humor side that we really really
have like you know when you're fighting
a gym lord and he gets too beefy arms
like the guys don't even know what's
coming right like that's the thing these
I'd have no idea of the campaign I keep
them in the dark because that's what
makes it really fun for them and you get
to see and they get to be really candid
Romans really bad at faking reactions
there's so many times I used to do some
let's play stuff with them
where we'd have it really good oh we
can't record audio you want to try and
do that same joke again he'd do it I'll
be like no you know you can't you're not
a good liar at this roping you can't you
can't do that joke again we've lost it
we've lost your reaction that was so
good the first fan and so because of
that because of because I want that
those pure reactions from the guys they
don't even know this is coming so you
know like it's silly right this is giant
floating GM what's the lore I sometimes
write some things on my character notes
let me I'll give you a look at what this
looks like for these campaigns at some
point I plan to just release like all
the stuff I work on them but I have to
get it set up and I have to give it to a
way I can properly release it and we're
slowly working towards building
something like that building the type of
system that would allow me to easily do
that week to week just release the
campaign but uh that's stuff that I
don't even know how to do right like
website stuff isn't is in my forte
I mean you know I'm I don't put out the
bush website so I need to work with
stuff but that's stuff that like go in
this event are great at and or to get to
do stuff like that I'm just stalling for
time while I loaded this up by the way
anyway so here's this campaign thing now
some this one's actually done at Leslie
I think this is the one I actually
edited because you can see green Coble's
fully depleted um so this is how I did
it
so mom health was legitimate but the
some people have asked why you don't see
mom health now the reason why dungeon
masters
I'm gonna this is this this is
apparently gonna break a lot of coops
art especially if you've been a player
your entire life and
dragons sometimes judge masters cheap
Dundrum ass being a dungeon master is
about making a good at making a good
adventure telling a good story it's it's
really it's trying to stay true to
whatever belief you have with the group
some sub teams are perfectly sticklers
some DMS are you know they fudge things
a lot of Dungeon Master's don't even
show their own dice I show the dice
although every role I have to do because
it's exciting for chat and my table but
when it comes to balled up behind the
scenes of how much health things have
that's a whole other story so let me see
if you guys can actually read this
properly you know this video I'm just
gonna oh yeah you guys can you guys so
you can see a blue cold here didn't
actually die yeah he had one health but
I think the encounter had gone so long
maybe I had just miss clicked the
encounter goes so long that I chose to
just finish him off looks like green ko
both killed legitimate yellow kobold
here
that's Felipe so that this is what I was
using for his health bar that I was kind
of copying around and there's all his
abilities you can see that he only had
the racial trained guard because the
other kobolds didn't used the double
dice roll when cooked when dead bones
had to take over take it that was an
ability I could give upon dead bones so
that it would be more interesting to
play for the final fight as you as well
talk about but it's because I'm not
always gonna give things I think they
actually had blessings strengthened I
think they forgot to use it that's
because I mean this was an NPC character
that they adopted and it's kind of I
don't have a great way to necessarily
pull out cards without taking like two
minutes out of the stream to do it
that's something that I can definitely
set up though but it's gonna take me a
long time of cataloging again making
save files in tabletop simulator really
what I need to do is I need to make a
set of mod tools that will import a lot
of things I need really quickly and
that's something I'm gonna be working on
on making better like you saw me go
throughout the night using different
pieces
the board I just flip them over and I'd
be like okay this is the cloud that's
cuz you know I for some reason forgot
yet again is the second time I've forgot
about this one to get that you have a
cloud you know to have a cloud for the
fog spell last time I just use Randall
and this time I didn't even have
anything so just like though I ran into
a problem a couple times tonight where I
didn't have the forethought for all the
other things on the board when I was
doing board planning so this is this is
how I developer I mean I make I make
these designers I put any information at
the top is this the encounter and
eventually I get these chat upgrades I
try to price them in a way that made
sense this was so not enough like 50 100
200 and you guys just immediately
knocked him out like I'm honestly
thinking they need to look more like
this like the rabies you got to put a
500 then I got to put this at 750 and
that's got every 1,000 and you sometimes
we might not make it you know and I
think that's okay but to be perfectly
honest this event right here that's how
much it made anyway off you guys like
just from the draw donations like I'm
pretty sure needs to be tenfold I think
I might go a little less than this but I
I really think I need to be looking at
just making these events last longer so
they don't just instantly happen I don't
think I got any quits with Chris on the
kobold because I don't think they ever
proc their try and guard once I had bad
dice today on this game it was pretty
rough but no this is this is what my
doctor looked like it was just lots of
things lots of events lots of ideas and
this is how I'm going to be making it
each week and eventually I would just
like to share my design campaigns all
the board's stuff just give it to you
guys and it'll be good it'll be a great
tool like if you've never played in
these role-playing games you want to get
into it with a couple of your friends
you know if they if they've never seen
this show perfect you can use exactly my
campaign the way it was you can have all
my notes and everything but if not you
can go and just cherry-pick encounters
change them how you want
like we really want to get it so at some
point you go to our website and you can
just see all the stuff all the cards and
stuff right that you could take the
cards and you can make your own custom
class with your group with your group if
you wanted print them all off in a nice
printing formats we'd love to get to the
point where we could actually just print
a set and like here's the set one of the
card the classes that whatchamacallit
maybe make it a monster manual book like
this tide this type of art project gets
close at the mouth and excitement over
the idea that we could do something like
that and we said I know I'm tired
because I come to a full I'll just talk
and talk and talk and talk and but know
this this is something that we're gonna
slowly develop and we're gonna make it
as cool as we want and we're just gonna
give it away for free
like any with free cost whatever I don't
like my whole thing is I want you guys
to love this and want to support the
show part of it but the actual game that
we're making behind the scenes to do the
show know that guys see that is yours
you may you may all have that for free
I believe the cards already in like all
the reddit documents and each week I'm
just gonna keep updating that with the
immature and then one week we're gonna
have this website we're gonna interview
two guys and you'll get all be able to
get all the cards all the information
make the cards do all this cool stuff
just to be able to play the game on your
own if you want to and for some of you
you know you'll never play it but you
just fund I'm the type of guy where like
the longest time when I was kid I never
played dungeon dragons many my friends I
only really started playing it when I
became an adult to play it with family
and you know with online friends for
this type of stuff I don't ever want to
pretend like I was a master of the game
or anything I definitely wasn't but I
was so interested in them you know I
loved reading the books look at the
cards and making my own ideas and stuff
it was funny the first guy in the reddit
thread who dropped a comment about his
card he's like yeah I think this would
be cool I made it I think I just took it
I made a card and I threw in the trigger
deck we didn't actually get to see it
this week but we could of it like it was
there the card was there for them to see
and then the funny thing was he he
called it like four
blade but he spelled it wrong so it was
like vote prowl blade and I was telling
codes like you should fix that I was
like Orko you can we could come up with
a concept of what a vote Perl blade is
it's completely different so and that's
because that's the thing is this is
really a humor thing right this isn't
your serious roleplay we have lots of
those most of them are serious role
plays and we have a few jokey roleplay
stew like I know Joe Hills makes a fun
one pitfalls and penguins which is
really great and that's what I want to
make right is this is the one that's
just serious enough that you can take it
serious and it can make have serious
stories but overall the entire point of
it was just to make you laugh let me get
rid of some of these fogs of war because
we don't need these due to - they just
make the map look all push posh and so
we're gonna talk about some events and
what could have happened basically any
event that I'm not really gonna use for
a while will kind of go over that here
so there was Ella folks and technically
the LF L could have spawned right here
funny enough you may have saw me
deleting them in the middle of the game
because I just I'm gonna be doing the
changes on the fly right in my mind so
the yellow Falcon counter not to spoil
anything it may have had a he may have a
big mommy but elephants in the woods
coming out but um not to spoil anything
was there was no diplomacy involved and
well so what that means is the carrot
suck and the character saw them they
would have been combat so we had just
come out of this cave and we've been
doing nothing but fight fight fight
fight fight fight fight fight fight
fight fight fight fight and like I said
we make them we make more money when the
guys are fighting when the guys are
fighting they get those donations events
right and that's great and all but it
doesn't necessarily make a better show
and I don't care if you know like I want
to make this trust me if we don't make
enough money cuz I don't do enough
donation event that's my fault
right but at the same time I'm not going
to push combat down everyone's throat
because you know when the guys are
sitting around in puppets you know
people are less likely to donate because
that's the if the show is a package
thing right you got to make the show as
good as you could make it not just
as much as you can make there's many
things we could do to make more money
and we'll try to do some of them because
that's that could probably be good more
money means we get to do bigger and
better shows right but at the same time
not at the expense of a good show so the
other so talking about the duel
encounters like the LFL one was and the
reason why I talked about like you might
bump into Ella Phelps is because they
pretty much should have both paths had
the exact same encounter just in two
different places this is a little trick
that I'm gonna keep using just the idea
of having the same encounter twice but
it's technically different because you
fight in a different battle location but
generally it has all the same elements
like in my document it's it was the
number two encounter but where it was
placed you know because the where
everything is isn't sensitive to the kid
to the little combat part of the
adventure regardless it was very easy
for me to just be like gonna put it here
and put it there the other place I did
that was in good old snake forest here
the blood snakes and that one was a much
more obvious because you saw this this
bloody trail and of course there was
this bloody trail but they were really
different weren't they
this one is a lot easier than this one
but we'll get into that um so this first
encounter I mean so we had the kobolds
the Coble's in my mind how I how I wrote
them is the kobolds there's only two
things they don't want to fight you but
they don't want to let you go into the
cave so if you want to go into the cave
you gotta fight the cobbles that was
that was my logic rule generally when
I'm writing these campaigns and I'm not
actually gonna pull up my notes just so
we can look at them for reference
general gonna write these campaigns are
write these these ideas and I kind of
write some information about how the
characters and the monsters and stuff
should behave a lot of that I can improv
to be perfectly honest I could improv an
entire campaign with just you know you
give me 10 minutes to put the tiles on
the board whatever all improv it and it
won't be as good but I could definitely
do it there's been plenty of times the
past I've had to do things like that and
I'm
confident my ability but I also liked it
when I had make a lot of things to play
with because then it lets me what I'm
improving really easily
lets me it like what I improv very
easily for example there was there's
nothing I wrote or an idea that this
kobold should become an ally that is
very much just because of the situation
that was created because you know this
this guy proven he like cogs code aside
the hug the cobalt Coco rolled hi I
rolled low okay this culpable sit out
and then it just kind worked and so the
nice thing was I had had all I had this
health I had abilities he would use I
had his weapon I had all written down so
I already had Philippe's character kind
of just like developed in the back of my
game master pocket right I don't think
he ever used blessings strength and I
think if I I think when I get better at
this I'll be able to use my NPC
characters more but I was still I was
juggling a lot of things right I was
juggling a lot of things that I still
need a lot of practice to get better I
think if I'm doing this year from now
which the only reason I wouldn't be is
if I couldn't because I'm in love with
this the only reason I would not be
doing this is if or rather I I think I'm
so I think I'm a year from now doing
this I will be way better at being able
to play NPC characters because that was
also a lot of fun I guess I'm really
good I'm really good at disconnecting
myself from the emotion of trying to win
or lose these type of games especially
up front Amell is live nothing to do it
but we're losing four players it you
know you always feel like you're playing
against the game master right you always
feel like you're like against them like
oh yeah sooo many versus you but for me
I'm just like no I just I just I'm
really just going for the story and I'm
gonna I have this weird sense of like I
know the games truth and if you believe
in the dice I will tell you the truth
and it's very obvious the dice rules hi
the characters have happy endings the
dice roll know the characters have sad
endings
and and it's just a string of like us
playing unluck and you know obviously
I'm gonna have a so biased here there
but I try to do away with that bias as
much as I can just that have that bias
be meaningless and so it was very cool
because this was not something I planned
to do at all to get to play the part to
Philippe as an active part in the party
which is why initially I was like oh you
could play for him and Coe was like no
you played him for me and I was like oh
that's that's fine like you you will
have noticed I am very lenient you know
I I don't I'm not a rule stickler I will
bend the rules on the fly in a way that
I feel is more balanced or bear balanced
or bear fair oh man that was I was gonna
get quoted balanced or fair to both my
party and my fans you know things that
are rewarding to everyone I tried really
hard to give people rabies you guys were
like reminding me and I was like you
know I'm like these characters all have
these movesets
and these things I'm trying to do with
them and like the bites supposed to be
like be this like game long punishing
thing that happens and wouldn't you know
it just in case that miraculously cured
is just but I didn't have a cure for the
rabies right but the guys had this whole
joke where they like throwing waters on
things so I was like ya know that'll be
the cure for rabies just you have to
throw some water on it because that's
really that's a way for me to connect a
joke to something that's happening in
the story but no Philippe Philippe was a
fan favorite and that was purely because
of dice it's because of dice and his
character is easily likable now we're
gonna go into talking about these
characters a little bit I need it and
you're gonna know if you don't know
realize this yet you're gonna realize it
next week I think I echoing this
statement to all the guys and they all
pretty much were on the ball to stay
true to your character
not necessarily the party now I don't I
don't like to be an Tea Party the reason
why dead bones when an Tea Party a
little bit is because it was getting to
the point where he was tired and he
needed to go to bed
and that's that's what happens when this
dream gets laid and we have DDoS and the
adventure just goes and goes and goes
and goes and so what he was actually
trying to do was actually just find a
way out I told him later that if ever
that is a case and there's like I was
talking about the guys because this is
something we couldn't have possibly
known if there's a time where you need
to leave the game that is something
should let me handle and not try to
force your way out of the story by going
anti-party like that but no we had dead
bones and roman who played thieving
assholes and if you remember if you go
go back and you watch their character
creation a little bit they were the same
at the beginning that they were at the
end they they didn't really respect each
other didn't respecting one other group
they were all about just the end game
prize
KO's gnome was a little bit more like no
no I'm a good guy especially because
right from the get-go easy shows he's a
really loving he's a lover not a fighter
and just in like a vault it's almost
like Justin was a was like a baby and
then he went through a teenage rebellion
and then he became an adult in this
entire campaign Justin actually probably
has the deepest storyline out of all the
characters because he kind of went from
being like this this just this this
useless like not not useless but this
guy taken for granted he was always
taking for granted right he's always
taken for granted he was left for dead
but still in the end he managed to just
escape you know he just still managed to
just get out of there when the things
looked it's it's worse and he looked at
huge perilous and Roman had a hilarious
in to because Roman almost got his
comeuppance like when when Romans
surrendered at the end of the game chat
was furious but I had told these guys
that surrender is an option like this is
a role-playing game if you want to just
give up in the middle of combat you
should because he because he's being
true to his character and his character
is about self-preservation right he's
not about saving his group is about
saving himself he's a greedy little
gnome right and that when he said he was
surrendering I smiled because I was like
Roman that
is so true to your character and the
hilarious thing is he gets away with
dead bones so let's let's go on that so
they fight these kobolds we fight though
with the whirlwind kobolds this
encounter was just overall pretty funny
it was it was a good encounter it had
lots of potential for characters
I had kobolds at least one of the two
paths you see kobolds the wooden Coble
is almost guaranteed throughout the
adventure couples were very much you
know on for a rounds character and of
course I've tried to make the show like
the bit like I like me trying to do in a
Finals cartoon every week that would be
really hard for me to do and put out and
it actually make any significant amount
of income this not so much but it's
still the same formula in a lot of ways
and it still has a lot of the same
characters and jokes and traits because
it's it's it's another baby of mine it's
another big project of buying that has
come off that way and so because because
kobolds Roux is such a big deal I put
him in and glad I did because feels got
to be a badass
so our characters got Phillippe which is
larious I love getting to play that
chance coming in here was a fun
encounter so this is this so this guy
had a two parts one you could wake him
up waking him up cost fifty dollars and
I the thing is like there's no way for
me to touch toon these on the fly
nor did I really want to because I just
kind of wanted to leave them anyway just
these were these were my expectations
we'll just watch you guys shatter them
then itself was fun because the thing is
if you guys are gonna shatter my
expectations I you know I don't need to
adapt on the fly for making more money
you've already shattered my expectations
now I'll just have to adjust my
expectations coming in the future um but
no he was super super fun he you guys he
he was awoken all of his abilities right
at the get-go
and I was just like oh my god this is
gonna get crazy he had like a hundred
stamina and they legitimately killed him
there was no fudging involved this fight
I didn't I knew I didn't have to like do
like skip abilities to do anything like
that I really tried to to win and I know
watching from home that you would've
been like but Rob you could've done this
this is this to be better and that is
only because
I was giving maybe 20% of my brain to
like men maxing trying to win the game
and 80% to running a show you know
between managing puppets managing those
cards cuz I have to activate those cards
make sure the donations come in come out
play the movie what's next you okay your
turn oder okay here's your role here's
what happens he's mentally exhausting
and so if ever you're like Rob you could
have played that encounter better you're
right I have a lot of improvement to do
to really min/max myself but so do the
guys the guys made lots of mistakes too
like giving Justin the blunderbuss the
second they mentioned that I was like I
got her I got a nerf he'll dwarf that's
he can't have ranged weapons to do that
he'll do probably needs a nerf anyway
but the kid but the thing is the
characters were really not fine-tuned
and that's okay I can balance adventures
towards characters that are weaker than
positive for example KO had this dragon
bow and imaginative Roman had the Dragon
bow right his Roman could do frost bolts
and Dragon bow for seven damage of
return and most of Romans turns because
of his spell set and his skills and just
what he could do were just doing that
that's all he had Coe had a blunderbuss
but he also had like what do you have he
had blink and was this other skill Oh
fog he had he had blink he had fog and
he has blunder Blas like he was going
between using his blunder and using his
bow which is really helpful for him it
was funny remember he really wanted to
sell the soup wonder bless the character
creation but if he had did Philippe
Philippe would have never been a badass
I almost call me almost calling him
Felix Philippe would have never been
that badass he turned out to be and that
was really really cute I think all the
guys use their skills if I'm not
mistaken I think they use their skills
and I think they used their items
something happened with their items I
could be wrong with that we might have
missed some things and we'll just get
better with that because as we get
better and better and better and better
we're gonna be on ba on the par with
trying to remember all the little queues
and stuff like you saw me nerf spell
blade or spell spell word
not spill what was it called blade turn
geez you saw me near blade turn on the
fly and I and you know sometimes just
gonna do that because it's just like wow
this is really complicated let's you
know this isn't gonna work like I think
they used our frog on a stick once and I
don't think they used it again even in
the last encounter I think they kind of
forgot about it but they'll get better
too but I know this was a great
encounter it was fun it was long it
wasn't that long though I think the
kobolds is really long because of all
the internet troubles we had but I think
this one was it which is a good amount
and if the encounter because the
encounter felt like you had a little bit
of discussion before it you know they
walked up there looking the crystals
they killed the boss and then they also
had like the post thing just talking
through the little Philippe I really
liked the the the focus of you know a
little bit of roleplay let's do some
puppets let's have some fun let's have
some conversations the puppets really
proved their worth many of the jokes we
could not have done without them it
makes awkward silence funny which is
kind of interesting right like a good
example is on the bridge with Nessie
like I got the role play as Nessie and
you know I just on the fly I was like I
could make his eyebrows go up and down I
was like okay I'm gonna do that and
that's a really really good like ability
to have because normally just having
silence and you can't raise your
eyebrows and people people can't get
that trait but you can do with the
puppets and so it can make a lot of like
funny timing jokes that are gonna be
really cool and we're gonna expand on
those puppets from week to week to week
giving the guys they need laughing
things on their puppets that's really
important it might feel like it's
breaking the fourth wall but I think if
the characters were laughing it would
just make us all smile more
so whatever we'll break the fourth wall
a little bit we're already doing that
all the time like this is the same type
of role play that you guys are probably
used to with like dwarfs versus zombies
and Lomb right like I'm not very serious
with all this stuff because when comedy
is your focus it's much more better to
be able to go in and out with every
other sentence like I'm talking about
the game now it's talking character and
you know nobody's really trying to pick
and be like what is that in character
was the nonon character you just kind of
assumed one way or another either way
you're not really thinking about too
much you're just like is
this is cute I like this but I noticed
was a gate thing and then so we skipped
the elephants there's a lot of combat
and I think at this point of the night I
was like okay I wanna get him to their
final encounter so what I was thinking
is that's the funny thing right at this
point I was like wow we're running at a
time like I think it was maybe around 10
p.m. because we had started late and all
the you know troubles and all that I I
think it might have been around 10 p.m.
or or somewhere around there but I was
like man I need to start winding down
this campaign I had already talked the
guys about going to midnight and no all
the guys apparently went were ok we're
going to 1:30 which we didn't talk about
but yeah at this point I was like I
gotta figure out how to do the boss now
the boss could spawn in the town but the
way the fight was designed is I could
bring rain at any point in the game I
could have had her be right here right
she's just in the force she finds you
there is many different ways that I
could have had Gwen at spawn all of
Gwyneth's abilities for designs that
they didn't have to be indoor/outdoor
they could just be anywhere and
basically I'm always gonna end each
stream with one major encounter because
that's really important to have one big
boss battle I can't always have them
fight a dragon but I always have them do
one momentum as' encounter that's
designed to eat to have some sort of
conclusion it's it's the show
that's over time might start to feel
formalistic when I'm going from alright
it's a public encounter puppet puppet
encounter and counter puppet puppet
encounter boss I understand that and you
know you guys can probably know me at
this point if I start to feel likes
getting stale I'll throw you guys
curveball and mix it up but I like that
I think that's gonna be really good to
think it's gonna be really fun I think
just like especially because now you
guys know they don't have to win in fact
you guys are itching for these guys to
play some characters that could kick ass
and win and that's a that's good too
because what is this the neuron campaign
and this campaign they've both lost in a
little way
that's okay but that's kind of funny
because you don't know if they're gonna
win and you don't know who's gonna live
you know who's gonna die it's a little
game of Thrones in that way but anyway
so they come out of cave
I'm detailing I'd only want to get
forward we get the Nessie Nessie had an
encounter this Eagle bear Chris bonny
Eagle bear I don't really know why these
tiles are low-quality I think I must
exported the file incorrectly or
something but um Nessie has his Eagle
bear who isn't an eagle bear one of his
donation girls would've been sprout
wings I think we're gonna see Nessie and
it's bear so we won't get to the depth
with this is what could have happened
but Messi was an encounter that I think
it was written to my documents that he
hates dwarves but likes gnomes and I
think I accidentally said it the other
way around and the second I said it I'm
just like and just go with it and so cuz
because the joke because because I knew
they had to have either three dwarves or
three droves of gnome or three gnomes or
three Doors in a gnome or three gnomes
in a dwarf
it had to be one way there had to be a
dwarf in the party and so the idea was
this guy's just races towards one thing
and then he was supposed to be raced
against Wars and he was known but he was
one of those gnomes who didn't realize
he was a nobody hated gnomes it was
really funny he gets mad for calling
people calling him a bridge troll and he
calls himself a bridge troll these were
just me not being as good as I could
man your isms there's I can get way
better at doing some of this role play
stuff I just need more practice in stage
presence and get my nerves under control
once this becomes a lot more calmer of a
show I think I'm gonna be really really
good at this stuff like if you ever seen
my Pokemon streams I can be I'm really
good at talking to myself already that I
can think of things on the fly that
he'll be a good that I'll be able to do
really really fun and better characters
I to be honest I was very disappointed
in myself in that respect all of my
characters that I was working with a
role playing of the fly for really weak
all the reasoning was weak but that is
just something else to improve so you
could fight him if you wanted to if you
can't pay his toll but funny enough
these guys just paid the toll I didn't
really believe it but these guys were a
band of greedy thieves and it was
somewhat out of character but I guess
they were fine because they didn't want
to mess with an eagle bear
that was pretty understandable I like
this character because I love tricking
my party every now and then you know
sometimes you know felt good especially
because of this battle of just them all
rolling 20s me rolling ones he was this
was a girl the girls gonna come up girls
gonna flirt with a boy girls gonna try
to get the boy kiss and then she's gonna
walk away with some of your stuff really
surprised they fell for it I guess I
guess do you like Justin is still very
much new to all this stuff but you know
I wonder if the only thing I did with
Messi was say that he has no family no
nothing the blabbity blabbity blah and
then she maybe really said that
hey I'm related to him I'm her sister
that should have been a surefire give
away cuz cuz generally I that's what I'm
talking about to be fair you know is it
fair to have some random character walk
up in steal some treasures no but it is
if I gave them the clues to prevent that
and they should have the second she says
she said she was someone who doesn't
exist and I'd already proven she doesn't
exist it means the guys weren't
listening and I believe it's fair to to
be like well I'm sorry you lost your
treasures you know I believe that's fair
I did a little role it was high enough
for me that I didn't have to critically
fail myself explain what I was trying to
do and then this steal some treasure
I stole Justin's amulet of bones which
would not have mattered although he
could have given it to potentially no
there's nobody who died nobody died in
the campaign I said Filipe died but
that's because at the end of every
campaign I'm gonna tell you how I think
their story is going to end I said it in
a very like serious that's how it ends
but unless it actually happens on a gay
board it doesn't happen so for this for
the sake of of everyone out there for
the lipe is not dead although I have
said that Gwyneth is going to decapitate
a man for a couple of months in prison
well that's going to happen at some
point and if there's a chance that that
doesn't happen we will see but I but I
will but that allows me to foreshadow
different things by just telling you
details of characters because there is a
chance that we never revisit Phillippe
remember I want to make new
characters each week and just developed
this really big backstory of characters
of people like you can hate Roman for
surrendering but I bet you you won't
when he comes back as a villain I bet
you if because now because what was his
name her name
Nemo nermal I don't remember her he's
character name but I can now bring her
back and I already know how she acts I
already know why she back she'd probably
come back to rob Marva truths right and
she probably still had dead bones
probably is the first time they backstab
each other but they probably do that all
the time right they probably worked
together it was dibbles with slink
Spinks something like that squeaks I
think he was squeaks and these names
don't really matter because I always
refer to them as her names but they
matter for the characters so it's good
to have this stuff documented I have a
patreon and I know I have a patreon his
name is cs1 I know there's a there's a
couple of youth of been doing it but the
the documentation anybody he does any
documentation of NPCs or the stories of
all these characters it's gonna be
immensely helpful for me because it's
gonna mean that because I don't have the
greatest memory so being able to have
fan resources to improve my shows like
that is really useful so if you're the
type of guy who likes writing and stuff
I really think I should find a way or
you guys should find a way to get
together unlike the Buffalo was a sub
rate or whatever and try to work on a
per wiki project or a documentation
project maybe it's just an open document
honestly that you guys can add it and do
like little submissions to each other
there's something that helps document
this stuff because you guys will have
way better memory that I will for this
stuff and if if there's ways for me to
like look back at these characters in
the future I really just want to get way
better ways of up keeping this stuff I
in you know in a perfect world I wish I
could take the time and watch every
single show back after I do it and take
my own notes but I don't think I had the
luxury of having that type of time to do
it every week right now but anyway you
guys are awesome
so we came in here so I had full
attention for this to be the last
encounter of the game and the reason why
is because at this point in the game I
was like
if they go through this forest we're
gonna have to go to secondary of the map
it's good it's gonna be a it's gonna be
longer and I tried I tried to force him
in the combat but this you know you
gotta give him props these four bumbling
idiots they had a good plan
you know like that that fog that Co did
right here was pretty genius and like I
I tried I put a guy over here and I gave
him a horn pulled that out he you know
he doesn't have that a horn written on
this sheet okay just let you know
everyone's not there despite I didn't
say make sure he has for me to call
other spell planes and that was the
special game who or what does game
mastering power of pulling the horn at
his pocket and oh yeah totally was there
because I I tried because I needed these
guys to go into this fight because this
would have been a good place to have
Gweneth come in
somebody told me Gweneth looks like
kuvira from league of legends and now
every time I go to say her name I'm like
oh Venus just kind of does look it's
same blue barber big big strong women
there's not a lot of those characters I
guess there's not a lot of big Armory
women I didn't when I talked his career
there I didn't I didn't want to talk
it's like because that's like
disingenuous to the characters it's like
now I'm just talking like this this is
this is the big stronger voice yeah it's
time to kick some gnome ass but I know
these guys really defeated this like it
was there's a man again like didn't go
to combat so we all get to do the cool
of the nation event which was hilarious
you guys will see at some point there's
this this tile which is a boat which was
an event and I will one day I'm gonna
use this type of thing maybe even in the
next month or two you'll probably see
that they reappear in another sense but
if there was there was a lot of cool
stuff that could have happened here
right there is billick and that's that's
what I want to show to be right like the
chat has the power to do really cool
things but they didn't get in combat the
fog was really smart they came over here
and then I was like oh god if they go
into this forest they're gonna be
fighting elves and the
but they were so smart they put another
fog down I that fog ability we thought
Romans
ice speed was really good just stun and
being able to shoot but that really
that's that's five damage a turn plus a
stunned well Justin's possibility does
that every turn right you just got to be
in melee range and you could toss and
you can stun somebody every turn that's
that's pretty that's like as if that was
what Roman was able to do a Roman could
do it from range that's way more
impactful but I know they had that fog
and I was just like nah man this is the
way that we've been using this fog it's
gonna be so strong and then the second
they got into this forest it started a
different encounter so I was like okay
nope they get away from the elves blood
florist was hilarious because it was
really showing how important dice rules
are to comedy and well would this has
already been established but to the
development of characters up to this
point uh Felipe was pretty just kind of
a funny little addition you know he's
he's got this he'll it was a kobold he
just he works for anyone you know k he's
just like yeah whatever you know I'm
just saying that with you guys
he liked coke is his friend but he
respected the boss cuz you know that's
the boss that's how he's lived his whole
life as well as the block there's always
a boss for coming what would I know what
the dough if there wasn't a boss like he
was perfect at the bench dimension but
when he got into this goddamn force with
these snakes
he just started killing him I have this
tend to see that when like we see those
really good roles like the the twos that
when I rolled the bad ones and the good
20s for people that I'd really like to
put a little bit more of a story in it
sometimes I just make it so they do
ridiculous I like it too so if you do
something 20 you do something ridiculous
and that's what he did if you like just
grab that damn snake I think that was a
20 year old right I'm trying to remember
you have that 20 role and he wrapped it
around his his womb that he got from Co
I think like I think he quite crippled
him and then just made him a badass and
that wasn't intended like this guy is
just a fully improvised character just
he's he exists and all of his legacy is
not based on why won't my grand plan for
him but fundamentally just the
randomness of dice and it's dice can be
so crude us in this game but also so
rewarding at the same time that it's
just kind of like life you have a lot of
happy days and you have some sad days
and the sad days make you really
appreciate the happy days and it's it's
like you get to feel that for these
little characters these little goofball
characters we all love it's like you get
to feel that all the time because
they're just you get disease carries
like oh he called them k4 for Kobol for
which was a Helen just was on top of
this humor like I've told people for a
while that Justin is the type of guy who
he comes in with the the punchline he's
so quiet he's in the back he doesn't say
a lot of things he lets everybody else
shine way more than him you know you see
you got Roman Romans like that you're
big he's got he's your big power voice
he's like me when when I when I'll do
Let's Plays no other content creators
and I just like completely overpower
them by just like talking it began or
genic and doing stuff that's what Roman
doesn't Roman does you got Coe who's
like that who's playing this lovable
he's always he's just always sitting the
lovable idiot stuff you have dead bones
is playing he's just good old dead bones
playing the cynical European card and
then we have the Justin in our group and
just an axis just like this teddy bear
this is teddy bear guy and but justin is
so funny some of the funniest moments in
the stream are when justin does
something like when he yells at roman
because he's just fed up with them and
when he Nick's names himself K for wants
his friends to call him K for kobold for
those are really really good so this
encounter could've been slow really hard
but these guys had their super movement
gem which I don't necessarily need to
move I don't necessarily need to rev it
might have felt overpowered to you but
the truth is it's kind of fun being
overpowered for all of us here who play
in a lot of computer games you know it's
it's kind of fun when you're when you
feel like you're better than the game
like it's like the main
like you've you've just you've
reconfigured the game that you've you've
broken it I only really like it when
things are so do not make the game fun
the type of a power that just ruins
everything
Justin's ability had the potential to do
that but for the most part no I just
made him the exact character he was
trying to be that guy who was just
supposed to carry these shitty-ass domes
on their adventure through the woods by
just being you know the the blundering
like he was just a sponge for the group
just that bubbly and you're not gonna
see that that that's something that
Justin excels at like at being that type
of character and we we do it a lot like
he plays that same type of character in
Lourdes and this week everybody just
tried to play what they're comfortable
with but in future weeks we're gonna
have people play with the knock-up for
with like because we're gonna played
such an evil character this week I
really am tell pushing Roman to do
something next week of being just the
you know the most righteous of character
you know just just be that righteous
attitude this week where you'll be the
guy to take the blow and give your give
your life to your friends because I want
these guys to go on all different levels
of this scale all different crazy parts
so that they can really show you guys
what's going on like show show you guys
the different types of things to just do
roll plagues
you know roleplay can scare so many
people they're like they theaters like
this nerdy fucking thing just
make-believe
everybody does it when they're like a
kid it's make-believe but now we're just
doing an outlet make-believe you know
why we do it it's funny it's just funny
this is funny and entertaining that's
why we do it so they can be can be
really entertaining so we're I'm gonna
push them to do lots of different fun
things so that they don't just always
feel like they're the same character
each week they should be the same person
but they shouldn't be the same character
um says nate force was pretty it was
pretty well because of their gem they
were able to get here really quickly the
boss did not have a lot of health but
luckily justin was rolling like super
low I think this guy only had 20 health
I think in this case I think I fudged
the dice up I don't remember like it
said 40 it said 20 stamina and I was
like 20 stamina that is not enough
Justin's going to swing that only
four hits I might have just kept that or
I might have buffed it a little I can't
remember I have to go look back but they
made it so fast to him that III buffed
it up because these things are supposed
to slow him down but they got half way
through the maze before I even started
the event
sounds like damn they really just booked
it what's supposed to happen is they
walk to the entrance of the forest and
they start but because these two events
blended together the way they did I kind
of just had I kinda had to start it once
they were already in it and they just
decided to book it like they were like
oh no we're just gonna book it and they
were fast little gnomes and dwarves so
they just went by really quick it was a
good encounter though because we really
got to see Felipe a badass so it worked
out at this point we had ended the
campaign and we have probably used up
almost all our time I think we had 45
minutes to midnight at this point and so
what I'm coming into map to I was
actually thinking I'm like man I I wish
I could have saved this man but to be
honest mehgan's or did these maps that
beautiful we plan on just giving them
out to you guys and you can use you like
you can just go through like eventually
we'll have all these tiles it'll give
you all these little tiles and stuff for
you guys to just put the characters on
and just build your own little games and
like it's fine if we got to make more
maps each week we will make these maps
each week I don't want to be stingy on
resources when it means sacrificing the
quality of the show so the problem I had
was the characters my design was the
characters because of their forests
we're supposed to start here because
that would have gotten they would gone
they would have seen those clock dials
there was a whole lot of event over here
they could have gone to see that that
elephant event with the with the dwarves
over here but we didn't have time for
that and I really wanted like I didn't
want them to just run at a time now I
could have definitely just spawned
gwyneth over here after they dealt with
the dwarves but I was like no we only
really need one more event I don't
really want to start another compa
combat event I want to finish the game
so I started just used a little improv
II skill and spawn here which was fine
you know this is for sure they're just
the king
the forest it was a little forced flip
the board over there's a little event
here that was where you would've saw
coober but coober didn't get to give
them in this week unfortunately and that
Cooper had two places he despawned
but there was no time for Cooper's they
were not supposed to go in this cave I'm
like guys because I really wanted to
push him towards the town I told him
that I told I had game a lot of my notes
on this after after the show talking
about lots of things that could have
done better to help out but they were
not supposed to go into the cave and
meet the great monkey fish the great
monkey finish was a hilarious Babel
encounter because he was supposed to
hate disobey and the second you mention
is 'van which got started but again I
had this cool step for this monkey fish
and I was like yeah you know what I'm
gonna go a completely different way than
how this is right on the page I could
have stuck to the to what I wrote in my
book like he was just supposed to just
spawn these terribly mutated little baby
monkey fish but I didn't want to do that
I wanted to I wanted them to be pushed
here so I decided you know what I'll
give them a little pet I'll just figure
out some some way to protect them from
the elves coming in so that they can go
back into the cave and one of the
funniest things that happened mmm one of
the one of the funniest happens if
somebody said something along the lines
of well we'll just stay at night and Rob
the key and I never told these guys that
I really wanted to end every night on a
combat oriented event so they weren't
there we're gonna stay we're gonna go
for the sneak to key plan I didn't like
that idea I didn't like that idea
because I really wanted to see them go
into combat one more time but it was so
perfect like they asked we'll just wait
til they sleep and I was like oh wait
they're elves I'll just write some lore
it's some really obvious general elf
floor oh yeah these elves don't sleep
and it was just like oh yeah no I
actually make sweet nope everyone should
have known that like I was like yes easy
past this guy robbed this town was fun
they really should have gone in this
building this was an alchemy lab there
was poster poster poster potion potion
for them to search around and just fill
up on hee
potions which they would have needed but
these guys didn't want to explore
buildings there was a little girl that
was gonna do the the Grinch single oohoo
type of story
cry for help he had to make her not not
upset her or she would be a problem
these two spell blaze in this building
are unarmed so if they come in from
another way they would have gone to
encounter where they would have
surrendered and offered up information
basically because they could not fight
this jail cell was interesting and I'm
gonna use this quite a few times in the
future this jail cell had no one in it
and the reason why was I was gonna put
someone in it that got lost in the
campaign that mattered so the ideal is
imagine if they left Phillippe in the
woods
they left Phillippe behind okay I would
have put Phillippe in the cage right I
kind of made this just as a like just
like okay this is something in case I
need a plot device later down the road
it didn't it came into effect as serving
as a jail for dead bones and so that's
kind of like I like to leave a lot of
things that are potential maybes just
try to think of as many like think about
what the players would want to do really
get into their minds and then give them
choices and options I didn't really like
the dead bones split off on the party it
worked out well for a story it was it
was it was really fun in a lot of ways
seeing characters go anti-party and then
come together like that is great it's
really risky from a storytelling point
of view because it means dead bones
might not get anything to play but
because we had an NPC character it
worked out we had a little use some
discussions about that last night just
talking about like hey if we have like
NPC characters this makes sense but like
if you write yourself into a corner
you're not gonna be able to participate
and that bad I don't like but dead bones
was doing it of course because he was
you know he's on Europe time and just
like anyone who is Europe but stayed up
that late
it was somes coming up we have to spell
blades sleeping in the barracks we had
to buy the door and these would have
prevented you from coming in the city
from this way and then and then of
course we had a Gwyneth missus akavir
look like hanging out I like the idea of
starting with a big female lead
boss elf I've loved female elves being
cuz I think I don't want to say they did
it first but I really liked how World of
Warcraft did elves where the males were
very much like just they were not
warriors they're mostly just like
wizards and sorcerers and things like
that but they're but the females of the
race were all just battle trained
badasses like how they are in Warcraft 3
that was that was cool and so I did that
here when when I was what inspired here
made him son clerics I like the idea of
them having this magical attack that
didn't do damage it just sapped your
energy on front of realms live is based
around this single resource pool it's
your health and it's your mana or
stamina or whatever you want to call it
it's all one resource pool I do that
because it's simple for people to
understand you'll notice that a lot of
the ideas and the cards and stuff
especially if you never play these games
I hope you were able to follow along
with some of how it works the logic the
the little the gameplay Ness like if you
watch this in your brain when went who
would be really cool if they use this
card with this card boom that's what I
wanted to do that's so I hope that's how
a lot of you felt with it but yeah this
this all just played out so cool I
couldn't have planned at this entire
part out any better it was great to see
you know Roman go for the tour first but
then he had the he had to surrender and
give up it was great to see Felipe just
in the act of saving his friends and
just his hatred of elves or what have
you
blow thing up it was cute that dead
bones was being a little coy with it and
that he did that knowing he might blow
his cell open so his other character
could escape it was shifty and dirty but
it was funny I I liked just the the the
the Sun tile mechanic you can tell that
I've played games like World of Warcraft
the rated cuz I approach these encounter
too soon it's designing bosses for me
right and that's that's how I'm always
gonna approach it and it's it's a little
tricky because it's not just about
making it so they have cool abilities
they have to be cool enough that chat
can watch a little video and then go oh
shit this is gonna be hard next week I
will do
- giant purchases at the end of the game
and one will buff our allies and one
will buff our enemies I think I might
maybe I won't I still I have tomorrow
and a few days to get everything ready
but maybe I'll go back on that but I
will play with some ideas of making some
events positive for our guys just
because it would be fun like if there's
an event called you know you know you
know dead bones gets a mace and just the
mace falls down from the ground there's
a lightning bolt and you seek Jeb Don's
character anime to get it that's really
fun one of that's pretty much what sold
me under the logic of I didn't really
want to make Czech compete with each
other but I like the idea of watching
animations of our characters so that's
really hard because we did this weekly
and the how we do this with Nick and all
the animations stuff is very much a
tight process with limited time each
week and it's something we'll expand on
eventually we'll probably have to get
more and more people involved so we
could do more and more bigger better
things but right now it's it's just so
it's a really fine line of balance to be
able to put on this type of show and man
I've been talking forever if you've been
watching this long unless you must
really really like this stuff I'm glad
because I can't wait to do more of it
basically I'm gonna hang up here Nath's
I'm just past midnight I'm now onto
Monday again III this it was this was a
dream come true and I have a excellent
opportunity to build a brand new
something it's this is some sort of phew
it's a fusion of a lot of different
ideas it's it's a big thing of internet
culture of live streaming of these
tabletop games of us nerding out of like
all this community of like paying people
to do a show not because you have to but
you guys just want to see it and want to
do it and that's it's all really new
territory for me so I'm gonna try to
take it slow because I know I'm not
gonna get everything right the first
time and I'm just gonna try to be as
honest I can with like talking to you
guys about this and
talking to my guys about this and
hopefully if this just comes off as just
a genuine thing of passion love the
nerdiness if if that's what if those are
the feelings they just get expressed
when I'm talking about the stuff then I
think I'm relaying how I feel about all
this I love fucking finish the dog and
glad they didn't kill him
right you guys were crying about the
poor lady flee pay but imagine if they
had killed Fenris look at them so use
that like now I don't have to have
Gwyneth come out without her just next
time Fenris is already there he's just
ready to go and it's not some and Fenris
as a donation perk it's like give Fenris
its are my teeth it's like armor like an
auto arrow turret on this back just
spent risking abs to project
yeah that's it's it's I like the comedy
because lets me do silly things anyway I
have been ranting I've been going on
forever
so thank you so much for everyone for
this week I can't wait for next week I
hope that we only produce the the
greatest and best of shows we can for
you and that they just get better and
better and better
thanks everyone for watching