marijuana's basically catnip for people
it has gained increasing acceptance in
recent years in fact one small bright
spot on election night was pro marijuana
referenda passing in eight states a big
win for lovers of weed so we are really
excited I mean this is a huge victory
not just for Californians but for really
the country and the world everybody here
should be so excited by this it's a
little weird that those celebrations
happened the same night that Trump was
elected it's like celebrating your
baseball team winning on the deck of
this sinking Titanic
bit of a mixed bag today but still go
Sox Yankees suck now as it as it stands
44 states now have some form of medical
marijuana law and eight have laws
allowing recreational use and that is
good news the war on drugs was futile
expensive and opposed overly harsh
penalties especially on African
Americans who police data suggests over
four times more likely to be arrested
for marijuana possession although
interestingly white people are a million
times more likely to be shocked by that
statistic and this is clearly no longer
a fringe issue in 1969 a Gallup poll
showed 12% favorite legalization today
it's 60% exactly marijuana is something
we've just all gradually decided is okay
like Mark Wahlberg as a serious actor
you know what
sure I've decided I'm fine with that but
the legality of marijuana is actually
much more fraught than you may think
in fact if you have marijuana right now
even if you are acting completely
legally according to your state you may
still be in serious jeopardy and that's
not your weeding juice paranoia talking
you could lose your home job or
possessions Greg and yes I know I'm
freaking the shit out of any stoned
viewer named Greg right now
but that is not a bad thing because this
story is genuinely worth worrying about
and let's begin with going back to why
marijuana is so heavily regulated in the
first place it was legal at the start of
the 20th century but anti-drug hysteria
killed partly by racist stereotypes
about who was using it led to it being
gradually outlawed around the country
and naturally it was Richard Nixon the
Mozart of racially motivated lawmaking
who targeted it in his war on drugs
releases that he was open about in
conversations he recorded yes yes quick
you start with footnotes you know who
he's talking to there Billy Bush yes
does our people just open up to that guy
always have yeah Nixon Nixon signed the
Controlled Substances Act in 1970 and
it's still in effect today
marijuana is classified as a schedule 1
drug the highest classification
alongside heroin schedule 2 a step-down
features drugs like cocaine and
methamphetamine and marijuana is not a
Schedule one any more than a hedgehog is
an apex predator you're not scaring
anyone Rowland
get a tattoo but that federal law is
constantly clashing with new state laws
and it's causing big problems for
instance legal marijuana businesses have
struggled to get bank accounts because
at the federal level they are still seen
as criminal enterprises so if banks took
their deposits that could be considered
money laundering and this was meant that
businesses had to operate all cash 100%
of our revenue comes in cash this is
federal taxes that we pay in cash after
our payroll when we pay our twelve
employees they're getting envelopes of
cash these are state taxes that is a
shitty way to be forced to do business
on a suspicious scale cash stuff tell
vlogs ranked somewhere between unfold
hundreds
didn't white powder and a wad of damp
ones containing a single pubic hair and
if you are wondering why he was talking
about paying his federal taxes yeah
amazingly under federal tax law you must
declare income even if the source of it
is illegal the tax code even has
provisions like if you receive a bribe
included in your income and if you steal
property you must report it's fair
market value which seems such an obvious
trap to catch criminals it has really
been listed on the form as this is a
trap are you really this stupid
oh my god you're filling out a federal
form admitting guilt aren't you you dumb
dumb idiot so now other businesses have
all the tax liabilities of other
businesses but what they don't get is
one major advantage the agency bars them
from making most normal business
deductions you know you could end up
with a tax bill far more than you know
any potential profit you could ever make
that's right you can't deduct certain
expenses and that can mean that you pay
double the amount of tax that you would
if you were selling any other product
and just think about that that means the
shop where you bought your weed may pay
double the amount of taxes paid by the
shop where you ordered that shitty pizza
Craig yeah I'm talking to you again
Craig I told you this was important pay
attention and it is not just businesses
facing difficulties its customers too
just look at Brandon Coates who is
paralyzed from a car accident as a
teenager now he had a prescription for
medical marijuana but he was fired from
his job at the Dish Network after he
filed a drug test what was it like for
you when they said we don't want you to
work here anymore
it was devastating I mean it's hard
enough for somebody like me to get a job
people look at me like they don't think
that I can do what I can you know did
you think because you had a medical
marijuana car that you had license to go
ahead and use it well it was I was under
the impression that we had passed the
law and that we had made it legal
yeah it's frankly understandable that he
thought he was doing nothing wrong the
state had given him a license to use
medical marijuana legally and yet he got
fired anyway and also he couldn't turn
to
with Disabilities Act for help because
that is a federal law and it doesn't
protect marijuana use all of which is
pretty frustrating as like driving
exactly the speed limit and getting
pulled over by a cop who tells you sorry
the federal speed limit is three and the
legal age to drive is 62 and also you
have to be drunk surprised you're fuckin
under arrest now and even if you are
only dealing with your government at the
state level decades of enforcing
anti-drug laws can result in local
officials making big mistakes as to
michigan parents one of whom tweeted his
epileptic seizures with marijuana
discovered in 2013 steven maria green of
lansing helplessly watched as their
infant daughter bree was taken from
their care the reason given the state
sanctioned medical marijuana users home
was too dangerous for their
six-month-old because of the plants
inside it would place our residents at a
higher rate of armed robbery and
therefore was an imminent danger for my
child to be removed that is just
completely absurd if you have valuable
items in your home we might take your
children and i will say that is going to
add some real excitement to the prices
right from now on I really want that
entertainment center but I love my kids
fuck it sorry Tommy daddy's going for
the plasma screen it's a dream son a
dream of mine and look I know that some
people will say we'll hold on the
medical efficacy of marijuana needs a
lot more study and that is true the
problem is it's very difficult to do
that because again federal laws are
standing in the way to study marijuana
you need approval from three different
federal agencies which can take in years
in fact one scientist was forced to wait
six years just to begin studying its
effects on PTSD which is a long time I
frankly wouldn't blame her if she just
said fuck it I'm studying dust chocolate
during sex help red wine make you lose
weight and this at least that way I'll
get to go on the Today Show and if you
are conducting a federally approved
study on marijuana you can only get it
from one place doctor mamuno solely
oversees the University of Mississippi's
marijuana project its mission to a law
enforcement and produce pot for federal
study mostly related to addiction
all intents and purposes you're the
government's sole producer of marijuana
it's true the sole source of
government-sanctioned marijuana is that
guy at the University of Mississippi
so please update your stereotypes about
the University of Mississippi which I
believe is the official slogan of the
University of Mississippi and while
researchers wait for marijuana to study
whether it helps with PTSD plenty of
veterans will tell you it absolutely
does
take Danny Belcher he is a Vietnam vet
who'd been prescribed a great deal of
medication for pain and depression but
as he told the Kentucky legislature in
2014 he found that when he tried
marijuana it started really helping him
I do have my bola pot in my house if I
wake up at night in that nightmare when
I'm wringing wet with sweat and I see
Cramer his dead body Rodriguez his dead
body if that night clerk gets a bad I
can't wake up I realize it's just a
nightmare I will like to pipe up I'll be
a criminal I'll go back to sleep but
next morning I will get up at 6 o'clock
like I always do now 4 days a week I go
to a gym I run now further veterans I
couldn't do that if I saw their damn
drugs the VA had me on exactly so for
all the talk you hear of marijuana being
a gateway drug in his case that gateway
led to peaceful sleep rigorous exercise
and community service pretty nice
fucking gates it turns out nice one to
walk through if you get the chance now
you may have noticed that he said he's
acting like a criminal there which is a
little odd because Kentucky actually has
a medical marijuana law on the books but
these shortcomings of that law touch on
many of the reasons why legal marijuana
can actually be a bit of a gray area for
start Kentucky's law has many
restrictions it only applies to one
marijuana product and it requires a
written order or a prescription and that
is a real problem because under federal
law it is technically illegal for any
doctor to write you a prescription for
marijuana now so most states that they
get around that by just calling for a
recommendation
or certification which doctors can give
you but even it Kentucky's Lord did that
it Danny went to his doctor to the VA
they couldn't give him anything because
they're a federal Hospital and federal
policy prohibits VA doctors from even
recommending marijuana regardless of the
state law and regardless of their
medical opinion which again is a bit
weird a doctor shouldn't be ignored
because he recommends marijuana a doctor
should only be ignored because he is
televised we all agree on that we're all
on the same page on that one I think but
here's the thing it gets worked even if
Danny had a private doctor and Kentucky
rewrote its law where would he get
marijuana from because Kentucky's law
also neglected to set up any system for
legal marijuana distribution so he's had
to obtain it from somewhere else but
where would he do that and how now he
could have it shipped right except no
that would be a federal crime but what
if he flew to a state where marijuana is
completely legal and just brought it
back to Kentucky here's the thing no
again
that is also a federal crime could he
drive to a neighboring state to get what
he needs
unfortunately no because two of those
states have total prohibitions on
marijuana and the rest don't currently
recognize out-of-state patients now if
you are thinking well hold on could he
train a carrier pigeon who carry the pot
from Colorado yes that's a good idea and
cool Birds stamp but but as a practical
matter there no partly because it's
illegal and partly because you know the
bird will eat it on the way stop flying
and spend the whole night giggling about
how owls seem like they have glasses but
like don't have glasses and that's crazy
right they don't know but it's there
right
the point is if you live in Kentucky
despite there being a law that
ostensibly gives access to medical
marijuana there's virtually no legal way
for you to get it now things practically
improved toward the end of the Obama
administration because his general
attitude with essentially this we still
have federal laws that classify
marijuana as a illegal substance but
we're not going to spend a lot of
resources trying to turn back decisions
that have been made at the state level
on this issue right he's attitude to pot
was basically I'm not going to hassle
you over this and unless you make me
essentially the same policy as a
security guard at a Dave Matthews
concert and his administration issued
guidelines in that spirit by the end of
his term it was actually a little easier
to study marijuana and for dispensaries
to get bank accounts but those
guidelines weren't permanent and that
could be a real problem because our new
Attorney General is jeff Sessions
the concept of golf expressed in Man
form and he he has been pretty clear
where he stands on marijuana this is not
a non dangerous drug this drug is
dangerous you cannot play with it it's
not funny not something to laugh about
and in trying to send that message with
clarity that good people don't smoke
marijuana well Lady Gaga said she's
addicted to it and is not harmless yeah
okay Jeff but Lady gaga also said I
believe that men and women deserve to
love each other equally as well as touch
me in the dark put your hands all over
my body parts so please Jeff if you're
going to live your life according to
gargoyle quotes accept the entire canon
and listen I'm not saying there
shouldn't be laws that place sensible
restrictions on marijuana as there are
with other substances but our federal
laws desperately need to be brought up
to date and perhaps there is no clearer
sense of just how establishment that
view is becoming than this the cannabis
caucus is a bipartisan effort to protect
state marijuana laws and blow out
outdated federal prohibitions on weed
believe it or not these are the guys
pushing for legalized pot in Congress
yes there is now a cannabis caucus in DC
and it's co-chaired by these four narcs
and if even an 83 year old Republican
from Alaska has come around on this
issue then it's probably time for our
laws to catch up and there are a bunch
of ideas out there one bill proposed
just this week would remove marijuana
from the Controlled Substances Act and
officially renamed the ATF the Bureau of
Alcohol Tobacco marijuana
Firearms and Explosives which doesn't
really make sense to get all the awesome
stuff together in one place
in fact why not keep going and make it
the Bureau of Alcohol Tobacco marijuana
firearms explosives monster trucks
motorcycle jump sand sick half leather
jackets with Tigers on them by the way
that jacket is even sicker and perfect
this is my jacket this would leave it
morning it is an actual six thousand
dollar Gucci jacket as anyone usually
love to buy one of these it's worthless
now I just made your jacket uncool and
worthless by wearing it but that bill is
just one proposal fixing all of these is
a huge undertaking marijuana laws affect
everything from environmental
regulations to international treaties
and ideally we should also go back and
expunged records of people convicted of
low-level marijuana offenses in the past
and all of this I know is a lot of work
which is why we should really start
right now because I would argue that it
is absolutely worth it
for people like Brandon Coates and for
people like Danny Belcher and perhaps
most of all for Greg who has been
freaking the fuck out this whole time I
can see you Greg and I can hear your
thoughts