Cole basically cocaine for Thomas the
Tank Engine what we've heard a lot about
Cole this past year particularly from
President Trump in fact arguably a key
reason that we have this cautionary
Bible story in the White House was the
ability to connect with mining
communities during the campaign even
doing this in West Virginia nice nice
okay okay let me stop you right there
it is not easy watching someone I
doubted on a day of hard labour in his
life show how he thinks coal mining
works if I watching a four-year-old's
play store oh that's right I even you
have hand them your duckie and then you
get cookies yet idiot but what that
crowd probably remembered from that day
was how Trump speech ended will start
winning winning wedding and you are
going to be very proud and for those
miners get ready because you're going to
be working your asses off alright thank
you everybody that's right you're going
to be working your asses off like that
right that's how you do it maybe some of
this you'll do or maybe this Mabel your
boobs oh your mama's right you mutt
you're going back to the coal mines
aren't you I don't know what you people
do but Trump promising to bring back tol
jobs is undeniably potent time to listen
to his EPA Administrator it's a promise
that he's already keeping since the last
fourth quarter of last year - most
recently added almost 50,000 jobs in the
coal sector in the month of May alone
almost 7,000 jobs okay so the only
problem there is that those numbers are
bullshit the Bureau of Labor Statistics
have the actual number of coal jobs
created since last year has been just
1,300 so that 50,000 new jobs plane was
off by 48,000 700 which for this
administration is actually
uncharacteristically accurate I I just
assumed in the figure we've more like 12
mining jobs and they're not actually
jobs they're lobsters and Trump didn't
create them he just remembers 12 times
in his life that he saw a lobster but
look there is no doubt Trump claims coal
is a huge priority for his white house
and let's set aside tonight the fact
that it is environmentally catastrophic
which we shouldn't because it is but
this president clearly doesn't care
about that he pulled out the Paris
agreement citing coal as one of the
reasons he's lifted a freeze on new coal
leases on public lands and revoked a
rule to limit coal mining companies from
dumping debris into local streams with
miners behind him both times so if coal
jobs are so important to him let's talk
about them and let's begin with a number
because it's smaller than you might
think while President Trump has talked
about
reviving the coal industry which employs
76,000 people retailer JCPenney on the
verge of bankruptcy employees 114,000
along Wow
so there's a lot that is surprising
therefore start I didn't even know that
JCPenney had employees anymore
I thought anyone who walked into a
JCPenney was just handed the keys to the
store say here see if you can make it
work good well but 76,000 co-workers is
less than you'd expect although in the
areas where they are concentrated coal
mines are central to the community some
schools have miners as mascots for their
sports teams or even or even they have
coal industry sponsored fairs where kids
make a variety of projects perhaps none
as awesome as this one it's about a
mother : my clothing is on a journey to
figure out what is what is gonna be and
what it could be grow I love that kid
and by the way top-notch use of air
quotes there because you and I both know
kid that lumpy is not going to grow up
lumpy is going to live a short life
underground until one fateful day his
friends notice he's missing
where's lumpy they'll say has anyone
seen lumpy they'll form search parties
and put posters up around town but in
the back of their minds they know the
truth they've always known and one day
there's a knock at the door it's the
news they've all been dreading all along
lumpy has been burned to death in a
horrifying ritual alongside the entire
lump family this is why we don't name
them because then we get attached
anyway the point is when contours go
away communities feel it especially
because these jobs are high-paying a
coal miner can make upwards of eighty
thousand dollars so that's not easy to
replace and the industry itself points
much of the blame for lost jobs at
President Obama with one of the loudest
voices being this guy these are my
employees I care for them deeply Barrack
Obama and his Democrat followers are
destroying entire cygnus of America mr.
Obama is an outlaw I pray everyday that
this man's in confidence will be
overcome that is evil agenda will be
overcome when you have a 52 year old
coal miner in your office crying because
you were forced to lay off that's what
Obama has never seen because he's never
had a job what are you talking about he
had a job listen to yourself his job was
destroying entire segments of America
with his evil incompetence or his name
was not Barrack Obama about that man was
Bob Murray the CEO of Murray energy and
we will get to him later but his claim
that Obama's regulations have been job
killers is worth taking a look at
because while coal mining jobs
undoubtedly did decline under Obama is
worth noting the coal mining jobs have
also been declining for decades we just
look at that trend line cold industry
jobs declined and roughly the same rate
as careers in the Zeppelin industry and
babies named Adolf Oh some still exist
there's just not nearly as many of the
many lives
and I'm not saying that vomit
regulations had no effect but
researchers have found that they had
very little impact relative to other
factors when they studied the decline in
expected demand for coal from a decade
ago they found that nearly half of that
drop was owing to the drop in natural
gas prices and another 18% was due to
the growth in renewable energy like wind
and solar and there is perhaps no more
dramatic evidence of coal losing out to
solar energy than this work has begun to
power the Kentucky coal mining museum
not buy coal but buy the Sun we believe
that this project will help save at
least eight to ten thousand dollars off
of the energy costs on this building
alone it's true the Kentucky coal mining
museum is now using solar energy it's
like finding out the Rock and Roll Hall
of Fame was brought to you by smashmouth
and the hard truth is even if
consumption wasn't declining companies
would still be cutting jobs and they are
increasingly replacing miners with
machines you had all this mechanization
going on the people leaving but it's
come to the point now where they don't
do underground mining if they can get
away with it they do mountaintop removal
and surface mining you can mine a whole
mountainside and I'm talking about a
whole mountainside within a year or two
with around seven to twelve people and
you that's how you need he's right
coal mining like almost all industries
is facing increased automation and I say
that well aware that in five to ten
years I am probably going to be replaced
by a robotic English tea kettle that
screams depressing money stats at you
and look the rise of alternative energy
is a good thing for the earth as a whole
and some point out that as coal jobs go
away new green jobs are opening up which
is true but not where coal miners live
at West Virginia and Kentucky for
instance ranked near the bottom in solar
jobs per capita so for the people who
face layoffs the future can look bleak
and it's really depressing or even hey
you have kids and going to work one day
and may say well you don't work here
anymore
you gotta go home
it's your family's handing your average
enema
yeah and that is devastating and I know
that it does not help someone in his
situation to be told statistics by
someone like me in a TV studio possibly
powered by coal who doesn't have the
skills or muscle mass to be a miner and
who looks like the result of a drunk
threesome between Chris Hayes Austin
Powers and a potato but I know that but
the question is what does help someone
in that situation Donald Trump insisted
he's helping miners by reducing
regulations on coal companies but too
often people conflate coal coal miners
and coal companies and imply that when
you help one you help them all but they
are not all in the same boat although
they may insist otherwise for instance
when the coal company Alpha Natural
Resources filed for bankruptcy two years
ago their CEO stressed how painful that
was our more mine closures possible they
are unfortunately and for crutchfield
that's clearly the hardest part of it
all when I asked him about this photo
displayed prominently in alpha
headquarters a photo called daddy's
hands the emotions were hard to hold
back that is the backbone of America and
we have that photograph just to remind
their body who we serve that's a nice
sentiment just slightly undercut by the
fact that according to court documents
alpha later asked its banks bankruptcy
trustee if it could save three million
dollars by terminating the health and
life insurance benefits of around 1200
retirees while at the same time seeking
permission to pay bonuses totaling up to
around 12 million dollars to top
executives including that guy that you
just saw which is the sort of thing that
might make daddy's hands want to do
something like this and you wouldn't
really blame them for that and yet coal
CEI was constantly kind to workers that
it's us against them take don
blankenship ex CEO of Massey Energy he
once held a rally featuring Ted Nugent
Hank Williams jr. and a rousing speech
from Blankenship himself and though that
our safety and health of coal miners is
my most important job I don't need
Washington politicians to tell me there
and neither do you
[Applause]
okay so speech aside that's a hell of a
look it takes a brave man to go half
Kerri Strug
and half their time to make the donuts
God and if you thought if you thought
the presence of a man who's just been
ejaculated on by a flag was as upsetting
as that rally to get well guess who else
was there
you believe in God family country we
believe America is the shining city on
the hill right we believe his friend how
you doing down by the way there's a
really hot looking chick in the third
rail there Hayes oh man I'll take you
backstage to me back a little later
you want to meet me later what the fuck
was that in the course of his speech he
referenced God quoted Reagan and engaged
in sexual harassment that man really is
Fox News but but notably notably a few
months after his rally against
Washington safety rules Blankenship's
company had a massive explosion killing
29 miners and Blankenship denies
responsibility but in the wake of that
disaster he was sentenced to a year in
prison for conspiring to violate mine
safety and health standards he actually
just got out and now has to rebuild his
life with absolutely nothing but his
estimated golden parachute of 86 million
dollars and that will help you get back
on your feet 86 million we'll help you
get back on anyone's feet you want to
get back on Fred Astaire speech that's
no problem
for 86 million grab a hacksaw we are
digging up Fred Blankenship is already
lobbying the Trump administration to
oppose more onerous criminal laws for
mine owners say they will not improve
mine safety and I would like to think
that Trump would not listen to him
because you know he loves the miners so
much but there's not much evidence of
that what there is evidence of is his
affection for nine CEOs his Secretary of
Commerce is Wilbur Ross who ran the
company that had the deadly sago mine
disaster and he's also close to that man
that you saw earlier Bob Murray who
claims that Trump called him shortly
after the election to deliver a special
message he said tell your coal miners
I've got their back and then he said I
Love You Man
well congratulations on that Bob you're
now in the very select group of people
that Donald Trump has said I love you
too along with presumably the worst
Baldwin exactly one of his two daughters
and the hollow-eyed business ghost that
greets him in the mirror every morning
and Marie actually illustrates the
device that can exist between a coal
companies interests and those of its
workers and I'm going to need to be
careful here because when we contacted
Marie energy for this piece they sent us
a letter instructing us to cease and
desist from any effort to defame harass
or otherwise injured mr. Marie or Marie
energy and telling us that failure to do
so will result in immediate litigation
and a cease and desist letter is
incredibly something that we've never
received before on this show not even
the nation of New Zealand and sent us
one and we want to be kicked those
eminent burglars in the ball almost
every week so so I have to proceed with
caution I'm not going to say for
instance that Bob Murray looks like a
geriatric dr. evil even though even
though he clearly does because Murray
Energy has sued people in the past just
last month they sue the New York Times
for libel they also sued everyone from a
contributor to The Huffington Post to
these two papers in Ohio in fact
Murray's current general counsel told
reporters that this paper had included a
potential economic loss of and I am NOT
making this up 1 billion dollars which
when you think about it is exactly what
you'd expect from a geriatric dr. evil
and though Murray energy have insisted
in the past that they only sue news
outlets
as a matter of last resort and never to
chill free speech their letter also
tells us that they might pursue our
damages to the fullest extent of the law
including to the level of the Supreme
Court of the United States and that
would actually be a real mistake because
we have a personal relationship with
those judges and I'll give you a fun
fact if you've scratched Justice Alito
just behind his left ear he pees on the
floor that truth that's true of the dog
and the man so so as we have been
explicitly told to cease and desist let
us do neither of those things and let's
talk about Bob Murray because
on TV in defense of coal workers but
let's take a look at his actions shall
we because Murray's company recently
unsuccessfully sued to block a rule
aimed at reducing miners exposure to
coal dust that causes black lung a
disease which killed as many at 10,000
people between 1995 and 2005 Murray
insisted that the rule was illegal
destructive and did nothing for miners
but nothing for their health although
last year with the rule in effect
government reports indicated respirable
dust levels fell to historic lows and
look if you even appear to be on the
same side as black lung you're on the
wrong fucking side that's the equivalent
of watching my girl and rooting for the
B's and some of some of Murray's
employees have clashed with the company
over safety a few years back
Murray proposed a program where miners
could receive bonuses based on the
amount of coal they extracted it was
voted down by employees who believed it
would have an adverse impact on safety
in the mines but the company did it
anyway
saying if workers didn't like it they
could just write void on their checks
and amazingly around 62 employees did
just that with - going even further one
returning a check for $11 58 by writing
kiss-my-ass Bob on it and another taking
a check for $3 22 and writing each shit
Bob and I have to say well-played miners
because you could have sent that message
on a cake or you could have sent it on a
bear with a big stuffed heart but to
write it on your $3 bonus check well
played to you sirs and then there was
the deadly collapse at the Crandall
Canyon Mine in Utah Murray attracted
attention for a bizarre press conference
in which while rescuers were still
working he was making bold claims about
the cause of the accident this is her
first major accident I've ever had in
one of my coal mines in 20 years of
being in existence their first major
accident and this was caused by an
earthquake not something that Murray
energy or Utah American did or our
employees did or our management did
so here is the interesting thing about
that to this day Murray says that the
evidence proves he was correct that an
earthquake caused the collapse but that
was decidedly not the conclusion of the
government's investigation which found
it was caused by unauthorized mining
practices and there was no evidence that
a naturally occurring earthquake caused
the collapse Murray does not want us
talking about the accident saying it was
an incredibly difficult time for the
families and though he admits that he
was unable to satisfy the expectations
of the family members he says he showed
them honesty sincerity and compassion
throughout the crisis although according
to both a Department of Labor
investigation and congressional
testimony by some of them their pain was
exacerbated by Murray's behavior while
they waited for news of their loved ones
all we heard was earthquake earthquake
we did not want to hear about
earthquakes but wanted to know when we
were going to see our loved ones again
Murray more than once yelled at us
when we asked questions Wow yelling at
distraught families when they asked
questions is not okay it is barely okay
to do it with five year olds and they
asked over forty two million questions a
day I give up why are birds is not a
question I know the fucking positive
China Stu village go go go go there
[Applause]
and there is one more bob story Bob
Murray story I would like you to know
about
it's an apocryphal tale concerning how
the company began Union miners claim
that Murray used to tell them that he
was sitting on his back porch
contemplating his future when he was
approached by a squirrel who hopped up
next to him looked him in the eye and
said Bob Murray you should be operating
your very own life and we asked Murray's
company about that story and they told
us it never occurred and you know what I
actually believe Murray on that one
because I think deep down we all know if
squirrels could talk they wouldn't be
giving career advice to coal executives
they'll be loudly lifting their favorite
nuts okay let's go
acorns chestnuts walnuts almonds cashews
are good or of course technically not a
nut
Brazil nuts not my favorite Bowl I
wouldn't kick him out of bed either do
you feel me guys do you feel this and
look to get back to jobs Murray argues
that he has provided thousands of them
to mining communities and he's right
about that and for those communities
that fact might understandably outweigh
everything else especially if Murray and
Trump can bring coal back but notably
even Murray himself is careful regarding
that can those jobs come back if it's a
Donald Trump presidency I don't think
those jobs can come back ma'am but we
can stop the destruction I don't think
it can come back to where it was but we
can stop it and that's what I've told
mr. Trump and he gets it uh hang on
there Bob no he doesn't he's a a he
barely gets what mining is he may well
think it's just running up to things
that he wants and yelling mine that's
that's possible and and B B these
repeatedly told miners that they're
going to be working their asses off if
Trump really cares about miners you'll
be putting a plan in place for their
futures as mining continues his
long-term decline but he isn't doing
that now luckily there are some small
things being done by others at one
company called bitsource in Kentucky has
been hiring miners as software
programmers and paying them through
their retraining but weren't numerous
code languages that work CSS
PHP HTML Javascript twing and Yemen and
that's really impressive so much so that
I will ignore the fact that twig and yam
all
sounds like a bootleg Russian DVD
knockoff of lilo and Stitch the look
back that program is encouraging but it
won't suit everyone and at present it
only has nine jobs for former miners and
Trump is actively hurting the chances of
other projects like it his new budget
proposes cutting funding for the
Appalachian Regional Commission which
helps revitalize communities affected by
coal mining job losses by funding
employment programs that have helped
among other things bit source and you
might wonder well why would a guy who
says he loves miners all the time do
that well for a sense of how he really
feels
just with a Playboy interview from 1990
where he said and I quote if I had been
the son of a coal miner I would have
left the damn mines but most people
don't have the imagination or whatever
to leave their mine they don't have it
and you know what they certainly don't
have what Trump has specifically
inherited wealth and hair like the wispy
pubes of an aging yeti but the point
here is Trump needs to stop lying to
coal miners we all do
stop telling them that their jobs are
all coming back when they not stop
telling them that coal is clean when it
isn't and stop pretending that this
isn't an industry in the middle of a
difficult and painful albeit necessary
transition an honest conversation about
coal and it's miners needs to be had and
we should neither safe nor desist from
having it which actually reminds me one
more thing here and Bob Murray I didn't
really plan for so much of this piece to
be about you but you kind of forced my
hand on that one and I know that you are
probably going to sue me B you know what
I stand by everything I said although
just to reiterate I do not think you
claimed a squirrel talk to you even by
your standard that would be a pretty
ridiculous thing to say so I believe
that you have never been spoken to by a
squirrel until that is tonight
nothing fuck about
[Applause]
yeah either way that mr. nothing but I
understand that you have a message for
Bob Murray I do okay hey Bob just wanted
to say if you plan on pursuing I do not
have a billion dollars but I do have a
check for three acorns and 18 cents oh
that's that's very nice of you mr.
Nutter Butter it is yeah it's made out
to hey Bob
[Applause]
you