the white house the building inside
which Donald Trump and I feel this isn't
mentioned enough is regularly naked and
just just think about that he might be
naked in there right now making you just
leave
maybe there's a bandage somewhere on his
person we don't know we just know that
he's there and we all have to live with
that
but while Trek himself is divided there
are two White House figures who are
widely admired Jared Kushner and Ivanka
Trump they're like America's William and
Kate except in this case both of them
are attractive and I'm really many many
people have praised for them the only
adults in the room the moderate the
centrist frankly Democrats are Jared and
Ivana you know thank God his kids are
you know their day-to-day they're a
positive influence on him his best
running mate by the way would be a bonk
I don't know that I've met a more
composed brilliant beautiful in every
way person well that is high praise from
senator bob Corker I've never met a more
brilliant beautiful person I imagine
that went down great with his wife and
two daughters happy Father's Day dad
giving wanker send you anything but the
Liberals the popular assumption is that
Jared and Ivanka will be moderating
influences basically if Trump is
thinking about pressing a button labeled
nuke earth they will on behalf of all of
us guide his hands towards the bun
labeled hey maybe don't and they both
have official roles now a banker has
recently taken an unpaid position as
assistant to the president and as for
Jared well he seems to have a hand in
basically everything he's been planning
this week's visit of the Chinese
president tomorrow logo and he's also
tasked with brokering peace in the
Middle East the president tapping his
son-in-law to reform the criminal
justice system not to mention he's
running the new office of American
innovation where he's responsible for
reforming veteran care tackling the
opioid epidemic and overseeing the not
so small feet of revamping the entire
federal government holy shit it is not
unusual for powerful men to give their
son in laws do-nothing jobs but leave it
to Donald Trump who can't even get
nepotism right to give his a do
everything job so given the power that
they seem to hold tonight let's take a
look at Jared and Ivanka and let's set
aside the question surrounding potential
conflicts of interest between their
business ties and their positions in the
administration instead let's focus on
answering just two basic questions is if
uncle really be moderating influence the
people claim and what in Karen's
background justify such a gigantic white
house portfolio and let's start with
Ivanka Trump's only daughter except for
and yet somehow including Tiffani now if
anchor is reassuringly familiar because
you've been part of the Trump brand
since she was a child she even co-hosted
Trump's Miss Teen USA pageant at age
fifteen featuring this noted noticeably
odd moment let's go back to the vodka
thanks Eddie
and I can't guarantee my brothers were
loving that or any of you up there
single oh yeah why do they have say that
yes Eddie my blood relatives are rock
hard right now you heard me the men with
whom I share parents probably have erect
penises at this very moment but for any
public drama of the Trump family Yvonne
has been cast as the calm reasonable
endure voiced one a dynamic that's
perhaps best exemplified by this moment
what's the favorite thing you have in
common with your father either real
estate or golf Donald with your daughter
well I was going to say sex but I can't
relate
what is wrong with you you colossal
fucking creep
you found the only possible wrong answer
to that question what's your favorite
color
Hitler still that's that clip that clip
actually illustrates a lot of what we
like about Ivanka she's the exact
opposite of her dad he's crazy she's
poised and restrained and she is
impressively on message at all times
just think about how little information
she gave you in that exchange she was
asked what do you have in common with
your dad and she said real estate and
golf those are not personal details they
are core components of the Trump brand
that any stranger would associate with
him if you if you asked Huey Dewey and
Louie what they had in common with their
uncle Donald's and they said either
feathers or no pants
you would think wow the duck family
really doesn't spend a lot of quality
time together and that ability to
apparently say nothing and yet
consistently support her dad can
actually apply to her political views as
well
because the assumption that many of us
have that she disagrees with him it's
actually based on much just watch our
response to being questioned about what
they specifically disagree on my father
agrees with me on so many issues and
where he doesn't he knows where I stand
but it's a representation of something
that you disagree with him on and that
you think that by speaking up to him it
made him change his position or soften
his position I think most of the impact
I have over time most people will not
actually know about
oh well that's convenient so we should
just give her credit when good stuff
happens and then blame others when bad
stuff happens that's not a job
description of a political adviser
that's a description of an Old Testament
God and that answer there enables you to
project whatever you want onto her based
on secondhand rumors and assumptions
which is exactly what Gayle King and her
co-hosts then did what is it they differ
on and weirdly she is she is not she is
not going to share that information with
me anyway she's not sharing that
information but I think that that's
between her and her
but what do you think I think about
climate change certainly I think about
gay rights I think some of the
immigration ban Planned Parenthood and
certainly Planned Parenthood
oh yes yes certainly Planned Parenthood
as well why not
and you know those things all feel true
but there is not a lot of evidence you
know it's the same way that I assume
Johnny Depp's penis also has its own
miniature hat and goatee I don't have
any concrete evidence that that is
actually the case but come on Rob right
probably and when you look at what the
Trump administration has been doing it
is hard to see much of Ivanka's
influence there take Planned Parenthood
which he certainly cares about well last
week Donald Trump allowed States to
block thumbs to it or maybe take climate
change Ivanka did reportedly bring Al
Gore to Trump Tower but unfortunately
just three days later
Trunk named climate change denier list
scott pruett
to head the EPA and maybe that is an
example of Ivanka's moderating influence
maybe Trump's initial choice was a guy
strangling a dolphin with a six pack
ring although just just out of interest
let's look at an issue that Ivanka has
been very outspoken about last year at
the RNC she brought up family leave and
child care when the Trump campaign
released their plan for that she sold it
hard we think we proposed something
that's incredibly comprehensive it's
very innovative
it's a bold and fresh solution there's
no policy on Hillary Clinton's website
pertaining to any of these issues child
care elder care or maternity leave or
paternity leave for that matter except
none of that was remotely true first of
course Hillary sight had pages on those
issues so it seems when it comes to
lying about easily observable facts the
Apple does not fall far from the orange
unless let's take a look though at that
comprehensive bold fresh Trump child
care proposal because according to the
Tax Policy Center very few of its
benefits went to the lowest income
families in fact families with incomes
between 10 and $30,000 would receive
average benefits of just $10 a year and
the only daycare that cost $10 is a
padlock okay
okay mommy's going to work and mrs.
master lock is going to keep you in your
bedroom for the next eight hours Thank
You bunker you're the best and look look
you may still like Ivanka that's fine
she can be appealing and that's frankly
not by accident she's been trained in
the art of Trump branding to be as vague
and likable as possible so that everyone
can plausibly think that she shares
their values whether or not that's
actually true and if that sounds like a
harsh thing for me to say about her I
will point out she's basically shared
that message in one of her books
perception is more important than
reality
if someone perceives something to be
true it is more important than if it is
in fact true this doesn't mean you
should be duplicitous or deceitful but
don't go out of your way to correct a
false assumption if it plays to your
advantage
she's pretty much telling you to your
face not to trust any assumption that
you are making about her so it is
possible that she is doing nothing to
moderate her father and I understand
that but the bear is an impulse not to
want to think about that just like you
don't want to think about the fact that
it is also possible that in the White
House right now her father may be
bowling naked yeah maybe he's wearing
bowling shoes
maybe he's forcing Mike Pence to play
alongside if we don't know we just have
to deal with the fact that it's possible
but the truth is we may all be thinking
that Ivanka was doing a lot more than
she actually is although the same can
emphatically not be said for her husband
Jared Kushner the man remember
responsible for among other things
repairing the Middle East something that
his father-in-law is actually pretty
confident in I have a feeling that Jared
is going to do a great job I have a
feeling he's gonna he's gonna do a great
job
he is so great if you can't produce
peace in the Middle East
nobody can okay then nobody can or or I
am wrong and future history books will
say and peace was finally brought to the
Middle East by a sentient Kohl's
mannequin who read a book once
but Jared actually has even more
responsibility he's also reportedly been
the primary point of contact for two
dozen different countries and if you
look at photos of Trance meetings it's
like Where's Waldo he's in all of them
when Trump met the leaders of Congress
very was at a listening session with
business leaders there he was and a
meeting on cybersecurity very was and a
meeting with a Saudi prince
there's Jerrod Japanese Prime Minister
boom it's J dog
Chinese president visiting you got
Kushner in the house discussing the air
strikes on Syria where's the cloche
where's because Gary you look good
basically Jarrod is either being invited
to every important meeting or he dies in
the White House in the late 1800s and he
has been haunting it ever since
Jarrod's portfolio would be unmanageable
for the smartest man on earth
so is Jared Kushner the smartest man on
earth we already know that he's the
coolest he can really rock a trill pair
of sunnies but but what is going on
behind them this guy can be quiet but
confident and as it was described to me
he is a visionary if you have meetings
with Jared Kushner Jared whistles it
doesn't talk that much he absorbs it I
see Jared as like the Alexander Hamilton
of the new administration he's super
thoughtful he's a he's a he's a three
times listener 0.5% talker stop
he is brilliant because he's quiet just
because you don't talk does not
necessarily mean you're thinking
something amazing it can just mean that
you're sitting in a meeting staring
blankly at people's moving lips thinking
about why baby cats aren't called cat
ins or whether all goldfish might have
peanut allergies but since they don't
ever eat peanuts we'll just never know
about that whole 0.5% talker thing does
point to something genuinely odd about
Jared because for someone would the
amount of power that he has have you
ever heard him speak seriously
what does his voice sound like you know
do you and look it wasn't easy but we
did actually manage to find an interview
with him talking on TV in 2009 and here
it is maybe this is real estate yeah you
saw the newspaper it was a website and
online ooh your big ticket yeah I know I
know I know I know what you're thinking
you thinking hold on you just took that
clip and you dumped in Gilbert Godfried
but you don't know that for sure
listen to it again my main beef this is
real estate yields only newspaper it's
another website and online media victims
you don't know for a fact that that is
not his actual voice and that is the
real point so in the absence of Jared
spoken thoughts we've been fed her to
rely on secondhand evidence of his
brilliance and the first thing many
people cite is his education jared is a
great young man went to Harvard very
smartly went to Harvard Jared is a very
easy number one at Harvard guy he's
incredibly smart yes but that's not
really evidence of anything the
Unabomber went to Harvard Ted Cruz went
to Harvard and yes plenty of smart
people went there too they'll tell you
about it but it is worth it is worth
noting that officials at Jared's high
school were reportedly dismayed he got
in because as one put it his GPA did not
warrant it if SAT scores did not warrant
it so who knows how he pulled that off
I'm sure it's absolutely nothing to do
with the fact that his father pledged
two and a half million dollars to the
school shortly before he was admitted
and I'm certainly not saying that
a textbook case of paying for admission
I'll leave that to the textbook the
price of admission in which that story
actually appears but the project however
Jared got in after graduating he took
over his father's real estate business
after his dad Charlie was sent to prison
and I don't have time to get into why
let me just say it involves blackmailing
his brother-in-law a sex worker and a
hidden camera in an alarm clock in a
shitbox motel on route 22 called the red
bull the red bullet that the whole story
I promise is amazing trust me it is
worth of Google you're going to need the
safe search off but but but how has
Jared run the family business well he
made a big splash when he bought 666 5th
Avenue for a record 1.8 billion dollars
in 2007 but that deal has not been a
raging success the entire deal was a
miscalculation they absolutely paid too
much at the time he bought at the very
top of the market so then the market
turned 10 years later the building is
struggling to cover its debt payments
okay so cushiness purchase did make a
splash but it turned out to be more the
kind of splash your phone makes when it
falls into the toilet
now that building is obviously not Jared
hold record in business he also owned
thing New York Observer which even the
papers staff found a little odd given
that several people described him as an
unenthusiastic reader with little use
for newspapers let alone books he also
recently spearheaded a Brooklyn
development called Dumbo Heights and one
of his partners praised his involvement
there saying he's very uncut 'red in his
mind I think that simplicity allowed him
to filter some things out which could be
a compliment or a savage insult and to
give you a flavor of what Jared's vision
for Dumbo height is I'd like you to
watch a video that he showed to a real
estate conference which is the most
infuriating combination of meaningless
tech nonsense and stock footage of
models pretending to conduct business
that you will ever see Dumbo Heights a
dynamic space mechanically engineered
for optimal performance and unrivaled
connectivity this campus is the staging
ground for the next generation of
and creators change is forged on this
campus in the fire of great thinkers and
visionaries a community built for
collaboration
when innovation is cultivated the world
rises to me don't know it's hard to pick
it's hard to think but I think my
favorite phrase in there is actually
bragging that the development is
mechanically engineered because what are
the other options there
how many office buildings are naturally
occurring or created with a wish on a
genies lamp and if you are starting to
get concerned that Jared's business
record may not qualify him for his
current jobs I should point out one
other prominent item that is on his
resume the 2016 election a few weeks
after it was over
Forbes ran a cover story titled this guy
got Trump elected which does sound
impressive and it features quotes from
Jared like we played Moneyball asking
ourselves which states will get the best
ROI for the electoral votes which is a
sentence that can only be forged in the
uncluttered mind of The Wizard of Dumbo
Heights but in fairness the article does
give some examples of what specific
technical expertise Jared may have
brought into the operation they used
targeting that they found a way to get
people on Facebook and Twitter and they
evolved into this 100 person secret data
center down in San Antonio and they had
data do everything data determined his
schedule his rallies even when he spoke
about in the rally and what he spoke
about the rallies really data determines
what Trump spoke about at his rallies
look I don't doubt that there were a
hundred people in the basement somewhere
money balling the ROI but I would love
to see the data that recommended this I
love these BOTS look is a beauty is it I
just I love charts I loved
and they always said you know it's too
tough putting your screen up you got to
get guys cause too much money I don't
like to spend money this is a cheap
version of a screen okay just as good
but you need good strong hands so look
you ready so there it is hi sheriff
you really mechanically engineered the
ship out of that one
you know what Trump did win the election
and I wasn't there so who knows maybe
jared is single-handedly responsible for
the entire victory but that still
doesn't mean he has the specific
knowledge to tackle government reform or
the Middle East or the opioid epidemic
can somebody please reassure me that
this is okay Jared is incredibly smart
very talented has enormous capacity he
is humble in the recognition of what he
doesn't know and is tremendously secure
in his our ability to to seek informed
viewpoints no not you not you I know
your game now not you and also to that
point that he will seek informed
viewpoints that will be harder since
there are still hundreds of key jobs
across the government the Trump has not
yet named nominees for summer agencies
central to Jared's duties including the
Department of Transportation the DEA and
the va va it is too bad the trunk can't
appoint someone to nominate people on
his behalf although even then I am
pretty sure that he give that job -
Jared fucking Costner and yet the truth
is for many people the main thing
qualifying Jared for his positions is
not so much who he is but who he isn't
as many questions they have about Jared
Ibaka and their qualification their lot
more qualified than people like deep bad
and I like everybody would prefer to
have them rather than mr. Bannon
involved in decisions if he James Baker
no he's not James Baker the answer's no
but if you know you Fannin no he's not
Steve Bannon
all right that is true Jared Kushner is
not Steve Bannon but that is a low bar
that recommendation would get you no
other job we shouldn't be excited about
a top White House adviser simply because
he is preferable to a man best described
as
every dark thought humanity has ever had
inhabiting the long-dead corpse and a
civil war-era plantation owner that even
his fellow plantation owners called a
bit much there has to be a third option
here and even some people who know Jared
and like him have some serious questions
I know
Jared Kushner buggery lived in my
building there's no lovely young people
does this person have any qualifications
lovely guy true level-headed yes he's
temperamental II seen versus the present
got it
having said that what is this guy done
in his life ever just listen to what he
just said lovely young man seems
level-headed what's he done it does not
bode well that Jerry Koosman of
neighbors described it like he just got
arrested for murdering eleven people and
look in the end this isn't even Jared's
fault it's the fault of the guy who
appointed him because think about it
this way imagine anyone other than
Donald Trump was present and hold that
thought
it's nice right in fact back in Manton
and I jump this stock photo guys was in
office inside and he said hey everyone
I'm going to fix the Middle East and
opioids and the whole of government in
general and I found the perfect person
to do it it's this creep Alice creepily
silent 36 year old heir to a real estate
fortune what does everyone think you
would justifiably be fuckin upset at
that and I know that all of this may
seem like an evisceration of both Jared
and Ivanka but it is really not I don't
know enough about them to eviscerate
them just as you don't know enough about
them to justify putting any real hopes
in them because it is dangerous to think
of them as a moderating influence as
reassuring as that may feel because
believe me and it gives me no pleasure
to say this if they are the reason you
are sleeping at night you should
probably still be awake and if you need
help doing that simply remember Donald
Trump may currently be airing out his
balls
and Lincoln Bedroom sweet dreams