we like to talk about someone you may
not have thought about for a while the
Dalai Lama a man so enlightened he's
basically the original woke Bay
according to a Gallup poll the Dalai
Lama is actually the sixth most admired
man in America and when you mention his
name to people in the street you can see
how widely he's revered a lot of respect
inspiration from what he said he says
like slumping clothes here's some really
great quotes about life he said a lot of
good things I guess he's a peaceful man
in the bounteous
okay so he's peaceful admired and have
some good quote that is pretty broad
they could be describing either the
Dalai Lama or Matthew McConaughey but
but what what happens when those same
people are a simple follow-up what did
you did it down on me
I have no idea I'm not even alive I
don't know II just I'm not really sure
he's a very important secure for
Buddhist God right no no not a God is a
person even life he just said oh shit
like he owns the Dalai Lama money he's
alive oh shit I gotta disappear for a
while that guy does not fuck around now
the Chinese government however have a
very different view because instead of
vaguely loving the Dalai Lama they very
specifically hate him
they refer to him as a wolf in monk's
robes and have banned his image they've
even retaliated against Americans but
even meeting with him Britain's Guardian
says China reportedly banned a lady gaga
that's because she met with the Dalai
Lama in Indianapolis to discuss yoga Wow
not only incredible that they banned her
for that it's incredible that that
events happened at all Lady Gaga was
with the Dalai Lama in Indianapolis
discussing yoga studies only slightly
less ridiculously Elton John leading ben
bernanke on Easter Island to talk about
rumors
now the tiny cover of hatred of the
Dalai Lama stems from its desire to main
control of Tibet a region in southwest
China and Tibet was something of a
celebrity cause in the 1990s there were
Tibetan freedom concerts between the
Beastie Boys and Richard Gere even
brought it up at the Oscars that was
when it was this kind of is something
miraculous the really kind of movie like
could happen here where we could all
kind of send love and and truth and kind
of sanity to Deng Xiaoping right now in
Beijing that he will take his troops and
take the Chinese away from Tibet and
allow these people to live as free
independent people again
so
but it's in der stadt and discard out in
this side we send this thought we send
it out right now oh you know what I'm
sorry there's been a mistake the
thoughts are actually supposed to be
sent to the producer of moonlight I
think is not a joke
moonlight these thoughts are for you
there's been a horrible mistake
we like fake before but there is a lot
about the bet that you might not
actually know for start it's larger than
you probably think China saying it's
this area but the betting exiles will
say it's even larger encompassing an
area that is roughly a quarter of China
so it's very big in a confusing way at
which and which is true is also how
director Lars von Trier characterized
Willem Dafoe's dick seriously
he tells reporters it's too big
everybody got very confused when they
saw well I'm saying you could bet is he
willing to pose dick your planet Earth
it is surprisingly large appointed China
invaded Tibet in 1950 and ever since
they've imposed strict controls on the
institutions of Tibetan Buddhism their
temples and monasteries have been
destroyed and hundreds of thousands of
Tibetans have been killed and things
inside Tibet are still grim when Freedom
House called countries and territories
for political rights and civil liberties
Tibet came in second worst behind Syria
and ahead of both Somalia and North
Korea the whole territory is a gross
human rights violation which is
interestingly another way that lars von
trier has described Willem Dafoe's penis
and perhaps the clearest sign of just
how bad conditions are is the fact that
since early 2009 146 Tibetans have
self-immolated in Tibet and China
setting themselves on fire in protest to
which the Chinese police have been less
than sympathetic William Lawson Jeon was
on the fire
Kenneth P 13 and he caught him and bit
him because Lawson Gary is on the fire
so the police
Clarissa got on fire so letter the
police are demanding the family to be
Los Angeles the family that we needed a
compensation for burning of their own
the closest well every part of that is
fucking horrifying and China is unlikely
to loosen its grip on the region Tibet
has incredibly rich resources and dolls
and lithium to River supplying
hydroelectric power and water to over a
billion people so they are very
sensitive to any perceived threat to
their control which brings us back to
the Dalai Lama traditionally he's
involved a spiritual and political
leader of Tibetan Buddhist sort of a
cross between a Pope and a president a
pope Siddhant if you will but you
shouldn't so please don't China has done
everything they can over the years to
diminish his power he even fled Tibet in
1959 under fear of arrest and he hasn't
been back since an escape that was
reported at the time by the most British
man who has ever lived
the young Dalai Lama revered by his
people as a living Buddha was reported
under arrest by the rest but according
to other sources is safely in hiding one
clear effect read tyranny is not wanted
by these intensely religious people yes
damn that unwanted creeping read tyranny
down with those thieving imperialists
and would like to have majesty subjects
in power a Maltese Rhodesia Jamaica
Barbados Kenya and Uganda
nighty night sleepy time
over 15 years
the Dalai Lama has lived in exile in
India and he's lived quite a life
he's met with the last four presidents
and when he was a child
FDR gave him a beautiful Patek Phillipe
pocket watch which he still has to this
day and george w bush gave him an even
greater gift fun painting his portrait
this portrait and I guess Bush killed
was not least the same with you I give
his time as president not bad for a
five-year-old now
the Dalai Lama officially stepped down
from running the Tibetan
government-in-exile
in 2011 but you still have profound
importance to the Tibetan people as a
spiritual leader and a figurehead and
here here is where this story gets
absolutely amazing because he's 81 years
old so thoughts have inevitably turned
to his next reincarnation but it turns
out there's a bit of a problem with that
let me explain broadly speaking when the
dalai lama dies he reincarnates as a
child somewhere on earth and
traditionally a key person in the
process of finding him if someone calls
the panchen lama and when the Panchen
Lama dies the dalai lama plays a similar
role in finding him and so on and so on
they're basically playing a buddhist
version of hide and seek
so the ninth panchen lama helped
identify the current Dalai Lama who in
turn identifies this six year old boy at
the Panchen Lama but this is where it
starts to get tricky because that boy
has not been seen in more than 20 years
these are the last known pictures of
Garin Chokey Nima the boy chosen to be
Panchen Lama the Chinese authorities
rejected his appointment arrested the
boy and his family it's true China
kidnapped a six-year-old and no one has
heard from him since although just two
years ago a senior Chinese official said
he is being educated living a normal
life growing up healthily and does not
wish to be disturbed which is a little
suspicious because it's not the kind of
thing a former child stars publicist
would scream into a fault she's growing
up healthy living a normal life and
those track marks on her arm adjust
where they inject the vitamins she's
fine she's fine the China didn't stop it
just stealing the Pancham
they had another trick up their sleeve
in an attempt to discredit the Dalai
Lama's choice of one of the best top
Buddhist spiritual leaders Chinese
officials used a 200 year old ceremony
to name their own
Pancham Lama yes they made their own
fake Panchen Lama they basically
counterfeited a religious leader like a
knockoff handbag that doesn't say coach
that says coughed and Chinese tactics
here are obvious if they control the
Panchen Lama they can use him to pick a
new Dalai Lama who might completely
coincidentally be very favorable to the
Chinese government meanwhile the Dalai
Lama
understandably is pretty pissed off
about this the landing now I want to
make clear there as far as my own
rebirth is concerned the final authority
is myself no one else that obviously not
Chinese Communist yes that is some
forceful language too very saying they
can make that decision over my dead body
except you know specifically not that
he's now actually saying that he will
either not reincarnate as a Dalai Lama
at all or if he does it won't be inside
Chinese control Tibet it will be
somewhere else which is incredible
because that means that when he dies we
should plausibly wind up with two rival
Dalai Lama's and the already fraught
situation in Tibet could spiral out of
control and for the time being there was
really only one person who can fill you
in on what is happening in the Dalai
Lama's head but he lives in India and
that is a 14 hour flight away and the
reason I know that is I went to speak to
the Dalai Lama in India in George
yes I travel to the Himalayan foothills
of Dharamsala India a journey that
involves considerably more uphill
walking cows and monkey trafficked and
I've been led to believe also talk with
the Dalai Lama about China conditions in
Tibet and what comes next for him your
holiness it is an honor to speak to you
may I say Tashi Delek personally thank
you how is my pronunciation - I think
we're good
in my defense I just started learning
Tibetan 40 seconds ago ha ha ha
so let's talk about China because the
Chinese government absolutely hates you
don't they yes publicly one government
official said you're a wolf wrapped in
monk's robes and photos of you are
forbidden in many places you don't to me
look like an evil wolf if they describe
me as a demon you're a demon oh yeah
then I immediately reacted yes I am
limit with warn yeah because I think
classic Dingling right yeah I think
that's when I look at you that's what
they see well whatever they wonder say
that's our freedom I have no say no
negative feeling I just feel a laugh
like that
I practice you see taking others anger
suspicion distrust and give them
patience tolerance and compassion I
practiced that but it seems the Chinese
government are particularly good at
taking your positivity turning it back
into negativity and oppression of the
Tibetan people and they'll hand it back
to you as it was yes just outside the
dalai lama's temple is a local memorial
honoring Tibetans who've self-immolated
in protest against Chinese oppression
acts that put him in a very difficult
position this is a hard question but the
self-immolation that has happened for a
hundred and forty Tibet yes had burned
themselves it is very very sad indeed
yes
why is it hard for you to definitively
tell them to stop doing it
this is I find very difficult sort of
situation the right from the beginning
when I first heard that firstly I access
my solo or fatness then meantime if I
say the action is wrong than their
family they will and - reset warn our
family member and did something against
Adams wish right I don't want to create
that and then certainly I cannot support
that whether the end of killing from
Buddhist viewpoint it's a self killing
not good so they are more my person is
very very difficult
so then best thing is remain silence -
quite the tangle Lama is preen fully
aware how powerful his words are and he
occasionally uses them in targeted and
sometimes surprisingly specific ways
like this example which he offered up
out of nowhere one of my previous visit
Mongolia is it dead - grotto
what cur the russians are hard Selassie
they like a drink
yeah vodka then I suggested drink much
less vodka yeah I loved it ahead instead
of that they dead the traditional so
drink horse milk wait hold on poor horse
milk what you tried to wean them off
vodka by giving them horse milk oh yes
then they follow what they're in for
since then I think majority of Mongolian
no longer and if you hold on that is a
that is a huge claim you cured Mongolia
of alcoholism yes using horse milk yes
yeah not too late to the point I'm just
concerned I would see horse milk and I
think all of that came from all
ourselves then oh no that's illogical
once differences cold milk and hospital
or differences one comes out of a cow
the other I don't know how you get it
out of a whore
[Laughter]
finally we were having fun and I knew
just how to keep the party going let's
talk about a lighter subject death you
are going to die and when you do it's
going to be a massive problem because
there are issues regarding your
reincarnation regarding China I I do not
much concern what that survived in
because it is red being all seven
billion human being and then
preservation of the sheik buddhist
tradition but which we kept but you're
intertwined with that no no it's an
individual person not less important you
know right but then get is a loyal arm
but what is him
over two thousand citizens ears still
very much a lie so do you think you
might be the last Dalai Lama very
possible you do yes you might be if I've
become last hour lower I feel very happy
what because you were a good one oh yes
I may say quite intelligent
oh oh you calling yourself intelligent I
think a little bit of arrogance very
well but if you don't resolve your
reincarnation issue are you not worried
that China will appoint their own Dalai
Lama and he may not speak like you're
speaking now that also it may say so
yeah there's also you see one of this
foolish and I shop sighted child retard
to using human brain properly it's
helpful that's that that is a guaranteed
way to calm the Chinese government down
to tell them they're not using the human
brain properly I told them our brain
usually you see have the ability to
create common sense the Chinese
hardliners in their brain that one brain
is missing then
but if I think the Chinese leaders
Chinese Communists this is death but
much concern about the image of China
I'm happy to sit here and criticize
China with you because I know the
consequences for me are not necessarily
as bad as they are for you so so I wish
you see they called me demon so I won
another demon so you become demon no no
no you can transfer you can't we
incarnate the demon into mate oh oh yes
yeah no no no no no no you can't get
with you cannot do that you don't any do
that fmz oh no this is not how I wanted
you think of yu-gi-oh so the dalai lama
seems determined to keep his
reincarnation plans private for the time
being leaving millions of Tibetans
waiting for an answer and as our time
drew to a close I wanted to cement our
new friendship you were given a watch by
President Roosevelt is that true yes
true at that time I think one cosa
patek philippe was actually a beautiful
voice pocket pocket watch right well I
have a special gift for you it is not a
beautiful watch from a president but it
is a special watch from me here it is
it's a calculator watch oh right
Roosevelt may have given you a fancy
watch but that is water-resistant
wonderful thank you Rosalyn Rosen watch
I think old fashioned yeah this new
fashion well not so much new fashion as
from the 1980s okay thank you thank you
thank you but thank you my demon friend
[Laughter]
[Applause]