there are certain fictional characters
that have taken on such a significant
role in our culture that it's difficult
to portray them as anything other than
you grieve eiated symbol they become and
assemble like this has gone on to mean a
lot of different things to a lot of
different people civil rights political
activism and social justice but it's
important to understand the character
and the history behind those symbols so
let's take a step back and look at the
origins of Diana Prince the Wonder Woman
Wonder Woman made her first appearance
in the pages of All Star Comics number 8
but unlike Superman and Batman who
receives cover positions for their debut
Wonder Woman only appeared as a backup
character showing up in just the last
eight pages of the seventy page book
before eventually graduating to the
cover sensation Comics number one a year
later and it's in that book that artist
HG Peter and writer William Moulton
Marston created that will become the
central pillar of the DC Trinity as well
as becoming one of the most iconic
characters in the world and always began
in 1940 in Marsden a harvard-educated
lawyer and psychologist was offered the
position of educational consultant of DC
Comics after Superman publisher MC
Gaines read an article in the Family
Circle where Martha addressed the
untapped teaching potential of the
comics medium and Marsden wasn't a
writer but he recognized the market for
female character and a predominantly
male focused industry and offered what
he called an antidote to the
blood-curdling images of masculinity
within the superhero genre so this
Wonder Woman was meant to give a
different perspective to the typical
comic book reader demographic and
Marsden learned her to be an amalgam of
the two most important women in his life
combining the attributes of his wife
Elizabeth Holloway Marston with those of
olive Byrne one of his former students
who later became the couple's love and
on top of creating Wonder Woman
this was the trio who studies form the
basis of the modern polygraph with their
systolic blood pressure test after
America's entry in the world war 1
Marston attempted to interest the
Committee on psychology at the National
Research Council and their work and its
potential to detect
and that concept was later incorporated
in the Wonder Woman's lasso of truth
which in its original incarnation only
compelled obedience and acts of binding
tying and restraining put a big part and
a lot of those early one of them stories
because as well as being a lawyer
psychologist and inventor Marston was
also a very enthusiastic bondage
fetishist if that wasn't obvious given
that diana is either bound chained or
gagged on the cover of the majority of
her books but that was also an attempt
to combat the damsel in distress trope
that was so commonly found in comics of
those days she's the one that had to
free yourself from those restraints
liberating herself from oppression alone
and a lot of that was partly inspired by
the abolitionist campaigns of the
previous century as well as iconography
used in the women's suffrage movement
which Marston is Elizabeth and olive
were very heavily involved in and their
first way of feminist ideologies really
helped shape the core of that character
which is why many people even today
still take issue with Wonder Woman's
induction into Garden Fox's Justice
Society of America in all-star comics
number thirteen where she formally
became the team's secretary and this of
course was a decision killed by sexism
that backtracked everything the
character stood for and ignored the
original creators vision except no it
wasn't any of them in fact this was
Morrison's decision having demanded
final cut over Wonderland's plot and
dialogue during her time in the JSA
despite the fact he was already busy
writing her as the central character in
three other books so a story was devised
to keep Diana on the sidelines of
all-star comics so that Marston could
focus on showing her full potential in
the pages of Wonder Woman sensation
comics and comic cavalcade there was no
chauvinistic agenda behind that piece of
history so many people attribute to
sexism this was just an artist wanting
to retain creative control over his
creations and let's not to say there
haven't been any missteps in that
character's history because there have
been quite a few but it's about the
growth that characters undergone over
the years and how she more than any
other character that era literally
evolved with the culture and became
something much bigger than was Larson
and originally envisioned a woman from a
foreign land wrapped in the American
flag coming to defend and protect the
values of a world
people turn their back on because she
saw something worth saving that's more
relevant today than ever before which is
why it's so surprising that when a woman
has had very little representation in
mainstream media compared to her
contemporaries there have been dozens of
stand-alone Batman and Superman
live-action films
dozens of standalone animated films and
dozens of television shows
Superman has had 15 standalone video
games on various platforms and Batman
has had 38 you want to get so many
Wonder Woman games there have been 0 not
a single one no Castlevania style
platformer from the late 80s no Wonder
Woman skin gotta blow a rip off nothing
what she has had is one
made-for-television movie which is
essentially Wonder Woman in name and
nothing else
one three season television series from
the 70s one direct-to-video animated
film and after 76 years she'll finally
be getting her first theatrical film
this June it's strange that a character
was so much cultural influence has been
largely left out of that culture for so
long and the argument has always been
made that one woman isn't as marketable
because she's not as familiar a
character as Batman or Superman but
that's only because she's never had the
chance to be the world needs more Wonder
Woman because we need more people like
one reboot the champion of
self-confidence compassion and tolerance
and a reflection of all the progress
we've achieved as a society and when you
distill all those values into that logo
then you have a symbol of purpose I'd
like to thank the good people over at
Verve for sponsoring this week's episode
Verve is a new video streaming service
that's home to some of the best anime
gaming sci-fi and fantasy content on the
web you can download the Verve app today
and try out a 7-day free trial to combo
pack and get access to all your favorite
channels like crunchyroll
Funimation and roosterteeth all ad-free
and an HD right from your Xbox
Playstation iOS and Android devices and
with Verve you can catch up on the
brand-new season of attack on Titan or
if you need something to tide you over
until the return of Rick and Morty I'd
recommend checking out Harmon quest in
series creator Dan Harmon over on the
sea so sign up today at Verve dot co
slash combo pack that's vr vc o slash
combo pack or click the link in the
description below and let me know what
you're watching
[Music]
you