there's a cynicism that seeped its way
into the majority of modern science
fiction our futures have become
dystopian apocalyptic totalitarian and
not much else that sense of optimism
that's so integral to the genre is rare
to find these days
which is why Spike Jonze betrayal of a
brighter future in his 2013 sci-fi love
story her was so refreshing
it brought a humanity and a warmth back
to technology and depicted a time not
too distant from our own that's worth
aspiring to and one of the driving
forces behind this lighter vision of the
future was production designer KK
Barrett and if you're not familiar with
the role of a production designer
they're essentially the head of the
various departments that are all
responsible for helping to define a
uniform visual aesthetic for the film KK
has worked on a number of Spike Jonze
projects as well as Sofia Coppola is
lost in translation which is another
link that makes that film such a great
companion piece to her and his approach
to capturing Tokyo's vast technological
playground in that film was the same
when designing this futuristic Los
Angeles he said it was all about
choosing the right fragments of this
massive available palette to represent
cacophony off-screen a visual theme
inspired by Japanese photographer Rinko
Kikuchi whose images illustrate everyday
life through these quiet slivers of a
much larger narrative but the goal being
to build a future that's rich and
distinct that still leaves much to the
imagination you give the world a
parallel story of its own that informs
the characters as much as the dialogue
conveying the bigger picture in as
little as 5 or 6 set pieces and to
achieve that same sense of scale of lost
in translations urban landscapes they
took LA's modest parabolic skyline and
augmented it with CG composites of
Shanghainese skyscrapers creating an
amalgamation of downtown Los Angeles and
Shanghai hyper-modern pudong district
where the majority of her was filmed and
collaging these two cities via visual
effects allow the LA exteriors to match
the density that floated shot in
Shanghai so in montage we can cut from
the loser a pedestrian bridge in
Shanghai to this shot outside the Disney
Concert Hall in LA to the Shanghai la
hybrid composite skyline to the CG 747
art installation outside the Pacific
Design Center all without breaking the
illusion that
is one single seamless sprawling future
metropolis but not all the city was
manipulated with the effects both
Theodore and Amy's homes which are just
redressed versions of the same apartment
filmed on location at the watermark
tower have windows facing northeastward
into LA's financial district and it's an
honest view of the city that just
appears more dense than it actually is
due to the overlapping nature of those
few buildings and the decision was made
to forego green-screen windows so that
cinematographer Hoyt Avon Hoyt Tama
could install large mirrors on the
helicopter platforms the adjacent
buildings to bounce back sunlight into
the apartment giving it a much warmer
more naturalistic quality than what
could have been done with isolated said
and her does away with all the cold mono
chromatic tones typically associated
with the future in favor of a Jamba
Juice inspired aesthetic with blue tones
being very sparse and usually a soft -
saturated shade as you can see here at
the beach or here at Catalina Island
with the colors of the sky and the ocean
being completely washed out even light
emitted from computer monitors and
phones is much warmer and more inviting
than what's commonly used in film and
there's a textural property to the
technology of her that you don't often
see in sci-fi with its paper and cloth
and wood and glass pastels and
incandescent bulbs technologies advance
to the point where it no longer needs to
prove its sophistication in its design
with cellphones looking less like sleek
Apple products and more like a cigarette
case or a business card holder from the
20s the computers which were made up of
wood and canvas with no mouse or
keyboard are more akin to a frame piece
of artwork than a window into digital
entertainment advertising is Tex list
brand lists and visually subjective life
exists on elevated walkways outside of
billboards and traffic or any cars for
that matter it's a simpler future and
that's also reflected in the costume
design especially with Theodore's
wardrobe with its absence of denim and
collars belts ties and baseball caps
it's a subtle evolution of fashion that
draws more from the past as fashion
trends often do and that's what I love
so much about her rather than trying to
forecast innovation or technological
progress it draws from the past to be
more relatable in the present a vintage
quality that makes you feel almost
nostalgic for the future it is very
important to us not to celebrate design
advance
by looking at technological items that
date a film data story nor have it be
about that it was about characters the
film is about the human experience and
our relationship with technology not
about what the technology is or what it
does we're too caught up in how our
world will change for the worst rather
than how we will stay the same her gives
us a glimpse at a lighthearted more
hopeful future where characters are free
to resolve their interpersonal conflicts
and experience life without being
oppressed by those dystopian or
apocalyptic or totalitarian environments
which is why 10 20 or even 50 years from
now her won't look like a dated vision
of the future just a charming alternate
reality where people cleaned up their
lives and finally got their shit
together
and if you want to learn more about some
of the filmmaking techniques discussed
in this video you can check out this
week's sponsor Skillshare Skillshare is
an online learning community with over
17,000 classes and design cinematography
editing and so much more and with a
Premium Membership you can get unlimited
access to these high-quality classes
taught by actual experts working in
those fields all for less than $10 a
month with an annual subscription making
it one of the most affordable learning
platforms on the market and the first
500 people to sign up using the link in
the description below will get their
first two months absolutely free so if
you want to learn something new
improve the skills you have and unlock
opportunities doing the work you love
head on over to sk l sh slash captain
christian and get started today
[Music]