animation has a long history of sharing
the screen with live-action as you can
see here with the enchanted drawing the
first piece of animation ever put to
film the magic of animation from its
foundation was about bringing these
two-dimensional characters to life not
just on the page but in the real world
and nowhere has it been done better than
in Robert Zemeckis and Richard Williams
1988 film Who Framed Roger Rabbit so
today I want to look at the three
fundamental elements in integrating
animated characters for the live-action
environment and what made Roger Rabbit
stand out from the rest of them the
first and probably the simplest from a
technical perspective is eyeline eyeline
is important for a number of reasons
that establishes an emotional connection
with the animated character in the actor
it set the blocking reference for the
animators and it also convinces the
audience that both characters are
occupying the same dimensional space and
when the effect works is a seamless
interaction when it doesn't the actors
seem to be blankly staring into dead
space which is the case with a lot of
the animated scenes and Mary Poppins you
can see her eyeline never quite connects
with the other characters and no matter
how beautifully animated the Penguins
are it still breaks the illusion now
let's look at this scene from Roger
Rabbit where Eddie and Roger arrive
outside of Maroon Studios Rogers
character model stands roughly three
feet tall and you can see here Bob
Hoskins actually misses his eyeline same
mistake as Mary Poppins but the
animators used a creative workaround to
correct it
having Roger stand up on his toes
against the wall making them a bit
taller to reconnect the eye and there
are a lot of clever moments like that
throughout the film here Rogers hand
comes up higher to jump on the bed
because that's where Hoskins is looking
in the shot and a lot of these gestures
were done out of necessity
simply chutes were absolutely not an
option the live-action portions of film
had to be shot in its entirety before a
single frame of animation could be done
because the animation is drawn directly
on the photostats so that meant any
contact made by a toon had to be a
hundred percent premeditated which
brings us to element number two physical
interaction
soompi only one for me any level of
interaction no matter how small or how
large chairs bumping windows crashing
plates shattering okay a special sex
division had to develop a custom
mechanism to mimic that movement and a
lot of times those mechanisms were
specific to one single effect maybe
Herman's cigar for instance was
manipulated by a copycat system with
servo controlled motors in order to
create all six degrees of movement
something that couldn't have been done
with string marionettes and it would
have been much simpler to just use an
animated cigar or have the weasels carry
animated guns and most people wouldn't
notice but there are rules that govern
the universe of Roger Rabbit
if Rogers drowning in real water then he
spits up real water and every little
detail like that serves as a reminder to
the audience that yes these characters
are inhabiting this world just look at
this shot of Roger on a soapbox it looks
as if every slight shift in weight has
an equal reaction when in reality is the
reaction influencing the movement as
part of the reason Roger such a klutz
throughout the film gave the production
team more excuses from interact with the
environment it's about blending the
medians not just sandwich hang them
together and far too often with live
action animation hybrids characters
exist almost exclusively in separate
planes if we look at the scene with
Eddie and Jessica she's on his lap in
his coat she grabs his hat
she has real presence and weight and
that's what sells the illusion but if we
compare that to a similar scene in Ralph
Bakshi's 1992 film cool world you'll see
there's nothing really connecting these
two characters I can cut out Holly with
a pair of scissors and nothing would
change you can also see how subtle
camera movements make it seem like
Holly's locked to the front of the wind
almost floating against the background
and the separation between the character
and the environment would consider an
obvious which is why historically there
was an unwritten rule amongst animators
who mixed mediums to keep the camera
stationary and there was really only one
reason for this rule because they're
lazy yeah I mean we're supposed to be
able to turn things in every direction
that's our job so you can shoot your
movie and we're just
the character in me said wasn't that a
lot of work yeah twice as much work
camera movement is an essential part in
making these moments feel cinematic and
the animated element in Roger Rabbit
never compromised that move it's shot
like a real film because it is a real
film and you have to remember this
synchronization of the characters
against the camera was done before the
age of digital compositing there's no
tracking software to account for the
movement to keep the characters and
corresponding motion this is all
accomplished by eye and by hand not only
drawing each frame for drawing each
frame in perspective and that becomes a
lot more impressive when you consider
the layer build of each character which
brings us to the third and final element
shadow or more specifically light and
shadow accuracy and this is what set
Roger Rabbit apart from its predecessors
each tune is their own individual layer
but there are also at least five
additional cells of shadow and highlight
layers for each character in each frame
built up like a watercolor painting
starting with a mask as a backlight and
a shadow mat painted with hard edges and
the soft ended in the optical printer a
second shadow mask is a cast shadow and
inner positive and an articulate mask
learning physical interaction with the
character and when composited together
it gives a realistic three
dimensionality to the characters now
keep all those layers in mind when
watching this did you never take a look
at the changing large presence change
somebody's made-up Tatiana - why this is
called bumping the lamp a phrase coined
by Disney during the production of Roger
Rabbit to describe going above and
beyond what was expected of the
animators it would have been perfectly
feasible with Roger States flatly
eliminated throughout the scene like a
cartoon normally would but instead the
animators put in the time of shade every
cell uniquely so that the practical
light would bounce off in the same way
metaphysical option and they had to
account for that dynamically shifting
Lighting's every contour on Rogers limbs
is closed its face the cast shadow he
creates on the environment loved texture
of the light the slightest difference in
color temperatures the lamps weighs even
larger spheres have a slight
translucency since a much thinner in the
rest of his body
they sought effect audiences had no
expectation for the global realism in
1988 but all these seemingly superfluous
details helped sell the effect at a
conscience merkel and the best part of
this film is that without having noticed
any having no technical knowledge of the
animation process of the filmmaking has
no effect on your enjoyment of Roger
Rabbit it's an incredible film by its
own mix the storytelling heart and the
humor that's where the true movie magic
is but it's those technical subtleties
and the dedication to the craft that
really inspires you artists and that's
something to be admired so in your work
always take the chance to bump the lamp
because somebody out there will notice
[Music]
you