20:16 was an incredible year for music
one of the best in recent memory
and for all the negativity that came out
of that year we certainly needed it but
the one album I seem to always come back
to regardless of my mood would be it
relaxed or agitated its Frank ocean's
blond there's a cinematic quality to
that album that keeps drawing me in the
lyrical storytelling in the atmosphere
at paint is like nothing I've ever heard
before and it's impressive how without
the use of a visual aid the music shapes
such vivid imagery images of childhood
and lost summers and especially cars
something that's been a staple of
Frank's work since the beginning of his
career from the you know clinic McLaren
f1 GTR in the video for my keys to the
1988 BMW e30 m3 and the cover of
nostalgia ultra cars are his language
but not in the conventional pop hip-hop
usage where cars are used as a symbol of
status and wealth and specifically
masculinity instead Frank's cars
articulate a sense of vulnerability or
intimacy and he also uses them as a
conduit for storytelling a sort of
visual shorthand for landmark moments
throughout his life is music like
driving alone is very private and self
reflective and cars are used with the
framing device for his memories when I
had Lexus not present over like that
work I guess I'm just inspired to tell
stories in my life like times that I've
enjoyed and I mean a lot to me off and
go back to him sewing when I'm making
music that's really all you can draw for
right you know you when you're
storytelling is you know your your own
experiences and memories and personal
wisdoms and knowledge so when I pull
from that place it comes with all the
pictures when I'm when I'm trying to
make a song even the form of it even the
part that doesn't have words the parts
that aren't words is still you know
really trying to make a photograph out
of something that you can never see
there's a cinematic influence that's
present in all his work even down to his
name originally Christopher Edwin brew
the change came from his
Louis milestones 1960 film Ocean's
eleven starring Frank Sinatra and that's
something I really appreciate about
Frank he isn't subtle with his
influences he proudly wears them on his
sleeve and that offers a level of
transparency with his work if you go
back to his first mixtape it's filled to
the brim with references and samples
from Radiohead MGMT and the Eagles and
if you're at all familiar with my
channel you know I use this soundbite at
the beginning of each of my video that
isn't lovers in Japan by Coldplay not
exactly it's actually the intro track
Street Fighter which samples lovers in
Japan and I use it to set a mood as
comfort and nostalgia for my videos the
same way Frank does for the album hence
the name nostalgia ultra people think of
Frank as this enigmatic figure
mysterious and hidden from the world
because the other practically
non-existent social media presence and
that's hard to come by in our fame
obsessed culture but the reason I feel a
closer emotional understanding of his
work than most other artists is because
of its personal depth and restraint when
every moment of celebrity is shared on
social media it loses a lot of the
allure of storytelling your
heartbreaking ballad about a lost love
is a lot less heartbreaking when it's
trending or when it was ghostwritten
Frank disappeared for four years between
projects actually live a life before
telling us about it and with blonde his
adventures cruising suburbs of Tokyo and
rwb Porsches and throwing parties around
England are all felt in the album Frank
takes you on a journey through his mind
the whole time keeping you as close as
the passenger seat and I think he said
it best in his interview with GQ he as a
writer and as a creator is giving you
his experiences music is just a
communication of identity and Frank's
lyrics act as a sort of inner monologue
fragmented memories triggered by
different melodic ships and even if we
don't know the reference for those
memories the atmosphere of the music
shapes the context and without speaking
explicitly to movement to
political stances Frank is able to make
small introspective observations that
are just as powerful as bold statements
this music is incredibly emotionally
dense despite its component parts being
very minimalistic some tracks like solo
being as simple as a single organ
accompanying Frank spoken but the
instrumentation is precise and
purposeful and that clean lines
stripped-down production is what really
allowed Frank to define himself as an
individual for and you can see that in
his decision to use some of this
superstar features at just musical
texture throughout the album Kendrick
Lamar Jonny Greenwood even Beyonce
appears on the track pink and white
harmonizing in the distance but without
checking an album note you probably
couldn't even guess you is their artist
is passionate and as insightful as Frank
don't come along often and with very
little output just a mixtape two
full-length LPS and one visual album
Frank is proven to be one of the most
gifted and enforcement of this
generation and even if there's another
four years between projects I'm excited
to see where he takes us next
[Music]