there's always been one essential
component in the way we consume
entertainment and that's curation it
looks at curation with our music our
films or television a sort of cultural
gatekeeper to oversee a library to large
to sift through alone and for most of us
who grew up in a pre social media age
our gateway into the world of anime came
from one place we call it Konami an
exclusive uniquely styled block of
programming that was designed to bring
an awareness and respectability to an
artform somewhat overlooked by American
audience tsunami debuted March 17th 1997
after programming executive Mike lazzo
Tech Sean Aiken and Jason DeMarco to
produce an action block that would
showcase from Cartoon Network's newly
acquired teen-oriented IPs something the
network had been attempting since its
inception with the super adventures
block in 92 and then power zone in 96
the original lineup being cartoon
roulette Thundercats Voltron and the
real Adventures of John quest and to
give the block an atmosphere and the
personality they use CGI interstitials
hosted by Space Ghost own Mopar voiced
by the late great see Martin croaker one
of the principal animators of coast to
coast it wouldn't be until the summer of
99 during tsunamis midnight run when a
major design shift would introduce the
tsunami operations module or Tom as the
new permanent host of Konami originally
portrayed by the voice of Dragon Ball Z
is Crillon sunny straight before being
replaced by Steve bloom in 2002 on and
the animating gaming's material and
through Tom they were able to express a
reverence for anime that hadn't been
seen on any other network people think
tsunami was the only place to get this
content but anime was airing on American
television long before 1997 the Sci Fi
Channel had a block in the mid 90s
called Saturday anime which would
showcase more mature programming with
things like Acura and Dominion tank
police unfortunately it was buried in
the ratings dead zone one night a week
so it didn't reach a very wide audience
or even as far back as the 60s with
Tesla atom or mock go-go-go it's just
that most people weren't aware of their
foreign origins due to some pretty heavy
westernizing
they just knew them as Astro Boy and
Speed Racer
but tsunami brought anime into the
mainstream with its cultural identity
intact it wasn't just the shows it was
the connective tissue the curation and
the aesthetic and the respectful
treatment of the broadcast the feeling
that someone is introducing you to
something they had a great deal of
passion for and when that passion is
relayed with care it can become
infectious but when it's insincere
the contempt for the material becomes
very obvious just look at the bonds
treatment of Dragon Ball Z when it aired
on the WB and real nasty character and
that's a result of not understanding the
material not understanding the
demographic but tsunami understood its
audience and its goal was to speak to
kids directly resident down to them it
also served as a great introduction to
the long-form serialized programming
with things like Gundam Wing as opposed
to episodic content which was pretty
common in animated shows at the time and
things like the month will be izaki or
giant robot week help kids make the
distinction between a style and a genre
anime is not a genre and that was
something important to articulate during
the early years of Toonami
this was a form of entertainment the
majority of American audiences were
still four decades behind on so they had
to make it clear that even if you
weren't the biggest fan of Sailor Moon
that wasn't representative of the entire
block the programming was fluid so there
was always something for everyone the
phrase Toonami faithful was born out of
this constant threat of failure of the
network
despite tsunami being a staple of nearly
every kid's afternoon television viewing
experience who was always tearing on the
edge of cancellation and in 2008 due to
rising competition and a somewhat
unpopular design alteration tsunami had
what seemed to be its final broadcast
beautiful friends that's a more than 11
years
tsunamis final broadcast and we'd like
to thank each and every one of you who
made this journey with us tsunami would
have been anything about you and Tom was
right
without the outpouring of support from
tsunamis dedicated fanbase the block
would have stayed dead but on May 26
2012 something no one saw coming
happened
oh hi Adult Swim got the results of the
test back definitely have April Fool
what started off as just a clever April
Fool's joke turn to a full-fledged
internally and externally driven
campaign to get tsunami back on the air
that your ship that night from the
normal few hundred thousand viewers to
that one point four billion something
like that so we they were able get into
programming everybody good for free
after hours and we did it just really in
the beginning to try to get it back on
the air for you guys not these bad
bitches wait did you
noemi's resurrection really demonstrated
the power of the people and taught a lot
of kids with value in supporting the
things that you love being vocal and
persistent and sharing your interest
with others the way Toonami shared them
with you there's an art to curation more
than just an algorithm it comes from a
genuine love of the craft and a
meaningful relationship with the
audience welcome to the anime thank you
[Music]
you