[Music]
there are two reasons the majority of
established web animators all came from
new grounds and it isn't money or
notoriety it's freedom and community
this is Tom folk the creator of
newgrounds.com a site that remained
uncensored unfiltered and unadulterated
or shepherding an entire generation of
talent for over 20 years and as it
evolved over those 20 years from an icon
controversy with things like club a seal
and Teletubby Funland to an established
multimedia social networking platform it
was able to make its mark on internet
history by becoming hub for artistic
expression and a constant trendsetter
for the online world like with the
launch of the portal in April of 2000
the first ever automated real-time
content submission system and this was
put in a place of five years before
YouTube it also introduced flash ads
monetization before YouTube's
partnership program as well as being the
first site to offer a community voting
system with glam and protection points
that's what forbidden due grounds from
just becoming another video dumpster and
it gave users greater control over the
site's content making the platform when
we find something that since been
adopted almost universally of online and
it also set trends with the content
itself giving birth to the first-ever
viral video the numa numa dance in fact
most viral content from the early 2000s
has its roots in new grounds but most of
the site's allure in those early years
came from its animation and it made its
reputation by being subversive and
strange and a bit nonsensical oh god
your videos but also beautiful and
stylish Newgrounds has a house aesthetic
but these were all individual voices
each of their own stories to tell I gave
a platform for audiences to share and
discover but also to learn the process
of animation more than looney tunes and
more than disney Newgrounds will
probably have the biggest impact on the
future of the animation industry in
terms of inspiring young artists to
pursue a career
direction because it's by far the most
accessible when you're young and you
have an interest in animation you look
at a film like The Lion King and you ask
what tools were used to achieve this how
many peeps how much money
where do I start when do I finish how
does this get the scene these are all
questions that when growing up outside
of the industry can take quite a while
to figure out some of them behind the
paywall of a formal education and for
decades the only path to a career in
animation was through those art schools
but we finally have different avenues
emerging in the late 90s the advent of
consumer grade digital cameras an
inexpensive audio equipment brought the
rise of the independent film community
anyone with the dedication and the drive
could reduce the film and that's exactly
what happened in the world of
independent animation if you had an
interesting idea you could finally just
make it everything you needed was
available there were obtainable goals
and accessible software and of course it
was limited but it was all about getting
a foot in the door flash and new grands
became the two most useful learning
tools to young aspiring animators and
game designers and it really
democratized the production and the
distribution of animation and games a
better generation of artists whose
individual creativity to flourish and
mediums that were typically very
labor-intensive it was the new flipbook
but rather than finding it in a cereal
box with the corners of classroom
textbooks it was online for everyone to
see
these kids in their bedrooms were
building massive audiences before the
age of social media but it wasn't just a
community of appreciator so this
community of like-minded creators all
inspiring critiquing and elevating the
Tom Hope said the world is full of
gatekeepers and the web was the first
place where anyone could share anything
with everyone everything by everyone
animators voice actors programmers
illustrators and musicians there was a
portal for each one to submit to grow
and learn and it's a tight-knit
community that's really responsible for
the cycle of maturity and success
Newgrounds is unique in that it's one of
the few independently operated sites
that survived the dot-com bubble without
being swallowed up by larger digital
media conglomerates like goo
I am and it's always been heavily
creative focus which is why new grounds
today isn't nearly as large as it could
have been total creative independence
unfortunately isn't very lucrative
that's why you saw many creators whose
new grounds is a springboard to YouTube
which in the early days was much more
beneficial for web animators do entire
ad rates and so of course it was
Overland by user exploitation which
caused a shift in YouTube monetization
priorities in 2012 from a view based
model to a minutes watched model which
once again made high quality short form
content much less profitable and it left
a lot of talented artists without a
revenue source practically overnight but
it never stopped them in fact some of
the most creatively exciting content on
the internet still comes from those
artists raised on new grounds and
there's also been a lot of successful
mainstream crossover animation teams
like Studio yato which started out as
just a freelance text submission on
Newgrounds in 2012 has since worked on
projects like skullgirls and Cartoon
Network's ok KL or creators like Thomas
and Adam being originally known as the
super flash brothers are now first party
Nintendo developers with snipper clips
on switch you always hear about the Cal
arts class of the 1970s that went on to
lead the Disney Renaissance a community
of like-minded individuals all
challenging and motivating one another
eventually transforming an entire
industry and right now we're on the
verge of another animation revolution
only this time it's the class of new
grads it was the advent of television
that wiped out the antral cartoons and
cable wipe def broadcast cartoons and
now we have the Internet but the medium
itself hasn't disappeared it's just
evolved so ignore the claims that
traditional animation is dying or dead
because it's not and it never will be
we're just in the midst of another
generational shift and when compared to
legacy media new media is still in its
relative infancy and we're figuring out
where animation fits into this new
system but the foundation for the future
of animation has already been laid it's
a whole new playground for creators
[Music]