[Music]
many things come to mind when you think
of a David Fincher film that signature
steely color palette his
unconventionally structured narratives
and of course some of the most
interesting characters ever put defense
you know if you mix equal parts of
gasoline frozen orange juice concentrate
you can make Nadel but what they're
usually not seen as our visual effects
pieces even though a film like the
social network has more visual effect
shots than Godzilla and that's because
Fincher's true trademarked is deception
and it's accomplished primarily through
the use of CGI and digital compositing
venture has always been on the bleeding
edge of technology and he's immersed
himself in the visual effects world his
entire career starting with his work on
Return of the Jedi at ILM in the early
1980s and because of those three decades
of experience he knows exactly when and
how to use an effect effectively take
this opening sequence from Fight Club
for example we track down the building
phasing into the garage revealing the
vans loaded with nitroglycerin bombs and
set up an important setting for the
third act of the film now without CG
that setup would have to be done in four
different shots the garage the van the
bomb and the timer and technically
that's still the same visual information
but none of those shots establish
distance or location in relation to
Tyler and the narrator Fincher likes to
let you know exactly where you are in a
scene and the use of CG allows him to
flesh out those environments in a way
that wouldn't be possible with
traditional filmmaking techniques
how would you establish 1960s San
Francisco outside of the title court
well you could open with the Golden Gate
Bridge its iconic it's a visual landmark
that hasn't changed in appearance since
its construction so it's appropriate for
any period and it's also used in every
single movie so the audience know
they're in San Francisco but we're
nowhere near the Golden Gate Bridge and
sodium we're downtown at the Chronicle
and rather than just showing us the
exterior the building
Fincher shows us this the San Francisco
waterfront as it appeared in 1969
complete with a historically accurate
skyline as well as a reconstruction of
the Embarcadero Freeway that fell during
the earthquake
of 1980 and most people would never
guess that that entire cityscape was
created in computer in fact nearly every
exterior shot in zodiac is digitally
altered in some way to be
period-accurate Fincher one of the
details of the crime seems to be as
authentic as possible and ironically the
only way to do that was through CG if we
look at the murder of Washington and
cherry you'll see this isn't just a
simple chroma key backward the shot is
handheld so the entire environment was
built from the ground up using camera
projections to create a 360-degree 3d
model of the intersection that could
then be tracked on to the original
plates to match perspective but more
than historical accuracy Fincher uses
these CG techniques to bring depth to
the storytelling like illustrating a
city's transition into a new era through
the construction of a landmark or
building tension through eerily precise
framing and virtual camera movement it's
all in service of the story
take the Henley Royal Regatta sequence
in the social network for example it's
57 shots and every single one of them is
a visual effect 3d tracking software was
applied to digitally replace each
background as well as create detailed
depth maps that were then used to
simulate the look tilt-shift photography
which adds a sense of isolation to the
wincle vie and their attempts to expose
Zuckerberg everything around them feel
so insignificant compared to what
Facebook has become and if the effect
that sells that emotion but it does it
without drawing attention to itself and
I think that's the essence of all the
visual effects and Pinterest films
they're almost never obvious in fact the
real trick of the scene isn't a
background
it's the Winklevoss twins themselves and
know this isn't just a split screen
cloning effect this was done by
capturing a 3d mask of army hammers
performance in CG and having it
digitally superimposed over Josh princes
face creating a hybrid of actor and body
double that could then portray two
distinct but identical characters within
the same frame even the simplest shots
have a surprising number of complex
visual effects one of my favorite
examples of this is the zodiacs first
murder sequence it seems relatively
straightforward nice exterior two
characters inside the car being shot at
a Zodiac as blood splashes on the radio
except it's not at night it's shot in a
studio the exterior is the digital mat
the two characters in the car as well as
the zodiac or blue screen composites
shot on different plates and all the
blood is CG like I said he's a master of
deception and Fincher likes to use
digital blood as often as he can
zodiac has some pretty gruesome murder
sequences but not a single frame of
practical blood was shot same with Girl
with the Dragon Tattoo every drop is CG
including the blood being washed off a
Miko space in this scene which is a
whole nother level of impressive and the
complexity of the visual effects in the
back end allows for much more simplicity
during principal photography not
worrying about redressing the set
multiple times gets finisher the freedom
to shoot as many takes as he likes and
he likes to shoot a lot of takes and we
shot fifty sixteen I think we probably
shot thirty thirty-five takes and we
probably shot 16 takes he did that 17
times this was many many many takes
Pinter also utilizes CG in moments that
would otherwise be difficult to recreate
over those several tanks if you ever
wondered how those gummy bears bounce so
perfectly off of Nick's head while
staying in frame it's because their CG
same with Amy's perfect cut as well as
this gap in Elizabeth's hair since the
scene was filmed across multiple days
they composited separation and her bangs
to maintain continuity between shots and
that same attention to detail was
applied to all of Miguel's
evidence boards with notes and photos
being digitally altered to remove in
accordance with last-minute script
changes and scenes being cut from link
and yeah it's easy to think these are
expensive unnecessary solutions to minor
problems but modern audiences aren't as
forgiving when it comes to technical
inconsistencies and continuity errors
and Fincher knows that his films are
about detail his characters are
investigators and detectives and
obsessives and those traits are all
reflected in the film making an
incredible amount of technical artistry
shaped so many moments most people with
a blind animosity towards cg would never
even notice take the motorcycle chase at
the end of Dragon Tattoo for example
thousands of man-hours of work when
ended digitally replacing Elizabeth's
head during the sequence even though the
simple financially practical solution
would just be to conceal her face with a
helmet and let the stunt driver perform
with no digital trickery it's even been
established multiple times that Lisbeth
always rides with her head gear but that
doesn't serve the narrative she's in a
hurry she's in pursuit of a murderer and
she's reckless enough to chase down a
killer in spite of her own safety the
use of CG allowed Fincher to shoot the
scene efficiently and safely without
compromising the logic of the character
his visual effects are always in service
of the story they're not there to be
recognized they're not there to impress
they're there to immerse Pinter
understands that what technology you use
is never important it's about how you
use that technology to communicate your
vision until the best story you can it
takes titanium and aluminum and steel
and glass and lasers to do one thing
impart feelings and that's the magic of
cinema I'd like to thank Squarespace for
sponsoring this week's episode whether
you're looking to set up a blog
portfolio or online store
Squarespace gives you all the tools you
need to build a beautiful website with
no patches upgrades or installers
required and their great selection of
designer templates and award-winning
customer service makes launching a brand
quicker and easier than ever before sign
up today at squarespace.com slash
captain to get 10% off your first order
that's squarespace.com /ka ptai n
[Music]
you