whether it's through an elephant
warm-mix retires on what pavement with a
rumble of an air-conditioning unit
Star Wars has continued to build on a
landscape of sound it's been grained in
our cultural consciousness for the last
40 years with film the goal of a
traditional audio department is to
reinterpret the visual environment into
a complementary aural environment giving
realistic contextual sound to the images
on screen but what happens when none of
those sounds exist when they have
sourced to draw from how do you convey
the sound of light or speed in a vacuum
well that's the job of a sound designer
this sound designer in fact Ben Burtt
the creator of the majority of the sound
effects in the Star Wars library which
houses over 5000 unique sounds and
continues to grow with each new film the
terms sound designer didn't really come
into the filmmaking vernacular and so
Burke's work in 1977 before then film
sound could be broken up into two
different categories the production
mixer which is this guy here and the
pink booty shorts whose job entails
capturing onset recordings of dialogues
and background elements and then there's
the sound editors who fabricate
different sonic effects and studio for
my creative enhancements to existing
sound that's the tradition of the
division of labor in feature film and it
has been since the talking's of the
1920s since I was an exception to that
traditional division of labor I needed
to describe myself in some term so I
began to become sound designer which
essentially meant that I although I
emphasize my creative work and sound
effects my job was to coordinate all
that you heard in the final sound
occupation and only about 15% of the
final mix the first Star Wars is
originally recorded audio the rest was
added in post with ADR and forward but I
yes
now I am only a master of evil god the
sound gives those visuals credibility
and can take something that seemed
relatively awkward during production and
transform it into something epic
the sound and the score allow those
moments to have wait but some sequences
rely on the sound alone told that motion
a good chunk of the lightsabers rules
are played without Schwartz letting the
rhythm of the sound design dictate the
Edit and creates a cinematic atmosphere
and when the score resumes the sound has
to play against the music and the
dialogue seamlessly a Fault in any of
those three elements could ruin the
entire mix Vader's wheezing for example
could have very easily become a major
distraction but instead of sounding like
an asthma attack they were able to turn
a very unnatural sound into a natural
characteristic of his voice by matching
the low frequencies of James Earl Jones
is delivery with breath to a scuba tank
regulator and that simple effect gives
more context to that character than any
expository dialogue could some
characters like r2d2 develop completely
through sound r2 has no dialogue or real
physical action yet he's able to have an
entire spectrum of motion just through
beeps and Boop's c-3po has limo tick you
Layton he's humanoid and he has a human
voice even bb-8 to a degree has
different physical cues that you can
attribute a motion to like the lowering
of the head of thumbs up r2 is just a
trash can on wheels but we always know
what he's feeling and Bert was able to
achieve that by combining his own voice
to mimicking the sounds of an infant or
the synthesizer creating a performance
that kept our Tunes language very
abstract and robotic while maintaining a
human element you can empathize with
that's what grounds these effects every
sound has its roots in organic
recordings rather than artificial ones
and that brings a familiarity to the
unknown
the visual world of Star Wars is rusted
and gritty and lived in so every belt
gear and exhaust used in the Foley helps
sell that authenticity it was essential
that each sound be unique making a clear
association with the visual it
originates from especially in chaotic
sequences like the attack run in the
second Death Star the Millennium Falcon
Star Destroyers x-wings Y wings a wings
type fighters and explosions are all
distinct and clear enough that you can
locate them in the space of the frame
even with your eye
closed and that was important given the
fact that most cinema audiences in the
late 70s and early 80s would only
experience the film through a single
channel mineral sound system a sixth
track seventy millimeter version as well
as a Dolby stereo version of the mix
were also on exhibition in the film's
original release but out of the
seventeen hundred and fifty theaters it
screened in only about forty of them
were equipped to handle anything other
than the mono track this was the 70s
after all and technology was pretty
slowed a little out but the incredibly
dynamic mono mix of that first film was
able to fool many audiences into
thinking they were experiencing a much
more advanced sound system than they
actually work and if we deconstruct some
of these effects we can see how that
illusion is possible the lightsaber for
example is essentially just the hum of
two harmonizing simplex projectors
interlock motors and idle along with the
buzz of the transmission signal from the
cathode ray tube television set and the
combination of those two sounds creates
this which is the foundation of every
lightsaber blade and when played in the
steady state condition to a speaker and
recorded by a moving microphone to
create a Doppler kitchen and that makes
for a very authentic sense with movement
to death even through a monorail sound
system but we've come a long way since
those early days and the sound design is
something that's only improved as the
sagas progressed here's a list of the
things many people myself included take
issue with regarding the prequels but
the one thing I think we can all agree
on is that this
is absolutely incredible there's a
belief that good sound design is
completely invisible that Foley should
only be perceived on a subconscious
level and that the sound should melt
into the image as to not become a
distraction but I think that method of
thinking stifles creativity the sounds
of Star Wars are just as iconic as the
characters vehicles and weapons they
give life to and not every story
warrants aural spectacle at the forefoot
but film is in equal parts and
audio-visual experience and when the
sound is relegated to playing second
fiddle to the image you're limiting an
entire spectrum of artistic expression
I'd like to thank Squarespace for
sponsoring this week's episode
Squarespace is a great all-in-one
website building platform that offers
easy-to-use tools with no patches
installs or upgrades required and with
their award-winning 24-hour customer
service and a great selection of
designer templates to choose from
Squarespace is the perfect option for
anyone wanting to build their brand
online sign up today at squarespace.com
slash captain to get 10% off your first
order at squarespace.com slash ka ptai
in
[Music]
you