if you've ever wondered why George a
Romero's 1968 or classic Night of the
Living Dead seems to be everywhere why
it's been remade and remix so many times
why references to the film seem to go
beyond homage and why it's playing in
the background of nearly every
low-budget indie horror film that's
because of a mistake made on this shot
of the opening credits and it's that one
mistake that gave birth to an entirely
new sub-genre of horror that would
eventually grow into the
multibillion-dollar zombie industry it
is today
you see prior to Romero's work zombies
were very different from what we know
now typically only found in Haitian
voodoo folklore as living beings
enslaved by supernatural power ideas
that were explored in the early 1940s
with films like shock tune airs I walked
with a zombie zombies to me were you
know those boys in the Caribbean who you
know do the wet work for Lugosi and I
thought I was creating a completely new
monster you know the neighbors suddenly
turned into flesh eaters ghouls and
that's what I called them ghouls in the
film and I thought they were completely
you know and after the film's released
the ghouls became the new zombies and
the new zombies no longer belonged to
Romero and that's due to the fact that
under the old Copyright Act of 1909 this
little symbol was the only thing
standing between owning your work and
not owning your work which is why nearly
every film up into the late 1970s had
that symbol clearly affixed to the title
or credit sequence something that night
of Living Dead does not and that's
because after the film was completed
Romero's production company image 10
made a distribution deal with the Walter
Reed organization who suggested that the
title be changed tonight a living dead
from its original title night of the
flesh-eaters and this was to avoid
confusion over Jack Curtis 1964 film
called the flesh-eaters Romero agreed
and the name was changed but the Walter
Reed organization mistakenly omitted the
notice of copyright from the
his title card and under the Copyright
Act of 1909 the first public display of
your work without the symbol word or
abbreviation of copyright and the year
of publication meant that you lost your
copyright forever and the work becomes
part of the public domain and those
requirements were stripped back under
the Copyright Act of 1976 but my no
living dead was released eight years
before those laws went into effect but
the film's entry into the public domain
became the ultimate distribution tool by
virtue of the fact that it was openly
available for every theater UHF station
and video store to license for free and
its ubiquity led to zombie movies
becoming the dominant genre for
low-budget independent film matter
living-dead provided a template for
young aspiring filmmakers to follow and
expand on one of the few entries into
the public domain that was still fresh
and ready to be explored the Romero's
copyright mistake had been caught before
distribution you have not only retained
the rights to this film but also have
exclusive rights to the idea of the
zombie as we know it today the concept
of a slow-moving flesh-eating ambulatory
corpse would have been protected as his
intellectual property even though Romero
didn't originally create the zombie he
gave them a distinct set of rules and
physical attributes and alterations to
existing work within the public domain
can be protected under copyright you can
see this type of copyright protection
being enforced through Universal with
Frankenstein's monster when most people
think of Mary Shelley's classic creature
the image that probably comes to mind is
Boris Karloff's green skin flattop skull
protruding forehead and bolted neck but
the description of the character in
Shelley's original novel was much more
vague describing only a yellow skinned
man with black hair and lips and even
though Frankenstein has been in the
public domain for over a century
Universal still holds exclusive rights
to those alterations made for James
Wales film in 1931 and the threat of
copyright infringement looms over anyone
outside of Universal wanting to adapt
that character universally even filed
suit against Mad Magazine for this cover
from 1964 asking for an injunction
against further distribution and 250
dollars for each individual infringement
as well over a million copies being sold
and pricey legal battles like that or
like Christopher Lee as Frankenstein's
monster and hammers 1957 retelling looks
so much different and why I Frankenstein
has just aaron eckhart with scars Romero
could have easily had a similar
stranglehold on zombies as Universal
does with its monsters and had not been
for that initial copyright mistake the
1909 Act allowed for protection for a
period of 28 years from the date of
publication with an option of renewal
for a second term of equal value which
meant that 1968's matter of living dead
wouldn't have been submitted into the
public domain until 2024 and with the
Mickey Mouse effect on copyright
extension there's a possibility zombies
could have stayed out of the hands of
the public for many more years after
that which would mean no Shaun of the
Dead
no thriller no Resident Evil and no Game
of Thrones every zombie film television
show video game and comic can be
directly traced back to George Romero
Walking Dead creator Robert Kirkman even
originally intended his book to be
titled Night of the Living Dead because
he assumed the name recognition would
boost sales and he was free to do so
because the film is in public domain and
I think that's what makes Romero's work
so special even in a sea of copycats
with every up-and-comer using his
intellectual property as their own he
was still able to tell original
thought-provoking stories that stood out
from the rest right until the end and to
this day the three best zombie films
continued to be Night of the Living Dead
Dawn of the Dead and Day of the Dead so
if you haven't seen the masterpiece that
started at all you can watch it online
download it for free even packaged and
resell it if you like
so go share it dub it remix or remake it
learn from it get inspired and make
Romero's hard work worthwhile and if
you'd like to learn more about copyright
law I'd recommend checking out
information doesn't want to be free laws
for the internet age from this week's
sponsor Linkous blink astiz a digital
learning app that distills key insights
from the world's best-selling
non-fiction books into information packs
you can listen to in just 15 minutes or
read on your favorite device blink as
was created to help you fit learning
into any moment of the day and with
2,200 books and blinks and 40 new titles
added each month blanka's is the perfect
option for helping you vet books before
you buy them refreshing your memory of
previous books you've read or helping
you discover titles and writers who've
never heard of Wicca starts at just
$49.99 for an entire year but by signing
up at blink is calm / captain Christian
or using the link in the description
you'll get 20% off a new
subscription or you can just try out
blankets for free right now so head on
over to blankets today expand your
horizons and uncover subjects you never
knew you loved
[Music]
you