[Music]
okay so is now the earth no it's not the
earth would turn so this is good playing
a co by chat made it so more goblins
alright the goblins have finally showed
up and they jump on the bridge all of
the goblins they don't they don't have
that much health I really like how these
donations aren't coming a lot ones cuz
if they came all once you guys would
just gets so overwhelmed Phoebe feels
like the perfect time for these guys to
come out alright so they're gonna so
they're gonna pop out and they're
immediately gonna bum-rush Rovin here oh
my god oh wow okay and here we go the
gun blasting the dodge okay when goblins
okay so before they do anything you just
see them rushing and you're gonna win
blast somewhere
I already saw what goblins did before
get now alright where did you want to
win blast - you just want to get over by
your friends
I'm getting over by the burned-out tent
yeah okay you do like a wind jumps when
you just land over here on top of the
rebel tent okay so that kind of
interrupted what the goblins are gonna
do this one green goblin is gonna slash
at the ice elemental or the frost
elemental are they gonna try and take
Roman away alright co o the frost
elemental is gonna take three damage
would you like to take it for him yes
okay one two all right
it is now your guys turn so Roman it's
your turn
okay you still have the goblins going
after custard right uh the earthwards
yeah there's two words turning at Bertha
yeah and you gotten five new goblins
that are now rushing you guys okay then
what I want to do is I want to summon
sprites at the kind of in this area at
the front of the bridge
so kind of block them off kind of block
them off yeah smart okay give me a role
buy us some time
buy us some time maybe oh maybe get 20
nice
all right let's see did you what you
wanted to do at the front well I want to
know what like like here here here yeah
okay that works
it kind of close them in you can pick
where they go exactly if you like oh
then I want one here and then I want one
here smart okay are you done uh I'm
gonna move over this way we're slowly go
moving more towards the back I'm getting
more space but I want to kind of be
looking down the bridge yeah you guys
are like a kiting group who likes
certain counters alright is now co-stars
turn so before I do anything I'm gonna
do these guys first they're both gonna
walk up and Justin's gonna get attacked
by both of them so this is for six
damage Justin alright take six five six
all stealing yeah Justin's now standing
up he's no longer hanging it with Dave
sorry - do I have any control over them
like I caused them to disperse know what
the so it's out these are mindless like
a variety mindless the like air spirits
can't be controlled you can pick where
they summon and then they able to attack
enemies these things have one order
and once they are assigned that order
that is their only objective in life and
once they fulfilled it they kill
themselves like they just returned back
to the earth the Iceland until you have
full control along he's like he can't
talk to you but I mean other than type
of thing that only you can understand
but you have full control over his
movement in actions I'm gonna have my
ice elemental punch the earth Lord
that's behind him oh my god it through
that way chart I'm sorry okay oh sorry
he just he's just whiffs trying to hit
that earth elemental and I'm gonna try
to hit the one that's next to me with
what you're my oaken staff
Oh your dagger you got your diary get
some help I should use that damn dagger
oh no a trade a okay I traded it for you
oh you did straightest shit got one
stamina think of the wood guys argued so
hard for me to trade it it made sense
now you're like right and you smash this
guy to pieces right sweet all right
oh that makes it Devils turn huh that's
time to shine good folks all right I'm
gonna get up this up and up in here you
can't get around there's no kind of have
to delicately balanced on the yeah doing
that
so with that move - yeah Roman kind of
covered it up I'm just gonna I'm just
gonna throw a flare at the one I can see
like the green one I guess okay I mean
it might get room it's elemental you
realized that right yeah but I don't
care about his elementals don't have
sorry do this before dead bones they're
not your brother okay you shoot flare
but you precast it accidentally and you
blind yourself now nearsighted and your
range is reduced to 100 so the mean like
guys reduced to one yeah you you solar
flare yourself so you will be blinded
for at least an entire turn so your next
turn you will also be blinded okay you
still have a move
pre-attack but I'm not good I guess
Akeno I'll attack the earth Lord behind
you yeah yeah I'll try and get that off
Justin okay you smash it
you now have cheating ginza prot yep so
what was the distance between it let's
see it reason where's for to damage
three squares but it has to arc so you
would have to arc it through one of
Romans guys so if you want could I
Artemis guys you could kill one of
Romans guys and then hit two goblins
yeah totally totally nice foresight
Roman so gyro flee yeah I mean if this
guy wasn't here it would have just my
sprites shut up yeah oh you don't need
to roll for this
oh it all just happens this is just
damage this is Oh sick so one and then I
got a do three damage to these goblins
so green play good job Roman set it up
right alright is now just this turn okay
let's see let's see at the very least
Justin you need to get the hell out of
the way because it's like Deadpool yes
duck yeah alright cuz I'm gonna go here
yeah and I'm going as you are I mean
it'll be the fourth time you might hit
it this time yeah I'm gonna ride with
fireball fireball the one in the middle
the grey one okay I hope that it crits I
know why wouldn't you go for the blue
one you you've missed your fireball and
you hit the green one killing the Green
Goblin
well knocking him unconscious wounding
him ice alright uh you alright
you can for pro play but you've already
moved so you can only possibly hit
allies at this point
well can I can I stay I can't for pro
blade the downs I had to try to doesn't
murder him he's like he's around for me
isn't he well I have a tier range on the
blade oh what'd you do kill you kill the
Goblin
to range to range doesn't mean like this
is mainly ranges next to you
one ranges I was fairly considering that
that would be three range to hit the oh
okay no I'm saying that the green guy
that's down yeah he wants to hit the
green do you want to kill oh yeah that
goblin is now dead dead
good Rex gobble yeah sorry and now I'm
going to blink okay yeah all right all
right I'm going to blink here okay okay
and I'm going to use uh ice blast first
things you to roll for the blink to make
sure you die yes oh yeah that's right I
always forget about that don't worry
free attack from the yelling alright for
that okay you can blink there then you
get free attack alright alright so roll
for the free attack who you trying to
take ah gonna hit those remember cuz of
work Pro blade going for gray guy yeah
they want a fireball this is a free
attack oh yeah this is the sword alright
so you get grey for - okay and now you
can do your action alright now I'm doing
the ice blast
6oh all right your ice bless is a little
bit weak
so only just for damage all these
goblins one two three four one two three
four one two three four all right I'm
going for the vorpal again I'm the great
guy take him out
absolutely and you with okay all right
now uh yeah and I guess I just kind of
yes hands down his pockets so fast um
I'd be in heaven when do these air
sprites attack so four is supposed to
one damage at the end of your turn they
are controlled by the game master at the
end of your turn I didn't get to attack
with these Romans so they should know
gracious I'm just gonna do a little bit
of damage black show taking one purpose
of taking at least one green probably
got punched for whatever damage or
double this I got a ring I gotta
remember that these like pets always go
on your turn like all of them so they
either go before or after depending on
the circumstances okay so this cop was
gonna move he's gonna he's gonna chase
down Roman he gobbles his sense fear oh
and these three goblins are all going to
try and steal from Justin blink yeah go
ahead
do you want to drove with a blink on a -
Justin uh I mean that's only one Goblin
there's only one goblin goblin grab that
he's with the other two are going all
right I'm trying to get out I'm trying
to blink on out please
okay the yellow goblin is gonna try to
win blast you as he sees you try to
leave so you try to blink your blink
fails it's gonna cost you your stamina
and you're not gonna get robbed but
you're gonna get blasted for one two
three four five six seven
nine and they're gonna push back to the
point where you're almost about to fall
into the water you're tearing oh god
Bernie sprites that I could have chillin
read purple goblin is gonna go one two
three four
shit five yeah it's dead now he's gonna
try and steal from dead bones hold on oh
so dead bones he's taking a lotion and
black diamond is stealing from roaming
dude cutemon win what's the way Roman
wind blasts the gut Roman wins last back
but he still gets full damage on the
black Goblin killing him and Cohen
really good pals
yeah one quickie then what about
Justin's coat in that situation music oh
yeah did you just to take we just
damaged Misco he should've so we'll give
him two three health back remember this
like you guys got to remember this stuff
just that doesn't remembers captain yeah
they did the ideas he was in his face
right also since this real quick so
Cyril that 20 give me one more help cuz
of my treasure
oh yeah he can heal himself yeah thank
you thank you so Roman you jumped back
from the windlass that dock to the
treasure but you and code now get
freedom to spells so you get the first
spell here black eyes so black goblin is
passed oh alright and red cup or a
purple Goblin still there yeah this
purple Goblin see full strength
none of the goblins the same full
strength at this point okay uh I'm gonna
lifedrain him I won't care what you know
hold on I mean see no no I'm gonna stun
him I'm stunning him with the grandeur
Raven's claw grin Raven's claw okay yeah
I don't want I don't want to really kill
him you
everybody get up it's all 100k you're
gonna stun him but the hand just whips
it grabs nobody like you just with this
the space over next to him excuse me so
go you have a fleece Pelt - oh yeah um
I'm gonna be weird and on the cast
blanket of Darkness right on the bridge
on the bridge on the only on these guys
try to avoid just oh oh my sprites do
don't worry about the sprites oh I don't
care about the sprites at all yeah oh my
fuck all right your blanket of darkness
but you put it on top of you guys so I
can't move that it's a new cast nothing
that matters
I guess doesn't fucking matter well I
mean there you go effectively yeah yeah
just in case we go for a little you know
play the rock jumping game still there
sorry
poor Dave he's just lying there with
cold balls weird yeah he's gonna go
crazy
get out of here I think he's pretty
happy about his balls I need to get
better like like thinner tiles please we
know Dave's there we know he's there he
doesn't need to be in it
fuck Dave I'm not even do this I'm just
gonna do this for the blanket of dirt
yes colour identities before I went to 3
4 1 2 3 4 1 2 3 4 and a B 4 blanket
oh that's the because we don't have good
resolution in this program for some
reason at the dorbz how was it not on ko
he's at your service
okay so it still effect ko it's not like
the fun students yes they look like okay
and black Goblin was like passed out
here I think yeah
oh yes there's the blanket of darkness
that just got casted that illuminate
dent right no what makes you insane
yeah it's kind of worse yeah you lose
your mind you're gonna be mental for the
rest of the game dead bones it was your
turn oh is it my turn now
yeah wait wasn't that was Romans
interrupt those the interrupt - yeah it
was the goblins turn so Roman should
still get a turn so wait so that goblin
went purple goblin stole these governs
all did everything so yeah now it is
that Romans turn thank you yep okay Tom
what's going on I want to go ahead and
try and wash the blanket of darkness
away I'm in West oh okay yep it's like a
smoky thing sure yeah it's a smoky thing
I don't want to do damage
I just want to whoosh it away yeah okay
that for ya
okay the blanket of Darkness is whooshed
away backing you thank you
the two blankets of darkus have started
to merge starting to form a dark
elemental spirit Oh what just got washed
away it's good okay I can't movies I
redid my my blasting so yeah this
blanket of darkness has now faded it's
that wasn't a long time ago cue it's
your turn Co and then it's we're on the
actual turn order now injury we know
confusing confusing like that yeah but
it's right for your ears whatever they
are oh yes I would err spirits okay here
we go oh here we go here
so we're gonna do this one's gonna
attack blue first just one spirit and
then whiffs this one's gonna attack blue
now
okay blue goblin is passed out and then
this one's gonna attack yellow chopped
spirits okay and this one does one
damage to yellow
all right now it is coaster okay I'm
gonna have my ice elemental attack the
remaining goblin with rape frost all
right the Goblin has is passed out and
now it's your turn I actually meant to
attack this one but that's what was even
here yeah I can't okay you're welcome
that was good what's more you're welcome
for ice yeah you're studying me I really
wanted that darkness to stay around
Roman so we could roll to see if Dave
goes insane like really low he couldn't
deliver got insane and then I had him
can't fight you guys this fight would
never end
alright good win spirits totally unless
you want a gem I have the Ruby yeah
because I think if you want to go on the
thing you have to shimmy at least that's
what he said last time
no there's dude oh you go right go
around yeah
alright and I'm gonna do a Life Drain on
him okay we roll please don't be fuckin
curse a cave for
alright and the Goblin doesn't matter if
that's 13 or 11 and the Goblin is
knocked out
yeah combats over alright right stamina
oh it's so blatant I wanted to crush
that
his head with my mace oh okay go ahead
and roll for this I'm making sure you
guys gonna make sure that these guys are
dead you're just gonna make sure the
motors okay x1 by now you swing and you
hit the frost elemental code you want to
take this hit don't take the hit oh my
god just let it burst
you'll get your health back you some
another one it's fine and get the rest
it's not about that it may be as an
attachment to it you can't just go
around killing anything so willy nilly
expected to be no consequences yeah go
crazy don't like take the damage go I
feel it every time these spirits die
really I think you kill the spirit oh
you can't possibly feel the yellow
spirits dying oh well I feel it no yes
you can motion yeah I don't know if I
want to take a leak - you want to take
the hit or not
why won't you take that I don't know
about this it's fine but that's a really
good mace you're gonna take the for
damage from the maze all right what's
the arc no the arc the arc is not gonna
hit it better be like the best elemental
ever though worry I got this whoops you
didn't see my mouth moves Oh
all right let's go all right our
lightning art okay yeah it's gonna arc
to all three of these things I want to
kill everything yes
purple it can go to purple then go to
green that I can go to blue yeah that's
fine yeah yeah I'm gonna make you roll
for this as there's allies in the way
that might zap Romans oh okay well I
don't really care about the other blue
yes complain about how long combat is if
any splint no I was just this isn't all
three the goblins are electrocuted
they're all dead
I don't like there's any goblin alive
maybe yellow still breathing does the
other one stomp on yellow skull go
Oh code does a soccer ball kick on the
goblins skull sense of flying roaming
when code does this he says pull
would you like to cast the spell that's
the goblin flooding in the air because
it was a net 23 I am an amazed at he was
able to do a kick like that I'm
overwhelmed I have to go for it all
right give me a roll let's see this oh
you missed though you miss your wind
black off and it just goes flying and
lands somewhere else good alright I
think we're ready to get back here ready
to scream oh God
excuse me Dave okay so chap managed to
get you guys another piece of treasure
well yeah nice piece is a treasure
I agree channel I think these treasures
extra treasures are too expensive but at
the same time I don't really want them
getting four treasures for free okay a
little more armor and a blunderbuss
and a blunderbuss so just just to keep
in mind the potion was on this we're
just assuming that was that years potion
did booms that was mine I grabbed it
back as you grabbed it back yeah you
still got that fireball yeah is there
any problem with handing back the Ruby
Co are you gonna be annoying or it's
just like I'm gonna be annoying sorry
it's gonna be annoying and keep it Roman
roamin you're gonna have to talk to Co
to get this well first I just wanna see
so Justin you could wear this spell
armor with your coat but I don't think I
could wear can i you couldn't take it up
take off one of your robes so you'd have
to take off one of your robes Justin but
I think it would still be worth it
because s-10 spells yeah turn off it so
yeah so and yeah I get copies yeah
what'd you get Cosby spells just know if
you're okay with that lieutenant captain
okay I am very okay with that yeah
excellent Justin so what happens to my
cloth armor
you can either give it to someone who
could wear a Roman or you can just you
know keep it
chuck it decide it's getting kind of
ratty you know right it's a few Roman I
mean if you want to double up on robes
you know is I think it's great I love it
I it just makes sense to be able to have
backups I will take your robe but I will
laugh it up I feel like I don't have a
staff in my hand I don't know what to do
I'm like fighters
I feel right all right and this
blunderbuss a blunderbuss I mean the
blunderbuss proved to be way valuable
assets but it's really useful for AoE
but but I mean you may want we've got a
lot of range already and may want the
potions you guys are I think I want the
posts I think I'm gonna trade it in for
a quickness Pope elixir a quick this
elixir yeah I think I can tell I'm
improving but there's some things I
don't do proper that's why I can't sell
all the cars right here just in case I
accidentally make a mistake all right so
yeah sorry I was Mike's timing is out of
control now with that spell all right
you're done good I love it so that gives
you what 10 more stamina yeah he's gonna
be like 30 what this is our new tank
assume has a lot of healthy leaves you
to take you gotta remember the cost of
your spell's basically just doubled
right yeah yeah so I mean I think I
think it's time we regroup and talk it's
time for time for talk all right so wait
you guys just go you're piling on
I'm the he's the pieces of the corporate
colonel corporal yeah and actually after
that after that impressive display back
oh and Reuben Co you're now corporal Coe
and you are now the Corporal Brahmin
where's your ice guy is he with you
cause he just staying back is he hanging
out is he hanging out he's right here
he's right here I can't I guess I can't
really promote I know what private frost
elementals they have a name yeah what's
his name my name is ice Lord
I suppose the privatized Lord private
ice Lord privatized thought Roman
corporal and a half a corporal corporal
half do you want the Corps for the raw
you go talk to Dave if you want that
round
Dave you know you want the hell you know
no you can't have all they don't want it
all right
maybe well maybe if you go loot the
goblins you can have a full private yeah
well let the goblins that's a deal
Oh Franklin you actually the same rank
but not listen to a stupid I sword you
know he's the same rank as you he's like
he's the only one who's stupid ice lord
stupid he's technically higher rank than
him unless he does the Goblin looting
that's true actually yeah unless you
actually go loot that goblin the ice
ball is gonna he's gonna be on the fast
track to corporal I'm not the goblins
it's an order you can't yeah sir yeah
it's happening that's just what's up
what uh what am i you're a corporal
you're all core pistol yeah you're
you're on your way cuz I don't I don't
know what our next ready so you're happy
I wasn't next to be Hampton okay can you
be corporal colonel yeah you know what
you can be court
yo you could be cousins since I'm
lieutenant captain you could be corporal
captain now colonel corporal captain I
see
wizzy you still laugh at us squad shit
I think we're leveling up we're leveling
up ma'am we're gonna we're gonna show
Gwen it's an alpha squad ma'am we're
gonna we're gonna be alpha squad well
almost
um well I mean yeah speaking of which
are there any sprites around promote a
sprite notice she found the little
goblins body slightly fish him out of
the water
yeah and he had something of mine he had
one of yours
yeah no no he didn't yeah had a Ruby Oh
what oh yeah I guess there was a Ruby
but I gave that to privatise Lord
awesome thank you all right let's go fun
Casa meta blanket of darkness nothing
babes caught up Davis caught up and
gotta go no he tells you he's not coming
whoo no no with the other day Davey
Davidson looking into prison patrol key
oh the prison Patrol Davey Davidson this
is what you don't name all the elves
Dave okay you guys are moms so the ones
that named them okay okay so you guys
are moving down the road and as you come
up as you move down the road you can see
a carriage surrounded by a bunch of
spell blades and you guessed it good old
snail Eric himself Dave Davidson Dave so
well yeah Dave Dave isn't Dave just a
spell blade oh yeah I didn't have a son
Claire
dave-o captain dead bones upin that's
actually the tenant captain now I got it
before I found this sick mace wait what
showing the mace okay this is it mace
but you don't you don't actually you
can't promote yourself just because you
pick up a mace that system tenant on it
you're still no but I yeah but it's just
it's a auxilary teittleman's it's not
you know it's for building morale just
let them these guys they need it all
right stupid titles I don't listen to
the robot elbow understand that robot
peasant it's it's the noble speak they
don't know I know woman with that
robotic accent yes it's an we've got you
know what Dave Dave how how are you
how's Gwen is how is she doing
it's going well I'm not gonna lie to
talk well things are not going well we
had a bunch of bandits trying to rob us
the other day
we're actually escorting a prisoner
that's Oh Oh with that take them up your
mind bount ins your actions it is the
Kabul prisoner okay well hmm you but we
best get you moving
we don't want that thing getting out
yeah we absolutely don't want them
escaping chill easy no chilly whizzie
yeah hopeless here corporal corporal
captain chilly wizzy now carpool kids a
chilly we see what did you get promoted
just like a minute ago who promoted you
uh dead bones I I could promote my own
men don't you capital you're a Lynn
that's not how it works
hey you came just to be throwing out
promotions left and right what did he
get promoted for you killed a fire
elemental yeah a fire elemental that he
made in a fire elemental and then he
killed it and you promoted him for that
I mean he was he was he showed
initiative oh no I just got promoted for
uh-oh oh yeah we killed a bunch of
goblins yeah like six of them
you killed six goblins and you promoted
them for that lieutenant they were all
privates we killed six goblins just ten
minutes ago as well just behind the way
but it Dave I just oh okay yeah hey Dave
you know that this is theta squad right
yes I know that you're saying squad yes
exactly so I need to inspire morale so I
give them little titles and promotions I
kill the Goblin and I'm a private yep
that's a private private laughs man over
there Sun Hat give me that evil eye you
get a problem you would have make it one
day wrong with our leader I can tell
that he's just can't hang out promotions
left and right promoting himself because
he finds a mace where'd you even get
this it's Beth the water you said you
found a mace you found a hammer in the
water I decided that was enough to give
you a new title I mean it shoots it's
just lightning Dave lightning so it's
just kind of it's got a weak enchantment
on it and he decided this is what you
would do I go left in it I don't think
we have to take this you know Dave look
man I was really happy to see you look
and now you just you're harshing my
mellow man you know what how about I
just go on my way before something
terrible happens it would really be nice
right Chad Chad has role the natural and
unnatural d20 this means that the
prisoner inside of it is going to get to
roll an actual 20 oh no escape oh whoa
you guys this is bad yeah you want you
want to tell him who's escaping it's
it's chimera isn't it dad it's kind
there yeah I know it's kind man yeah I
don't I don't know who they thought it
was but it's definitely chimera chimera
all right so it's the primary the Cobalt
he's a very very powerful sorcerer
assassin and he has multiple treasure
cards
these them yeah that you can look at we
can see you can understand he is he's
notorious dead bones already knows all
of his abilities he does he's not really
sure what spells he's currently mastered
but first off he can't roll once if he
rolls with one it's a 20 it'll reduce
his max health but effectively since you
know it's just for this battle
he takes 3 10 pitch and he gets a 1 on
the roll so yeah he has ran frost
obviously his ray of frost is 5 damage
and his 10 range it Pierce's which lets
some chain stun multiple of you guys
he is the eyes of knock knock nil all
those abilities and items have their
stamina costs removed all of his
abilities are freeze
I love you name things that you can't
pronounce well it's because it's Abraham
its Abraham Lincoln Edwards and finally
his the winged Kings curse which means
he takes an additional turn after every
opponent's turn now mind you these
things might actually be balanced for
player characters because the opponent's
only have one turn I play all the
opponents at once and work for you guys
it means that after every one of your
turns he gets turned in a full turn so
keep that in mind he has no ability cost
if you were in a line he's gonna be able
to stun you all and he has basically a
10% chance to roll 20s I mean we have
these guys helping us out right yep you
have those guys helping out we really
owe all these stuff we keep my life you
know all this stuff
and you've heard the legends of chimera
the : yeah the Cobo okay if we kill him
we could take his fucking look at that
shit though so first off chimera has
busted out he has the first turn here if
you guys are still you guys were over
here you were talking to Dave
we'll have you a bit a little be a
little bit closer have you like it's a
little bit sad later because Roman was
in the back I was like this I think this
is our setup so this guy's gonna bust
out and oh boy this is gonna be
lot of silliness um let's see blue smoke
blade so first off he he doesn't have
his weapons yet so he needs to get his
weapons so he's going to move over here
to the back of the caravan and try to
open up the chest to get all of his
weapons if you guys would like to
interrupt you can just need him to roll
to I could blink but that's not really
gonna I don't wanna get up in his face
face actually you know what Justin you
just put on a brand new shiny coat you
could probably not worry about he's
strong he's struggling to get his
weapons out of the chest fuckin lucky
cuz he keeps rolling too like he's got
this fall back fine Batu's we're good
alright
it is the elves turn now so they're
gonna move into position
to stop him at all costs he can move
here I'm gonna have green is going to
flare and rhetta's blues gonna flare and
they're both oh no Blues gonna rain
frost beans gonna flare so this is
greens flare it misses and hits blue ah
ha ha Wow let's yeah so blue is now
blinded so blue is still gonna try and
cast free of frost even though he's
blinded man alright he's gonna get ray
of frost he's gonna land on the cobalt
cobalt is now stunned blues now gonna go
for his they're both gonna do their free
attack whiff and a hit so he takes 3 +5
damage takes 5 damage from these two and
now it is Romans turn okay can I see him
from um you can't see him but you know
where he is you saw him bust out of the
carriage I would have said he busted out
through the roof just we jumped on the
roof and then he slid down to the
backside to go grab his equipment okay
all right um I'm just gonna move closer
to the bush I can't really go very far P
some reason it's weird so I'm going over
here and I'm gonna cast flame sprites
over in this area
yours bear sprites hair sprites okay
give me your rule five okay you're not
gonna get to control these let me grab
that I will troll anyways well no no no
I mean like where you decide to go so
there they're still gonna be friendly
for you but they're just all over the
place you can have one here though okay
so that's your turn so now what is
Easter so he is going to again try to
give us equipment out yes alright he
manages to get his equipment out of the
chests so now he's he's fully equipped
he is equipped with some you know the
you know of the blades they're windfury
blades dead bones they do injury rates
yes they deal three damage and they let
you use another weapon this turn and he
has two of them and he has a work blade
so he will be able to go three damage
using another tag three guys tag and he
will be able to attack wordplay to
teleport yes imagine if you had like if
you were dwarf one week and you gave
something like a wind theory blade to
next week then you played a gnome or
something got the random treasure of a
Winfrey blade and they bought a work
blade he has like the exact possible
best abilities if they must forget him
type of also being a kobold he gets
worried yeah you do you should be sorry
you've been doing double rations are
double rules I just said that I forgot
yeah no I completely forgot I totally
forgot yeah I forgot cuz there's always
a Koba oh yeah he also has the tracking
guard thing so if he rolls a 20 its and
it has to be a natural 20 no I guess I
has to be a 120 he gets it one or attack
quick quick thing yeah it's seeing a lot
of
about something having to do with a stun
there's somebody was he stunned by the
ice beam the frost ring I'll tell you
for this role was bad this was bad he
can kind of have his weapons no these
guys as weapons catch it mean still mean
to me
let me have my fucking weapons so I can
start doing things yes because there
will be a limit on this
[Music]