okay you guys ready
we've just got to take poor Bo and his
men and then we're set we could save
your little brother Roman everything's
gonna be fine
we can do this we're the team that took
down chai Mara the cobalt think about
the house I mean eight elves well they
didn't really do much but get hit so
take either for your accomplishments man
yeah okay see what poor boy was walked
up with two other spell casters spell
casters well like a little poor casters
yeah you can tell they got rooms of the
staff so you're like okay okay you know
but you notice that he only has two guys
uh-huh he does not have the guy was he
gonna come out yep poor will come out
and talk okay
are you ready to fight but mate poor Bo
where's where the rest of your guys are
we gonna call them what were they gonna
kill was it mumbo and jumbo you want
mumbo and tumble what was the name of my
grave who's anyone remember I don't
think it really matters too much
laughs suppose you forget his friends
names it's fine we can say ebo and Dave
oh okay you just start screaming and out
of this giant cave comes two giant grave
hoops
poor Moe jumps on top of one okay and
the other two sorcerers get behind him
those are orcs
oh yeah the dead elephants there was a
monster brought back to life with the
barf stuff yeah and by the way just so
we can keep it clear life tap won't work
on them oh are you Rudy
poor but we're just gonna need one
minute and we're we gonna fight you
hotel for validity
wait but we do anything we got you guys
listen to me right we took down the
elemental we took down the whispering
snake of Emerald Lake we took down
Garland's we took down chimera we can
take down port bow hold on I believe in
us
let me let me try this is totally gonna
work right Oh what you gonna do
I hate rice we don't have we don't have
them Co add some of those no we have
nothing I don't have anything we can
summon well you you've got your friends
you can some of your friends yeah I know
but he's got like 10 feet tall yeah well
uh we don't have that
that's stupid we're elves we have way
more money and so yeah but I don't think
you buy those I think you make them I
don't get it but okay anyways come on
squadron strike ready this might be the
last time we met we we might all die
squadron strike well that's not a really
good way to go into this but we might
win no there's quite funny because you
basically did one of chats abilities for
them which is hilarious summoning the
demons for them I mean technically they
could summon war dudes but you brought
what you pigs with fight yeah Sally you
know later losing I think anyway we'll
see we can do poor boys ready he's on
his steed and he'll let you guys have
the first turn he's gonna let's have the
first time right Roman light him up do
you guys want to get a position or is
this how you want to be actually yeah I
think we will probably want to position
ourselves a bit better like I think I'm
fine there Justin can go like there
yeah come on come with a missile oh sure
you want to put ice man in front of you
or behind you oh yeah
happen to the donation oh yeah yes oh
man you guys are going even know what
these icons - I'm sorry chat I don't
know why it's broken I can't can you
chat without telling them so you won't
know what these things do but there's
nothing there's nothing positive okay
that's what they can know each ass
there's nothing positive to help our
heroes everything you do only makes it
worse
makes it so they're gonna have a harder
time fighting them so is this okay is
this the way everybody wants to be I
think they're already happy with this
yeah yeah I'm good okay all right Roman
light them up all right so poor boo is
on top this ll Phalke yeah yeah nobody's
on the other one nobody's rounding the
other one or something uh nope is he
just like right standing on it so he's
standing on its skull and he's got his
hands on the hooves like on the icon the
horns okay he's just standing on top of
it oh my lord
all right so I'm thinking we could try
and win blast him off
mm-hmm if you try to write the other one
I don't think yeah I'm gonna I'm gonna
try and do that I'm not gonna yes
gonna go in the terrible a pile all
right I'm gonna wind blast at I don't
like that idea okay do I have to whine
aside at the shaman oopsie-doodle line
of sight of this shaman no these two big
elephants are just blocking them like
like they think about mothers are kind
of like squeezed in behind them like
this one on the red side you could
probably get but this one in the middle
you're most likely just gonna hit one of
the yellow silks yeah we're gonna have
to fucking roll like gods yeah we're
gonna need a lorry let me actually
there's purple stuff on the ground good
a problem you don't know like walk
through the purple stuff and burn or
anything so okay I'm gonna go over here
then I'll have last item
oh wow can you really from that I guess
you can okay it's only five you're gonna
wait you go sorry no no no no no no no
that was a yeah it's supposed to drop
here okay little little okay all right
ah I'm gonna guess one blessed the red
one I you know what horrible is up there
I don't yeah you don't wanted to come
down
well yeah I'm terrified of what this
little shaman these are so all right
we're doing one blast on the red guy
right you hit the red one four nine one
two three four five six seven eight nine
okay this is now coaster okay so first
I'm gonna roll for I will let you know
these big things are gonna be highly
crowd control immune like trying to
freeze them and stuff is gonna do a most
another thing they're huge can't stun
yeah no I'm gonna shoot frost at po boy
Oh
the tiles no I'll take it as a 15 anyway
the 15 hits poor Bo and portables kind
of it just kind of grazes off him it
does to damage but it does not stun him
Danielle magic oh wow okay and for
myself I'm going to cast the blanket of
darkness oh yeah cried on poor Bo's
night space love it big money big money
it's a four by four I believe okay do
you want to encompass nine that's fine
too so how do you want if you want a
compass thing the red guy or the green
guy because it's gonna go like a box oh
by the way real quick
apparently the amount was incorrect or
something like it's filling up the
progress bar oh is it
Oh
you know what jet we'll just we'll just
take this off for now you guys have been
awesome today anyway
I'll give you if these guys start to win
I'll use the enrage event don't you
worry
I think we've been having problems with
the donation stuff this'll second half
like all of my commands for it have been
really really leggy and slow so if these
guys start to win I'll I'll use it for
you guys but they don't like these idiot
you guys have already been you guys ever
been so great to us in there this isn't
working too right and I'll really want
you donating this stuff you don't even
know what it's doing okay so do you want
to come to the right guy or the green
guy you want going over this way or do
you want it going towards the pool
probably going over the sentient rather
than the fucking thing you know the big
skeleton man well either way it's going
to right that's what he's saying it's
gonna be either red or green yeah like
it's gonna be covering the yellow guy I
mean you can't really have the the
purple one be in its long as before
blows in its flying in it so yeah let's
let's I want to lean it to the the red
side okay so like this yes sir it's a
4x4 yeah it's a folk faux bifo okay so
it's like this shadow alright mmm
they even let me have more colors I
really wish I had like just long black I
wish I had a color paddle it and we had
better lines like not these generally
lines
yeah that would really really make what
this this program can do all right okay
that makes it Dempster yeah so if I get
up to this square in front of me I can
probably hit the yellow guy right
there's like you look em in the legs
yeah you can hit the guy yeah so I'm
gonna move up to here yeah and I'm gonna
just cast a rolling fog cuz I'm setting
up a combo for Justin here over poor Bo
and the poor Co from my my one that
stole earlier
so flare combo you're trying to get poor
boat or you're trying no no no no I'm
not using play I'm using rolling fog Oh
rolling fog what oh you're trying to
double stack this this is final that's
well that's yeah that's that's Dart
that's blanket of darkness I'm trying to
cast the fog so Justin next turn can are
you so how are you casting it so are you
casting this like up top on porpoise
face or by the feet I'm gonna cast it
can I cast by the feet and cut and get
the red guy yeah are you like at yep did
you step into my no I'm only gonna yeah
I did that you'll see why I did that so
I'm gonna just try and catch my fog over
there alright and the fog certs what do
you want this fog doing just trying to
encompass them all just trying to come
on it to cover where the blanket of
darkness is covering basically okay
that's gonna try to do them all right so
you don't want me hitting it yet it's
not yet this is this is a setup we can
maybe get to up even and that was a
spell so I get my basic attack I'm gonna
hit the big yellow guy with my mace
choo-choo 14 okay and lightning mark one
two three four no lightning emanates
from it when you hit the is it not Elif
elk why is it this is not coming off the
mace it's coming out Owens no you don't
know you just you just hit it against it
and lightning didn't work you know I
need to travel it didn't conduct okay I
didn't nothing happens so okay that's
right that's me all right okay I'm gonna
move up to here oh oh all right oh and
I'm gonna cast uh what they call ice
last just as got a lot a lot of Justin
has a ton all right so I'm going to be
honest it's not a fireball nineteen all
right everyone here is gonna take seven
damage except for the two elephants they
take not okay
so they are taken on really mean the
magic they're immune to magic okay
Oh sue thick damage they are poor Bo and
the screen gun yeah poor little green
guide 672 all right
Co all right well I'm gonna use my uh mm
let me think
what's up might want bust out a mirror
at some point not on poor Bo but all
right I can only capture what I know but
we just that that's one less I'm gonna
use my weight I'm a nick green guy with
the work blade okay I didn't confuse
guys to be immune to magic ten you hit
him for three all right yep if that were
played to three it was I think was
always three no is five yeah it's a lot
why does a full move yeah and I guess
that's it
mocking this PS you see like that's a
great combo for him because he's a spell
blade he can run in try the AE and he
gets away like it's yeah yeah it would
have been great but you know they're
immune imagine all right um okay read
Kabbalist so this fog is gonna have
moved so let's do it like this probably
just assume that it's under the yellow
guy because yeah yeah we'll just assume
that it's under the yellow guy so poor
Bo the yellow thing and this guy are
affected by the fog right now so this
guy's gonna try to move out of the fog
yes to roll into a sadness first oh
sorry
let's do some madness rules oh that's
right madness rule horrible madness rule
we looking for babbles a good Oh God
horrible poor Bo it does not like the
fog
he's turns good he's turns gonna be a
lot different than what's going on Red's
rolling okay red guys also kind
of really afraid of the fog right now
he's like what's going on in his head
is this the darkness or the fog this is
the darkness no necessarily do anything
you have to do something in the fog 9:00
and so this world was for the guilt this
can affect yeah that didn't do anything
so poor Bo is kind of like flailing and
pain right this guy not so much on the L
note is not effective right now so we're
gonna roll for red trying to get out of
the fog while slightly going insane and
goodness yeah so he falls into the pool
splash he's dead no he's just in the
pool like if you tried running out at
you and he's a call a near an animal
okay
poor bo is gonna have a turn cuz he's
just panicking but his panic is gonna
make it so the LFL is going to charge
the yellow one yeah no I do like stove
okay she called him skillet akela felt
nice yeah all right so let's see Co ice
Lord and ISIL or doesn't get one Co and
dead bones you're gonna roll to get out
of the way dead bones first Dodge yeah
cuz this guy's gonna run straight
forward and Ram it to the wall Shh
Oh Lord alright if you're gonna be able
to jump out of the way nice 17 guys
gonna learn to roll at safe place not
all of your colonists alright so do you
want to take the damage of that he take
I take my damn before you take your good
the damage is gonna be I can't tell you
because you don't know you've never seen
this damage before like it's a random
amount of damage you're not sure I'm
gonna tell you after you take it so I'm
gonna kill private nice do you want a
second soon I have to sacrifice the
massive choice
yeah well you don't know how much damage
is gonna be what if it's
skele felt stampeding with porto right
yeah I mean I was but he's still on top
okay I'm estimating that this is gonna
be a pretty serious amount of damage so
I'm not gonna take the stamina sorry
sorry I slurred you have to ride it out
oh is itto my memory I'm goes back up it
because of that though so and you're
gonna take one two three four five
damage I get pushed out of the way I
think it's too late but chances you have
blade turn oh if I forgot about blade if
you would like to assign a five damage
for yourself right now you could I don't
know you can't you wrote one anyway
you don't get a choice in this yeah try
using your blinker b15 damage isn't too
uh he maybe next time this is slammed
into the wall you're what happened to
those porks that were like poor both
fell off and he's still in the darkness
okay
and I thought where'd the fog covered
the fog is just horrible
no one chat so this one's gonna come up
this was gonna come up and he's gonna
take his horns and he's gonna try to
pick up Justin and throw him onto his
back oh I mean it sounds fun but
probably not do I take all my damage by
the way or yes you did
okay Chatwood probably has no idea
what's going on because I updated your
stamina so you would have had this big
gap of hit points right they wouldn't
see the number proper him so I wasn't I
wasn't talking about Chad I just wasn't
sure you mean on our thing Oh enough no
you shouldn't be a fourteen yeah he was
it he was a twenty-one that he took five
plus whatever costs he's used as a cab
didn't he didn't know even before that
happened so no no he gave this back Oh
your backs back you don't get that help
I see I see I see so I feel like there
would be no penalty to ever casting
these things
oh they died right whatever
like well I'm saying so I got my max
back but I was at 19
you took five off that puts you in at 14
well that was four
all right cuz I didn't tank ice Lord oh
yes sorry yes sorry I got hurt you
didn't say you didn't tank guys those
dead-weights shit shut up I'm doing it
right now there's only five guys on the
field I got this all right you're
getting what did I roll on this I wasn't
painted 15
all right Justin you've been thrown onto
his back okay okay it's on his back
sweet Justin you might have made a
friend
green guy is going to walk up here and
he's gonna cast lifedrain on Roman your
sight oh all right
Roman cast mere sight on this on this
guy and it actually burns his eyes so he
can no longer see he's permanently blind
you near Saigon guys so hard that this
guy will no longer be able to see you
Hara Phi you also get human KO get two
free spells so your spell first Roman
alright um I'm gonna win blast green guy
okay seven you just barely hit him like
it's a it's not a very strong blast so
I'm gonna do four damage your true yep
now I'm I'm inside of a rock wall right
now who's gonna land against the wall so
you guys gotten to know and you know oh
he'll come for one yeah yo thanks buddy
oh god I don't know what to do I don't
know how to deal with these guys yet
they're not okay so I can only do a
spell so I really co yeah well you can
cast earth Lord right but we also just
saw Justin jump up on yeah I know but we
don't know what the consequences of that
are yet yeah we bad tap
I guess I'll try to fuck it's a spell so
for my spell I'm going to I'm gonna cast
a blanket of darkness over here so for
so these six guys so right in the center
there stay away from the tiles so you're
trying to get all four of these guys no
no these guys right here let's let the
eight-six
yeah I'm blocking the entrance with a
cloud of the darkness yeah so these six
guys here or or those four guys I guess
I'm sorry which one one up higher sorry
what a fire okay I see I want to get the
most you want to block the exit most
things the most he can yeah that's the
same 30-foot Oh better okay whoo that's
the free spells whose turn was it I
think it was that was he's blind down uh
let's see what can he do now screaming I
mean he Cassie
okay he's going to try and cast
lifedrain on Roman anyway he's just
gonna guess yeah just approximate so
glad these are things aren't kobolds he
hits Roman Wow Wow
because he 15:18 dgg just named that you
either you did it without his eyes
he just gets he just guessed yeah but
yeah but the range of is Italian ears
that wants it to one yeah but he burnt
out nice mmm yeah so near say isn't
affecting him it doesn't affect him
anymore because he's not you guys know
why I use his eyes to aim this spell ah
I see you burned out his eyes so he
didn't notice he so he's so normally be
getting hit by a mere sight you can't
cast spells cuz can't see so what he did
is he
has no eyes and he's screaming in pain
and he's just violently tried to hit you
with a life tap anyway and it did and it
rolled anything no I was not happy about
that but nobody gets hit for for it's
okay it's your turn next when you just
take it back and there might be other
things going off and the flame work gets
healed to full full whatever his max
health is I guess they didn't have that
much else okay red guy was in the pool
falling again and so he ran into madness
all right poor Bo needs to know you
already wrote for poor boy he said he
was gonna take a turn yeah poor was
listening in turn this guy's lifted like
done everyone I think you've done all
them comment okay so my turn ends
however all of the porks are now
grunting and screaming because Co has
attacked the porks whoops this was a
this was supposed to be an honorable 5v5
battle and Cobell engaged all of the
porks so all of the porks are furious
right now I really have a game here to
watch they came here to want to fight
and you just covered them in a black in
the darkness sorry you guys I thought it
was a great idea to this shit happened
it's okay we just need to kill poor but
we just need to kill poor Bob focus fire
yes focus focus fire
so Roman its you're dreaming fur Oh No
okay um all right let's see wind
blasting guy and guy
perhaps oh yeah you're stupider you know
you want to try and life to him back is
like he's gonna make it a little battle
ping-pong I want to see one two three
four five six seven eight nine
okay ko I'll just look after that it's
your turn
he looks just like before he life damned
okay um can I get this thing out of my
face
well drink it off um I'm not on it it's
just like it's so I'm just like wildly
casting spell or you could pull out the
mirror no it's like a fucking pokeball
okay trap it maybe those how much help
these things have then it's one less to
fight no it's got full health I already
know oh it's like a pokeball I thought
you know what I think the best thing I
can really do is catch the cloud of
madness right here get these live five
guys yeah just keep going man just keep
going cuz if they're all ableto
the best thing I can do is just fuck is
my fuck up as many as I might each other
yeah they're just gonna be all fucking
mad oh you cast your cloud a madness but
you kind of do a lot of overlap so it's
only expand by two by two here oh good
I'm glad I didn't cast it inside my own
scholars all right
it is now turn alright
I'm gonna arguments I'm gonna back up
here yeah
so here and can I see purple in the fog
yeah you can see him he's like stuck to
my boss I mean it's my fog all right
he's fucking I'm gonna be any use so
flare you guys thought flare Christmas
cool looking fireball of the fist is
even better you can't see poor it's my
boss a sorcerer
did you kill fog or did my cast at the
fog then you can't see through it
because you might can't see I'll do it
cuz I use the spell you use the spell
only jessica's well right I've got out
of proximation of where it's being
technical though you can see through it
you're fine
I'm shooting I'm human I'm shooting a
fireball at poor blood I like the idea
of them being able to see to the fog
because they have it it's fun 9 all
right you hit poor Bo oh boy how much
damage it's gonna be so many but no it's
the fireballs between this is Raul is it
one two three four five six seven eight
nine ten and then probably gonna take
nine ten so another ten one two three
four five six seven eight nine ten and
all the fog is going to blow up this is
all about lead it's also going to
destroy the fog that was created by this
it's causing rigor it yes which causes
to collapse so one two three
well yeah but now at least it's worth it
it was worth it
damn big big damage and he's still
crying right I get I got I got a melee
attack but I can't like do anything with
it so just an intern
all right am i controlling this guy I
don't know he's never lifted you up and
you're kind of like sitting on his head
like grabbing on to his hoof and you're
not sure why he's lifted you up there
alright well I can't imagine he's
friendly can someone get this thing off
for me let me find ya their floor to do
it poor boys more important aspire for
let me check yeah I was gonna do
something different yeah I think you
should focus focus fire poor book
we just look real quick at spaces why
would we focus fire poor beau killers
I'm gonna because we are here the leader
and they're gonna be fuckin oh shit they
kill poor beau here's what I'm doing all
right I am going through rolling fog
what are you trying to do man see I wish
I had colors for this wait wait wait
wait wait guys long faces yeah what what
if it's a curse and if we kill him we
become poor beau I'm okay with that
oh yeah that's not so bad
you're trying to cast it to go like this
uh yeah I want it to be like a line here
and then it's like expanding up that way
this is really trying to stop people
coming in or blight them all up and
always you know or light them all up in
the hallway of the land again first
really think we should focus fire cut 14
okay don't work so you cast rolling fog
and nothing okay
what yeah what it is now the mob streams
okay it's just weird
yeah hmm this elephant is gonna pick ko
onto his back
daddy magic things like a scenario Danny
okay beyond them to cast magic shit
peace port was gonna walk up wait wait
wait
isn't he mad though no man he was just
like oh yeah he was in the knives mad
that's why he was stuck in the fog and
fogs gone down now he's just pissed so
portable walks up the dead bones and he
screams throughout the cave okay I mean
we have all get school events for it but
no let me let me bring it up for you
guys okay
okay so every pork in the cave is now
coming to defend poor bow through this
one engine yeah every single pork is
going to be let through there actually
is though like if you look a lot with I
mean this there's still a lot of pork
and well you didn't go up in it no don't
worry about it
no the fog didn't go off yeah so this
this elif elk is going to he's gonna
move with just on top of it just makes
you fat the coats and he's just going to
try and stomp on Roman no my bus to
treason okay go ahead and blast the jump
out of the way room
Justin do a vorpal from up there
yeah blink ahead it might not work
yeah but it's is gonna be a Magic eight
so if it's magic like if it's an anti
magic area - he put the darkness up
already I did - darknesses that's my
last two turns that I've had okay
horrible scream - disguise stomper over
12 we where's where you jump into you
could jump three spaces I guess yeah I
could totally do that
I'm okay so did it stop at me so can I
jump backwards or there's gonna keep
coming at me it's it's top down stomped
at you it's not charging it's okay thank
you so it's gonna miss and I'm gonna
move three back this way okay so poor go
did it did a roar poor was also gonna
swing his weapon at dead bones
I said he doesn't have a weapon he's
just gonna punch she's gonna punch I
like it is what I do yeah 6 6 ok
portable missus mr. this guy's gonna get
out of the pool this blind guy is gonna
walk up to dead bones okay and he's
gonna try to Point Blank life tab or
Life Drain 99 so it hits dead bones but
only barely has dead bones the Downloads
only takes two here and he goes right
back up to full health
goddamnit how does he go I don't know
they've got a finger thing it's a facial
or bullshit like remembers remember the
last fucking phosphate it was like
sunfury tails and she know the other
ports are moving in on you but they're
not really babble ish so they're moving
up oh yeah darkness rolls darkness rolls
I just do one big one let's do one big
roll to see how many are gonna get
affected this is oh my god the exception
of these two that walk out every other
one has gone completely insane so we're
gonna use from that one we're gonna use
red ones for two three if they've gone
completely insane
this one right you know to the darkness
is working I still think we focus fire
poor boy by the way okay so with this
darkness these guys are walking up and
they're fighting each other
and these ones are walking up and
they're fighting each other so it's just
chaos going on in the dungeon right now
yeah these guys are moving forward
and anything that's moving over here you
can't tell but they're all moving closer
so okay it is now Rome's turn well
effects no thanks hold on my elephant
huh yeah
LF L kiss Calif elk okay sorry yeah so
Roman
okay so we got blind guy here life tap
the living shit out of himself that
bones and keep skyrocketing I don't just
i straight-up think we just focus for
our poor bro I think this is a terrible
idea
I think it's look how many ads there are
and these things are immune to magic do
you have anything that's not magic you
can hit those guys with come on Jeff
ante magic just fucking go for poor Bo
you might roll 20 and then you get to do
more fucking things and you can do
whatever but I think you spoke as well
folks fire pourable man you love
pointing out 5% chances I can't play for
you but I'm just saying uh there's too
many nodes I don't know I'm going along
with this yes there are trash mobs are
they really cuz these elephants aren't
fuckin shitty from rice elbows yeah well
the great guys are that yeah until
there's like ten of them until they
surround you right yeah yeah uh hold on
no we got it it's gonna be a different
way wait you hit or bow and thingy no no
I can't hit both I'll have it to you by
two um so let's carry went to the pool
did I was there anything was there any
side effects after when he came out of
the pool do you look the same you look
stronger a weaker no nothing hold on
what if I do this I'm gonna grab Justin
and take him off the millivolt I like it
okay alright yeah so what I'm gonna do
ravenclaw Justin off the elif elk
just can't swim probably sucks it
getting off forces all right you went to
go use it on Justin and you just get
them off the yellow felt but you didn't
grab them you hit them so Justin takes
five damage and then two from falling
off the elephant it's just nice playing
out that's fine
yeah actually that's really the worst of
the case yeah seven stamina to turn to
get off vanilla though that's
immediately gonna pick you up it's fine
hmm well he's got a term if we can do it
give it turns up yeah he's got a turn
you