okay as you walk into the cave here
let's do it like this you see three
ports and they're just kind of like
sitting by this pool of purpley goo
that's bubbling constantly the ports
look at you but they don't even really
care this let it stand there one of them
is stirring it with a little chain ladle
Hey look at you and one of them just
like knobs do you like oh like the usual
just kind of oh what's up yeah that's
all right all right well it's time for
some diplomacy we haven't talked to
anything this game combat hey hey pork
pork pork did you see a little kid run
past here little small elf it's very
small elf nope no cd did you put him
into that whatever that is nope
me no see that know me know do what what
are you doing with the thing what's what
is this making more porks wait you're
making pork
making more porks how do you make a pork
you dig a pig huh really that's all
works
that's fascinating something squadron
strike combat has started wait wait wait
wait you want to do something that
kissed him go who is your leader
horrible horrible poor boys boss Barbeau
is strongest can we got to Porto oh poor
poor boo sleeping poor boy sleeping in
his pool in his pool
wait pool
sleeps in the purple stuff at this point
the green one in the back you're talking
to the red one the green one is going to
roll dice oh whoa whoa whoa
wait he's like actually rolling bones in
the back of the case he starts barfing
up purple into the pool this was the one
with the lady just starts going into the
pool it's gross
and it pops a guy yeah and this guy just
says walking into the cage ah man that's
disgusting
I really should we really needed to
start with warm oh are you I don't think
we need to talk the poor bloom but you
know where's house yes let's see poor Bo
don't see poor boys my brother
elves don't see poor buh-bye now you
leave this place why do friendly wait
door kill elves we can we kill elephants
vanilla Phillips Ella folks Porter what
if one of us wanted to become big boss
me won't be big boss fight poor walking
away from you well squadron strike
you're now talking to the blue one so
you're talking I'm talking to the blue
one now ask him the same question we
want to fight poor Bo you know talking
to the green one who's like I just
finished barfing and he's stirring the
ladle you got a little yeah I got a
little spit in there and god dammit
he just slurps up his purpley vomit into
his mouth we're here to deliver a
package for poor Bo present for par Bo
oh you give Portville present what
horrible president tribute many Chinese
okay booth many shiny ports the tribute
what love shiny okay you fuck you Father
book this way
alright you guys could be on to
something here boss look we just got up
yeah get in there
and then we deal with the big one all
right that's how this works it's a
leadership thing we just gotta take out
the head
I trust caucus we didn't do it good look
Roman we're gonna so we're gonna save
your brother if he's in there with your
banister don't be able to invest in
playing with your hand buddy what are
you talking about look we're gonna save
your brother but we we just gotta take
up the bit poor Bo big poor boy find out
okay this already are you on board on
board squadrons are on board all right
squadron strong courage that squadron
strike thing squad just banister okay
well we were talking I didn't think you
guys would beat that guy oh yeah you
didn't think we'd beat him it kind of
thought you would lose this is that was
pretty strong good twenties good 20s or
what say it did that right a surprising
fight those guys either it was a ready
for this
I'm just making everything persistence
all this stuff will go across the board
so get any one second while you're at it
Rob the puppets are also in front of the
car I thought I should just let you know
well thanks
true thing I'm sorry guys I don't know
why that I think I was silly and but in
the break I renamed my program and said
that broke it so I'm sorry about that
I could hopefully I didn't miss any
treasures here lucky I know how to talk
to porks I mean they're really stupid
it's really easy I do it all the time
with you stupid or friendly Oh
done done this is called pork hunters
yeah we are pork hunting
this is attacking for us the porks try
and befriend them no we look up we hunt
for the porks that's what we do we bring
them food what strange dimension have we
entered in here is does that say ray
what is that there's text on the ground
I think one of my cards didn't come over
the gasp yeah what is missing
I don't know if I made a skill actually
I'm missing my padded armor right there
what am I missing
oops oh no your your good one huh code I
think I'm missing I'm missing a
rejuvenation potion I think because I
had yes I traded and stuff this one wait
am I missing spell emitting a spell
you should have five spells no you're
fine no wait Oh what about there are yes
I still have a fuck I still the fireball
enough fog from have you never have you
never used the fireball never use where
did you get the fireball from I got the
fire but when we fought like way ages
ago like a deck in the fire fight okay
yeah that's what I got a fireball in -
and a fog yeah I thought I sent all
these to be persistent but they seemed
like only be persistent for like it
doesn't actually save that effect on
these cards like you have to remember
before
each show I just I had to remember
before the show yeah
okay so we're all our guys this is huge
yes are you are you missing a fireball
oh yeah Bravo
okay got it Rob just give me the
Powerball it's I that's what it was okay
you guys have entered enter a cave that
is much bigger than you first thought
okay let's see Megan I thought you guys
it's a lot of parks like as you come
come on you can see like pork speaking
out of caves like all over the place
yeah there's a lot of porks huh okay
like you like when when you first enter
this one pork comes up but he's just
like well they start talking and pork
backe back and forth to each other and
you know these guys these guys are like
laughing cuz you know you said you
wanted to fight the boss all right yeah
but don't know no one no there bring us
for tribute right yeah oh yeah that's
right they bring you for tribute so he's
like Oh exciting tribute
so he's like he's like I'm gonna follow
you around - so apparently every time
you walk forward and these guys tell
them to treat you I'll put the hooded
pork is gonna be like I'm gonna see this
tribute so the situation is gonna get
out of control quickly as we move
forward so unless you guys want to
change the plan they're gonna lead you
there but but they're gonna have a
procession with us Oh oh my god I wanna
come with - and follow these guys you
guys diplomacy squad you want to take a
chance take a second while you're so
this is you guys like just chatting
amongst yourself you actually pay
forward I want to make I want to make
something we're gonna be talking in
elvish they have no idea is that right
defend them I don't I don't know I don't
know how porks feel they talk in pork
all the time the fine band this we are
stirred that this is the problem
we're surrounded and the more we go the
more porks are gonna come does anybody
have any ideas but we Street it like a
stealth mission we look we get them to
take us to their leader
we've seal off the area and we do our
thing we just decide we take we take it
too big we take up war bow yeah so once
outside don't know what's true what's up
Roman what about the other hundreds of
porks that seem to be following us
there's a lot of shit he's got no he's
gonna we're gonna cave in or block the
entrance somehow right we can block the
entrance we've got stuff that does that
we can show put your choke point it
didn't mr. Roman didn't you ever see
that premiere of Dubai pyramids the
puppet names I don't know should i film
the block you can tell them the block
yeah I can tell them the formal wall yes
they're like pokey man's look what just
choke point it's it's tactics 101 we
will get inside and then we'll just you
know thin the herd this is why you're
the leader Justin are you okay with this
give any suggestions anything chilly
willy bannister could you move so I can
see Justin better okay you don't have to
move this anyway let's just let's just
let's do that all right
squadron strike somebody I think we're
just gonna keep going till we get to
poor but without as many porks as we
come with us I think this is good
there's a lot of eight we have a lot of
AOE we cool we have to fight most of
these anyway right like yeah man really
they're friendly remember yeah they're
friendly actually you know what I have I
think I might have a leadership idea
well you guys could keep talking as much
as you like you're just walking to the
cave following oh well do you want you
get okay can I see that guys can keep
talking as you're moving right all right
I've got new new strategy because this
is a lot of guys go you can just you
move back a bit if you want no yes I
like you a lot right now I know but it's
yeah and I love it's great but you're
kind of stepping on banisters toast
a married sir just a little bit as you
walk past the pic though you can say oh
hey here's where you would have ended up
do we have him oh you get us you talking
I'm sorry okay right so a new plan you
guys ready for the new plan but we
didn't even we didn't even do the old
planned oh yeah the new the new plan
inaudible there's way more there's way
more porks than I thought about it
honest what we're gonna do is we're
gonna get into poor Bo right and we're
gonna challenge you us poor mute me and
you guys stay the squad vs. poor Bo and
his Elite Guard huh
porks like to post like challenge
they'll do it they're not yeah think
about that's really a different plan
kind of because we won't have to fight
luck like all the porks that are behind
us there's linking a lot of ports I may
be bad if we kill for vote no because
the leader rules here you sure you're
strong do you I don't think they care
Roman I don't do they care I'm gonna
just take your word for that I guess
yeah don't worry guys I've been hunting
porks way longer than you guys have
I mean worst case scenario they just get
pissed off an attack us right I mean
they were gonna attack us anyway by
sometime so think of it like that
if so if things look bad whatever you
started I like the idea of fair combat
as you guys are walking past you can see
what looks to be a pink I know and you
can see what was the name fetus Phineas
Phineas you can see Phineas unconscious
in a pig pen does this change the plan
are you gonna break formation that's my
brother look I think he'll be fine if we
start once we start fighting they'll all
come to a watch he'll be fine what is he
in a pen does a nice is there like a
pool is he just surrounded by pigs so
don't know so there's only three pigs
this looks like some place where they it
looks like pig pens it looks like this
is where they keep people they turn into
porks
okay but it looks like fitting this is
just like unconscious or sleeping laying
down in a pen
there's the porks that are like just
nearby that are just kind of like
they're playing some sort of like ball
and stick game there's like a bunch of
sticks on the ground and then you just
take turns throwing the ball at the
sticks and then honking at each other
you do not understand what is the
objective of the game is but it kind of
looks like funny well boss ck me I have
an idea what's your idea
I also am an idea but I'll hear your
foot yours first okay this right here
throw that let's tell them that we have
to go to the bathroom just go in there
no their pork sporks will just shit on
the ground that's just how they do it
yeah but they don't care but they know
that were elves and they know that we
don't do that
they don't know that we're elves you see
poise yourselves earlier they call
themselves you're about that step
through the puke on the ground there's a
lot of icing a ground it's going to
start dirtying your clothes as you guys
move forward we need to shit or get off
the pot yeah look Roman come back you
still go back which one of us looks the
most like a pork probably your all the
Alps I don't think anyone looks like a
pork you does anybody know disguise
anybody learn that and nobody nobody
mind that okay well I can't assess right
a lot of coats it's kind of fad past the
pool these three guys walk up and these
guys start talking on okay I think I
think we're just gonna have to go with
plan to hurry but I think Plan B should
be less is literally walk that way while
those guys are talking I don't go and
every time one walks there's like hey
what's going on it's like these guys
gonna get the kid to give that other
boss tribute they're like Oh tribute I
want to see this see we've just gotta
roll with it now we've dug ourselves
into the pocket minute you got a
committed to the plan as why does it
take so long to say things in L
because it's very long language it's
just you know there's a lot of Al's and
rolling it all right but if I got all
the till T's all right all right let me
just want this by you guys real quick
okay okay what's your plan now but if we
keep into that main room we're gonna be
swarmed swarmed it's gonna be like a
hundred times worse
yeah just bog off this wall and you're
gonna fight now let's just do this you
want to fight now but yeah I'm just
throwing it out there I I don't know
just I really like the challenging into
combat idea I think that could work
we if we challenge you to combat and he
says no then you turn around and you're
all like hey motherfuckers this is just
a pork screaming and like all the pork
said of this game come out all once to
do what see I feel like maybe we should
just do the tribute we have some like
really cool stuff you know what we wait
maybe we do the tribute thing we and we
don't piss them off and then every
challenge we can we can get his brother
into the mirror that I have somehow and
just leave I don't but when we just
break the mirror later and he pops out
we need to kill the porks like that's
well at least we need to think that we
need to thumb the ranks because they're
attacking the town not recently but they
listen to the guy in the sky wait so now
we're just pork slaughterers yeah yeah
we're assholes you know we all right so
here's I'm thank you what's what's
what's the idea chilli we go with the
challenge idea uh-huh they don't want to
challenge the tribute that's I like it I
don't want rib you that's a good idea
you fight like guys I think I think
private ice Lord has an idea here okay
your uh what's your input isolate you
promote me as a shitty idea isolate what
it's good
how does that wants to become tribute so
if we actually really shiny he is there
we could convince him they're made of
gems yes a gem person it's fine cuz we
can we do the challenge you didn't want
a challenge we do the tribute that's
it's gonna work it's good we got this we
got this guy's got a plan Roman reason
you're gonna run out of time talking so
just just this is it guys alright so if
we got a combat let me take the lead
okay yeah no you're gonna the plan is
Justin
mhm you blow the fuck out of them with
your fireballs uh or ice blasts I don't
really care yeah yeah last time leave it
up to me okay I got we I believe in you
guys anymore
look at my eyes look at myself into this
iceberg I slowed to a rhyme a tribute I
got prize I'm sorry
shut up I sleep you did this it's kind
of your plan and a back-up plan you may
never been do you right now it's insane
we've never been this prepared before in
our lives
alright as you say Justin as you as you
walk into the room yes can stay on the
screen as you walk into the room okay
the pork start like making like a
passage for you to walk through and then
huh they stand there except for the ones
that let you into the game and you can
see a lot more porks okay okay and
you're just walking forward yeah we're
just going up to Parliament we're going
all the way we're going where they're
leading us yeah alright we do this get
your game face challenging the chilly
willy don't challenge it to Chilly Willy
junk and win you can totally win
Julia don't sing back house I don't
think that counts important don't can't
we at least know ass
I mean we can ask really really that'll
be playing we'll ask you that desire
spell plane yeah really really will ask
him about Alaska I don't have torques
play chilly willy we'll ask him we'll
find out a whole alphabet of side plans
we have an alphabetical plans and we
also have the plan of just fight things
and well uh if we die we we die right
here a lot of clickety-clacking I don't
want to die hey hey Romans do you run
you hear about plan D nope not spline
David Wow it's great
hey I like that plan the porks in the
room walls like tribute to you tribute
tribute mm-hmm should you tribute my god
I just looked at this alright so the
last guy he's walking up okay hmm
all right yellow tube you ready we're
gonna have a trip we got to talk to poor
Bo talk to give tribute get a weird
tribute you attribute which tribute for
poor Bo your troop you you feed our bull
and all of us be happy well wait we feed
him so he wants something to eat yeah he
loves the e elves you feed portable and
he no hit me anymore no no be anymore I
mean I'm I'm sorry that you getting here
but listen we brought shiny things for
poor Bo we didn't we're not tribute um
shiny thing is very very pretty yeah
look here
look at shiny things shiny man shiny man
will never have that right poor boy
gonna love it okay you give that the
portable we see if you like it so I
don't okay you won't get hit anymore
like what's your name what's your name
no what is what what poor cut what pork
you call Tork call you what are your
Gork pork
I own pork pork mmm Everest why actually
actually give themselves name poor Bo
didn't even name himself that's what
other people named him okay and so they
only know the leader same chilly willie
do it yeah will you spork oh you love
chili with you never mind you want to
play chilly willie
no you you need to give tribute
everybody here waiting for tribute so we
don't get hit by porn okay but we're
gonna go up to poor boy and give him
tribute okay won't get any more poor
ever look here look here okay
oh you die weather too we're gonna be
good all right he's leading you to the
pool mm-hmm these are all you coming up
with all right I'm gonna stay back I'm
gonna stay like here just is gonna stay
back a little bit okay yeah right here
everybody else
yeah the rest of us are going straight
up to him okay as you approach the pool
you can see these steps and this is the
big vat of acid and the pork goes up and
he goes
Boop and then all of a sudden a hand
just reaches out grabs him you hear so
wheeling grunting dysphoric different
sounds and just a body comes flying out
of the pit okay and then go out and then
all of a sudden boom Portville comes out
oh shit combat is started all right
before I started
so combat is started but I mean you
could still go for the diplomacy I mean
he doesn't even know what's going on
just the guy doesn't take a turn to dupe
diplomacy or what can we just shout
things before stuff gets bad absolutely
like if you if you start taking a turn
to try and diplomacy with him oh I have
to use a turn to diplomacy well then
there will be his turn well you you
start firing spells it would chase the
porks are gonna go up there's no tribute
happening because they think you're
paying tribute still right only pork was
come out and he's vicious cuz you know
that's these poor bones so if we're
going like you're normal and you are we
going turn order here or uh yet would be
going by turn order if we're gonna do
comment if you're gonna do diplomacy I
mean I'm so got an idea but if we're
doing diplomacy is that like a communal
turn or is that just like communal turn
so think about like who's gonna go first
either you guys are gonna go first and
you're obviously gonna start with rope
or the enemies are gonna go for the
enemies are gonna go first but the enemy
would only be poor Bo the other pork
obviously be attacking yet until poor bo
has attacked so okay
so Justin what was your little idea
before we commit to this one way or the
other if we start fighting here I wanna
I we've got all these Forks in that
hallway in a good position yeah I want
to throw fog at it and then throw a
fireball at it yeah yeah and I think I
think we're doing pretty good like we
got really wanted to shit I really want
to try and get the fucking leads with
poor but my guys can like just at the
table so not like actually game if you
want to talk about how
want to handle this that's that's fine
yeah yeah you don't have to hold just be
blindly oh goodness
we could try the diplomacy route first
because I mean if he gets mad and just
smack see it's still our turn again yeah
is this the return if we still try to
talk I mean if he uses his turn to
retaliate Oh use our turn then it's our
turn again because they won't attack so
maybe it is worth doing diplomacy my
pourable would attack if you yeah if
diplomacy fails
okay so Roman ko you worried what do you
think cuz just let me see our diplomacy
I'm good with diplomacy okay jet Co I
just came up with Plan F okay what's
finance real quick fuck this let's get
out of here that's not I'm sorry alright
so I'm gonna use in the turn and shout
bourbeau yeah who are your bow you are
now or go big bad org no baby boys
business of porks scared you you bunny
else you for you good guy you Pisa funny
elf is the euphoria all right let's see
if port your joke there entertains Porco
so high-tech oh yeah no portable you've
actually kind of calmed down poor boo a
little bit he's less coming out swinging
more like he thought it was funny that
you wanted to fight them you think I'm
not serious
considering you're swarmed with porks
poor poor Bo yeah you funny little elf
hoo-hoo-hoo poor Bo killed to become big
boss who was pork who was poor but
before poor boy poor bono like talking
about that poor boy why not kill own
mother to become poor bo o he poor Ville
has to kill ma mama
marble barbecue Mambo to become bored oh
boy will kill Mambo you don't like to
think about that
that's sad poor Bo did did poor Bo kill
Mambo alone or with people who killed
Mambo alone for about killed mom oh
hello miss bumble but for Buddha to kill
Babu typical port bow what why did poor
will have to become poor bow because
poor bow is strong Porto want to be best
pork the best pork you kill other strong
pork you kill other strong men are you
stronger than me I think we me and theta
squad can fight you and your best pork
of equal number
buddy thinks you could be portable and
even dumper but so so you wouldn't fight
me and my porks
versus your men for MA
check this out yeah roll the seat poor
who is entertained ordained you not you
not as funny as other elf Coco back off
back off get back don't so poor Bo and
three elf
three pork versus theta squad no port
bow no and tombow and rumble aha and
that book and that book over there yeah
that guy yeah pork over there okay yeah
oh wait do you get that you get that
little little thing to port yeah I think
you want pork down but tasty or Steve
gonna fight with these as well yeah okay
so do you all versus us all four become
poor bow the halls just echo then they
just echo with the laughs of all these
porks laughing that you want to fight
poor Bo oh okay
if you want to die poor go fight you
that is okay do this let's do this fair
and square
okay so these other ones are just gonna
back off into the side mm-hmm
let me know if at any point you want to
just engage in combat
poor bows basically just he's he's like
gone over to like tell his men that
they're they're gonna be fighting you
guys has he gone off is he gonna puppet
screen he's gone off puppet screen yeah
alright everybody get on puppet screen
all right it's gonna work we've got this
plan we've got this you guys ready
Justin get up here before
that starts no actually mean move your
tile get close to us before combat
starts
you