[Music]
all right so it is now coast turn okay
oh man I'm really torn between going for
the refried beans over here
I don't think we want to go into red
beans all right well I'm gonna use my
sweet Ruby and I move to go over here
sweet and backing up hold on if
technically his ice pet has the Ruby
that he gave it to him that is a good
point you said you okay that's fine you
use them you can use its turn to give it
back the Ruby anyone
all right so I'm gonna have my okay fine
I'm gonna have my private ice Lord just
start going over to engage in battle for
is he is he able to get close enough to
do that nice it was like you got a ruby
too right he's got a ruby you should be
able in two three four five somewhere
like this would be able to get him okay
that's good something yeah we'll do a an
ice beam or whatever the wave frost
sorry trying to stun yeah I won't try to
stun
good I mean really - all right you miss
lis hit the carriage great oh here's the
Coney where though it's the carriage
don't have to turn these would have
moved to do that for Roman this one's
gonna suck tank right yeah the two would
attack two are attacking him
they both miss Adam alright and I'm
gonna summon a nerd to attack chimera
one hold on do you want for this I don't
watch pool I mean I can I can summon it
face this way and they can walk yeah
he's so move the range from that spell
anyway since you're giving it a command
he says don't do this thing you summon
an earth Lord let's grab a spirit okay
and then he's gonna move for you so one
two three four five check in him the
Ruby and you need to stamina me for that
okay yeah oh and stamina me for mine
okay
no come here Stern all right chef well
pretend he was stunned on his cold last
turn since that's true he did get to
stun by the Rhea frost all right how are
you doing it's no people this is e well
this time I'm gonna get my items for
sure just gotta let me know he doesn't
have his treasures yet no because chat
was right he was stunned
so then how is even taking turns after
us it he hasn't got his treasures oh
because they're not treasures if you
look at him you know there it's what is
it passives the wing Kings curse he's
cursed oh okay okay
these four are always affecting him
there they are not Trish they're things
you just they're things they couldn't
remove brands markings whatever to news
that's one of the things we can't
possibly steal from them yeah yeah I
thought about that so I'm gonna take the
18 there now I got everything my weapons
out of my chest that's the last free
turn you gettin all right dead bones it
is your turn alright before I get up how
big is the carriage I mean it's a big
carriage it was a lot of space because
they had it was very
very well secured just not so you're
enough for cheater 28 20 s right I don't
know it's a normal carriage size I
probably wouldn't be able to tell us a
carriage I'd say like the size of like a
small room or something okay there's no
way I can toss a carriage classic
carriage uh no it's it's really
reinforced yeah I I can't see him at all
can I even if I get up by the earth
casino if I got even up here he's pretty
big overall Cobalt he's not as tall as
an elf like he's still he's pretty short
so if I got maybe up here could I see
him from here yeah but you're starting
to go like into a woods so it's kind of
okay well I'll just try and get like I'm
trying to get visual on him at least
okay now you can at least kind of see
him but you're like look yeah through a
bunch of guys fighting him type of deal
yeah well you know I'm gonna set up a
blockade seems like it's the only thing
I can really do spells for everybody oh
shit give our mister one stamp you know
okay hoo-hoo sure gets one stamina
okay so Roman free spell you can't move
and I can't really see anything we're
gonna cast some more air sprites that's
what I'm thinking
I want to cast in the back area okay
kind of block Aegean islands I Cyril
oh and that big Philippe
I warned you guys I told you guys in
Philippe wouldn't like a peacefully Tory
you know it's a thought they should have
known they should have known it was
bleep a because I we clearly didn't say
it was Philippe we just we just said a
couple yeah they just feel tricked you
shouldn't jump to conclusions guys man
reef or is that about right Roman you
want to move baby that's one over here
in case this one dies oh that okay uh Co
you have a free spell so I guess that
word
yep like that if we can do this me to be
really proud of us seven all right you
someone earth Lord he's just gonna be
there though okay okay um same command
by the way his last yeah okay so it is
now this one that one doesn't get active
idiot check you can hold on so it's now
that was dead bones it's true that was
differences turn you didn't blockade Deb
bones I'll let you move up forward if
you want from them yeah look it's okay
it was a twenty right honorable okay yes
yes ibly basically care yeah up there
with the blockade then yeah in fact you
even can shimmy with this guy would you
prefer I can get in front of him who's
twice like it's 120 yeah yeah it's just
like jumping into action yeah you're
trying to protect these other elves yeah
gotta jump to the engine you bad guy up
um all right so this guy's turn alright
we're gonna try to what are we gonna do
I gotta I gotta I gotta play this guy's
smart if I actually want to win
okay so first I'm gonna do ray of frost
and I'm gonna do it in a line to get
these four just cheat array or Frost
right down the middle of you guys and it
will do five damage
11 Roman do you don't want to take any
of these hits to you just because it's
fam itself
yeah so these things just explode this
guy gets hit for five what is he blue
one two three four five and he's gonna
be stunned so I'm gonna flip him over
then he's gonna attack dead bones once
because he doesn't really realize what
you're doing I'm gonna catch you why did
you get to attack why does he see Freya
Frost yeah didn't you tell a joke that's
actually been moved to a different thing
so okay plus he kept trying here you put
a Stebbins you heard the joke right Roma
just didn't hear it over there here's a
pretty ya know Roman Roman heard over
the robot crackle it was really funny
don't try to give me your typicality
bullshit Roman or I will have this guy
jump over the carriage ready I'm going
for the things that aren't you first
okay
whisper did you six okay so he swings at
dead bones dead poem's can you block it
it bounces off so realizes can't do that
so he ghost this he goes to move in to
take out this elf
he ain't gonna waste his time with
spirits he's gonna do another Winfrey
blade and he misses oh yeah so - dice -
nice - nice thank you dice no I'm going
to I'm being fucked we're not used to
kobolds it right I got it I gotta try
and remember that
okay and he misses so he doesn't get
another attack after that okay so now it
is just restin yep just you can probably
see him if you move down yeah can I see
him if I got behind dead bones
you're like sense in the woods like
you're gonna be if you cast a fireball
there's a really crowded so okay you can
see her I could can I see him from here
yeah great want to move there and uh
it's all spar ball Adam okay
oh well well whatever maybe he's got
spell armor who knows okay you're just
looking not to kit him and you can hit
him for nine damage sick one two three
four five six seven eight
don't say the horrifying things my
higher findings
all right spell arbor you kiddo know if
the elf has spell armor man so he's now
seeing how threatening justin is so he's
going to ignore this guy try to run
around him 1 2 3 4 5 and he's gonna try
to flare he's got Flair he's gonna catch
but you knew all this stuff about him
that bone he's gonna catch no most of
the dog I didn't know he had Flair 20
the music it's a it's a 20 yeah does he
has the idol oh shit
so he's camp so the fog is immediately
gonna spread in the way he would like it
to create this barrier just like this
keep in mind it's fog
yeah that's flammable yeah but he can't
cast the spell now he's good question
did he he didn't cast that on me
technically right no I get to steal that
steal that no guys don't you feel that
he did get he didn't cast the fog no he
definitely did you definitely get a copy
of that so you get a compact yeah nice
here's somebody go through these cards
real quick and just find this I got you
I'll find it yeah okay um so that
happened he's gonna have won three
attacks so he's gonna work blade the
yellow coal bulb cuz he hasn't use that
I get to play a lot this time guys so
yeah you get had a lot of fun wrong 15
all right so he hits this guy for was it
three damage on yellow one two three and
now he's gonna teleport
let's go link yeah so oh man blink one
two three four five
I'm so blockading telerate right behind
him for this plague right behind him
he's being fancy right justice your turn
all right stop make a copy of that fog
for me I didn't know if you want me to
pull it out of the deck yeah yeah yeah
all right so it's it's a single-member
wait no it's wrong Easter it's rich it's
no it's enemies turn right or wrong just
yeah yeah after just so it's enemy turn
so we'll do the elves first
[Music]
what all right Chad's giving you guys
reinforcements something nice so you
have four more spell blades coming down
the road that is awesome though I'm
absolutely terrified that we are able to
have yeah yeah it's a good thing in a
bad you should be scared
good god items all right so this guy is
going to try to one of the green guys
gonna try the enemies you asked yeah
this guy's gonna try to start shimmying
through the forest just to get all the
way around and then yellows gonna attack
this is a body over here so we'll just
move the bodies out of the way so greens
going that so we're gonna have green and
yellow attack green and yellow so array
of frost and a flare this is the Ray of
wide only one to well I guess that works
anyway this could be the ray of frost
this can be the flare so the flare will
miss hit nothing the rare frost will hit
him and stun him so to damage to the
cold he's stunned so that is his turn
and now it is Romans turn mm-hmm okay so
he's behind the carrier so I still can't
see him yeah you're way out of the way
and now you either gotta go run through
a fog or climb on top of the carriage or
try maybe you can get behind
alright do I know this hmm you see you
kinda see what's going on it's a
carriage I mean it's kind of blocking
line-of-sight but you can just see all
the jumping you know the general
vicinity so when you start to walk
you're not gonna be surprised where he
is you could summon more sprites I'm not
summoning more sprites okay I'm gonna
cast wind blast at the fog oh that's
right Thank You Chet I need to
take three hills from him for that one
he rolled oh yeah it was it reduces his
max health but I'm but I'm just treating
it like three days oh you're drool oh
you actually given to that oh okay I
thought it was just basically does
nothing to him but I did actually take
three hill from him so I'm gonna try it
I'm a cat's windblast at this fog I'm
gonna try and move it away I mean I know
well its fog it looks bad so you want
you you know you will know what rolling
fog does you're you're an elf you study
love magic yeah you know what that is
yeah oh yeah I know that that's
explosive and bad okay you're blowing it
like into the cave almost I'm blowing it
to the cave you you conjure wind blast
but for some reason like it's just you
like bounce it off this cave wall the
wind does some sort of random physically
thing and justin is now fully
encompassed by this fog yeah so is COEs
elemental you've just made it worse a
quick question can i blink out a fog you
can try you don't we don't remember you
people have tried the last time like you
can blink one way and then just come out
the wrong way might merge your do you
don't know which direction you might
become part of this and then I want to
move I'm gonna move away from the the
treeline kinda in the back a little bit
yeah about here yeah you guys also also
consider that this isn't a video game if
this if things get bad you might have no
choice like right now the the elves are
trying to re apprehend this prisoner but
you know you shouldn't die do it kit
right I mean unless you feel you're that
noble of a person dead bones but seeing
as what you've done to these are the
three elves is not a character that you
guys would die for some other elves I
mean I didn't hit any else but I think
since I know that I get sky mare I would
probably still try my best shot
position I'm just gonna put him here
completely forget about him and then my
sprites need to do their things yes okay
my sprites are moving in sprites are
gonna swarm man those things are used to
so one two three four damage potentially
come on sprites okay so only two of them
are gonna hit see they okay damage um
got like I know how many Corrections are
gonna be unless these guys point out the
corrections guys just I don't we've got
a backseat DMing I don't know if you
know this there's like 17 units on the
board all with different passes and
abilities except just if I miss anything
that's important to these guys
characters definitely bring it up like
you guys are responsible for remembering
things like Justin's coat and things
like that that are going off though okay
[Music]
turn was that that was Roman stairs
Roman ounce cobbles turn so he's gonna
continue to try and kill green at what
can I do
is there a frost
I'm gonna try to win blast this yellow
one all right double dice 19 cop yellow
the yellow one is dead he's not dead
he's unconscious and now I'm gonna start
swinging at this one
here's windfury blade one hits his wind
three blades - OH
misses yeah double four so I only hit
him fruit three Green is somehow still
alive good before look at Katie's okay
that means it is everything right then
yeah we should nobody else on this turn
okay now is now coaster
alright go so do you want that your
elementals to go first these green ones
are a joy to go there laughter your turn
um I'll have them go after private ice
Lord okay surprise didn't he see through
his pet can you see to his pet me
through his pet like candy does he know
what's happening yes okay see we'll see
through the frosted connection because
I'm a camel on the Kabbalah I'm gonna
say that you've been out I'm gonna say
that you have some form of communication
and you probably have some form of
vision but it's not like your normal
fishing it's however he sees the world
so yeah you can we're gonna be able to
see through I don't know if I would let
you hmm
no okay well let's just go full on no
yeah you can see through your pet so you
could use your pet to line up something
that you normally couldn't see through
if he can see it sure we can give him
line of sight
your pet can see you can see it okay
it's really good
well then let's let's do ray of Frost
with private ice Lord rain frost hits
he's now stunned takes two damaged sweet
alright the the shitlords can go do I
roll for them uh no you don't the Rope
for them they're still moving right now
oh you have to roll roll me one dice for
this guy because he's lost in the fog
will he find his way he absolutely will
find his home and he will be charged
through to attack the snow like bulls
right yes so now he's go he's gonna
attack it oh yeah you guys are get
spells here the second - he's gonna miss
his attack but now go and roam and have
a spell right now they can cast I guess
more things wait there was a sorry this
is fine out you can roll the 20 yeah
that's what he's saying
yeah just don't use he'll alright uh I
guess I'll drop probably Oh a room and
I'll give you give you some locations
buddy no problem Fran I really like you
Oh chilly really is the good I'll do
that I'll do that right after here they
they haven't needed it yet anyway
also was blue was the blue out stunned
this one here I just wanna get that out
what do you mean was he stunned Oh was
the other guy
oh why did he do a free attack on the
purple cool bull well apparently he's
not dead he was just stunned or so I'm
I've been repeatedly told I just want to
clarify he's dead he's dead
always he was stunned man he had one
health of my sheet uh the stun was so
bad that when he tried to break out of
it he cut himself and Eve passed out
boom there we go
ROM solves problems like this is a hard
thing to do because there are things
like stun effects and there's so many
guys a lot to keep track of and there's
passing out and there's probably
different ways we can have tokens to
have that we haven't mastered it yet
now he's passed out Chad do you want to
know something these guys each only have
nine health which is one full combo of
the coal
every single one he gives one round them
every single turn just he that one's
gone don't make me bring it back or I'll
stop going for the elves and I will just
start crushing the hero's blessings
because he's going for the elves cuz he
doesn't see all the elves are the same
but he's not Wow yeah I'll start bastard
being cruel if you're gonna start
backseat DMing every goddamn point
alright so what was go yeah or any of
the other elves um Noble although
they're all spell blades every single
okay very simple they're all spell
blades they all have like one of two
spells unique dave has his own set of
things okay it was just very sure okay
can I please do the spells Roman what
are you casting for this priest casting
wind blast I need to get rid of this fog
you're freaking me out
like you guys are getting upset about a
thing they're gonna lose an actual spell
and it's gonna be bad that's way worse
than losing blue guy who would have just
got one hit by a winged fury okay
cast your role for blowing away the fog
18 all right you blow it away but not
all of it okay you get it like this
buddy there's a little bit of fog just
like hey but it's not on the blog's got
pushed into here but it's not gonna do
anything less somebody walks over there
uh Co you have another free spell yep
I'm gonna summon a earth Lord yeah
same command yeah okay and whose turn
was that that was still my turn was
Coast that was alright
oh that was off his element yeah gotcha
yeah his elemental disc oh now this
elemental I think he's just moving 1 2 3
4 5
what did you do on your turn 1 2 I do
anything yet he hasn't taken it yet it
was just direct contact now what are you
doing
all right I want to move five actually
before I move any summit and earthworks
okay okay there's another one and he'll
go move one two three four five and I'm
gonna move five away towards the 103
just a mgico like digging in the dirt
like just constantly just like hey all
right all of you get a free blade turn
trissur card really the card let's see -
one new source of damage for combat once
per combat number combat yeah so it's
like if you're gonna die you can not so
you do that I chose it I run away yeah
that's fine
well I mean it's like your turn but
anyway no you can't get out of combat oh
sorry is this a passive or is it just
like an immune you get to choose when to
use it
alright but and if when we use it is it
gone he's like one-time use no you keep
one for combats okay okay cool yeah
like say you're about to like take a
huge amount of damage you're like all
right blades here yeah all right cool
it's a single source of damage but for
example if he attacks you with a weapon
and you blocked the first one it
interrupts his ability to keep rolling
his weapons so if he tries to attack you
with that three hit combo it'll still
break the entire chain like if you stop
his ray of frost that eats up the ray of
Frost who he doesn't get the free turn
type of thing gotcha
all right it's his turn he's fun you
stop you stop it okay I'm gonna flip
them over flip them back
let me think like that's why I started
moving bodies just out of the way yeah
there's not a lot of space welcome let
me think
so it's now everybody else is gone it's
now dead bones sure yeah alright dead
bones it's your turn so I'm kind of
blocked in by these little fuckers
aren't I
yeah so I can really only just move up
like one space yeah
you can sell probably shimmy if you want
to go in and shimmy attack
I want hmm could I shoot me past and
then set up a blockade sure okay yeah
try that me a roll see if you see if I
can do with humble like a goofball oh
okay all right
just want to see if I can moose not like
I got a lot of do not love this Eclair
not really okay you try to push him but
he's like no my god this she's got this
guy's a choice tasteless duplicated you
can still block eight if you want yeah
oh they're deep okay now with the sister
yeah all right
this thing is annoying we're gonna rheya
frosted so he's gonna do a rare frost
it's gonna hit this green guy Dave and
this and it's gonna go into the fog but
it won't ignite the fog so we said
something like yeah come on I'm I'm way
cooler than you guy shooting at the ice
guy we're not doing that joke thing
that's that was last week only we're
getting really sorry the card 15 16 16
ko you either have to take 10 damage or
start sacrificing these pets do you want
to take ten damage for the earth guy now
five damage okay do you want to take
five damage for your little buddy yes
one one two three four five all right he
won't be stunned though because he's a
frost elemental what it makes sense
Dave is also gonna take five damage and
Dave's gonna be stunned one two three
four they've got Dave so dave is stunned
now he's gonna turn around and he's
gonna whirling blade down the screen guy
fifteen that's that's hit number one
he's gonna do it again he's gonna do it
one more time okay how much griot rehab
create is getting hit for the first
attack that he's hit by the second TAC
then one of these yellow spirits gets
killed then he's gonna work blaze so
he's gonna warp
he's warping out this this new army he's
heading towards these guys yeah so one
two three four five he thinks you guys
are insignificant
he wants the I need it I needed taunt
ability all right I showed him otherwise
yet before the end of his turn how far
up kind blink he's already kidding you
like once to see your blockading you
whoa oh yeah the period of time he's not
gonna just attacking you when there's
right right just you can blink ten
spaces I think yeah yeah I can get close
enough though right it's it's my turn
yeah why I wanted to he wanted to blink
before hit the other guys turned ended
oh you want to blink into a double turn
yeah okay yeah yeah all right so I'm
gonna blink here and I use like Worple
you got I didn't get a roll the fucking
tell blink first
oh yeah roll for the blink first sorry I
always forget that yeah it's man
wouldn't be great if you just blink when
everyone 20 so nice family cost for this
this is gonna give you two free turns oh
all right so three turns in a row now go
Justin all right well I'm gonna refer
them to give Co some stamina thanks
buddy
no problem alright now I'm gonna roll
for the vorpal off the blink the 4-pull
misses okay alright and then you have
three actions few action to move it in
action oh yeah let's say two moves three
actions to do it so you can be can
spaces after this
all right uh I'm gonna stay where I am
throwing a fireball at him yes holy yes
all right
he takes 20 damage or he would but he's
gonna win blast this whoo he's gonna try
and dodge no that's not as fun let me
read the wind blast guard wing blast
wind blast may also be used attempt to
dodge delay of harmful Texas dents
attacked with damage component although
Dragon Ball Z is so he's going to try to
dodge out of the way he's gonna blast
themselves behind those spirits it's
pretty cool and he's able to do it
however that is his move and that means
both go and throw man get a spell again
you've come another step and Kota
stamina and you get still heavy snow
some moves Justin oh my it in all this
madness you you're just right here right
now you like yeah that's the fireball
the fire button yeah sure right through
you it's two actions to to move through
blue up on the mountain but you gotta
burn it cuz we need to do third yeah the
rock just happened rollin what do you
want to do you're the other side of the
map but yeah the one thing I could
really do is spirit sprites rights
all right I'm yeah done more damage than
a critical fireball so far yeah oh
that's a heartbreaker Oh Roman you cast
these spirits so perfectly that they
just surround him just happening right
you guys you guys are just destroying my
encounters what happening cuz good all
right so hold on Roman you're gonna get
into the spell and so is Co but Co you
have to use the first one go what would
you like to do with your spell I going
to summon an earth for ya
it's just minions for days right now all
right your cousin earth Lord you popped
out Roman you now have another spell
what do you want to do again
just fucking swarming with them
szura get down how far away is the ice
guy from me Oh one two three four five
six seven eight nine like at least eight
or nine spaces away I want to grab my
Ruby yeah a little tiny hand comes and
grabs it yeah mad ume-chan fourteen okay
Roman grabs that Ruby let's go over here
and put it which ones you over here
Roman
all right fine fine more oh you can have
it you're letting it out of it I think
it's serious time on this encounter mr.
Frese fell from a twenty please alright
it's someone earth bored but you're
getting so excited with the amount of
earth words that you summative in the
water thinking he was a water spirits
he's like oh this is an ideal he's
another pool Lord you know right now it
is Justin's turn Justin you still have
two moves two actions to me arrow
actions yeah you want to do it twenty
that was all right next what are you
trying to do
alright I'm going to move here yep and
summer bleed why would you swim you're
through blade instead of doing like a
spell oh yeah good point
I'm gonna I'm going to uh look at me
Martin well if you get a fireball crit
he can't dodge because he's already used
as we sorted and I mean you'll get rid
of these spirits but it's 20 damage yeah
like Roman ain't gonna get one was just
cast these cos ezel in the back just
like this is the only thing I can do
right now so yeah no I'm storm rolling
rolling fire
we're going for it 300k you should shoot
a fireball it misses this spirit misses
him misses this spirit goes over here
blows up the fog boom boo-boom boo-boom
boo-boom
kills this earth lord oh I'm sorry go
alright taking my way too fast and then
you have one action left alright
ai-ai-ai-aight can still do a spell
right yeah you can still do this but was
that the fireball to hurt you kami no
your chili wizzy for a reason buddy used
a lot of fire smell all right you you
actually you completely shoot the wrong
way
shoot it towards this guy okay you've
blasting 420 he's gone
no fireballs miscast yes are great no no
it's the two Reds on the board there we
go hey I'm in a twenty on one did you
did zero um whatever
okay now go into my blade you're rolling
for your blade twelve okay you hit it
for two all right
I said ass to page oh yeah that's what
they said like okay it's crappy I keep
accidentally murdering games oh you were
like this last campaign okay
hobo now is finally the kobolds turn
Jesus Christ
all right he can't move so he's gonna do
he's gonna do ray of frost
oh I should do a second anyway yes maybe
you get a 20 Thanks all right so Rankin
from you um luckily Justin you have your
damn armor so you're only gonna take
four from this ten damage spell I'm also
stealing the ray of Frost you're not
serious and you to copy us so why don't
you go ahead and grab that from the deck
for me you get a copy of rain frost it's
gonna hit this guy though and he's now
knocked out man you guys just not doing
well for these guys I mean we never do
well for how lies apparently yeah okay
so he's gonna have to start swinging at
these things but he's seen three
fireballs coming from you Justin he's
coming through good buddy so he's gonna
swing his first melee weapon at this
spear in front of you of Romans tank
spirits he's gonna snap it and then he's
going to move whoa
you want to ask if I want to absorb it
oh yeah deserve it would you like to
absorb for three damage actually this is
a good point you might actually want to
absorb it to prevent it from leaving I
think you okay so he it's what I think
your III attack sorry what sorry I'm
just saying I think you deleted that one
and then he moved one that was above in
front of him the air spray I mean yeah I
don't not following I don't he killed
him he killed a sprite right and Roman
was gonna well no no yeah Roman kill
this price is the one that would be
getting hit no I know but you deleted
the one that was there and then you
moved one that was was so there was yeah
all right
Roman do you want to take the hit
remember this Pierce's anyway so it's
gonna hit Justin and it's gonna hit that
guy you're not gonna be able to stop it
okay I'm good with that I don't want to
take it yeah I just wanted to be asked
really yeah I'm sorry I care about
Alexander and you're just like deleting
them off the board as if it doesn't
anything okay
moves forward okay let's do this so
attack number two with the wind Theory
Justin gets hit little devils go to jail
and then number so just Justin's taking
three and then he's gonna warp late now
Justin takes another three and he's
gonna work blade right behind you
yeah why is he bringing so far wing one
two three don't even notice it on just
two why am I taking health away from him
whoops
one two three one two three took health
away from him instead Justin almost
damage the boss four six great okay so
that is his turn now it is the end
people its NPC yeah okay so in range in
range in range Dave's getting out of
this stunt fuck if they was stunned he's
a boss Dave's coming up pushing these
elementals on the way Dave is going to
cast holy light on Justin oh thanks sexy
big heels Justin gets healed for 12 1
through 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12
just as levels for full help from that
three spell blades so we're gonna blue a
red and a yellow red so that's a flare a
ray of frost and a ray of frost all
right ray of frost number one misses it
doesn't hit anybody just misses
number two
mrs. now the flare
he's specializing the flare to blind
hits him flare only does one damage but
on this on his next turn he's gonna be
blinded thanks umm what else is left for
NPCs I think that's it yes okay so now
it is Romans turn if you okay so let's
go first for you they're supposed to be
at the end then move in that really
complicated so if you want these just to
go I should say yes because you never
know what's gonna happen
yeah what's that the spirits go okay so
let's just move them they're gonna just
in case yes really
help horn off to just they just try
they're just trying to like dog you pile
this guy for you so there's four that
can attack so let's just go with four so
what for damage
one for three four and down now whatever
you want to do okay
now chat might wonder why did I do a
separate role because there'd be more
20s will one that would make these
spirits ridiculous Roman and ko would
just both get these things and just
stand all they're just summoning them
because they're just be so many natural
20s that roll yeah so for all these
little minions we always just roll one
and then kind of try to calculate what
it would have done based on those the
only accepts fact the only exception is
sometimes like earth giants and stuff
when they're going through they got to
run through a fog or something like that
that creates a scenario which is bonus
20s and stuff
[Music]