[Music]
all right so chat managed to give you
guys two extra piece of loot so there's
gonna be three items treasure time this
treasure time hmm nice well I know spore
I don't wanna get one for being leader
they got you boy yeah
two extra one plus two oh sorry I
thought you sitting up so here's your
demos you are the leader so you will
decide who gets what
all right core smell Veronica let it
rights you got a blood drinker it's a
melee weapon and when you you every time
you hit it with it it heals phenomenal
oh you get a weekly bi-weekly
so that's gonna be poker that's gonna be
phones potions and then there's the
Hartwell locket which anytime you're an
ally rules critical you may regenerate
one stamina to a player of your choosing
yeah Wow should be like oh I can't yeah
one for this week elite key I want to
miss Wiggly wench into two rejuvenation
potions there the one thing I think
he'll right
yeah well then begin kills yeah 15
stamina on the car wasn't updated it's
no longer limit one okay it's supposed
to be different but for this for today
it doesn't cost an action and it just
restores 15 stamina okay yeah so two of
those for the wiggly wench um Justin
mmm-hmm here's the locket you have you
earned that locket you heard that you
you know what Justin your lieutenants
huh Wow lieutenant Justin well what is
Justin this was feena's do lieutenant
Justin and Co I killed my cowboy yeah
look Co I know I know you killed a boss
you're kind of like what was all that
with your thoughts Co what well I was
gone I I've got a pizza and beer party
on the way to so you bring it way to
obligate ahead okay
prefect refers okay you know what okay
go theta
go would you like this knife do you want
this dagger yes please Co give Co the
dagger okay thank you
and Roman you get a burnt and decayed
corpse of your brother all right
chorus of I know it's it's fine
whoo - good blood drinker did Abby ko
ko' took it we did see your brother
yeah I didn't know Cisco do you actually
want this or would you rather have two
healing potions yeah you can change it
like that's the solemn control one
quickness isn't it you can trade yeah I
can have one quickest or two potions now
I think I think the blade is interesting
lying on it okay well I mean it's just
you're very rarely ever gonna do a melee
attack right cuz you're you're if he has
it's also not now my hat and what if he
loses all my magic why would we go yeah
if he loses all his magic sure but why
would co ever use a blood drinker on his
turn instead of just life training
slight dream sucks okay alright fine
I'll take two I'm just trying to look at
or you guys can fly to the first fluffy
meat counter if you take a quick so you
get the two actions for it so that's
true so yeah get to life drains that
might be worth it this would be well
it'd be eight no because yay
cuz he's only gonna get healing of two
for his uh which we called in no I'll
take the potions potion sounds good cool
thanks I'm Sally okay guys could
couldn't find your brother Owen um so we
did this for new he's alive no idea
where he is but you're good show
everybody at meet Justin Justin I am I'm
very very pleased with you Justin you
did a very good job
lieutenants Justin you - she sure does
look up to it Co you're you're on your
way you're on your way cup your boss
there you're gonna get there soon
yeah thanks excited you're working your
way up Roman Roman do what Roman do you
plan fearing the knowledge that you
diluted to a goblin or just say that's
not important it doesn't mean anything
to me just some goblin I put about water
whatever how's that it's not even
significant right good so we've not
believed it leadership yeah well I'm not
pleased with you in any way so there's
that oh I'm sorry I'm just busy killing
bosses and stuff I mean coke killer you
go to the ball you want to go in ball
formation yeah hide yeah yeah great whoa
so was there anything left of this guy
beerus was safe uh his brother i have no
idea
she's probably do we see a new roommate
what we check that we should probably
check that out meanwhile uh two spirits
have finally returned with a beer use of
evoke
a beer in pizza for co-pays when I walk
up and they just kind of like turn into
the pile of mud spilling the beer on the
ground I'm not go deliver the pizza the
pizza just falls flat face-first into
the turf of the girl that's watch game
five second roll god damn it
okay let's delete it hey wait
Roman Roman there's your treasure
probably just pick up the pizza original
treasure ha ha ha
next ancient for more mud yeah it's cool
banister I don't care if you have my mud
pizza beer sleep goes okay with barring
stir and I'll take it ruin puts a soggy
piece of pizza and throw to dead bones
and a mug okay go over that please I get
a reaction role in this no row Romo is
throwing the muddy piece of pizza at
dead bones
excellent work now you get the twining
uh would you guys like to cast a spell
Oh started excellent 20 use of the 20
there Ruben yeah excellence money room
yeah I want a cast grand ravenclaw on
dead bones and gets it back up and throw
it I just want to pick him up and shake
him
so I'm gonna ask this his froman's
attacking me does that consider him an
ally ha ha ha
I'm simply picking you up he's
aggressively doing something look shut
up pizza face okay you got a piece of
pizza on your face you've been sucking
around Roman now only has a piece of
luck hey guys hurry look at leader pizza
face I'm gonna just wipe it off
goddamn it Roman can't wipe off the name
the kids face no well well well those
Romans brother is not here he must have
been further further along
Roman do you remember feel like where
your brother may have wanted to go like
what he might have wanted to be doing
today he he wanted to fight orcs
porks ports are but yeah and I don't
slip of the tongue uh it's that's all I
know is he just was so excited to try
and fight porks so you know but is about
the question fighting folks is easy
Eve's here it does he know how to do
like the equivalent of you fighting
porks he's probably the ball somewhere
so you know he's probably doing a better
job than you right now is he alive
it's a shame if he's dead anyway we have
actual work to do this is Annette this
wasn't even part of our job this is we
got a poop we've got to go meet the
frist roll wagon but that was a mate
task this guy's grown I don't even start
Justin
you made the now you don't heat your
handle just was your fault just as our
biggest problem I mean just one man's
fault is under man uh dude there's three
elves lying around here I think maybe we
should loot them before we go you know
what you can take whatever you find on
the bodies and give them to me and then
we'll divvy them out if you want don't
really care all right but just know that
it's gonna come off your pay but it's
okay we'll just I can we we can blue out
there unconscious one of them one of
them was decapitated one of them is
heads don't even easier he's not gonna
talk okay no one's gonna know go go loot
them if you want
don't let don't let bearings to touch
bodies folk man like this is pretty
pretty cold to just walk up and try to
loot the dead decapitated person that
just killed it just have utilities
remorse from killing a fellow elf ha I
mean I feel horrible that it happened
but I mean I 100% didn't mean to do it
so now's an accident in battle ok
alright let's check out this unconscious
headless body
ok go ahead and roll
all right on the body you find a bag of
52 silver and three gold pieces you find
this kind of that off you find a
hankerchief with what looks like to be a
number but it can't possibly be a film
number and this looks like some sort of
like you know like where they where they
live or some sort of weird number and
then it says since since since is
Cynthia on it with like a kissy thing
what's a phone yeah no that's why I said
it can't be a phone because the phone is
what it's the it's the abbreviation for
your how can I like how can I know what
a knocking is okay exactly yes it's your
uh two coordinates oh my god number two
kiss repays and like lips someone kissed
it oh yeah that's what that elf I'm
about to have you find rabies if you
keep pull pushing my buttons here mr.
Kubik booster that's right you better
walk on that screen so what's the girl's
name is cilia you you know usually what
you say just gonna take you you do so
get it up and it's got a nice pair of
leather boots like they're they're very
they're very feminine but I mean elves
like that style on their males so you
know it looks they looks you think they
look fuckin badass just suddenly there's
some nice red key leather boots heal and
they have they have some felt trim or
wrong the top like some fuzzy at the top
yeah you decide to take those as well so
you have to boots you don't decide to
wear them I guess I mean you can put
them on if you want but they're not your
size so that's all a fine
so Eric um want to sprinkle some dirt
over them under the unconscious body
yeah on this guy's just thinking why for
what what they were loading a dead body
what are you doing well I have this one
oh that one this one okay I'm just yeah
so lean dead bones you're gonna walk
over there and watch them or you're just
gonna stand over here Billy nope
I'm just like whatever I don't care I'm
gonna track you not gonna make area
mistress wrinkle all right roll em guy
roll dice to sprinkle some dirt on them
nothing better God Alvin Alvin burial
thing it's alright you successfully
sprinkle dirt on the elf nice roll
sprinkle the shit up you're at a comment
repulser hug go ahead eat
yep ha ha ha wriggle dah yeah I want to
walk over it he's this guy's unconscious
is he unconscious yeah he's gonna cold
I'm just gonna slap him around a bit try
and wake him up not searched give a roll
oh yeah
Thank You dice alright uh you slap him
around but you accidentally kind of just
slap him in the balls
okay that's gonna wake him up yeah you
gotta kind of confused like you were
just going to try and pat him on the
thigh right you're just like hey money
you're gonna pat him on the thigh but he
kind of rolled over while you were doing
it and you just slammed him in the nuts
and he's kind of like oh he's just kind
of in pain whimpering now you can tell
you're off his feet that's the important
part
he's still alive though yeah okay still
alive just checking just checking he's
he's just on the floor
he's like why why did you do this just
to make sure he was still alive Saul
what did you do to my tent we are beyond
your control you guys didn't help at all
II just so you know a meteor hit that
tent wasn't doubtful that was this fire
spirit sounds nothing to do what L say
you can't pop I don't see him because
he's like down here yeah I know that's
why I'm looking down see every couple of
ticks I look down he's down here okay so
well uh so the rest of you guys come
back up after I don't know some sort of
burial service to remember the dagger
and looting is easy Dave the guy did you
die assume you knew him maybe did you
know him is my friend anybody know this
guy everybody know his name yeah it was
Dave now kid all the elves can't be
named Dave except this one I think was
actually named Davey that you call that
one either yeah Davey Davey yeah dahveed
I have no anybody else soon okay does
leave a headless corpse without a little
bit of dirt on it
yeah I have no idea what the dirts for
that was really is that like a thing you
do respect no officer you know with the
no place my apologies yeah oh you guys
just you know flea people out there
wolves like savages man it's really hard
to understand noble robots speak anyway
anyway we've got to meet up with the
patrol wagon we've actually got to meet
Co you're gonna be really excited for
this okay we're gonna kill me Dave Dave
he's the one that controls the patrol
wagon I don't really care about like any
of these Dave's but this oh you'll like
this Dave this Dave's great are we gonna
say it I mean you'll get sure here
that's why I'm excited let's go yes Jen
and Justin come along she'll just do
lieutenant bumming I watts PA isn't
looting I'm gonna air them captain
though dead bones I don't think we had
an agreement
I don't think we tend entirely happen is
it oh it isn't the Elven or not sure
knows it definitely is the Elven order
yeah lieutenant Sabbath captain dead
bones asked you to a lieutenant and he's
a private okay well no the other guy's
gotta be privates no their recruits a
private call what's a cool
second-in-command name that you've
associated that you with Justin yeah and
a title to support a chilly willy
corporal okay yeah that can't easily not
like in the Corporal UV below captain
that's yeah well just go to the
hierarchy it's fine yeah all right maybe
saying leftenant
Hey okay um we've had our differences
I'm willing to put it behind us and work
together because we we got to kill these
porks men okay I'd find my brother and
find your breath and find your book
what if he's fighting the porks how I
don't want him dead
do you know how bad that look at my
report a dead kid that's like I might
get demoted by the circle back to Corp I
don't want to be a cop anyway if we find
your brother than we kill the porks and
we do our Patrol I'll double your pay
huh huh I'll double your pay
yeah we good poor girl get to go what we
got him they're dead he's got what the
porks no Coco those are bigger they're
pigs go brother that's not my brother
there you just curious
all right well at least we can have a
barbecue party it is all right in the
middle of this one yeah yeah well you
guys are talking about pay oh my god yes
ja a goblin flips over the bridge and
falls flat on his face combat hasn't
started but it's kind of embarrassing
I'm really intimidated this book can I
roll for how hard I'm laughing in the
Scout these days yeah you may roll to
see how hard you've left at this Kevin
Foley let's see all right uh you're
gonna good hearty laugh it's pretty
amazing I was damaged due to you know
you actually have a laughable remember
if you have a lesson I'd like to do that
again I talk you can actually just do
this okay so I'm gonna approach the
Goblin I'm just I'm just gonna kick it
hey you alive okay buddy
yeah oh oh yes yes yes sir I'm fine mr.
elf would you like to buy some of my
wares I have so many many cool things
you love him yes I I sell I thought
you're listen to him but what do you say
it has no
no don't try to attack me what no honor
no no I have tons of honor trust me my
name is Justin I have nobody
however everybody surround him just
doing it like in a circle around a
mystery talk to the combat majestic
combat is started yeah we're just
circled is little dude's house got
attacking Oh clothes gonna be yeah he's
gonna be the shit you know
okay ready go ahead bye all right uh all
right let's fight this no do I get to do
that or do we have to go in order I know
you'll start out your turn that's how
we'll do it
okay also are we feeling fine now or I
guess yep feeling cool all right
um you guys took River if want to see
for else beat up Club
racially I'm uh I'm gonna hit him with
my oaken step right in the face
okay eleven you smacked the red goblin
with the oaken staff for two damage yeah
he goes out uh technically you did would
like we have to go through the combat
phase do you actually want to
participate in the beating of the
Cullens goblins are scum layer punch him
yes we're national pastime flair punch
enjoy
all right the Goblin is gonna you
interrupt that with wind blast oh shit
yeah the goblins gonna use wind blast
himself so I'm sure yeah and he is going
to win blast straight up that's a Dodge
move right you have it to dog uses a
mini blast and he goes right into the
water just humph just not what I
intended to do but he's now in the water
like I'm belly laugh
we can just go on we can just okay
Justin tries to laugh but also falls
into the water uh can I roll to see how
hard I laugh at that yeah sure yeah yeah
Chuck ah
oh man Chuck Justin's the same color as
the water it's hard to see oh oh there
we go
I was weird okay um so now it's thick to
the Gobles turn uh the gulls the gobbles
gonna try and jump back up he's gonna
try and move back up here real quick
getcha pop in the water there we go Wow
the Goblin comes up and does a barrel
roll and he's gonna throw a smoke bomb
at you guys
shit is he supposed to use that on
himself no way arrow smoke ball here
site yeah no no no what up okay Romans
interrupting go to site yeah ox he's
looking you in the eye yeah okay you
near-sighted the Goblin this isn't gonna
affect the smoke blast though he's now
nearsighted cuz he sucks you just throw
it Shh won't hunt or the rug okay oh uh
nobody can see the Goblin anymore
however Roman notices he's missing his
Ruby uh Deborah all notices he's missing
a spell ward Harbor
what oh there's no way you can steal out
an armored up so just how yeah I'm in
the water unit stuff it oh you good
point you're missing you're missing your
mace okay nothing to see I don't and uh
KO's missing is what he got go your bid
wishing mirror okay treasure is missing
Justin you're not missing anything but
all your items are currently wet do we
know that I think hmm
did we do so are we noticing now that
they're missing that's that's us
noticing it they're gone yeah the smoke
bomb goes off and so he's kind of like
looked around here like huh and you're
like what and then you somebody says
something somebody says like I'm missing
such-and-such then you go home being - I
miss would look nice it would be much
funny if you're missing your armor by
the way you could have been third in
there be like so now we got my army yes
had not though I'm not gonna allow that
to happen
yo Bannister it's time to get windy up
in this bitch yo yeah use your bling -
Ron it's your turn Roman change okay so
I know the stuff is missing and I just
still asleep oak in front of me yeah hmm
[Applause]
all right I will use a wind blast but
can I do it so it doesn't do damage just
does the wind yeah okay I just I don't
want to shoot it directly out in front
of me I want to brush all that smoke
away and potentially not the Goblin it's
the water again well I don't want to any
damage though I just want to do and us I
mean would not go back coming water back
that's surprisingly enough less
concerned about you guys after y'all
just try to uh throw a beat down on some
goblin who just showed up I wasn't happy
with a guy that isn't me we need to like
surround him and just start like
physically a salty dump you should know
that goblins are just the scum of the
earth
that's what elves do when they see
goblins man yeah goblins are just he
must not be Thanks all right uh Roman
doesn't win blast
he kind of gusts like dead bones his
face which were which actually helps it
removes some of that pizza that was
still Nate's organically they blow dryer
you blow them away all of the smoke bomb
but the Goblin is no longer there and
you could see the Goblin on the rocks
and he's basically grabbing his junk and
flipping you the bird
they Godwin has basically run off but
he's over we can see him yeah he's over
on the rocks might iron no all right I'm
going to rather I'm gonna grab him with
my grand ravenclaw and try to drown the
shit
love it
oh all right
uh-oh tries to grab a goblin with the
Raven claw but he doesn't in the wrong
order and he said he grabs himself and
he throws himself on like into the water
as well so now you're the waters go if
you did in the wrong order you're like
alright first I summon the claw and then
I do this but instead you said all right
first I grab myself with the cloth then
I throw myself weight and then you're
the water um whose turn is it it's a
dead build sir so deadlines to improv is
a girl in the water gobbles on the rocks
trying to make a break for it he's got
my mace so I'm gonna move your move up
here have a quick query yes go um
there's a one a critical it's a critical
fail it is a critical failure it's a
critical failure but it doesn't it
doesn't count for the elves no all right
just Rock oh that would be interesting
to put that on the elves for both
failures and criticals it would make
them yeah sure I anyway I'd like that
but we'll see I'm gonna I'm gonna just I
miss some amazed I'm just gonna throw
this my fucking flare at this guy okay
maybe should cast a flare at him oh yeah
throw it it's like a spell 15 1 2 3 4 5
you smack the Goblin like you leaving a
visible burn on his face he's gonna be
scared life from the burn and he fought
any of like tumbles back into the water
you look better now
so for standing on these tiles as long
as you're on the rock we can consider
you're either on the rock and if as long
as you're touching the water
we'll use if you're upside down to be in
the water okay okay upside down you're
in the water but as long as you're
touching a rock you can be standing on
it and it's Justin Justin you better
beat that thing down just you kind of
fell you're you got up you're still like
snickering a little bit cuz man that was
funny but everybody's kind of panicking
and yelling it at to get the Goblin so
alright and I'm okay I'm not I'm like a
flute I'm just kinda chillin here yep
you have so many goats on ya cuz the
goats yeah you float cuz the coats yeah
are the old the old coat and flat field
come flood stricken quick thing right so
uh yeah you need some stamina me real
quick
Oh like released and what did you do
breaky casted rape I did yeah
Ravenclaw's so 2 and then I have yeah
yeah I got it get it alright so can I
could I jump onto one of these rocks yep
alright and I see I see the goblin
drowning there like I see him in the
water upside that drowning he's just
he's like treading water he just liked
out over the water he's trying to get
back on the rock so he's right blinded
he's right in front of you like you
could kick him in the face type of thing
I'm gonna throw my throw fireball at him
it was quite slick fire over guns just
really hates gun could reach in and get
our stuff he's gonna shoot hahaha it's
not gonna break I'm just like I break my
mace oh man maybe he's got a little Ruby
maybe chilli busy thinks the Cobell the
gobbles cold you know what he wants that
you know he saw he saw a dead bones his
work with a scar he was thinking of a
matching today he wants to even it out
as a pilot that happen was for a
fireball right in his face alright so
Justin goes the cast of fireball and
completely misses um where you shoot
this fireball you just shoot it into the
waterfall just it goes in the water
phone that goes all right dice look at a
free melee attacker that you bet you
smell ice horribly if you fail to cast
it you just wipe them out of existence
oh you still hit him and you hit him for
to damage and that's enough to kill him
woo yeah the guy but however the goblins
and the water so and all your treasure
is currently sticking to the bottom just
the granite he's not dead he's just
unconscious in the water like drown
are we out of combat no we're still in
combat because the the key is browning
we still need to know turns to see who
gets the loot and stuff okay a new
problem can I uh can I temp to grab him
uh no because that was your action um
okay so now it is the good goblins turn
but
what is ahead you why not a goblin right
uh you've awakened the the whisper snake
of Emerald Lake lon
so the whisper snake of Emerald Lake
pops up over here you shouldn't be this
big he's little he's like that yeah he
pops up over here and he like romo
doesn't even see him sneak up actually
romancey to see if you see this guy
sneaking up on you perception role isn't
gonna have room and see if that sees the
whisper snake coming animal
it's like real D&amp;D um nope Roman does
not see it coming uh the snake comes up
whispers in Romans ear and then goes
under the water nobody saw nothing okay
nobody saw nothing Roman had his ear his
ear whispered we're gonna see if this
gob but his goblin is currently
unconscious and he's drowning but we're
gonna give him a survival role or else
I'm gonna have to kill him Oh God oh
okay know that the Goblin is this goblin
is going to is drowned to death like he
he goes in and he's just unconscious
he's not going to be able to wake up so
your treasure is now sinking to the
bottom of this lake grab it well no it's
Romans turn and so it's Roman it's your
turn all right I'm gonna move no you're
not combat you're gonna stay here you're
gonna go back to where you are how Roman
whoever whoever the whisper snake
whispers to you become mind-controlled
for that turn so you are going to have
to play anti-party for this turn if I
don't like what you did and I don't
think it's anti-party enough I'm gonna
play for you so whoever whoever is
whispered each turn has to play for that
part play for the member okay okay
okay I'm gonna win blast dead bones okay
I like it
okay we're pretty in tight pretty any
party I was like I get throw them in
there I'm like wait I could throw them
in there and do damage yeah
uh and since we didn't see him get
whispered so this is just an act of
aggression from Roman yeah it's just act
of aggression
just wait when Romans mind-controlled is
he counting as an enemy towards me
that's a six so it's not gonna do any
damage Roman um but it's gonna send him
flying on the rocks Devils a sneeze why
are you asking for it is Romans mind
controlled is he an enemy do I get the
spell nope he's still an ally damn it
you don't even know he's dead to me you
just think he's being an asshole
especially doing damage just pushed you
role to see if you land on the rock or
if you're going into the water what a
roll call are you Oh 14 I'm an elf man
I'm pretty nimble
all right you land right on the rock
okay damn it Roman SoCo it's your turn
you're in the water
what you don't realize it that there's
something going on the only person who
possibly could realize it was Roman a
still my natural this turn but I do
realize about the guy you realize about
the Goblin and you do realize that your
loot sinking to the bottom so you won't
know how far down like if I swim over
and try to pull him up to get the loot
yeah is that gonna be better than like
trying to use grand ravenclaw to grab
his father years oh no grand ravenclaw
would be way better to grab his body
like a hundred percent like let's say
let's say he's now sunk you know six to
ten feet yeah try to carry him out of
the water it's not gonna be you could
ravenclaw uh give me a roll I actually
give me a roll I want to see how well
this swimmer you are oh no I just want
to know for its roller future role for
future swimming of capability uh oh you
you're a good swimmer you probably
could've deal with water but I love
doing moves and shit I would still
recommend a grand Raven's claw if you
actually want to give me any water
safely somebody move up onto the Roger
glide over here are you going on this
rock yeah I would already be on the rock
keep their office and I'm gonna try to
grab the body with Grande Ravens claw
fucking shits all right a user grab
Raven's claw and you try to get out of
the water but you grab nothing instead
you pull up some seaweed
so you have a handful of seaweed and
because you had commanded the claw to
come to you you drop all the seaweed on
your head so now you're just covered in
wet seaweed oh my god yeah is now dead
bones turn dentals you saw him try to
like it this would have been like the
claw game at like yeah yeah any arcade
where you try to get the seasons fail
yeah uh I got I don't have anything I
can really do sighs okay with my turn
but Roman just hit you so why don't you
give a perception check to see if you
think okay
messing about or the Romans or is it
something Arcana check percent right you
think it's just Roman being an asshole
but yeah design doesn't change it you
think Romans being an asshole
yeah can I like to hold my turn or not
just gotta wait I mean you just you just
kind of have to wait if it just got a
skip it there's nothing I do you try you
try again get all things that also Roman
you're an asshole what's that now I know
okay so justin is there anything you
want to try to get it the waters I might
wait do I have any chance to get this
guy out of the water cuz I don't think
I'm any suppose I could really sit in
here do you have any spells that you can
actually use fireball fireball blue is
blazing freeze the water and then we'll
just cut it I could wait or you could
dive in and then blink out okay well
that's uhmm I will uh it's risky but
I'll give a shot just at first
give me a roll for how will you swim so
you're dying to know I want to know if
you're good with three coats 50 coats oh
boy Justin just let you know you can't
swim
okay yeah you barely got in that rock
once before and that was just cuz the
life coats but when you were in the
water you had a full-on panic attack any
time you were in water from now on you
are gonna lose your fucking mind you're
gonna be mental about it alright
oh sorry guys I'm really so yeah you
wouldn't even try you're actually kind
of panicking right now because you don't
know how you're gonna get back over the
bridge
your main concern main concern is to get
back over here now so all right anything
you would try to blink onto the bridge
yeah yeah I that yeah I'm going for it
that sounds like something I would do
freaking out yeah okay you're freaking
out and you blink but you don't blink
actually on the bridge you blink onto
like the edge you like so imagine you're
standing on it you're standing on like
your tippy toes
so you're like almost worried you're
about to fall back to it whoa and then
like the cards like now give me a roll
to see if you can actually move on to
the bridge or fall into the water
Oh hahaha oh boy so you fall back into
the water
you're trying to like claw back on
you're panicking you're fine cuz you're
in a life preserver face yeah he's
floating he's just not happy about
looking my series of coats
hey any and at this point Romans mind
control breaks Roman are you gonna yell
at anyone that you like something's
weird
did you notice anything no I didn't
notice anything okay we have aggression
towards dead bones that didn't really
feel that it wasn't - it was just like I
just feel like doing yes okay ko would
have been looking at this dead bones is
watching him Roman was still
mind-controlled the snake underneath the
bridge is gonna go up to Justin and
whisper in his ear
and again uh is there anyone who could
have noticed I don't think anyone's even
looking now and I don't forget the
Goblin dead bones gonna give you can
have a perception role just to see you
yeah did I notice on Justin fall energy
you might have saw from fallen sea but I
looked back Oh God doing the whole boom
sees it
dead boom sees it Denney just like me
his spells uh yes it is
Oh Deb bows not only sees it but when he
points out it the whisper snake just
completely comes out of the water now to
emerge yourself so Roman season hits
ease it just an easy absolute terror yes
fuck am I still fine he's mined it up
your kit okay never mind your mind
control yeah hey guys you're actually in
the whole time right hey quick cast
spells yeah yes you will however because
of this role great bones you can have a
turn this is a free turn in the
necessary turns turn yeah okay for free
try I'm just gonna throw flare at it
like just nothing else I can really do
that my mace uh yeah
thirteen okay um do Coen Roman get
featured you hit him for five and then
two free spells here
yeah Roman Co light him up Go Go Roman
uh when blast okay you're gonna win
Weston holy shit dude what Roman you go
to win blast but you shoot the air in
the wrong direction sending yourself
flying Roman tell me for you land on a
rock if you're going right through the
water
I need a roll also I brought sound
rolling the dice over here so I'm not
looking across the man for you guys
there you go thank you
alright I'll let you land on a rock
right here Roman
ouch hey you so you accidentally did it
but you managed to recover and pretend
that that was for skill code in order to
do a spell now alright I'm gonna help
I'm gonna try to Raven's claw the Goblin
body that's getting my mirror back
alright you managed to pull the goblins
up coat you rent you look through the
Goblin over here you currently have all
three treasures okay sweets obviously
people are gonna want the back but
that's like deadly things just mace
Roman doesn't have his Ruby and you have
the Ruby right now hey real quick yeah
guys I'm starting a shop I forgot about
my heart roll locket
can I yeah nice can I still heal someone
for one stem from that critter alert yes
yeah alright yet what does dead bones as
Oh like your bull rightfully oh no I
just do one from the broiler they're
missing some health all right Roman
Roman yes ma'am okay really gets one
stamina that was from before yeah
nice anyway thanks buddy Tazi Playa
flails in the water I'm like oh okay
I think he's flinging energy at us okay
it's now uh who strin yeah well that was
my free turn on the twenty roll sand it
had just whispered in Justin's ear so
it's a Libra moment er yeah yeah
no man it's your turn okay okay um can I
use I'll use Raven's claw and I want to
get Justin out of the water okay
yep go ahead and roll help the dice guys
over it's here next to it oh wow that
thing right we just we just keep it in
the area easier Memphis 15 okay where do
you want to put him you can put a
tactically ten spaces so basically okay
um I want to put him up on the bridge
cuz I've seen him struggle in the water
I don't want him dealing with rocks okay
just so right here place except for the
bridge so with my perception aligned
note whispering in Justin's ear do you
just notice the snake you have no idea
that there's a lot on your mind control
effects going on and Roman did the wind
blast like Roman must know that
something weirds going on but he hasn't
said anything just yet so it's probably
Justin's gonna be the one that alerts it
it's gonna be obvious once Justin goes
anti-party here okay so code is your
turn so King so get mine from going from
rock to rock here you're gonna have to
do a jump role for your move okay
and if you miss you're gonna fall so
keep that in mind to us know you can but
if you want to move from rock to rock
ever dead bones you're gonna have to
okay okay yeah okay so alright well then
I'm just gonna swim since I'm an awesome
swimmer so I'm gonna Ruby over here we
you're gonna leave the water on this
thing okay yep yeah I was he's taking a
be okay seeing an extra money mister
alright now I'm gonna be like hey check
out my sweet mirror nice okay yeah
that's a good use
it okay you you open up the mirror to
try and trap the target within it but
the Mears effect is not strong enough so
it doesn't do anything to the mirror it
kind just goes G and then it closes fuck
look right now thanks Alex oh you know
it didn't work I move over here I guess
it's like a pokeball dude yeah things
have to be wounded especially if they're
big fucking emerald snakes okay all
right I don't know I had to try
I know um okay so then ko moves over
here with the use of Romans Ruby
Devlin's is your turn remember you do
not have a mace your face to swim
yeah my mace just swam away but I can
still just I'm just gonna keep I'm just
gonna throw another flare okay this is
pretty much all he really can do you
know make sense
oh nice flare you hit him for 5 1 2 3 4
[Music]