[Music]
welcome everybody to uh forgot Valve's
live whoo hey yeah well yeah wait on
that one hey I hope you guys are ready
for another good show we have a lot of
fun stuff planned this week and man did
we just like get right into it or do we
have to like talk about something is
there anything I feel like there should
be some kind of warm-up how do you do
that right you got a show for I think
like a merchandise or something we want
oh yeah if unless you've been here for
over an hour in which case you've I just
want to refresh your stream real quick
below there's buttons for if you want to
donate if you want to support the show
also we have a blender brochure so if
you're the tech person who still wants
to support us and you'd like a shirt we
have that too
so please however you guys like as long
as you guys like this along as people
want to support this we're going to keep
doing it so the cool blunderbuss shirt
we got some cool cool events this week I
read you guys loud and clear and we're
try them this week we have positive
events now I have not listed all of the
events so you will understand if they
are positive or negative but generally
you can tell and if I trick you that's
also still really fun and funny as well
as we're going to after every every time
they beat a major part of the campaign
so they go through a major battle the
word now I'm now going to give them one
credit card and the leader of the group
will distribute the treasurer card if
you guys would like and you you know you
just don't like the negative stuff but
you want to see them get more and more
powerful we also have a bonus loot thing
and you guys can make it so they're up
to 4 treasure cards in which case the
leader will decide who gets what
treasure and technically dead bones
could just take all the treasure for
himself how answered can I can I just
say oceans yeah
don't forget that Wow Wow Wow um as well
as thanks to Co much to Roman's dismay
we have this new system on the table
which makes it so they have an inventory
cap
that's whatever this is however many
cards you get down here you can't carry
any more room and you have to throw
things away now I love my voice on that
but it's a lot skilled at folding like
you know fol de maua vita at cards fold
on top you'll probably end up being less
room because I'll probably expand this
bottom area to have more things that I
store in I've particularly out I'll fix
that
Oh actually I love the side it's got
nice for to I'll get rid of that open
space there got nice Sheen to it I'm
sorry uh ko you're buzzing why you
buzzing oh I'm sorry Mike sposa no
sinner me I thought I was buzzing I was
like oh no my head's gonna die oh it's
okay he's a he's a BL if he's a bell oh
okay so this week we're following a
group of elves we're in this city what's
the city name dead bones Dannevirke
danav er thanks
yeah they're the city and it's being the
city currently has a bunch of they have
a pork problem around the outskirts of
the cities they have these nasty little
pig works that are getting in the way of
you know daily elf to elf business and
so we're to start today by good old dead
bones here waking up at bed you know oh
you just yeah you're just getting out of
the bed just getting out of bed widen
more no I don't have a yawn emote oh
okay let's hear like you're on there oh
you know what wait wait hold on dibbles
oh they can see you what can't they see
you they can't see me yeah how can they
see anybody no no I mean like can't see
Papa bells so hold on ah
okay well then well begin the visible
adventures of puppet pals after that
really good you're on again I'm pretty I
was really just I said this so so you uh
you meditate in bed dead box huh
now we say guys I have to see some
behind the scenes stuff
straight-up we sleep are you meditate
while you sleep no we saw everyone's
going nuts I was obviously really say I
don't know what the sleep thing are we
haven't confirmed for don't sleep it's
just confirmed I sleep
I don't know I sleep well taking a nap I
was sleeping man Yesi dead bug sleep
dead that was a good one is the first
elf and he just oh you could or you can
establish that Nobel's meditate and you
know doesn't the commoner folk actually
sleep boom double stones oh okay there
we go that should be all Republic should
we all repeat or you gotta get out we
gotta do it over again you gotta come
back commune up gotta check out a start
from the scratch okay do over from the
top right from the top okay right three
two one action there you go no then
it'll go back go back over quick right
you came out before I said action okay
okay three two one Ackman okay that's
just that's just hey oh okay back off
back off come on guys get right Gary
three two one acting that's a guy voice
yeah I didn't say action I said acting
but I don't know who Simon Says
okay I know actin tinactin shut up okay
so uh dead bones you're waking up in a
bed okay say it smother find a what do
you do in the morning like how do you
how do you go about your day what's the
first thing you do is that was your
character's name again Carol Correll was
Carell do in the mornings uh you know
she probably gets up I don't know what
it was do them on to eat probably eat
right
probably ate okay yeah get ready elves
eat I was easy to establish so wanted to
why don't we go for a walk over here
you're gonna pass the innkeeper you want
to say hello or you type of guys just
gonna like stub the innkeeper wait I
mean I'm I I'm in an inn I don't live
here no no no this is this is a city
your corner just like patrolled in your
patient in so you know that you just
took the Utes you like when you got here
you're like you know what I like this
master bedroom suite at the end I'm just
gonna take that for myself so what
you're saying is so from the character
creation dude came and said there's
porks everywhere and we just like oh
we're gonna go home go to bed
no no just down is that what happened no
no yeah well yeah no they told you
there's a pork problem you have to deal
with it okay so what so you've been
dealing with this so you've been out
there you've been out there for Oh
no since--since just yes since there is
a gradual yesterday's yesterday like
yesterday you you guys went out you
dealt with a bunch of porks
uh Justin kind of lit the forest on fire
over here uh uh
nice yeah he was cold or something and
so you guys been fighting porks and now
it's just another day of getting up it
and dealing with these pig works yeah
probably say good morning to the inn
keeper lady man I don't know
okay the innkeeper snubs you and goes
into the room like wow what a team you
you've not you talkin entity respect
from anyone in the town yet people don't
really like you all right and be the
innkeeper now just take a look at nine
uh I'm probably get this would okay
let's head towards what are just cinco
in the yeah they're in there like the
bar you know their head in there after
morning everybody scale when are okay
there you go so you can approach them at
the table skin is like fate of squad
theta squad thanks it squad theta squad
yeah late a squad roll in roll hey bro
yeah rope come on roll dice right i
hatch freeze now
sure well acts alone hmm I haven't
haven't thought about catchphrase just
yet growling we need a motto they just
rely on terminate terminate squadrons
strike oh I like that one I like that
one yeah squadron strike wait where's up
gun sure sure where's wait wait where's
um where's the annoying one oh okay you
clear the screen we're gonna go see
where Roman is right now so Roman is
currently having breakfast with his
younger brother and the younger brothers
named Roman is Phineas Phineas okay so
there's Phineas oh hello whatever it's a
it's a such a beautiful body can I come
with you to say some points today
brother you know I told you you're not
ready for that
but brother why I want to be a big pal
boy like you I mean uh what crash scream
again well cowboy caballes I think I
want to be able to I cavernous like you
brother I I know we've had this talk
many times you're just not ready you
need more training you need to go off
the Kabbalist school and it just is too
dangerous no no brother I want to be I
want to be kabalists today please please
let me come on your adventure I won't
get in the way
Chet would love it if I came on to the
adventure why would you bring me big
brother
I hate those eyes ha ha why do you
always have to look at me with those
eyes I hate you brother you never let me
come on your adventures I'm running away
from home
wait no stop
come back you bet we can make dough okay
come back Phineas Phineas I was really
waiting for him do the weight stop now
so fitting it finish I guess I was code
is running out of town okay okay he's
running away Roman but as you passed by
the bar
dead bones here is gonna see you because
he was looking for you just a secondary
brother Roman get in here
what's going on well we need to get
ready to go out and we got a lot of ways
we've got a lot of work to do today just
too much too much to do so much to do
you're drinking at the bar no I'm okay
I'm here for these two you I just got up
shut up why is there a drink in your
hand there's not yeah I see it right
there
all right it's not a drink your tickets
it yep you just took a sip
you're clearly lying well stop drinking
let's get out there and kill some pours
who's live who's the leader here huh
who's in charge I'm not drinking
apparently it was a card year that's
goes over mine makes sober decisions hey
hey Elmer been here all night
I hate my job yeah I'm not going
anywhere today no we've got
cute what do you mean you're not going
anywhere we gotta go we've got jobs to
do
I got like 16 hours of meditation I have
to do right I know because we don't have
to sleep okay it's an awesome
you know rule there's there's there's a
solution to this you can meditate and
Justin will carry you guys I heard that
that one over there sleeps isn't that
weird
hello sleeper yeah this is awful I'm out
of here
get a dice kind of camp together down to
get sleep sleep us okay Justin how about
you you okay with this you're not doing
a good job inspiring your men like no
wasn't seem to be interested in fact
Romans having a seat Roman good good are
you gonna would you like a drink for
that you want to like bring the
bartender over signal her over would you
like anything to drink there Roman have
we lost room yes I would like some just
lucky meditating could I have a menu
please uh uh yes he passes you a menu
you see many different types of drinks
um well what would you actually depict
Oh Roman these are all is that them out
like one car one water okay no lemon
okay
it gives you a Quicksilver elixir so I
just put that over to everyone it's
pretty good pretty good drink pretty
drink what anyone else what anyone else
like a drink okay five waters hey very
thirsty meanwhile you guys are enjoying
the drinks uh a guard comes running up
comes running in he runs up right it
right up to the Lord dead bones here or
a captain or Downes rather okay
promotion Oh what what the hell what is
sorry all right
look at the dead plants captor dead
bones a small young elf little boy who
looks just like Roman uh just ran off
into that
fiery forest and Justin burned down
yesterday what he why does he wait why
did he run oh he was Roman he said he
wants to be a real cop honest and he's
now run off where's Roman get in here
wait this is my brother in trouble yes
sink your brother's on fire your brother
may be on fire fire uh he's sending one
honey
he said he 1 million caballes and he's
gone to help slay the giant flame spirit
the one that Justin created yesterday my
bad you guys know the deep God episodic
a liar right
what's up Roman it's not Dave it's not
let's see my brother yes we need to get
my brother it's Dave no something some
nuts no Dave Dave no Co Dave works the
prison Patrol you know that come on
you know Dave's Dave works the prison
patrol Co duh no why are we talking
about this when my brothers on fire ok
yeah we put oh so now now now you want
to go huh didn't want to do your job now
your brother's trouble you want to go do
it well let's go do it come on
I don't go Co stomach over there order
the name is jeanna don't get thanks um
get it like Roman
I mean just go back I'll deal with this
come on Roman Roman yeah alright
Oh go what why did you join why'd you
join this army I don't know I needed
money I guess you want the money you
want your money you do your job alright
yeah you want the money you do your job
when it's registered have you got no
empathy dave is a known liar I don't
this is intrude on you like um I'm not
Dave first off I not Dave I don't know
how many times I would say that I don't
even know why you guys are dating with
me are you lying no I'm not - look your
brother's on fire I don't know how you
gonna say no Dave Roman this is fixed I
don't trust you it's a 50% chance he's
not on fire we should probably go just
in case I'm going to save his brother
you guys can just stand here talk all
you want I'm gonna save that little boy
let's go
beta squad strike
yo Elmer hey you down for a 16th round
hey let's do it
you two come on nope hey get back here
come higher fire just means fire if he
dies it's your fault it's a little boy
Deb you're in trouble like getting these
guys to inspire them so you need to use
the oldest trick in the book for shitty
commanders like yourself you need to
bribe them everybody will get a pay
raise if they help save Romans brother
mm-hmm promise you might have it I have
to get like whatever it is you get when
your brother dies a widow's pension she
will deal with that when it comes to it
let's go all right I'm not really
sweetness the deal like I'm still not
gonna like it though anything for saving
my problem all right let me grab you
guys yep so you're gonna leave for the
town the stairs Phineas you know where
he is um so you guys are gonna go down
the road here and as you approach you're
not going to see Phineas but you are
gonna see some elves and the giant a
giant flame spirit that mr. chili Weezy
created yesterday why did you create
this again by the way Justin why did you
burn down the forest I don't quite
remember why I heard this it was
freezing in there power room please
uh-huh okay see ya
they just thought the force is a little
bit cold it was people rehabbed it was
before he had two robes yeah yeah time
it's I only had one robe and I said
before some farmers like oh you do that
it was like a sec he's a very
resourceful guy so you guys can see that
the flame spirit isn't attacking there's
two elves they seem to be like tethering
the spirit like they're calming it down
and there's like one else just like
sitting by the tent just like kind of
like waving at him just like don't do
like yeah it's a good job keep it up
guys you're doing good but he's not
really helping he seems to be the
manager position of this keep the flame
spirit under control up and on so a
little clearly
clearly we're gonna have to approach the
leader here and see what's up okay yeah
like that yes
boom till there's they all look the same
you're just gonna they all look the same
that sits out there although they just
got except I up
ah captain den bills could you come have
you come to help us slay the giant flame
spirit well we did come to slay but it
seems like your buddy what are they
doing I don't where I'm not really it
seems it's a very hard spirit I don't
think we could have beaten it ourselves
so right now we're just doing it
we've tried Jack you know you know
calming it down see if it'll just like
leave or something you know tonight a
tree but that doesn't seem to be working
and we can reuse your help we could use
your help but just killing the damn
thing that wouldn't go along
Justin can Justin can you get rid of it
you made it uh no no it's at it's beyond
your control
yeah yeah no I I've noted okay uh just
are you okay with us killing it cuz it's
kind of yours so don't you want to step
on any boundaries trying to be accepting
very okay kill it all right Sayed
squadrons strike okay this was a little
bit different of an encounter ever
excuse me did you guys you guys can
decide where you want to be before the
encounter starts because these guys will
basically release it from the tether and
they're gonna fight alongside you so you
can put yourself anywhere you want to be
they might be kind of our Nellie's
squares I don't think they get to decide
where they go I think the leader would
tell them where to go oh yeah well yeah
what's your bank do you want to do a
game plan before you uh I
Oh Travis how's the game plan oh you can
I mean this isn't it's really not a hard
game plan oh all you've got to do is go
roam and stay in the back Justin up
front with me so I got to do yeah you
two stay back
do your Wizzle boo-boo and then me and
Justin will do the actual work come on
Justin
I mean I'm going to go for the blue one
why do you think being careless isn't
actual we're not we're not fighting the
elves we're fighting the big fire thing
we're not don't what
don't hit the outs you only put up their
ire
our team side no never clearly he'll
like it
no they're trying to stop it look I
don't want you guys killing any more
people I mean a lot of shit for this
already you realize you've killed four
people
Dave in the last few days why it was
three the last one was the distinct bite
it's about to be four Romans brother I
mean that's like four and a half really
it's like you soon bro sorry
look not my bro my brother sorry very
stern looking for every elf you don't
kill you earn 100 gold not including
yourselves on me okay so mmm
should be pretty easy like there is some
kind of asterisk there there's an
asterisk there I don't want you killing
each other either just oh theta squad
strike sure all right we're going on air
where do you actually want to be dead
bones like on the board I probably gonna
sit next to these two chuckle fucks
alright so roben Co Justin where did
where do you want to be standing so he
told me in Roman to stay in the backs
yeah I'm gonna I'm just chilling back
there let's go to the back yeah really
far back let's get out of range all my
spells oh there like a range okay one
two three four I will go up in here and
I'm uncomfortable with it I feel like
I'm helping too much as it is these
things are heavy don't make me move them
around like this okay so our turn order
is Roman code dead bones Justin so it'd
be best if Roman started the first
attack all right whatever
okay so what's happened right now so
right now these so right now the force
has completely burned down okay there's
little tiny fires everywhere they seem
to be going out there's this giant flame
spirit but he's kind of like resting
like he's kind of like being subdued but
the elves are kind of like using some
sort of magic to hold them in place so
they're right there like whatever y'all
ready captain dead bones they're gonna
let go and then he's going to be let
loose and
the six of you because this guy remember
he's a manager he's not going to help
the six of two are going to try and take
down this raging fire spirit so it
shouldn't be too hard with all of you
but you know things could things could
go wrong okay okay um let's do this I am
going to move a little bit closer about
here okay
I'm gonna cast windblast on this fiery
log over here what what yeah I'm gonna
know that little fire he's gonna put out
the fire okay yeah
bye assume wind blast which will knock
an object back would create a gust of
wind sufficient to put out what looks to
be like a nurse okay a little to fire
you're gonna set the lake on fire really
really so we have a fire elemental how
much worse is it gonna be to fire
elementals oh man hmm whoa they eat wind
too far how do they eat win oh this this
is not a fire oh yeah go ahead and roll
fun a danger we're getting rid of us it
looks really angry go ahead and roll a
die to see if you uh okay can put out
the fire all right thirteen all right
you successfully put out the fire that
sparked this fire has been put out uh
upon using that spell though the two the
two elves let go they're kind of blasted
back a space like the backpedal and the
the spirit is awoken oh it's an ass okay
with that you guys are welcome that fire
is not a ding dream or is there anything
else you want to do Roman as it goes
turn way to go that's ghost turn three
good alright go you're up what are you
doing
alright I'm gonna I'm gonna summon a
shit Lord what is this shit around again
the King names of spells please sorry uh
call earth Lord O Lord
okay so you're gonna pick some some dirt
up some gravel and you're gonna summon
sheriff Lord
okay yeah let me use do I have one
I'm gonna use this okay all right so you
some of this so what do you tell him to
do okay give him one job and he's gonna
do that job until he dies essentially
all right shit Lord you know one job
keep an eye on blue elf over here slap
him if he does anything
you won't be able to recommand oh I'm
just letting you know that's cool
okay so you some of this thing he runs
up and he's just staring at like right
behind the blue guy waiting for him to
do anything so he can hit him okay all
right yeah they fantastic
goose look I move yeah they'll move
right you can own it I want to go this
direction can I go here sure yeah oh gee
I wonder what's coming oh yeah yeah I'm
going fishing shut up fishing ah he's
gonna go all right uh dead bones it is
your turn all right this is like I'm
right up in his face right
mmm and so far you've seen your troops
aren't really taking it's this serious
what sonic wind was that super serious
that guy like put out fire but he's blue
what is really threatening one of them
one of your party members put out a tiny
little fire and the other one summoned a
second manager watch the video that's
why they're in the back so I don't have
to pay attention to them whatever we're
getting paid they won't get paid if they
don't do damage anyway I'm just gonna do
some fucking flare fist as my attack I'm
gonna punch him with a flare okay go
ahead and roll the dice Jim with their
11 yeah uh yep so it hits so you do fire
you do five damage to the three basic
mace attack two three four no bleep five
yeah I know um how much does that cost
you only cost you once damage the cast
right yep yeah all right in a basic fee
based right neither free basic attack
with your own a slit does for ya
and you male you just whiff you kind of
break right through the elemental there
now who's not being helpful
uh-huh
dammit you're both getting I'm gonna
give both it your money to Justin he
hits yeah yeah
the person who hits the fire thing the
most gets paid more I hit the fire thing
I actually killed the fire thing I
should get the bonus dem bones you know
that there you do have treasure to
distribute so you I know that you guys
only have a barter you're not gonna get
anything you actually take it order so
I'm excited this is my turn it's your
turn Justin alright
chili was easy to drop a chili blizzy
yeah they say it like that - chili
bluesy trade oh good I was emotional is
it a 19 I'll take it yeah sixteen
sixteen six outs and 91 then yeah but I
do what I don't right so it's a five by
five radius here Justin so I think this
is about right just a little too big ah
wait what's happening I was opinion you
just something a blizzard so it's gonna
be about this big Justin where do you
want to put it where are you somebody
not on us it's like right over right
over something in the end yeah so like
the right thing yeah smart let's uh move
this move this move this okay like that
intense uh that looks about good
he said that's kind of not aligned
actually he was like here it's hard
about eight big ones yeah we can just
get a still name all right and uh and
I'm gonna go for a dull divorce lawyer
hit here oh my god alright go ahead and
lean back you little red guy don't
attack the head guy oh oh
swing your dull vocal Slayer and
decapitate this red guy that's right
Justin Justin
this is conscious that you wrote well
you will think critical right and it
kills targets and you miss so you slug
at the guy right next to you and
just like you basically you took a blade
swung it at the elemental went right
through him because he's an elemental
fire and just put a wrap and he kind of
took a hit took off read it oh my god
that is so bad already killed Eve it's
not Dave um so green guy is furious he
runs over and is like what did you do
chili wheezy first the force and now
Davey I can't believe it
and blue wizards gonna move into attack
and he's gonna do a flare plus a melee
attack he's trying to do something yeah
he's trying to help so for so is is
shitlord gonna go after him yeah that's
what's gonna happen hold on I got a roll
okay yeah shit Lord's gonna give him a
little slap so first he's gonna
so first is gonna try to do flare okay
and a stern look and he rolls a six and
the second he moves forward to do this
this thing's gonna walk up to him and
start beating on him for three damage
see if he can hit him hey John
alright so he's gonna interrupt the cast
he's like there's no damage just even
gonna happen and blue blue guy here is
gonna take three damage so excellent use
of your allies so far guys we come
across a Fire Lord he's got two leashed
elves it very easily could be supporters
yeah I don't see why you think we're
taking yeah then your cultists they're
clearly cultists you're a caballes the
fiery spirit that was the fire spirit is
going to unleash fire cannon at you guys
and it is a line attack and he's going
to use it like so to hit this side no
dead bones and Roman is it a spell uh no
it's just his natural ability okay cuz I
have to ask I had to ask nine so we'll
use that one for dead bones dem bones
this is only going to hit you for three
four blue elf blue elf is now
unconscious so I'm gonna try to be
careful this week blue alpha is
unconscious red elf is absolutely dead
like we're just gonna we're going to
throw them
he's dead now the blue elf is dead I
guess or shitlord is dead to rights his
job done is his he just returns the
earth he's just a pile of rubble because
that something does yeah did his job and
Roman is gonna take no damage Roman
sidesteps moves out of the way and so
dead bones just takes three alright uh
now it is oh uh so from Romans fire as
well that he put out it actually helped
because it stops spawning a fire spirit
so Debra oh wow you're welcome what a
helpful guy yeah let's get right here
now dead load stinks a little bit more
from these fire spirits that I'll spawn
for the fire way to accidentally do a
good job there you know he said he's
staying here I'm going to take that into
consideration it's better than trying to
kill the fucking Ally alright Roman it's
your turn does my my blizzard fix him
right I know I'm sorry yes your blue
ticks them for two things well at the
six I'm like a bunch of times right know
at the start is it the start of the end
of your tour is that the end of the term
so yeah he should have a telescope
should have already taken two one two
okay so now it's Romans turn just remind
me at the end of each turn
no Justin sure thing
okay so have a ah let's do this I'm
going to move over in this direction
okay yep uh I'll see let's just you
actually I mean I'll use my ID Ruby Ruby
thing to keep moving
all right I am in a cast wait how far
can I move with the Ruby is it just five
but have to look it's five well I don't
know how much I've really moved so I've
just gotten only about five and then you
probably move like one space forward if
you want to do all right and this is
safe now right yeah yeah this is all put
oh okay
okay make sure all right I'm gonna cast
summon air sprites okay in this
direction okay go ahead and roll yeah
not gonna use actual magic on little
things mean your spell's oh no oh oh
come on
excellent so you're gonna summon your
airscape disguise so you're gonna see
some of them in the absolute wrong way
that's why we're thinnest quad they're
surrounding your allies here so one two
three and four John allies okay actually
you only got three because it was still
one you have to actually you can still
afford
are they just gonna leave you know what
because once they're summoned they're in
control this this just they're gonna
they're these these these ones Broman
are not actually sure who's an ally of
isn't in la other than you so they're
gonna attack everyone you kind of bunk
up an entire spell
so these win the other non-tech you've
created four enemies it's all you've
done whoa I've created for neutral
parties that are unsure for enemies you
said they'd go back any one uh air
spirit still one damage to the nearest
enemy so it's not an enemy it's just
nearest target it's anyone yeah okay all
right all right for you guys it is now a
co sorcerer
all right I'm going to move right here
and I'm going to summon shit Lord okay
and let me roll out yes for that right I
should get you to tell me what you're
trying to do each time what if like what
are you trying to do with this this guy
so well hold on he can't be on the
outside of the tent come on um so I'm
gonna tell him to to go over here just
kind of like you know keep an eye on
things uh they have a specific order is
K you been available okay you basically
tell him to go do this one thing they
only have one like one objective one
objective so if you tell him to go over
here and that's an objective he's
literally gonna walk over there and kill
himself
normally these things you say go attack
the fire Lord and it goes next
firing does that every turn but if you
just walk over here and chill he's gonna
walk over there chill Firdous whatever
he feels the chill amount of time all
right I get it I get it I get it all
right
go too far and get me a beer I got it I
got taken away 1 2 3 4 5 yeah he's
clearly going for one all right you're
staying here and have a have a meditate
it is now uh did also you have not
stamina for me yet oh thank you that's
that's to shitlords I think Justin also
hasn't been stamina time not sure yeah
yeah free stamina what Roman do this
turn he someone wasn't changed some
sprites yeah okay
dead bones is your hamon I'm just going
just go I'm what up I see the air
sprites yeah you're surrounded by I see
this earth Lord just wandering off in
the opposite direction I'm just like
this I I'm just gonna use blockade and
just be like I put my hand up so I don't
know leave me alone stop taking I'm
taking a break
blockade now who's not doing anything
I'm going to tell I'm going to shove the
treasure down your fucking throat
alright uh so your bully Agata should go
yeah just locate it remember as your
movie turn if you guys want you may now
control dead folks you can move me and
you can move it around
however it's not like you're
uncontrollably moving him so dead ones
has to agree to the movement you have to
push me like I don't know it it's like
it's like a bucket you gotta push it
okay so now it is Justin's turn which
means
hey what the heck does anymore
oh alright so chat has given a chilly
wizzy a third piece of third coat so
you'll be a jerk on Justin
this treasure card will increase your
maximum stamina by 10 no you're gonna
hell you're gonna have well Wow Wow
you're gonna have to be stamina here so
what and so you also have lesser magic
resistance
this means that against most magical
spells they're going to be insanely hard
to hit you Oh so against general just
spell e type attacks you're going to be
basically immune things like standing
and fire things like anything like that
so you could stand in your blizzard for
the rest of the game you're not gonna be
affected you can stand in any of those
like you know area
bad bad stand things they're not going
to affect you anything lesser it
generally won't work on any
possibilities but it'll it'll let you
stand in your stuff like blizzards and
stuff so you cast the helmets now
so what see more flammable now no man
that coat protects them against all the
elements so whoa yeah justice it's just
a super buff cuz it's an element's coat
it's a really shitty coat
I think it should reduce his movement
speed by a bit but whatever no it's got
a waddle a bit more basically it'll
waddle around a little bug a like t-rex
arms you can't actually grasp things I
really hope this ends with him just
having coats and is there a coat he's
only guys away three coats now I mean I
really hope I got another winner could I
hope for every encounter alright so the
just in a staggered turn though it's my
turn uh alright how wide is the radius
on ice blast on the board like what
would that look like if I were to cast
it somewhere it's three in each
direction
oh no no so ice blast is a you should
think of it as a pppoe it centered
around you so it's these squares
directly around you so if you realize it
you'd hit these two you
the big guy these two little ones and
Crennel Hector Jonas that's an important
thing to note is the pyro pencil get
hurt by fire oh well you can try if you
like Justin as your - a wizard you
should know this and we all was
blockading you you created you created
me sire
so yeah nothing you got behind me then
wouldn't take damage from anything I
don't think it would've poked through
with it remember well all poke me he
could block he he can pee BAE now dead
bones won't take damage I'm not gonna
take me only the green guy which who
don't care about him and you know if
Garber the one I get just like it well
who you know what I'm gonna do
oh here's my play it's only enemy
keratins it's only enemies it says
public art artist I'm gonna like uh you
won't be able to hit both of these if
you're trying to cuz it's job yeah I
don't know if you're so I could hit him
in the boss
you won't brightly hit this you'd have
to go here and you're out right on the
right hair it's the squares around you
god stress I want me to take care I'm
gonna get as close to denier you already
shown disregard for other elders just
kill like I cut that over accident okay
whatever kill everything
these are stuck so accident kill the air
sprites and do damage to him I guess oh
yeah I'm gonna how close think it's
lazier sprite second will go 5 right you
get move one up to you so if you moved
forward you wouldn't hit green elf you
wouldn't hurt dead bones and you did
nothing like if you menu here a 2 X
brights just beautiful like that and
you'd be on this cool angle Roger
sprites uh dear Agra knows you're gonna
try and hit the good I want you to
commit nice thing so you're gonna get
right yeah no fuck that elf I'm doing a
I split okay gonna tack my air sprites
oh no yes lutely
they're my air sprites do doesn't matter
they're dead
hey Rob real quick yeah thanks Roman I
don't think we go like half size on that
die ok make the die smaller I'm
regretting my bigness request there you
go that's perfect
you made the time bigger
yeah so it's your fault I just wanted
like the biggest die ever you can all
blame comb alright so welcome this cost
you one mana Justin oh yeah this is
gonna get real this is gonna be really
really big this is gonna do double
damage so it does
how much is like last two at the latest
yeah there's a good time to blockade
this is gonna be four times damage in
this radius uh this guy's gonna get
fucking hell this guy's going to get
blasted this guy's going to jump out of
the way so he doesn't even get hit all
right well I'm going to jump you back
here and you're gonna hit all of these
plus him so these are all dead we'll
just delete them
sorry Roman I don't need and then uh
dead bones completely just blocks the
spell you know even some of it kind of
bounces back to just give it a nice even
fifteen damage to the boss and the boss
takes two more from the blizzard that's
why you're number two Justin were five
six seven eight and eleven twelve
thirteen fourteen sixteen seventeen
alright and I'm gonna go for my actually
well first Roman and Co get free uh free
spells right oh yes yes yes because of
your racial pass of being the the elves
Roman and Co now gets expels so Roman
why don't you take your still first okay
[Applause]
okay I just think about this okay look I
gotta go I wanna do it's and I could hit
one hmm maybe I don't want to do that
you ever consider that
yeah maybe don't maybe you want someone
more fucking air spreads Rob I want to
summon more air sprite just to get to
the lost ones that I have and know I've
given them a chance okay you believe
that's what I was gonna do anyway sleep
oh oh
I'm some of the air sprites over here
yeah I think I make an equal fight on
yeah fire sprites force air sprites okay
and code what do you wanna do with your
free spell
I would like to summon a shit Lord okay
use some of the shit Lord all right and
I realized that I also want to slice the
pizza and they only can do one command
at a time okay
oh yeah all right sweet one two three
four five all right
you have to the earth spirits on the way
if he doesn't understand toppings and
you just gets like ever I just whatever
next turn I'll eat any pizza
okay so that was those dead bones get
something too or no no cuz no it up when
I was filled with I misspelled laid by
my free attack I it just yeah you're
gonna freeze f it which is a lot to
finish staff or euro-pro blade okay okay
Molly I have a staff I'm just covering
code yeah that's right
that's really gone all right
and you miss alright with any mess
[Music]