go yeah okay so I'm so scared to even
try this but can I use my quickness
elixir yeah like I don't like what he
the way he said that Co no it's not
magical if you're wearing that it's a
magical effect No you'll get your tricks
okay okay you don't even need to roll
for this this is just a potion you can
have your actually I need you to roll
because if you know what it'll be funny
you'll spill it yeah it also gives you a
third turncoat this was like a high
quality pussy so this give you three
turns and you have a bonus spell Roman
your spells first now you want to write
aspire the poor below I I know every
part of me knows this is wrong but at
this point
give me there's if you want to drop
there's no Roman you could get co-op
there's there's like you you could go ad
focal I would mean that all his spells
are on top yeah I'm pulling Co off okay
I really hope I hope this works
alright again you slap Co four five one
two three four five
putting four six health code blasts fine
you doesn't take any damage from the
fall damage but you just slapped
you really need not stop helping your
teammates can you uh can you heal them
for one for the locket on that 20 you
bet you okay all right you have three
actions go and plus a spell so first you
got to do your spell for the role okay
oh wait that goes for the that counts
for the role or do i troll again this
this was the d20 so you still need to
roll but this is like this is your free
spell for rolling that 20 okay I get you
or drinking your potion okay I'm gonna
do cloud of darkness right here okay
yeah Nico is doing CeCe's one to your
very dangerous four loko if you have a
potion you're gonna want to consider
using it I know what did you rule 11
okay so it's gonna encompass one two
three four like this yeah beautiful oh
hey that's the promotion thank you yeah
I have potions so that I'm gonna use a
rejuvenation potion roll the fumble Oh
code drink this potion and it's twice a
respective as normal the neck nor the
cardboard ooh bodacious pushes like 10
so Cogan's 20 health 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9
10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20
yes Roman you have a spell for both also
due to poor what you did to Justin and
ko ko' still has throb gangs by the way
yeah and a free spell right I have a not
me oh yeah you have a free spell after
this - yeah alright
I'm win blessing Corvo okay yeah I
really like elves because they turn 20
what the fuck was that
there's no drugs yeah yes that's the bit
hmm wait this one will be a 20 Rome it's
fine
15 all right you get four oh four nine
one two three four five six seven eight
nine alright poor but we're gonna have
to start doing some stuff buddy
no no all right Co spell and then all
three actions yes yeah all right I want
to do another cloud of madness over here
and I don't care if it overlaps with the
wall I just don't want it to encompass
Justin okay nice this is just a wall a
giant cloud of darkness that makes these
guys could potentially go insane three
more turns for you and then I get three
turns Jesus all right cool well so you
have one move in three actions will move
300 points Wow who's in three actions
yeah I still like the hit and poor both
think oh just saying yeah yeah I want to
I'm sorry Ropin I did that mean to move
you I want to move next to Roman okay do
you have the Ruby you don't have the
rubies I don't know as close as I can
that's as close as you're getting you
can see poor little you see poor Bo San
I have three damn actions holy crap
Oh what should I wonder if it's tricks
the skelux if they don't have a lot of
health filter magic but if maybe that we
have some kind of earthy type yeah
really
you know what dead ones real die for me
oh just to see if I know anything this
could be that was just me thinking I was
the devil thinks about the elf Oaks and
he can confirm that they are definitely
immune to magic
they're definitely mean imagine a seem
to be immune to magic they seem like if
you're like near them like on top of
them and stuff it was like like
preventing you from casting magic or
something weird yeah look I think we
just hit magic like I'm scared that
you'll send an elemental Atta and it
will just fizzle out because it's made
of Matt yeah I think well first of all
they do physical damage they do physical
cache all right but they're still oh I
know yeah there is yeah you're imagining
we don't understand going on yeah yeah
so I think I think port bow well I mean
if I was gonna attack poor bow though it
would be with
yeah purple is not immune to magic okay
so you told me to like slap just do
whatever they give you send earthlings
we summon three if we put three
elementals on them that's nine damage
till he kills them
you know I'll summon weren't one earth
Lord for sons okay how's that descended
South I saw two other that's right
yeah you got your yeah you see what
happens this is something in an earth
ward okay it summons it it's going up
tore bow one two three four five six
they can walk 10 that walks into poor
bows range it can't really attack to the
end of turn like you want an attacking
poor bow yeah yeah I mean back in the
LFO ah the reason why I do it at the end
of turn is because I don't want you
gettin it's gettin crazy twenties so
right I'll let you do this one time but
you can't make this a strategy 16 ok
hits for Buffy 3 okay so it made it out
there and it wasn't
don't leave okay that whatever you want
to do from now on code you do do what
you wanted directions alright uh I'm
gonna do more authority key yeah it's
fucking pylon yeah no I like it
ugh pile that's even the even the score
here alright another one comes up runs
up to him punches him for three I was
just gonna make me hit what not alike
well we're using the wonderful okay you
have it at the end of turn so he's
earned again he's good yeah yeah and one
more of the same thing the only thing
he's going forward to see if he failed
the roll see like this is great because
Dada bugged it here 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 I
can't get into range
that's because he's gotten far enough
he's got a weird error with an answer
for another 3 1 2 3 ok
and I think that's it finally it's
coaster yep all right uh I want to i
ball port was probably looking still
good right oh yeah
all those looking pretty beastly yeah
all right I'm gonna take a leaf out of
COEs book I'm gonna pop a quickness
elixir oh boy
you can't burst them down on me yeah I'm
fucking going for it okay all right so
that's three actions right attractions
one move it's three actions now yeah
yeah and then one move that I haven't
used yet yeah so you think I can maybe
potentially get behind poor Bo oh you
know what oh do you want one more throw
Munsell and then I chose your costs
because I gave you three additional
actions so you should have had one more
oh oh yeah it was a clear shirt so I
have to roll for him or what sport it
came out push them yeah all right so
could I use my move to get behind poor
bone uh yes okay so I'm gonna try and
just get directly behind him like yeah
opposite where I am right now
yeah all right ask my moves three
actions alright first flare fist good
old flare fist okay you're gonna use
flare gotta love it
gotta love it gotta love it gotta love
it it's a six there's a 9x9 goodbye okay
you hit him for five one two three four
five all right free basic attack lemme
think Dean so you hit him for three uh
it has a lightning do you want to bounce
it it's gonna hit don't want to bounce
it makes you work
yeah so one two three four
yeah and can I have it bounced back to
poor Bo again then I can bounce the poor
Bo and then it can bounce to this yet
more time yeah I want to do that yep so
this six damage EJ okay and that's I
mean yes it's the first act that's the
first okay yeah so second action is just
gonna be a repeats just to be Flair fist
again okay let's just give me two rolls
yeah just do it all over again so it's
calm that's the last action you're
getting that's like yeah so you're gonna
cast your flare so let's go get one
again and you're gonna cast your flare
and you like preempt because you've
decided to do this stupid-ass flare
punch bullshit so you put the flare in
your hand and when you go to punch it
you don't let go the flare then you pull
out I just let it go in your face
hitting you for five okay and then I get
my choice six so cast it do I get my
basic no man you roll the one well
mr. Easton all right before the porks
all right I'm gonna move this is an
arrange of hitting him right yeah I
think so he's got a weird area all right
I'm gonna I'm gonna throw a fireball at
him okay all right you hit him for ten
wolf one two three four five six seven
eight nine ten poor boy was not looking
good good right I'm going to uh play to
get free attack basically that were
played okay this is BA 20 please
Beatrice
well it's warplane onboard pool yeah oh
we're played one two three okay all
right and I can move three spaces
you kinda get charged by one of them
guys yeah yeah I think it's my turn yeah
okay um yeah I really need that a rage
event was gonna happen
poor Bo has now enlarged okay so his
damage is doubled and his stamina is
doubled uh but so he's so whatever he's
like but it's a full D full heal no he
does not play it
so wherever he's at he's now double of
what he was he was low okay okay that's
not too bad
yeah porpoise battle yeah poor bo is
going to walk up he's just gonna shove
just another way as he's walking just
moving out of the way and he's gonna
grab one of these goblins the porks
already eat some oh shit he's gonna heal
off them
Oh No yeah he's in the heel gotta go
focus fire fucking focus fire we have to
slap him for eating them all you guys oh
yeah so I'm gonna have this LFO just oh
man what am I gonna do
I'm gonna bring these guys in you guys
to deal with that let's just fuck the
rest let's do some darkness rules for
these guys so we do a darkness roll for
their these three in this fog - they're
gonna yeah something's gonna keep these
four okay just go change one
um yeah I'm gonna have it so this one
died and this one died in the skirmishes
that they're fighting against each other
I'm gonna have this one walk right out
this one walk right out this wooden walk
right out this one still keep fighting I
know these guys now like fighting each
other I have this guy moving forward
fighting a bunch more have come from the
cave so we're gonna do four attacks on
roaming here my blast okay all right go
ahead and wind blast Roman and they were
gonna hit they rolled a four what he's
got so many attacking him those just
like before you I guess yeah yeah three
okay Roman tries the wind blast and he
just wind blast right here the porks
we're only gonna hit him for one and
they still him for one cuz you just went
right there but then Roman loses one for
using windblast so save two damage no
you effectively we're gonna take one now
you took two busy
w10 double with your village and now you
can't move okay um we're gonna have red
guy life tap co in range any any
interrupts Roman you want news like this
guy wait what's happening like oh this
is the non blind one yes it's like okay
you miss if you hit one of the earth
elementals but the earth elementals
don't have ice sunlight tap is gonna hit
coke okay
it only barely hits them so it only gets
super one Wow
oh my goodness um green guy is still
blind
green guy is gonna walk in front of
Corbeau and jump up and down
it's his turn give up and down this
purple elf elk is now going to charge at
both of you
oh man do I get to dodge I'll tell you
okay you both get to try and jump out of
the way
so who's this rolling Gophers me yeah I
figure I'm in front o get out of the way
okay he crashes through those four pit
Forks I'm gonna give one role to see
what happens these ports they're
probably all dead sweets just just
absolutely slaughtered and he thanks
Kelly Elk I wanna have this one I have
this one move forward and he's gonna try
to pick up ko oh just got off I sure did
go back pedals one space to get away
from them seriously anti-magic skele
films yeah the magic base team fighting
elves going to counter everything you
guys do um and Red's gone
Green's gone I win I've done everything
alright now it's your guys turn romaine
dad new shit can't move can you win
Weston oh I can Ruby you can Ruby I can
Ruby
yeah I can Ruby up to here Ruby don't
toss another Ruby orb oh look how is I
do not like this poor bow still look at
the little rough well he's one dude yeah
yes like he's yeah
here's technically as percentage didn't
change right he's they look exactly as
rough yeah but I mean did the heal from
the one guy Rob said he did but I didn't
tell you how much oh oh okay sorry
is there any visual change after he ate
the dude
there's a lot of visible change because
the enlarges I'll let you know right now
just cuz since you guys need to know I
guess he heals for 15 when he eats every
time he eats out loud okay I mean these
are all fighting if he walks into the
madness to eat these that's actually a
good thing so except he's raised so
madness may not affect him because I
don't know if he'll find out I'm just
saying there's yeah yes I that's not
something I would battle you can try and
kill mr. red guy if you really want no I
know I've seen those life tapping
bastards we're does not deal with that
anymore over port bow with wind blast
sorry just best five hands this battle
is gonna work nice I hope Green is in
the way because 17 what were you trying
to do wind blast hit port laughing what
port was gonna interrupt he's gonna just
gonna in it
poor gonna interrupt his interrupts
depends well sorry is it arranged in it
up absolutely um let's see showed you
the ropes of interrupts I want to go
with you can't cuz you don't need your
you're already focused on doing one
thing it doesn't make sense to like
someone else an interrupt I would be
okay with a dodged counter dodged but I
wouldn't be countered would it be okay
with the near saddle counter idea before
most spitting the bones of the pork he
just ate at you to try and negate your
spell and I got succeeded so your spell
was just interrupted Roman okay that's
it I might sir I don't have a move and
can't really do anything else yeah so
why is this battle so gross yes alright
I want to move in the direction of poor
Bo as much as I can just let you do that
let me see here what's the range on that
mirror can you see it from here that may
range there's got to be like melee range
like you gotta walk up to have you up in
his face okay all right
can I have my lords go now your Lords of
earth craft oh yeah no no I'm just gonna
let them go before are you gonna go then
I need to oh sorry
good yeah
all right so twelve damage one two three
four pretty much almost negated nine ten
eleven twelve
okay can I see how he's looking after
that uh when he started getting beaten
by those he fell to one knee
woohoo oh man alright um
come on yeah come on Co I know I'm
thinking like what's a good thing to do
now you have like attack spells right
just like I do I do
let's fucking hit him might get a crit
yeah
I'll go for a grand Raven's claw come on
big money okay
poor beau is gonna try and spit bones at
you you still got bones alright there's
probably a lot of bone really control it
like not spitting changed he hits you
for no damage but he interrupts your
spell oh okay you're still go ahead dead
bones
alright um so Oh quickness elixirs
aren't limit one per combat are they I
think they are they OH
doesn't show it on the card you can even
use yours anyway that's fine I can use
it I can use Netflix and there's not
gonna be any downside alright so I'm
gonna pop my quickness elixir yeah I'm
gonna use my neighborhood with a spill
role yeah what doc you mister hold this
fuck I'd rather just have it and not
have to worry about it
alright so I'm gonna use my move to go
up there says three actions right mm-hmm
okay uh Bobby Blair I need a one that's
gonna be flair for bows gonna shoot
opponent you uh huh Wow he's getting a
lot of fucking bones out huh he's
running he's running low though it
sounds like alright this poor girl
interrupts your flair okay first action
because you know Cassatt well you still
gonna be player to man player to forgo
we I got more flares than you got Bo
that's not true for Bo is gonna try
screw the bone to stop your flavor
you're cheating off blares restraining
bones come on damn it
alright does he hit his in his for Bo
portal has been so low like when he ate
that thing he was at uh-huh he was the
flare fist takes him out he was already
a to like I have horrible horrible falls
to the ground all the pork see that dead
bones have defeated has defeated it all
the pork stew start running away from
the cave into me the only exception to
the exception is notice running away is
all the madness ones are still mad yes
you guys are kind of in combat and the
grant the grave hoops fall back to bones
they're just pile of bones now they're
just yeah that's alright
the cool thing with a grapefruit they
only had like 15 health that's what I
was thinking they have to be physically
weak right we're like dry bones you'd
beat them yeah they'd get back up and
they were so like even if you had beaten
them they would have come back up and
the little Sorcerer's life tap for full
so they have little help too but you'd
have to be set a ratio or just their
thing out just right just what they did
or their influence collapse right can I
just say that was fine this is it the
final punch was a twas a triumphant yell
of fader squats right okay so you don't
really have to deal with these other
porks
they're just mad they're just gone
we're kind of just fighting each other
and everything there are they kind of
weak oh yeah these things are
one-hitters like oh you should just
detonate your fucking oh yeah that's a
just click and make it go away
we have to damage them inside of it and
then it implodes no can you just know it
says yeah I can go at any time by three
damage
so any catalyst can actually collapse it
causing all targets inside to take three
damage so yeah you could just kill all
of these with water just like oh yeah
destroying those instead of blow it
stupid yeah all you do almost like think
yeah you're a role you look like palaces
I'd like to do snapping your fingers
that's what I do 15 there goes snap
there's just an implosion of all the
ports getting like sucked into like a
vortex exploding up to the damage and
then all its again blowed into like
little portable saddle ever we won well
cut over there still well no there is no
there all done
and all of the other ports have no
interest in fighting you at this point
they've all gone to that they're all
like cowering in the corners of the case
how big is poor goes head how big is
poor Rose pretty fuck Sookie was
enlarged but now that he's been knocked
unconscious he's shrunk back down poor
Bo's head size of a dwarf it's what you
want to take a trophy back wait wait
wait guys I have yeah I have to do
something because I promised you know
what yes Co you you do a code full
permission was not dead okay he's
unconscious not dead you have my
permission I pull out my mirror okay
wait no no this is cozily no wait no I
don't blame no hope there could be
consequences
it doesn't matter code do it up what
comes what consequences well all the
kids they get out of this cave know me a
few of them cos kill him you can walk
out they don't know we killed Porco
or you means you want evidence yes we
can take these there there look
yesterday Roman thank you I'm doing it
I'm do it how many of them there were if
all of your ideas this you just been
terrible terrible ideas no wonder your
brother ran away the whole town hmm yeah
for the mirror absolutely if you drop
the mirror crack if you like this is the
moment of time you roll the one I mean
Friday for buddy this chat this one's
for you I hope it's good
rub rub your whatever's together here we
go
raise your dongers okay you suck poor Bo
into the mirror you did it everybody
oh man that's gonna be a it's the at the
gymnasium
can you see poor Bo inside the mirror
now oh yeah absolutely that's get sucked
in there with him though the beer can
never be used again now it once so you
can look at the mirror but once you like
activate it again
the mural break and poor boy will come
out Co you can have got a trick mirror
you can use that and again look at you
and it's a poor Bo all right so one of
the porks one of the ones who like gonna
help let's start with you it comes up
and he just walks past he kind of pushes
you guys aside and just walks up the
dead bones and he's just like you poor
bone oh man yeah and then and then he
just starts like he gets on all Hansen
fours and he starts nuzzling you with
his nose and when this happens all the
pork started : oh you did you know rub
their nose on you some of them kind of
like do little piles of barf on the feet
yeah puking on you okay oh man you you
are now the because because ports they
don't see race they don't see color they
don't see the sex they don't see
anything all they see is strength and so
they just they don't see you necessarily
as elves elves they see it was like elf
pork they think MLD like pork
yeah so they might know that you're a
different pork than them but they just
think oh dear pork from that place
so now that you would be in their master
you are now their master uh-huh
well well well well well well well well
well
you're gonna need new shoes I'm gonna
need a lot of new shoes yeah you could
wear two shoes at once like Justin yeah
like Justin no is this these ports have
like three hit points it's amazing I
can't like six yes he pulls out three of
the heads but he is now she actually
killed Wow see just like that's more
than him you can't force the Roman oh
right now I think hey Phineas yes do you
think I can join the theta squad this is
do you want to join me at theta squad I
would love to fight alongside my brother
yes Phineas you can join theta squad but
wait a second you are okay Barristan you
want to find a new job but wait a second
you're only allowed four elves in a
party I can't that's okay because
there's a new aeneas there's an opening
it's actually not you think
unfortunately Phineas
I can't leave wait what oh I'm the big
boss now I'm poor Bo oh oh if I leave
what do you think is gonna happen
this is Tartarus they descend into chaos
and who cares I don't want to be a way
out of this
no he's got a point if he leaves
somebody else will become portable whoa
there boss boss boss I have a really
good idea
what's the idea go away
all right yeah how long do you think it
would take the mirror just sink to the
bottom of the pit
right yeah I don't actually know but
with a break which I put it in there and
it just sinks down the bottom it breaks
poor Bo comes out yeah
later after we're gone and then you just
are free to look curse why would you do
that doesn't that counteract everything
you've done we just fought poor Bo for
no reason but not for know we just get
look Phineas is here this was the
objective right I thought you should
leave Co here maybe Co should look out
for the porks no no he doesn't want COEs
not wants to escape that's true you'd
kind of get here by itself yeah yeah but
you see what happened up in here I mean
it got it got crazy man really crazy
skel effects yeah there were skeletal
you're seeing skeletal folks yes I sleep
- hey hey sorry guys always had an issue
with lying
if you follow me I bet you they'll be -
I I kind of like for me this more than
you want to be Porter's attention also
rocks
okay hold on these attention in all
porks I mean supports have to come out
yo new boss Oh actually you know what no
no that's that's way too against
character no I'm the new boss make sure
these guys get out okay okay poor Bo
Marco okay I'm portable you making me
your new name Porco you maybe go does
that mean I get to plus other porks yeah
you're the new you're like your corporal
Porco
go tell the other porks to make sure
that these guys get out ok ok ok we'll
do books all right well unfortunately
that's that's the end of theta squad
well with me anyway it was good well
last Oh Justin Phineas I'm gonna miss
you guys Phineas I didn't even know you
that well but I'm going to miss you
Phineas Justin Smoak and I can't get
messy just in here I have to tell you
though by your captain now Justin yeah
thank you
you're the leader of theta squad I give
you the rain dude I'm gonna stay here
I'm gonna I'm gonna try and teach them
maybe I can turn them into an army like
I did you guys think about it's gonna
I'm gonna teach them wait wouldn't that
make these guys like or a chi or
something sure I don't know maybe I
don't know I'm gonna teach these guys
and I'm gonna have a little army and I'm
gonna protect the elf town and so dead
bones remained to lead I'll lead the
porks our four adventures left roaming a
little bit salty that you know that
never nobody likes his brother had to
shovel them up like that like a nickel
at the end I mean just saving his ass
and you know what they were walking by
Phineas was just like see Robin I told
you today just like you fucking hate you
mom should've aborted you just kept
going whoa leaving he's gonna rename it
you know what brief yeah I'm not really
chilly Willie's chilly Willie's wizard
crew lets you learn a food-truck chili
willies chili Wiz Zee's wild biddies
that's we are mean like old ladies like
biddies kanga I don't know why I don't
know question I'm the boss okay boss
this is gonna be fine while I leave I
toss the mirror over my shoulder all
right it doesn't wait I need you to roll
one more dive into the game this lesson
I want to know if the mirror broke and
Portville was released in which case ten
poses in trouble later or if it just
landed it's just lost in the caves oh my
god you know what you know what we're
just we're just not gonna have to answer
that question that's what he did that
the exits that's fine yeah who who knows
what happened there on that that's too
good at 22 for me to give an ending to
it's a role hanger who knows all right
thank you everyone for coming again this
week I hope you guys have a lot of fun
we do this every Saturday here on coast
channel we're gonna be doing it almost
every week in summer we'll probably have
a couple weeks off but we're gonna be
here next weekend so I hope you guys
liked it I hope you guys enjoyed it if
you want to watch this on youtube you
can watch it on the Bruce Willis channel
I'm sure somebody will be on chat to let
you know where the the pods are kept you
can go to our subreddit if you want to
discuss it remember there's t-shirts
that are just for this week of last
week's filipe assurance if you want them
and awesome honestly guys this is the
second week in the row where you guys
have just blown us away I'm like I'm
really really really happy that this is
gonna be something we can do every week
because it's a whole lot of fun to put
on and it's a whole lot of people work
on this so thanks again for all your
guys support and I hope you have a great
weekend and we'll see you guys next week
yay everybody
you