[Music]
all right helpless
Justin your anti-party you have to do
something anti-party if you do not do if
I feel you don't know you hadn't good
enough I'm gonna play for you
alright I'm casting uh Blizzard Oh God
God in this three East in this area here
okay so let me get the let's take this
Blizzard I really want to blink out of
it but I think I wouldn't know it was
coming so I'm not going wait hold on
interrupt
yeah you can interrupt with you tomorrow
sorry actually wait you any what's going
on you have to do a perception role to
see if you know yeah we wouldn't have
knows you don't even know if we put okay
we both do it or just ramen you could
both do it if you want to both try to
interrupt yeah I was thinking uh Roman
no Roman notices so hey and me gimme you
can see if you know yes
then you can decide who's gonna do it
okay you both notice that Justin is
channeling a blizzard at you you look at
his eyes his eyes are like emerald green
you're like okay Justin this blue box
what that's not right all right
Roman you're gonna be blinding Justin uh
that's my plan so I'm a right I don't
know what's going on yeah just I can't
let that happen
Brooke can roam interrupt and then can I
interrupt yeah so Roma candid rotators
yeah so Roma you can blind him first if
you want all right
catalyst near site
mmm nine okay so no he's nearsighted so
Justin you could not Blizzard you're
you're not able to bliss it you can only
do things with a melee range of one or
you can spend the turn clearing the near
sight basically hmm yeah I'm still I'm
still in a dumpster I'm thank you to be
a tea party though so what do you want
to do yeah well uh I think my only
option really is to clear the new your
site right that's your choice well I
mean I I could always hit you could I
blink in two dead bones I was like right
by your side you can't see yeah like
blinking you'd have to roll twenty rails
for going into the water and gotcha
you're not well right now you're not
afraid of the water so well I figure all
right so anti-party I'm uh I'm just
walking myself into the water
oh god you wouldn't you wouldn't be self
I would do that you wouldn't all right
Gillies for yourself is it you know I
guess I'm just trying to well go for Co
it was a lot here oh yeah I could walk
up to him right yeah all right go go
walking walking right it played no don't
hit him open it up with a firewall I
want to interrupt him blink well can I
borrow you doing that first day for what
for you do it no he's not using world
ladies just fireable okay okay and then
i'm using the board myself
philia good a little like one who knows
what's happening here right
well no mean Roman saw him okay so do
demos do you want to actually blink to
stop this fireball cast wait wait I'm
sorry I'm going actually no I am going
to be a I'm going to blink onto the
bridge they both know what's happening
Co yeah we didn't happen they saw Oh
Justin Oh cast both of them saw Justin
trying to attack them Roman okay with
the near sight so dead knows what's
going on so after the nearside happened
Justin started like bull rushing you
because he want to attack you so dead
bones is coming to save you though I'm
just coming to bling it up blank
alright you can blink so ten spaces one
to get me on the fridge five six seven
eight nine you can blink right up to him
boom
okay and election before he tries the
fire but I've got my free basic attack
yeah you do free basic attack you're
gonna attach it a good punch I haven't
got a way to just go yeah you're just
gonna punch him in the head just gonna
punch him for head right make it a race
good yeah to try okay you miss though
you're really really used to your may
swing you didn't get it so you I have
the rest of my action you still have the
rest of your blink yep that was just
your bonus okay I'm going to use tosser
on Justin okay and I'm gonna try and
throw him at the sea I just wanted to
make sure he didn't do anything to us
yeah actually no I wouldn't because I
know just doesn't like in the water now
I'm not gonna use tosser um is justice
the casting the fireball uh he's about
to yeah you missed your uh yeah I still
got an action but moon if you throw him
in this in the snake maybe old calf
students may be cast into the put
something on his hand and then we can't
cast things you could just push code of
the way to yak I try and push : dance
yeah I just want try and push Co out of
the way
yeah or you could toss go under the rock
you can't make it them no I just gotta
I'm just gonna try to push Co out of the
way this isn't even this isn't even
kisses Dave's balls whatever he's fine
with it
alright so she goes oh I gotta push Co
but you again you like don't you don't
push him hard enough you just go yeah
dynamic oh yeah cuz I lose this left it
was a good of a weak push
all right now hearts oh my fireball time
oh my god crits so bad I don't wanted to
crit worse than that if you crits I I
think I can I can help I can solve this
17 all right so fireball is in fact
nine-day night can I interrupt with a
chivalry fork oh yeah you can
I'm gonna use chili for Co so
warriorship early yeah just whatever
this entails and una cosa it's a six
damn it okay uh you can still take you
can still take the hit
yeah so you jump into the way
you're gonna take eight one two three
four five six seven eight
all right now I'm going for the vorpal
Oh God in this specific case uh-huh I
will give you one copy of fireball even
though it's not Elliot okay yeah I got a
free fireball spell nice spell where
armor has given you a fireball for the
love it's bravery
love it hey let's see if that bones dice
oh this is too important or probably oh
yeah it's not to see if they know that
part is dead bones important oh honey
Devils six another - it's not 20 yeah
it's just that's the end of my third
that's the egg turn alright you're gonna
wake up fine control
oh do it only last one turned the mind
control yeah don't last one turn you're
now free from the mind control so the
serpent snake moves closer to Roman
whispers in the Romans here Roman now
you know what's coming you can try to
resist the whisper so give her give me a
roll Roman I was waiting from to say but
I don't want to win I resist the whisper
Rob no I'm sorry you've been whispering
the years your mind controlled this turn
the Goblin is dead so now it is Romans
turn Roman your anti-party your parties
all the way over there what can you do
to be imperfect all away from me
um I'm going to go ahead and mmm
hmm now we'll just do this I'm gonna go
ahead and Ravenclaw on Co and dead bones
since they're the clothes done - well
it's a 2x2 square okay that's so on that
I thought oh so yep go ahead and roll
jeez oh shit sorry oh yes okay so you
are gonna ravenclaw
that's gonna be one damage um man it's
this so you're a tea party you Ravenclaw
Lautrec Kim if we're gonna we're going
to do this properly you roll the one you
were trying to do that so you're gonna
attack your ally and this is going to
break your mind control attacking this
so if you want you could now use your
move you've been freed behind my control
oh well the only so thing like that
how much does that do that's five damage
I believe oh I'm three four five all
right
um can I learn them now that something
doesn't seem to be right yeah yeah you
can be like okay my control don't let
him whisper in your ear no okay all
right guys something's not right
I'm not a big fan of dead bones but I
got really no beef with Coe so I don't
know what's going on careful about the
snake just not a fan of your dead bones
like I mean really I get one we're gonna
whop runnin all right um okay the snake
this is this not cool you don't be mind
controlling people uh going with the
wind blast are you use a turn no he
already does no I don't you thought I
got her no just a move yeah you move I'm
juiced Evelyn I usually party so much
it's cuz these kills are not late you're
the only one in the link for the
whispers make this whispering - um yeah
you know what let me yeah I'm gonna leap
over to this rock
okay give me a roll
oh boy okay shut up up you leave me to
the rock you jump the wrong way you're
in the water
Wow gonna go it's your turn
can I have my mace back oh yeah yeah
yeah saved my ass
boom mace alright uh you go to pass the
mace to dead bones and you notice that
the mace was not actually a mace but it
was just a stick dead bones mace appears
to be at the bottom of the ocean
there goes the mace is gone whoa I'm
sorry bones I'm just gonna snap the
stick damage just a stick to I just snap
like this you don't like boy wait we
don't know
oh you roll to snap the snake please
snap this I got a roll of snap the stick
I want to know if I can do bigots I
can't let you snap the snake you just
snap the stick
hashtag snap the snake up snap the snake
all right go
what you can do for your turn now kill
it um I'm going to can I do an inventory
check yeah when I got it for well I
guess I know I have the mirror sight oh
wait I already used the Ruby - never
mind I use the mirror in the movie you
saw yeah you know you got them yeah I
just didn't do you forget no you know
about the room because you know Romans
had it so when you had it you knew to
use it like you knew his right hour so
okay hey Dave hi oh I'm not David okay
yeah okay
excuse me there
Oh David still a little bit of pain
after being you know punched his balls
on the articles poster in the dick yep
hey still not you still kind of pain Oh
what is it what do you guys want now so
we've got this like whispery dragon
situation thing going on over here
it's like right there yeah you see it
yeah I don't think I could really help I
mean I would I would have loved to go
slay some porks with you guys but you
kind of wiped out me in my battalion
over here I'm
can condemn any ice I could really use
nice back man yeah hold on here comes
Hey wait and this is I got your debit
just as like your tape oh yeah alright
see you summon is frost elemental yeah
finally right yes Cathy whispered I
guess I do
oh my so you try to get the good water
uh but you kind of miss and you get like
this murky muddy water so it's not
really a water elemental he's kind of a
sludge elemental this hasn't actually
affected stats but he's a lot less
attractive and so people are gonna look
at him and go oh that's that you
conjured there's a shine team they're
gonna think less of you as a sorcerer so
right okay didn't can I put my seaweed
on his head make him a girl should
transfer series yeah I'm dreading making
pretty it'll help a little bit so the
reason why code looks like he's at max
health is because this maximum health
has been decreased by 10 for summoning
this thing so yeah so keep that in mind
so here is your guy OOP yeah slut
discipline see we don't have Hades kqf
so see we done said alright Dave got
that ice panic for me I'll thanks thanks
yeah let me let me just get that oh that
yeah that feels no no not that feels
good right there there we go
alright you know no problem I think I'm
gonna need a while I don't think I
wouldn't be able to do the same mistake
but you know you're a good guy unlike
that leader yours whoa hold on a second
this was this was so you'd help us now
yeah yeah I'm still kind of in pain I
didn't forget that chance to regenerate
my stamina I had literally one die if I
go in and help I could drown
alright take a turn meditate
and then you better be checking in we're
gonna we're gonna roll to see if he's
brave enough to actually get up and go
into battle after all that shit you guys
pulled uh he's not brave enough oh he's
not gonna be assisting you in battle
he might follow you after this but he's
dave has no interest
hey buzz even realized that you guys
decapitated one of his friends yet he
hasn't this guy under due today
this guy's still passed out Dave's skill
sitting he enjoyed he's got this
elemental kind of like like he's
touching his balls so that's nice and
that's big right good
puppets forget all that shit go help
your friend out think it over
we'll talk later all right thanks scuse
me Dave okay uh so your elemental spent
his turn
I guess cooling off this guy's balls you
summoned so that makes it dead bones the
string yeah a devil's I need you to Road
to a role before you do anything okay
that's never good yeah so so if that
whole situation turns him on okay thank
you okay
dead bones falls into the water
Oh No Oh am i dead oh my god all right
Devils you know you fell in the water
you're not sure why but while you were
down there you found a new weapon and it
gave you a promotion you're now
lieutenant as well
you know what I did here lieutenant this
is Dennis captain this mace still does 4
damage but it allows you to do an arc of
lightning
that'll bounce up to two nearby enemies
it'll it can bounce up to three times
and it does two damage so it can do an
extra six damage if you balance it
between things you can control how it
arcs that's so broken rich oh cool all
right all right sick that's like some
ACE cuz I - you're okay - okay okay
dad that's odd yes all right all right
uh so my turn right yeah Roman so I only
want you can get back onto the bridge -
that my turn or no no it's your turn
okay so isn't wait was my move getting
on the bridge know that was nothing that
was just an event okay I'm gonna I'm
gonna come back over two coats a right
of cohere I gone the bank and I'm gonna
go check yo whoa I found this that looks
really dangerous it's gonna kill a lot
of shit okay
I mean is Justin just okay that's all I
want
so you guys know I'm a now I'm now a
lieutenant lieutenant captain lieutenant
captain yeah leftenant leftenant captain
whatever you want to call whatever we
don't speak communist rut them elf here
back to the fight again oh wait so you
talk about my happy Oh what the hell all
right um so I'm again I'm just um
you know actually am I gonna set up a
blockade they're gonna tell Co Jojo and
Justin like you know get yourself LOC
aid get behind me
I don't think this thing's got range
attacks all right
right this probably gets free spells no
we ever use fulfills never name yeah
everyone this so this blockade you're
setting up uh to do it because of the
power of your lighting bolt you're so
you're so is a copy that you're gonna
leap into the air
would you like to land anywhere are you
just doing a bounce I'll let you jump
all the way over here
I'll to jump onto the bridge you're
super excited but it's just it's still a
blockade little block it your blockade
set up but you can set this up anywhere
you want no I just want a key I want to
keep my me like one over next to go I
guess so he's kind of okay gains the
benefit I have to move all right I do
where else would I go
Roman you get a free spell you're in the
water but you're still gonna be able to
cast it okay um can I use my claw to
pick me up
yes you can ooh all right I want to use
my collar picked me up and put me on the
bridge okay you're tired of this Rock
garbage I don't think your honor I think
you're in the water well no I know but
I'm B I don't want I don't want to deal
with I don't want it beyond the rug I
rocks beneath you okay you're back on
the bridge Oh
Co you get a free spell alright so this
isn't a turn right no this is just this
is just a spell anything that's listed a
spell you can cast the frost element is
great right you does he's not enough
okay is he not in the shape of an elf Co
than I you put some elf hair are you put
smell good Simmons peed on him you know
what to do well you should get behind me
but uh that's probably a good idea it's
probably I'll move behind you yeah oh
wait this isn't a fucking don't trick me
dead bones this is a turn can't move
yeah this is like like tricking go oh he
can pick himself Holly look at its tells
you're like just telling me stuff I'm
just like oh yeah you know go into town
get some groceries yeah God what to do
here I think yesterday right I don't
really have a oh I guess I can I hit him
with a good grand ravenclaw I'll do that
I'm hitting the snake all right nice
tell father give me a roll
all right bubble boom Oh what taking it
as a lens doesn't matter yeah
everybody's fine you him for five yay
one two three four five
alright is now justice my trick yeah
it's muttering just our job it behind me
and fire off some it wicked spells yeah
I'm gonna I'm gonna skip I'm dead bones
ear mm-hmm and I'm gonna throw fireball
fireball okay yeah you don't to be
worried about ever hitting dead bones
during a blockade like the worst
scenario is just you know do no damage
to him I mean I wasn't worried in a
sense that in the sense that it could
happen if it happens yeah you want
you're not worried you see the bad I
have enough self it's like basically not
ever gonna happen 9 all right you shoot
the fireball it whizzes right past them
it sends us him just a little bit for to
okay and uh that's it okay she's
protected intact Oh
prefect I've murdered Edwin reattached
stabbed dead bones okay so the whisper
snake is going to move right up to here
is gonna whisper into dead bones this
here so now I know Gabe belongs to the
whisper snake oh do I not get the cuz
we're already alert us I don't get to I
don't get to trial I'm sorry yes you get
to roll cuz like we know that it's
trying to do this shit roaming shouting
I've done lettuce for well I know you
want fun things to happen oh but it's
not going to happen cuz my man oh you
whispering I mean as a lieutenant you're
not gonna listen to any more so Lee did
I whisper it back and I missed the bag
heavy dead be a 20 by shifting whisper
bad we invented way all right
Roman it is your turn now then okay ah
does a snake still look to be in good
shape
is it feisty ya know the snake still
looks really feisty alright um and
there's nothing else really going on we
just got a goblin it's logic Rock dead
goblin it's just about the snake right
now okay everybody's aware of these guys
shenanigans all right let's uh
let's go with someone blast okay that's
like I have to do a roll but it's a fun
inning year-old the 19 so all right you
blast the snake with wind blast hitting
them for 9 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9
did you want to move it all um smooth
you know what no I'm good here
get good position I'm staying ok Co it's
your turn so remember you can control
your eye Salman till 2 he could do ray
of frost or you can start stacking up
damage with the was it cold ice bolt
nice blast wait what's the what's the
benefit versus ice plus so ice bolt does
1 damage plus one additional damage for
every ice bolts has been fired by a
frosted elemental or you so having
multiple fossil pencils lets them stack
it up because it goes up to 5 damage so
then they can be a free 5 damage but you
don't have ice bolt so it would take him
five turns to the max damage whereas
yeah you could just use him to rail
frost and potentially stun the whispers
think alright so since we're done with
Dave's balls I'm gonna have him move
over here okay and I'm gonna have him do
an ice bolt or whatever great frost I
mean just looking bad Chad good
okay uh um for to damage you do not stun
him though
okay as for myself anything this I can't
really stun him out
I can blanket of darkness him oh sure oh
my god drive it insane yep I'm gonna
make him go mad he's gonna whisper to
himself he's gonna whisper to us no okay
uh what's a three by three we got a look
we haven't used this one yet
blanket of darkness 2 2 2 2 4x4 area oh
I need to get some proper tiles that are
actually 4x4 and stuff this is right
though turn off the grid okay so where
do you want this you want to make sure
if you you don't want it touching you
guys at all right you want to like right
here yeah okay there you go okay look
just whisper snake all right so he's
what I'm a blank of Darius the targets
inside the field of darkness slowly lose
control their mind each turn and can't
see or tact through it so they can they
can move out of it but they have to roll
to see if they're losing their mind
so basically rolls one he's gonna
whisper himself you're driving that city
yeah alright demos it's your turn your
blockade has just ended mmm I just think
Oh er still they're still in range of a
blocking if I put it up again right yep
okay cuz I'm just god I'm hmm cuz I
can't control flare wait can I see in
this night in the smoke yeah it's it's a
blanket of darkness okay you guys can
see through it fine
it's do you know are stuck in it okay
that's not like this ah so they know
it's not like the fog think of it like
uh like like stuck in a it's like it's
like ya know it's like it's thinking
like a smoke that you can see through so
a really light smoke but inside of it it
causes them to go mental so this okay
like it affects the guys in the smoke so
badly that they can't actually control
themselves so okay I'm just going to set
up another blockade
we thought you said on the blockade oh
yeah fine for blockades and I'm in raged
for Rome and so don't worry Rome you're
fine I don't need you sure I'm gonna
keep lobbing fireballs so doing sickness
okay
again you with the fireball family you
hit this to go back to fireball school
yeah at this thing for years damage
he's a chilly wizzy he's not used to
fire spells yeah the color a trifle
let's see if the whisper snake goes muck
and cook goes mad for the love of God do
not give me a one come on come on come
on insanity come on Bert ah okay I
whisper snake is not going mad but this
area is still going to be affected so
the whisper snake is he's gonna go up on
I need to whisper
I can't whisper Justin I'm gonna whisper
co Wow do I get to go get the just a
defensive role I'll tell you the second
depends what I wrote depends on his
whisper roll no cramped you erm I know
and then the whisper snake is gonna go
onto the bridge and he's gonna be away
from us yeah he's gonna pop a behind
Roman huh oh shit
it's doing something it's gonna puke on
ahahahaha
alright the whispers the whisper state
canal do a hydro pump each turn which
does massive damage knocks back in
addition going over the whisper so he's
going to blast room in the back your
sight
alright do I see this uh yeah you would
like to give you under the bridge yeah
you were saw and go under the bridge you
would have heard him go ahead and roll
for an ear sight okay come on you guys
right resis you try to use things but it
doesn't happen so Roman is five but I'd
only get next to him could I still
chiller ewwww yeah you can over Shirley
as long as you can yeah as long as you
get you enter them hey I'm gonna I'm
gonna chivalry cursed all chivalry me I
got this no I'm Shelby I got this
Hillary I told you I had this now you're
wet well Lisa nook yep you're just gonna
be worse for you in a second okay
think you think I went here comes the
Hydra Pope you guys are about to be
hugging in the water
Oh God wrong you're gonna get some I'm
gonna win blast dodge ok runway to go
for the where are you in such oh man
alright I'll let you shift out of the
way but you still be on the bridge
somewhere nothing fancy
uh I'm just gonna move a couple spaces
all right and then the blast of water
goes flying forward all right Roman is
now your turn oh okay um cannot move
this turn because you used wooden blasts
keep that in mind yes
all right um let's use uh actually I
want to use grand
ravenclaw to try to stun okay you're
gonna try to hold him yeah
squeeze the snake clever yes all right
all right Wisco nearest ins right yeah
um so you need to you need to deist
Aminah me for my uh magic sauce yeah the
cloud thing oh thank you I would have
been - yeah uh-huh
alright I think it's the first thing
you've done since you did the elemental
so that's why your stamina is that mic
cuz it's not at all on okay that's a
relative bar yeah calling over my hold
on I decide who's gonna get stunt bald
on oh I'm sorry
now Roman knows that co is stunned so he
wouldn't try it dead bones is in the
water he wouldn't really be able to see
me I guess man I'm gonna stun stun the
water now uh hmm who's the worst person
I can stun with a one I guess it's gonna
be yourself Roman physics you know
you're holding yourself believes like oh
my god what if I stun Dave he was
meditating over there Dave off his balls
man he shipped off a piece of this well
I'm Shawn Michaels heads like oh thanks
frost bill Whittle your hands just great
on my balls
um okay so it's coaster code you are
anti-party this turn yep you're calling
over my ice elemental and I'm having him
rape frost on Justin okay correct
odet role for him or exactly no you
girlfriend yep he's your pen well ah
just my dodge is Justin I take one
damage just getting clip really wants to
take damage I even take damage I got
this coat on yes yes I'm sorry yeah I
don't know yeah oh that one
Jack was completely in vain yeah code me
forgot that yeah that ray of Frost just
goes into the codis went boom and it
kind of just like bounced off just as
belly let's see
so now Cole you have to keep that in
mind with trying to do any magic attacks
against Justin you've remembered again
oh yeah Justin's really resisted the
magical decks so you probably wouldn't
do a magic attack against Justin right
what about a magical attack that does
physical damage Oh like what summon shit
Lord and have him yet no it was a good
one
some tall Earth Lord they're not made of
poop oh my God he's gonna have that
forever it has to be before I just kill
it kill Justin forever oh fuck God he's
off to your feet Lord uh
no you're selling it but you summon him
in the water
uh and he turns the mud so he's just
like kind of like falling apart already
in the water but he really wants to get
his goal of kill Justin so he's like oh
he's trying to turn yeah just a diarrhea
monster he has summoned in the wrong
place hey God hope there's no part of
that
dead bones it's her turn alright it's
not made of poop if you find poop you
can show me the shit Lord until then
they're made of you know easy he's just
used to summing them in town where
there's a lot of you know horse shit oh
yes great horse anyway props how high up
is the bridge uh you can climb up up
onto it could I climb up yeah with would
like would it take my move to climb up
on it absolutely okay
I sell my action right yes okay just
making sure
just make sure you know what no I'm
gonna go actually I'm not gonna go next
to Co instead I'm gonna swim okay go
ahead you know ro see if I'm a good
swimmer eighteen all right better
swimmer the movies I'm a pretty good
swimmer you guys and uh I'm just gonna
throw a flare at him again I can I heat
actually can flare yeah and
it flares like 10 is it is it the first
10 right left I was ten uh sorcerer Flay
with five that's five o'clock oh can I
hit that's why it's Annabelle that's
five damage for one but yeah no you
can't hit him from there well then I'm
just two three four five not even close
alright I'm just gonna set up another
blockade locate defending the realm all
right you set up a blockade but it's not
really inspiring hear what Ceaser like
yeah great you don't even have a shield
I don't like this lock it with my knee
um okay so you're blocking it's just
this turn then yep yeah Justin your turn
alright I just I me again well my
fireball reach from I yell definitely
real career you get behind meteor right
there alright so so I'm gonna turn what
was that third time's the charm with any
of the fireball I think I know it
oh yeah they call you chilly wizzy cuz
you're very good with fuck you with G
chilly busy I was a whore well that's no
that wasn't real that was a problem
that's okay up fantastic just a little
bit better you Nick them for - yeah I
mean I'm doing damage I'm gonna lean
back on to Dave's balls cuz I'm so
chilly okay lean back
yeah I'm does I'm like leaning into his
eyes into like his crotch it is yeah
yeah yeah you're honest yeah just just
resting like resting my back my head on
it I go for you here excellent perfect
and that's what sir all right uh the
whisper snake is going to dive under the
water zone man Who am I gonna whisper I
mean the only one that was like oh
idioms that are really close shit water
he's gonna wish it sorry on his side
he's you know we ass right hand side
he's gonna whisper up and he guess he's
gonna try to whisper co again mm I'm
gonna try to wish for Co Co gets to
defend
- now when I'm mind-controlled still 80
nope
KO doesn't get to code you can enroll
the resist I roll so this is your chance
to resist because you went on his turn
code breaks yeah break seems to come
back and whisper - yeah and you don't
actually you you're whispered again
you're like yes my emerald snake I will
I will continue other ends I live too
soon uh and then he's gonna try and
hydro pump Roman again wait no what was
gonna stand here remember they can ask
yes oh you can't even your blonde even
arose I can't hit you I can't really hit
you yeah I gotta go for Roman goddamn
rogue UK even can't even interrupt fuck
nope
Sean for um so Robin it just misses goes
right past you so it is now Roman Stern
mm-hm
no but he was stunned from his hand
what's that Roman Scott break out of
your hand to get your back
oh yeah that's pretty strong I mean
which was a left-hander since your ghost
hand it's a ghost and that's 11 so you
don't break out of your stuff okay
Co you are AG party now I am I not
understood till my next turn you're on
slow down you can win bliss okay okay
alright get over here hombre hombre all
right we're gonna do ray of frost again
at Justin oh wait no we're not we're not
because we learned mmm so I'm gonna do
at the guy blockading how much like
physical damage does this the elemental
do or does he not do physical um here's
the physical attacks but you could have
on punch people and I'll give them a
damage value basically we can punch
people for damage soon it's like norm or
punch for one but I would just use one
spell here I'm sorry of frost on Roman
okay
I see this happening yeah
do you really only wind blast out the
way of this you won't be a massage like
he can stun it yeah and he can stop bad
I was on your side it okay oh yeah yeah
unison yeah I mean I see this thing
casting something at me yeah yeah you're
like no no Kay
none of this whisper garbage yep all
right sixteen okay you near-sighted so
now this can only do spells in one range
so it interrupts that that's his turn so
now it's your turn co alright um I wanna
do Co I'm going to do do Co summon
another shit Lord to attack Justin and
evil code does not like Justin well it's
you have a feeling it's the oh yeah it's
the only available it's flowing so our
only option yeah where the fuck is to
die oh there it is that's hiding near
darkness I think in Luke you move the
dirt busy sure oh I didn't see that was
the best part of pestilence disease
hmm yeah fourteen though he could recast
it I mean he could just straight-up be
like you like you guys got a son
whatever god why do I say that more you
should learn attack your teen shit Lord
and not your summoning another shit Lord
yeah okay I like that
then this other shit Lord is going to
finally climb out of the water but
riffing Justin this shit loads going to
actually attack Justin right away and
hits Justin for three yeah and where
does not stop pieces of dirt stone
punching you in the face
also I meant to charge me for stamina
for last time and this time
mm and it's 2 per for him too yeah
it's not super low last time I do
shitlord and I think that's all I did
yeah shitload shitlord got it okay uh
dead bones it's your turn you're
blocking my bow Kate has borne up first
thing I'm gonna do I'm gonna pop a
rejuvenation potion okay so that's test
yet to step for buzz wait this is $10
1510 I thought was 1515 I'll tell you
that's what that old card says okay it's
10 okay cuz the new card is going to say
it's okay that's it yeah whenever the
new cards each card is going to say you
can use more than one for fight and the
view curve is going to say all sorts of
things ten standard drink is potion it's
not constant action okay cool okay so I
still got my move my actions good um-hmm
is that snake in range of a melee attack
from me oh yeah absolutely not totally
glue yeah it's red all right door yeah
so first things first are gonna flare in
Claire fist good old therapist oh all
right uh so your flare hits him your
flare hits um just a little on the weak
side four four one two three four three
basic and the in the the snake the what
are there what is this guy's name
whispers nice person ink the whisper
snake dies he goes uh he just dies yeah
he you just you based on the flare you
shoot him with this weak-ass flare but
to shoot it like down his mouth as he
was trying to I was if I was a close
range one it was a close range down his
mouth hit a little stomach
you don't even know if that's really
dead he's just restricted yes just gone
he's gone back down into the water
well did it read it however combat is
still going okay all right well that's
my turn so it's Justin I guess well
Terrell you'd have a free attack oh no
way that was not oh yeah I do my free
attack but what am i hmm
smack the skies no I'm going to I'm
gonna attack the shitlord Justin yeah
really brave man attacking little
shitlords I just kill him dragon shut up
ko is no longer whispered snake so he's
not gonna take this hit oh but you miss
good great like right that's right
there's so here's how it works
coastal longer mine consoled when when
these uh little earth Lords get attacked
Kobe there has to take the damage or
have the earth Lord die so if you were
still mind controlled he'd probably take
the damage but he's no longer mine
controlled so these things basically
take any sort of damage they're just
going to fall apart so I got a leak
blending I did it I did it with the
making right so Justin it's your turn
you're currently relaxing on Dave's
balls mm-hmm uh like one of my options
but what's hard is to earth Lord's come
and hit you
the way these guys well up Justin all
right uh hmm give a spelling a look you
like a low-cost spell you can use on
that one you could literally hell with
the stick
you could candle if you don't have I
could ice blast no even when I do I
splash into a lot oh yeah I'll hit
everyone else you can just punch him
it's either punch him or know your vocal
type
I have my dagger yeah mmm re I'm gonna
try to dagger this shit poke it yeah
your shit Lord all right oh you swing
and you miss at the shit Lord damn it
wow I just continued relaxing on Dave's
balls from your relaxed position you
just like tried to like you're like just
sitting down in Dave's lap okay yeah
like a slice and Dave's like you know
what you're kind of pretty and you're
like you or to say if I love you and
then Dave perhaps and then you and then
you kind of like take your blading--
like get outta here earth Lord like what
are you doing you know if you know I
could have killed me hit me 20 times
leave me alone and you just kind of
missed with your whips
[Music]