okay so what do you want you have the
troubie now so you can move ten okay um
basically want to move to about here
that's what I want to be at max range
okay so one two or three uh it's like
here's good here's good
you sure yeah okay yeah well this way
I've line-of-sight okay yeah looks like
it go into the air and steal this
treasure which is actually there take it
back man it's swinging the card it's
jacket all right let's go and okay so
he's blinded I'm gonna go ahead and win
blast I'm tired of this crap he's going
to town or elf buddies everywhere yeah
and for once it's not us killing them
all
all of them innings yeah well we're
helping 15 all right so you hit him four
nine one two three four five six five
six
I'm he's blinded he's not gonna see this
coming and I can't win blast one two
three four five six seven eight nine
okay go ahead
uh it's anything less if you want to
hurt nope I'm good it's his turn he's
blinded so he's just gonna
he knows he's surrounded so he's going
to he's going to just wildly swing all
those weapons I don't want him real
frosting so I'm just gonna have him
wildly swing all three of his weapons so
the first one he's trying to he doesn't
even know where he's aiming so I don't
really know how I'm gonna do this I'm
just gonna randomly pick so first weapon
19:03 so 19
20 this is the cobalt least anything
he's just okay so he's gonna he's gonna
do this
Justin you're gonna take three from one
of the hits from the wild hits now can i
jewelry that I was gonna steal tell you
again what Oh out of this and he can be
simple yeah yeah can i shovelry into
justin you can just chevrolet and adjust
then it would go like this yes what
would happen yeah then you would take
that's what I want okay two three let's
go far oh very nice so you take the
three then red is gonna take three here
I just wanted to get a melee range and
then yellow is gonna take the critical
and just get trucked for 6 so 1 2 3 4 or
5 like that or I can't believe you don't
want to use a pick-up line
no that's you know that's on that's not
a pro pin appropriate Roman it's it's a
work relationship I thought you made him
your number two for a reason I didn't
plan to get surrounded I didn't actually
write this happen did you accept he warp
blades
wait hold on
interrupting get an ear sight him
because he was blinded before I was like
I don't need to do it yeah you rolled
the 20 no don't go off okay yes all
right
dead bones is nearsighted what sorry I
love people he missed someone's getting
hit also I'm not sorry yeah I know I'm
Bailey right didn't really care okay so
now it is co-stars turn do you want your
spirits to go first or second Co glad I
have them go well after after private
ice Lord private ice Lord okay private
ice Lord I think you'd still see them
yeah you're fine you can still see them
against the mountain
well he might as well just do a ray of
Frost then no need to move and people
said that having a guy who gets done
every turn would be bad except he's
gotten too negated two turns already
from this one pet misses hits just the
wall
Tuukka the ball okay now the little shit
Lords can go excuse me 1 2 3 4 5 1 2 3 4
5 fuck is this one doing 1 2 3 4 5 he's
feeling a little slow he's gonna go a
little extra this one is one to go what
are you doing
summon earth Lord I like eventually
they're gonna swarm mustn't you you
summon one buddy summon him out here you
know I like Roman how he's playing like
an actual therus where he just yes some
honorable line of guys
don't forget to take my stand yeah so to
stand with you alright it's time
oh I should be at did you take another
one
I should I smile I did the interrupts
and I wouldn't last I should be 11 okay
um just so you guys know they can all
see the exact numbers of their stamina
you guys just get a fancy bar to guess
with well we kind of need to know what
the exact numbers are yeah I know Chad
doesn't thinking they can just guess
guesstimate scarier the good faces yeah
it's so great yeah I think you think
they can figure it out from expressions
I was looking ok he's still smiling
freaking just think everybody's smiling
you said this is ray of Frost ray of
frost two elves 13 hits them both 11 is
dead his red dead spread is 1 2 3 4 5
yep
they're not dead they're just
unconscious I know has anyone died died
yet I don't think he's killed anyone you
know I don't he's killed any elves just
a separate part exploded one right kill
it though it just knocked it out and
then after that he's going to do hmm I
can't do two whirlwinds because I'll
kill them both so I have two whirlwind
than work so he's gonna do a whirling
blade and hits three just one that's
Rama doesn't want it to and kills the
other you don't want to stop these do
you Roman they're three damaged now it's
okay yeah Anthony and aim you're both
yeah they're twins god damn it this guy
I've almost got through all the ads I'm
all those time I've spent the last
couple tours just chasing this fucker
down Rocky's running away I mean you
could be shit really if you want to keep
these elves no yeah but then I be
shipped on the damage yeah oh I guess he
could have got that he's good at then
but yeah he'd be taking the hits for
these days he doesn't care about that
much they're not fatal squad elves
they're not pay two squirrels man it's
true
all right it's now no dead bones turn
those just near sight effect movement no
so I can still move my five spaces yeah
it's just for trying to do range attacks
okay well then I'm gonna get here I
guess next to him again okay
and finally oh man I haven't died since
so long I'm scared I'm real I it's been
so long all right I'm gonna use a flare
fists are clenched three three
all right so I get the hit with the mace
it pops this demon yep Hiromi you want
to take the damage for that terrowin you
want to take the damage the five damage
that went into one of your minions for
now I'm sorry Saviour all right and then
I get to get to masive in the face
basically we're gonna put that on the
wiki the Saviour understood
what he was getting into but he was sup
okay they knew they'd sign up for this
oh the greater good oh god that's a bad
role rule is a bad rule wrong way come
on mace mace in your face
that's four and then lightning so four
and then lightning came bouncing him it
has to bounce with someone else cast
about it has to bounce this one has them
back no well yeah I mean I'm gonna miss
bouncing off earth Lords like I'm gonna
bounce it off these sprites to hit him
as deep as I can
one two three you can only do one so
there's only ugh worth detector at once
I'll bounce it once well you wanted to
get for this guy what's that mean no
it's wrong no that's like three damage
right yeah three and then it's another
three so that's 4 plus 3 7 1 2 3 &amp; 4 5 6
yeah all right bro it is now his turn
man he doesn't like getting hit by that
lightning bolt and you're not blockading
good no I'm not alright
so he's going to do he's gonna summon
earth air spirits wait oh god what he
knows this no I don't want to do that so
wasting my turn
why don't we complain about that yeah I
don't know he's gonna do he's he's gonna
cast uh-oh man justin has a way to light
my fog mmm
Justin's like this best ally so far you
kidding me okay here we go
I know what to do here we go Ralph's
lost in a line Oh time I'm going to
blink out one rage because of because of
your size I can still blink oh I thought
bleep was in trouble yeah yeah you can
do that that's fine I'm just rolling
make sure it happens it's gonna be a to
me anyway yeah right go ahead and double
wink buddy yeah I'll be joining him yeah
Justin was the blink 250 nifty you're
the worst I can move one space when I
get a free attack yeah Justin blink out
of the way you guys will get your free
action your free turns Oh Justin your
blink failed
yes you take the damage from your blink
but they definitely failed so dead bones
he roll the natural 20 so you're not
gonna be able to interrupt this in any
way you just gonna keep going yeah so
I'm actually gonna have his go and then
you can take you later
that's fine yeah so do you want to take
damage for this guy Roman in the end
damage is 10 I will pass okay another
blue spell blade gets taken out Justin
you are gonna take 10 but you have your
armor so you're only gonna take more and
is that another separate spell what do
you mean rain frost is that a it is
spelled yes or no I already got hit by
anybody happens but I don't never gonna
let you have multiples you can I'm
saying that's just that's still just a
ray of frost to hit it okay
frost yeah here's the erases light
that's one of no does Justin get
cowardly a frost no because he got hit
with an empowered version no I didn't
see Grace's light and doesn't have the
the special thing light inside of him
yeah just checking
yeah yeah I know okay okay now I guess
that's trying to see what I can get from
this I know right so Justin sucks that
damage however the good old Davy is
gonna get hit by this oh and Davey gets
hit for 10 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 and now
he's stunned that's a lot elves all
right so I get my basic attack and my
action still yep
ok so basic attack is just gonna be my
mainly mace she'll be able to bounce it
off anything good nigga so him with it
okay so what you gonna be SEC for the
blink okay slang is a spurt the blinking
in the accident killed him for four
however he's going to counter your
counter with a wind blast to dodge it oh
oh don't you second one we got to keep
it fair man wind blast everybody going
right here okay this kills me so you
should mace now you have your I got my
action uh I'm gonna I how's he how's he
looking oh he's looking tired I know
okay I'm gonna use my action to clear
the near site okay give me a race oh you
gotta roll yeah yeah yeah yeah okay you
wipe your eyes clean you're all good
yeah all right Justin's it's just no
it's not Justin's because Justin to be
interrupted right
so is it just his turn but just know it
was your Justin's bleep okay okay it was
my turn and then I hit ya he attacked up
to my okay so it's just okay it's really
confusing guys I'm gonna try something
I'm gonna try something you're gonna go
for something all right so before the
end of my turn mm-hmm I'm gonna try to
roll a blink okay you just blinked and
it failed this is gonna be a really hard
rule I'm letting you hard too hard to be
talking here you think like you're not
this isn't gonna happen you're gonna get
confused things all right I'm on your
ass you try to hit somebody with a fire
ball hard all right let's see I can only
move up five right yeah I'm gonna move
up a little closer nice and uh
fireball impure yeah yeah I know you may
be trying to be trying your ice spills
you know I I mean I have a both my
spells area
you've also got summary of frost you can
you can try and stone it was ready to
frost you have that yeah that's another
thing I've got that extra rate frosty
I'm gonna do that I need to make these
move ten spaces of return kids are slow
I don't want to go closer just so Coast
things are doing something it's my fault
just being far away there's nothing I
can do frost yeah you do drink frost oh
yeah never used this spell before and
you don't hit dead bones but you just
immediately shoot it and hit this spirit
what was the spirits name sorry look
okay really well most of all right now
they're going down like you know
hotcakes sure that's what they're
supposed to be for but does it mean you
care at all and I'm not in the range to
attack so it's the end of my turn right
yeah unless you want to go for the bling
oh no I'm not go over the blink nope
okay let's try this
alright I need to make it to summon air
spirits and wind blasts for free someone
else Pierce I'm never gonna use again oh
wait yeah he used he can't move he used
a wind blast on me to dodge oh yeah you
would be able to move you would be able
to move good call
okay no he wouldn't able to move about
that stuns no no it's just a use I used
it to dodge so I can't use the move yeah
cuz they'll take my turn he lost his
move on his turn
yes I can't use my weapons my triple
fist turn good you got my key
there's a lot to keep track yup okay uh
he's gonna catch rolling fog on YouTube
alright so you both get a copy of
rolling fog unless you have one I'd I
already have I get a copy
yay make copy just doesn't get to me
eleven something it's not a great
rolling fog
where's-where's you over here yep hey is
that me that's just yeah that was you
look at the
okay to do to to go like that actually
it was a pretty shitty fog
well stern yeah we'll start off just
like that whoa hold on I don't want to
hit control Z because that does all
sorts of things you did those someone a
new one it's just a clone in case we
lost the original alright so whose turn
is it
it's the NPC's turn up yeah they're all
dead
well so let's see if Dave can get under
stunned but he was stunned Dave can you
get understand I will give it to him
because I want Dave to do something all
right what can Dave do you'll be
emotionally crushed as his entire team
and then their backups were simply
slaughtered around yeah I think you best
for Dave Dave's just gonna heal Roman
deeds ready for this stop yeah all right
man
I need this but now it's now's like it
start doing damage to you guys all right
so that guess that's all the Dave's turn
that's the only other NPC so I mean
there's this one little sprite button
yeah
oh you know that's one Roma strand sorry
now now it is his turn the monster turn
so he's now actually gonna move one two
three four five he's gonna be in the fog
the fog spreads he wants it encompassing
you guys and himself oh he's a sorcerer
master however there's a caster that's
right however both of you can see
through the fog because you have rolling
fog oh yeah right
so be while you have having fog you guys
can see through it so he's gonna go for
the gold ray of Frost
and you want both stunned unless you
want to try and do something I'm gonna
try and blank
you've been blinking a lot buddy go
ahead though actually mmm I mean you're
stunned so if you don't you're either
it's either stunned or I'm confused I'd
rather be confused and stunned yeah
that's just last time you blinked just
in are you gonna try and dogs out of
this blink I how much damage is it it's
gonna be hand it's gonna be 10 I'm gonna
be tied yeah I might as well try to
blink it I'll try to go for confusion
over Sun I kind of forgot that you guys
would be immune to my fog all right you
can blink out of the way weird you like
to go I would like to go here right I'm
gonna let you know I'm Justin Indy bones
you've been using blink so much that
future blinks are gonna be extremely
hard to cast from here on out okay only
for this point for this fight for this
fight yeah like I'm gonna things are
with you you've got you've used this the
point where it's it's getting crazy so
yeah okay I'm gonna take a roll on my
board real quick okay kill him Justin
what is that better making that a three
you missed now you have your action I'm
okay a fireball just cuz it's gonna
it'll trigger it'll hit you but it hit
me and him I think do the most damage to
me and you don't fireball right if you
fireball it will ignite the you know you
like this it'll hit him and it might hit
me it'll hit me for a good bit too but I
don't it's fine
are you sure yes cuz it's gonna drive
it's one fireball I mean you can't
hidden these very often anywhere but you
never know oh okay better than a 1:1 -
hold on he's on top of one I'm not on
top of a fog so all right he's gonna try
and win
oh man
12mm so he's gonna blast out of here
your fireball goes in your fireball
detonates Boom Boom Boom's bone dead
bones you're gonna take four from the
explosion one two three four
nobody takes he gets hit by the fireball
okay I'm gonna take my second Worple
does the whether the explosion remove
the stun from the frost free UMass yes
it does oh good perfect that's fire
versus ice tactical genius guys fucking
genius
alright so now it only not Roscoe's turn
right
it says Romain no it's Roman had a turn
no it's Romans turn that was wrong yes
because you just see win yeah yes Dave
and all that yeah yep okay this is
getting intense here all right I'm gonna
move up to about here so I've
line-of-sight to him okay kind of
between there yeah cover with you he
can't dodge out his turn cuz he just
used that the Dodge the 10 damage
fireball he can't move on his next
combat turns up alright how's he looking
like we've been doing a lot of fire keys
to my Iraq he's he's still nimble
he's definitely optical or anything but
he's no one wind blast away from death
if that's what you're asking
baby somebody landed like four or five
of their fireballs I mean I gave the
reason why he was brutal he did dodge a
twenty yes he dodged a twenty and then
he just dodged potentially like what was
that sixteen damage mother and plus
sixteen many more fogs like I give him
wind blast so he could dodge this the
big stuff but you guys would throw at
him mm-hmm all right uh let's go let's
go wind blast to the dome with our rolls
lately man we're not all right you hit
up line one two three four five six
seven eight nine
all right it is his turn let's see if I
can fucking keycap knows he can't move
he cannot move that's right so he's
gonna go for he's got a rape he's got to
rape frost Khan was just too good just
alright mm-hm
even if you're immune to it yeah you're
gonna take less oh no you know what I'll
shoot the rare Frost in Romans
directions your site roll your new site
goddamnit I was okay if he's going for I
can't stop it if he's going for Justin
but he wouldn't affected 15 alright he's
nearsighted he tries the rain frost
they're gonna interrupt it he can't do a
ray of frost they'll do another action
he's gonna do some and air spirit yeah
you know he's just gonna swing his
weapon at me yeah he's gonna do a wind
fury blade combo on you it's like what
is he dead so we wanna so he's good this
one this is three damage if you blade
turn it you'll interrupt the chain if
not he's gonna do two more attacks
because we all u9m okay so you use it
your blade turn blocks the hit phone and
that ends his turn
alright cool okay I have the earth Lords
go first this time
okay the earth Lords have just been
invigorated and can now move 10 spaces
because they are one two three four five
six seven eight one two three four five
six seven eight nine ten
okay so two of these are attacking for a
total of six damage so it's gonna do do
six one two three four five six he he
passes out yeah baby
yeah he's exactly healthy
so you pass it can we lose him so these
so these are all immediately gonna die
every single one of them because they
pay for someone for good their duty is
done and combat we still income no
competence come come it's over all right
so we can just loot this fucker no well
yes glutton you won't be I want to loot
him first no you won't be able to loot
him
Dave Dave comes up and he's like no no
no you can't take those items no why not
no he wants them there so he has orders
to deliver them to the silver moon pass
you want the items look look you guys
can't make you look unhappy okay I'm
happy that you guys helped us okay you
realize we just um come on Dave come on
look at one item one item Dave no you
can't have any of this stuff one day not
his this this isn't the UH song no no no
this is mine I can't give it away they
will know if it's gone this stuff is way
too will people you guys anyway come on
Dave
I'm sorry yes I don't even have these
made this treasure card so I can't even
give them to you if I wanted to not have
anything else on him at all yeah he was
a prisoner what you think check check
his but Dave check his but he's a
prisoner check his but Dave's gonna
check his blood combat I want my free
random treasure look the only thing I
would the only thing I found is gonna
only interest you know your earth Lord
guy over there you think I got it
alright listen Dave you gotta give us
something here man anyway just give us a
thing and just what do you know what you
know what instead of doing that instead
of doing that that donation thing would
do I'm just gonna give you guys
portraitures has that so you know yeah
yeah I got some random treasures here in
this bag you gots good Dave let's go
what I got a few more treasures you're
very good at one of them just you give
back to me you can pick which for you
okay you're a good Apple Dave you're a
good asset good don't this happen please
don't open my lips my lips are sealed
a where you co use the weather
water whoa whoa hold on now Coco moved
up coming down I want I want to do so
once happy after the treasures have been
distributed you want well they so will
give the treasures after the break so
okay how do you want to do you know what
he won't save and then I pull out my
mirror oh no what are you doing what
Oh words I mean it'll hurt do you want
to be realistic
do you really want to use this this work
but it's just so way he'll though was a
mere called it's called the mirror of
cool stuff it's not like I don't they
revealed this mirror to a target to
attempt to trap it within the mirror if
the target is later bro if the mirrors
later broken the target will be released
and the mirror destroyed are you using
it on Dave or the kobold you won't be
able to control him if he pops out of it
again just know that he'll pop out and
he'll pop out he'd be unconscious and
then we can loot him or kill him later
when this mirror breaks he's coming out
full strength with all those weapons
equipped if you use oh yeah okay yeah I
don't like that and Dave's not gonna be
too happy if you use the mirror on him
strangers if you do that you using the
mirror on Dave it was like he treasures
you want the treasures Co hold on over
there report fine all right cool good
all right Dave we'll take the treasures
now please all right Dave yes you're
gonna have these after this non
commercial break delicious
all right let's get your times gets it
up we're gonna do the treasures figure
out what's gonna happen with this cobalt
Oh
the story of chimera who is handing out
these treasures is it daisies yeah Dave
name is actually anybody sending you
some treasures for your good work this
will be one two three
Rahl wants to know his delete is this
leader distributed or absolutely he's
handing the dangers to the leader of the
theta squad good right he was very
impressed with how theta squad battle
teas they saved greatness he was given
his five David Davis oh yeah dave was
all down to himself
so alright we got work bladed a crystal
catalyst there's a king feel off there's
another bewitching mirror as I'm a stick
alright I want to convert the frog in
the stick into two more rejuvenation
potions for myself okay and then you
guys want any this anybody you guys want
you want these potions are these things
I have no Kingfisher yeah okay we're
looking at the Kingfisher I wouldn't
mind a warp lead can't the war plate
sure from 180
robes Roman has three ropes himself down
yeah Roman she's playing catch-up so
code you want one of these - I'll let
you all say to that your inventory is
going to be full with these last two
yeah cuz potions don't stack right
that's fine I don't need I don't need
any more of a bunch of shit Soko you
cannot you can actually you can take no
you can take these last two if you want
go if no one else wants them or you can
turn into potions okay I guess I'll take
the critical the crystal catalysts and
I'll convert the no no David just give
me showing you oh he's showing us more
you can take the one just now he's gonna
keep it so he can keep one well I'll
take that and convert it to UM
I guess a quickness elixir okay is it
just one or all right now I've got shy
what do I have three new Venetians ah
you have three minutes
awesome hey where's your blade turn
Justin it's probably I use it'll be
under some I'm using he says it doesn't
get lost Justin you get it I thought it
was a one-time use my bed just once per
combat yeah ah I'm glad you said that
yeah that's a really good thing you can
use it
alright so we were you were talking
James say that the treasures Dave's like
alright guys if you don't mind I'm gonna
to pack up this prisoner alright Dave we
don't we don't really it's your job do
your job Dave it's fine hopefully you
can kill Gweneth how awesome theta squad
is you know tell her how cool theta
squad is now right right Dave right like
I was impressed you didn't mess it up
right you all kind of actually did did
well that's the first time you guys have
theta squad this new date is a dummy
thing mention captain ice Lord don't
forget captain ice Lord he's an
important member of the team who he is
that's not really common he's fine he's
fine he's at member he's part of the
team okay he's been with us a long time
don't be like the firefight guy right
just be cool Dave all right be cool Dave
you know I'm saying be cool be cool
thing okay well I'm gonna back up the
cobalt that's it I'm gonna get on our
way you know what's gonna happen to him
Dave is he going he's gonna silver mine
he's going to seven miles yeah that's
where we take Dave Dave Dave hmm no one
can see us
Dave there's no puppets on the screen I
don't know what a screen is why did that
happen again
not a puppet oh that's the second time
just like in the middle of the stream
that we've lost the puppets for some
reason no I was wondering what you said
by there's no puppets on the screen I
was like what are you guys talking about
it's definitely opens on the screen okay
that's so weird
I don't know why that keeps breaking yep
yep so anyway yeah great great work
everyone I'll be going now is that it oh
well Dave have you seen a small child
that looks kind of like Roman like this
guy yes it'll look very similar to that
guy except probably way cuter Oh
Conway's got a little puppy-dog eyes
kind of lightweight this Dave's gonna
cast the skies I hope this is a
crocodile like that wait
Davey you Phineas no nothing complete I
saw this boy go into that cave as we
were just oh you Anna dick you probably
two before we got there everybody just
wish their okay anyway yeah you really
don't need this okay oh good you mean I
gotta do this voice what's the disguise
result whew yeah but you were example is
the best way to show you what I just
wanna know you see no I just wanted a
yes/no answer Dave I think I see a lot
of kids all day I mean I also saw this
one hold on yeah like I saw this kid
earlier - that's not a kid Dave that's a
that's a pork Oprah my eyes go porks we
fell back off it's Dave don't hit any
news
don't it's fine it's it's a disguise so
it's a disguise hey Dave yeah what's up
did that little kid who ran by was he on
fire yeah was he in 500 it's making sure
a lot of there's a fire elemental before
it's you know it's hot stuff please
change back I can practically smell this
thing
man it's a point you gotta get used to
pause impossible that's impossible you
can't smell what disguise don't be
ridiculous
no I'm complimenting or just guys don't
be a Dave I'm gonna suggest something to
you real quick
next time put the elves inside the
caravan with the prisoner oh no we had
some of the key you haven't looked in
the caravan have you oh oh that's that's
really bad well yeah well dave was nice
catch always fun always fun times fun go
find my brother I'll mention it to
Gwyneth okay I mentioned that the theta
squad actually you know managed to do
something other than burn down a forest
which I don't know that is do what was
last time you burned out a virus like
yesterday I don't know that our corporal
captain chili with Z or captain chili
with Chili's Mary didn't cast a single
ice spell entire one of the yellow chili
with H it's my name okay okay no do you
think do they call you chili wizzy cuz
you're to you know cold the cast cold
spell sir well because he because I'm
very I'm very chill he drives a nice
bushes to find out you gotta go plate
you gotta go play chilly willy with them
oh yeah I'm chilly wizzy champion you
should try that out see let's check your
chili wizzy skill
he'll show you going I'm just gonna so I
just follow him okay let's not play
chilly wizzy let's actually go get my
brother
hey do remember they already pooper
remember they were roommates at college
so I mean he knows chili was easy he
wants to hang out alright roll rolling
for chili wizzy
like porks books to meet kids I don't
know what we're doing it yes exactly
what they eat and they don't need am I
am i rolling they're more tender yeah
yeah you got a roll for your uh your
feeling chilly willie yeah I got a nine
year before do I win I think we all lose
all right so Dave's gonna take the
prisoner he's gonna put him up see this
big chili is Willie it was uh was his
really chilly it was how chilly was his
Willie was it's really that's pretty
all this time we're wasting wasting for
what we should actually we i forgot we
really should save the kid again
report it's doesn't look good the forest
is fine what are we doing out here I
we're just looking for this kid will we
we're looking for the kid right that's
exactly love this kid Roman well
actually we're going to kill the courts
we're going to kill the forks too don't
forget that we got a deal with like a
this is like you really this is really
worth it how much I mean just kill your
brother and see how you feel about it I
got a brother bro he's know me channel
brothers here
yeah when you can try killing my brother
but he's like really far away I'm gonna
question look you're very defensive its
rights my younger brother they get
annoying doesn't mean I wanted to die oh
wait I think I get it like what I am I
would make some noise yes okay wanting
to die no I do well then go do that look
hey okay come on guys we we've gotten
through how much how many encounters now
we're doing so very very well let's do
this would what change in theta this was
not gonna be the laughing stock anymore
we're gonna beat the new alpha squad we
were the last right yeah we were the
laughingstock we were nobody like this
you know cuz you always set fire to
things you're a complete asshole and
you're kind of grumpy sometimes oh I
thought we were a comedy oh come on
asshole
I know they said my brother get eat my
ports anyway we got to save the little
kid we got to kill some porks Fatah's
wad strike need a new slogan so long I
think
notice that dead boats has named his
combo like fair fist a flare face I
punch with my flare that's how I use
this strike yeah let's strike it up
alright so are you guys coming in not
coming in the cave okay
brutally we're here okay yeah you
actually strike wait wait are you doing
your thing outside the cave are you
coming in the cave with us no no no we
were like acts like we were would you
call it that is that a quad yeah you're
striking striking I got like we're we're
not no not not like a strike like that
it's like like a strike like a hit you
know like you hit that you strike some
actual strike it's just not like an
actual strike yeah it's a strike because
everyone makes fun of us no no not what
we're gonna make sure that nobody ever
makes fun of us ever again
by killing so many porks are we a
squadron wheres what we can be a
squadron sure okay squadron strike it's
if we take the theta out we'll just be
the squad we can be the squadron the
squadron super me this squadron Supremes
let's let's go save the kids got some on
save this idiot squadron strike