[Music]
okay so now does the monsters turn which
means oh all right oh my god it's
Armageddon
Bahamut oh you guys are gonna hit my
fire meteors every single turn so is
that like one of Justin's robes in the
wind
yeah these are these are meteors it's an
airdrop coat these are meteors falling
from the sky and each of them does five
damage so you're gonna get hit every
single turn you remain in combat with
this fire guy for five okay except
unless you let you dodge so you guys
kinda can't you guys can have a dog for
all the stirring so code you will do
like I tried dodge this meteor I'm
assuming you all want to try and Dodger
the way dead bones you don't have to you
just block it oh I'm gonna take it most
pieces ml I'm in this sweet tent ok is
the tent for cover of Shh okay what do I
die still gonna have to dodge or what I
mean you just if you want to dive into
the tent but for cover that's fine I'm
gonna dive towards this tag that says
meteor proof this is a meteor proof tent
to me to pretend to be proof tango have
a soul you wouldn't roll the dive into
your meteor proof Ted I really hope you
get a 1o 16 alright he's successfully
dive into the tent and you zip it up and
then the meteor crushes your tent and
you take five damage the tenants
destroyed oh geez Roman well meteors
coming your way what do you want to do
do app delete dodge you're gonna like
sidestep you can no fee I mean like die
it's a it's it's a big it's a big blast
radius it's as big as like Justin's
attack was it's a three by three so you
got to actually like jump bad the way
you don't have to use like wind blast or
anything like I'm giving you a free
dodge roll cuz I roll blow so you can if
you want to just dive you can dive you
can also just draw water if you wanted
to I guess I'm not dealing I'm not gonna
walk around wet like forever driving
absolutely absurd and I don't uh you
know I want to die but I have to dive
towards this grassy area I'm not diving
in the dirt okay he's too pompous to get
wet too pompous to get what wait on
smart to get wet okay that's nothing to
do with being pompous
you say some eleven okay so you are
going to barely get out of the way but
you're still gonna get clipped for two
okay am i dirty um no no no non-fire no
no uh but it did singe the bottom of
your robe damn it
yeah it just singed it but you didn't
you didn't like you didn't you didn't
die because because you wouldn't dive
into the dirt you just kind of just try
to like make a little run and you got
you got clipped okay okay deal with that
um Justin you want to jump out of the
way now I will my winter coat does
absorb this thing uh it'll reduce it you
know what it's volatile it'll make it
yet if you want to just take it like a
man you can roll for that yeah cuz you
have the weird girl I'm gonna roll to
take it like a man yeah Justin alright
Justin takes it like a man and only
takes one damage from the five nice
alright and dead bones you don't have to
take anything I'm just gonna face tanked
the shit Oh misspelled no it's that was
fun
dammit it's gotta be like class
abilities that are going on but I'm
gonna keep asking cuz you ventually you
might say yes alright uh so the wind
spirits the fire spirits are gonna
attack so let's have a fire spirit role
for this to be one did did Dan oh and
here's wind spirits come on wind spirits
okay so the wind spirits just absolutely
annihilate these fire spirits and snuff
out the flame with their bodies so that
one's gone Wow and that was gone and
then these two are alive okay Roman
you're doing an okay job I'm actually
doing a good job
I'll get old you my fire spirits I've
literally killed infinite fire spirits
cuz I put out a fire so I mean if you're
going by sighs justin's killed an elf
and that's what we're bigger than a
spirit so but actually still two and a
bit by one's unconscious want a blue one
I do fire spirits funds this guy is
going to do his beam attack yet again
it's gonna hit den pose Justin ko and
his guys OH
what Co because I well can I claim can I
do this it's really far it's really it's
a you know like a zigzaggy beam all
right you're right I don't have to hit
your spirits your fucking game let's go
get beer and pizza in fact actually I
can move for them first anyway one two
three four five one two three four five
one of them is smart enough to go to the
town the other want me to submit a go
this way to get in anyway let's do a
beam attack come on all right
doesn't do anything demos doesn't do
anything to just in clips ko for one
yeah what's Meehan look like hmm those
tents gone
yeah it's tension bushmen rock behavior
hit it yeah by the way is noticed a rock
I'm soaked this um god I can't really do
anything um yeah it's uh bromas turn we
get that a chilly bluesy Dan whoa who's
moving me in the water not wet clearly
I'm in the grass hey what's your play
okay uh I check my coat to make sure
it's not on fire yep okay are we good is
it yes you you anypony snuffed it out a
little bit it's fine just like okay
shake your leg okay okay um all right so
he's kind of looking a mine drection ish
I'm gonna cast wind blast yeah and the
big at the fire gun at the big guy all
right give me a role should I ask him
that I cut the dice in half every time
and that happens we get 20s five all
right come on you shoot the wind blast
you hit but are you kind of like you're
not gonna necessarily miss you're gonna
click the wind Lord but you're also
going to push Justin like way out of the
way like he just gets just gets thrown
from the wind blasts which interrupts
his channeling of his little a blizzard
of his no not as blizzard okay
annal is a because he can do what's that
attack the wizard won the ice class
whatever yet Oh
next year I would have been free for him
knock some of the way slops is
channeling oh he was taking da taking
damage anyways from the meteor he took
the last year I did take one cuz why I
said that's fine he took it with the
rope though he faced tank like a man cuz
he didn't want to move to keep
channeling of the thing yeah he was
trying to get broke it yeah so Roman
takes one for casting it Justin takes
one getting knocked back and oh yeah it
takes two I want to go over here and
then I want to give words of
encouragement to my ear sprites okay you
do know that they do not listen to you
in any way they like think though I
don't just just blow with them that's
their my air sprites so words of
encouragement okay but Rob when you talk
to babies they still understand what
you're saying even though they don't
really know what you're saying it's like
a dog
alright now it's your turn their ears
right so my tents been destroyed I got
hit by a meteor I still don't have beer
and pizza I'm pretty pissed at this
point so we're gonna summon a two by two
grand fisting event on this motherfucker
right here this is ass
I feel SEMA granted piston agreed that
you know you actually said the right
name of these things the spells so he'd
know what it is open though I know I'm
sorry you actually casted life train oh
come on what I'm sorry
you cast his life okay i casted your
grandeur say that the fucking name of
the evaluator right I'm gonna pick a
spell from now on all right so you just
slash him for five damage one two three
four five there's a nice clean hit are
you moving or anything what is that good
Amelio their fancy I'm gonna head this
way okay alright that seems kind of
productive seducing as the tail well I
realized that I also wanted pretzels
okay
I'm going to actually do their moves now
because I should have done that earlier
one two three uh so he's now I'm trying
to smash through this wall
this is the one trying to get beer it
was breaking uh he's just punching it
right now it's not working this one's
still going one two three four five
um and now it is dead bones turn alright
impose your blockade has ended you've
absorbed a lot of damage I took so many
today stroganoff oh yeah uh I want I
ball this guy again are we we have to
make the dead NIM or anything as he is
house he seems to be at full strength
he's just powered like is clearly these
not been doing anything yeah he seems to
be pretty much right there alright well
I'm gonna just as the only one all right
moving over to Justin so that was like
five spaces right yeah yeah alright so
gonna move over to Justin buddy Justin
what's up
I'm about to do something wait no not
wait wait I know what you're gonna do it
two three four five think I could toss
him at him ha Justin I'm going right you
got a role I'm gonna throw you you gonna
roll we're gonna cast spell Oh God
okay wait wait what is he only in this
next turn I see yeah you can give a big
big hug you like to go what yeah whether
when I throw you you care with it
are you okay I'm making sure you're okay
with it I'm gonna hit him like a tank
like a bullet or an arrow I guess we
don't have it with that winter coat blob
you're just gonna smell I'm awesome at
John fiery elemental I mean if you're
not okay with it I'm still gonna do it
like it might burn off a coat or two but
you're gonna but think for this way if
it works you get bonus think this is all
the benefit for you I mean you're gonna
roll regardless right I'm gonna go I'm
gonna do regardless Isaac I don't want
okay with it I'm still on the fence so I
miss my throne while he's thinking yeah
I'm just sitting there in deep thought
whoo hey so just as the unwillingly
thrown which is gonna make it harder for
him than not you know we send thaw it's
not the same Justin go ahead and roll to
see if you
actually make the landing here all right
you cannot you get you land here Justin
you take five damage and your stun for
the stern so that's it as the bluffs
done anything lately
oh yes blizzard blizzard
um it's at the end of this turn so oh
just it's just all Justin turn Justin
you can roll to see if you make a
recover from your stun or else it's just
gonna be care damage in a pass come on
Justin okay
nope you can't and you do two damage
from your Blizzard okay - so yeah yeah
yeah yeah so your spirits gonna spawn
this one's gonna roll go in this place
this one's gonna go and try and fight
love a nice - on to here with the
spirits
apparently you hit me for five and not
Justin oh that's a shame this is a shame
at night huh don't you give my health
awake and now for the wind the wind
spirits loose one two three four five
one two three four five hey what's
tosser one one yeah yeah one okay so
that's the wind spirits did you this guy
is like he was stuck he didn't do
anything last turn he's just running to
town now he's like fuckin he's just like
these everything's going terrible I'm
out of here
he's got nobody left to manage anyway
all right fire spirit is going to move
forward right here uh-oh
and he's gonna do is beam to hit you -
uh blink so you're gonna believe this
okay I'm gonna blink out of the way go
ahead before I even do anything
yeah that's uh damage for do you one two
three - me uh it was it's ten range
isn't it uh yeah you can flick up the
tail I think this guy's too rare
sorry he's like right here
great forces yeah I wanted I just want
to get buys want to get like I'm a
blinking past I want to blink up into
his face okay it's like they're yeah
link okay you're blinking successfully
you're right in front of them now you
can take a full turn
well actually I can take a free attack
first cuz it's a spell
oh there's some cheery stuff no it's a
combination man okay come on - all right
you miss and you lose your turn what
yeah man that's a - you fucked up you go
you're gonna do with you're completely
disoriented I missed about the - all
right I miss that I got the return taken
away here one number away from the
stabbing just another yeah hey lucky you
missed your turn um alright now you're
gonna get hit by the beam and you're not
even facing out oh here comes the beam
at you - like good feeling about this
five five five normally a five if you go
if you come from over here at you I've
it's a nice look it I think you should
flick it what's notify flavor flick six
yes going to say this dice is just
landing on these things it's on a tile
it's on a tile 11 you both think I live
can I blink out of the way you sleep -
yes yes link - hey okay alright don't
forget your free attack with the spy no
I need to roll for the blink yes you do
he drawers on the blankly do it oh all
right so you blink and you blink right
here uh you both take that you both get
hit by the blast but you can still take
your turn so one two three four five
throws actually Justin I'm sorry
you have your magical coat I only hate
nice nice - three four five all right uh
Justin II it's now your turn
because you blinked but you kind of
blinked way over here why I can
only gonna melee attack right yes yes I
can't is everything no you can just
swing at the air if you'd like no I'm
cool yeah raucous throw a code Adam I
don't want to accidentally kill Greenup
like action after a blink yeah he can
take a full lecture this one saying yeah
it's full journal yeah hold on German
use a spell right look you could use
when your spells yeah yeah well hmm do
you have a range spell you can hit him
with you can end with it what's the our
range on Life Drain Oh 10 there does
that end so you can hit him yeah yeah
imma go for a life to do it up 11 so you
can land your life train which only
costs one so you regain through so costs
one you retain four one two three four
it does for damage one two three four
all right now it is Romans turn Roman
you are kind of in trouble as you are
kind of stuck but maybe I do I mean I
can we clearly go through here quick
question no there's supposed to be any
more meteors or is it just the one oh
good point
you all get hit by a meteor thank you Oh
make it the roll no you do not get the
Dodge today at damico alright we'll get
to dodge no no this is your fault we
actually know they're coming dowing we
should definitely be able to dodge no
you're the first one you stopped coming
the second ones snuck up on you just say
meteors on air Justin you only take two
nice thank you alright okay now what is
Roman Stern
okay Roma you're kind of bidding
treating trapped here I don't know if
you notice that right but can i I can
ask it I can get escaped right down over
here yeah yeah all right so I'm gonna
move move my five goddamn I move another
five yeah well I'm gonna move you know
closer here ish okay I but seeing the
stupid laser beam shoot now hahaha mama
didn't raise no fool
uh we are going to we're gonna win blast
okay you just go to blast them for nine
uh yep blast one four nine right in the
face
come on come on
okay alright you're gonna hit him four
five God and keep in mind that wind
blast does knock back butts on something
really really this big isn't gonna work
one two made a fire though I mean you
know Sam not like he's a rock monster
that would clearly make no sense he
wouldn't be able to fire Rock yeah if
here's a wind guy he'd make a good angle
- no just flames a little that's a good
point I sure yeah you should get a
bigger shimmy when you get saved by wind
blast yeah it's absolutely not I'll just
work with that
alright is there somebody anything else
from you moved you attacked no I think
that's not good okay
Co it is your turn alright um-hmm you
see how far away am I again I'm like ten
away one two three four five six seven
eight nine you're just range for your
ten spells but keep in mind green elf is
right in the way yeah I don't really
care um so is this is this thing alive
does it have life essence Justin just
Life Drain it so yes you can life draw
we did okay yeah my Berenstain just did
spirits or living yeah its energy I'm
gonna go for a life drain then and if it
hits CL fan you know whatever oh I'm
making that a five and you have got a
stop rolling on the tiles man alright
sorry uh one two three four and you take
you take one and then I actually hold on
let me look at your gear what do you
have do you have put the staff yeah oh
my goodness
you only get minus one off your things
let me giving you - - well I'm gonna
take three damage up for that cuz you've
cast at least three spells and then you
were Jan 4 1 2 3 4
cool who did I hit though you hit elf
green oaf oh yeah it's like I'm ready to
ducted his hit points he is like
basically he's fallen to the ground and
is barely alive now he's limping yeah
he's like why well wait we're all on the
same side
why would you do this to pee and this
guy is almost getting your pizza two
three four
I have dice - what a morale boost that's
gonna be it's a huge morale boost this
other ones still trying to break into
dead bones his room at the end all up
and he gets in this turn swing at
yourself but she took a shortcut here
nice
hey guys goes those move right now that
is his booth that's that's what he did
though okay it's all turned a busty
devil
he's just a fucking spirit man he
doesn't get an action in the spell no he
does but he used it all to get through
there his move was that one booth space
cuz I was 11 to break through a goddamn
wall but if I wanted to succeed this
mission deep down I'm a little biased
for him so uh so Co you gonna move or
anything or is that it um yeah okay
alright is your turn I'm gonna turn to
the rest of the guys I guess I already
am turned that way cuz I've linked the
wrong way I was sick okay
hit him with everything you got and I'm
just gonna use blockade okay is locate a
roll or is that just gonna go so you
want to work yeah huh shocker it's
always a real difference it's always
okay I just thrown the shouting over you
fuck yeah me too oh so you go to use
your your blockade but you fumble and
you drop your sword that you were gonna
you know Perry the attacks with your
your your mace I guess a scary with
angel or my fists you know yeah cool so
your blockade is not going to work this
turn or work as well it's gonna work
very very good Michigan's some damage
but not always program that's a - you're
gonna be
nothing you're just lucky I'm even hit
yourself in the head with a mace yeah um
so it is now belay that order don't hit
him with everything you got uh you
should done with everything you got
yes Annette's rule - okay just as your
turn all right uh I'm gonna throw
another blizzard I think um I might do
that we're gonna die in he can't write
then once prank counter turn cousin
Frank yeah yeah yeah
Blizzard's have that little icon like
the little silver yeah yeah uh no no no
no yeah no no it's sin I don't know what
to cast because I don't want to pump him
with fire
I can't blizzard I guess just expecting
life drinker for now yeah is that all
why are you limited on your spells yeah
yeah you'd have to get up in his face
and ice blast you get a life trade over
for the back yeah yeah I don't want to
just lie up all that work he isn't
trying at a fire I assume I'm just gonna
pump them full up a fire fight a
fireball I don't know I'm just saying
it's gonna have those I brought the suit
you created this thing you're not baking
into the shank that I drove that I marry
I very clearly said that Justin created
kiss he only has one fire spell what do
you think happens if he shoots a fires
fell into it maybe he was a boy scout I
don't know all right so I'm gonna move
I'm just gonna shift my angle up to like
here and fall down vni then I just make
a double okay shift your angle and then
you're gonna I'm gonna go for the Life
Drain okay go ahead 13 okay so once
Pamela and then you gain 4 1 2 3 4 okay
and I think that's all yours turns ok so
another spirit one two three four five
ish then another fire they're smart
enough not to run through my blizzard
yeah they're funny they're smart they're
super cool cuz you guys are doing way
too good I do go out what totally we're
doing good you serious yeah I miss I'm
missing a key ability
make this really difficult for you guys
but I think I think I could do it
alright so you guys can be hit by
meteors
now I'm gonna blink okay you can do that
in a second
oh right sure you want to blink r19 no I
don't want to blink on the 19 okay
everybody's gonna get picked by five
then one two three four five Romans
critical one two three four five one two
three four five one two three four five
leave the would outweigh Swiss account
or not I I am has so happy that meteor
just hit you all you guys and fucking D
Emma's jobless make it make us heroes
not kill us and now I'm gonna blast you
with the beam Roman but it's going to
miss and kill green elf no your traitor
anyway like it goes like how it kills
green elf but you know whatever I didn't
write the image go um is there anything
else a to do this turn I doesn't kill
him I'm sorry it makes him unconscious
the only person that's been killed is
the one elf that Justin decapitated and
the spirits not really killed they're
just kind of dissipated into non it was
pretty sore yeah um okay I think that's
it yep it's grown sternum
okay alright so following your order to
give it all I got the ice that I belaid
that order I didn't hear anything refer
you for your elemental there's a lot of
background note is in whooshing that's
background noise of usually winning sure
so you can rewrite what do you try I'm
gonna do win blast I'm giving it all I
got
okay I hope you will join the 20 would
like just make the seconds right you hit
him for nine so alright and I'm gonna
move way the hell out of this I see a
new bombing I'm like moving back I gotta
be behind this okay find this bridge see
I'm crouching down back here uh you go
behind that bridge thing and a little
goblin is there waiting you fuck are you
kidding hahahaha you run another corner
there's like a
goblet under the bridge you like kind of
pops his head out all right so cool I
didn't put that there that was there he
knew you were gonna cross there all the
fucking encounters at once huh all right
uh Co it's your turn all right um see
we're coming might have started the
second encounter gosh taking cover
behind a bridge I'm not exactly the best
of shape right now okay right so I'm
gonna move up to cover and hide the top
line just body that's Oddie of a dave
yeah he's a chest high wall
um and I'm gonna I'm gonna go for a
grand Ravenclaw bitch slap on the the
fire bitch nein all right you swipe at
the fire Lord and you hit him for was
that five damage mm-hmm one two three
four five let's chip in on nine anything
else go where's that bet it I think it's
it not me oh that's it for me um my shit
alerts movers that later oh yes that is
thank you
we can't forget this is very important
to the plot this is very one two three
four five hey chat asleep is your lords
Philippe Yeti for who's Philippe exactly
right that was last week guys yeah you
had no known as you know I just knew
about him me some bard came into town
and was singing this tale about him but
you know snowballs are probably all they
don't know are there was no bird that
could be sing they make up stories I
could sing it is a Bartok sing okay
anyway you know what a keen wouldn't
come to this town this is an elf town
yeah I could disguise this takes place
in the past anyway no no this is this is
Pat this is after
Felipe for sure anyway anyway uh code
now it's your turn
what were you doin oh you did my turn
okay it was close turn no was cut was
just goes turn debts Co did what did you
do
life trained and then gr anybody fisted
yeah no I didn't do a live drain
yeah like slap yeah slapped the Firelord
for 5 ok oh yeah that's right okay um so
simple string yeah all right I'm going
to move up to this car in front of
Justin Oh God
just stop fucking touching I'm not gonna
click I was busy and look on your mouse
I'm sure I was going alright she's gonna
move on next Justin here okay he's
coming up oh no bolt boob up doing
nothing again excellent good job leader
here I might actually need these though
they think about it Roman you don't get
to talk this is something like a time
when the average to you mister triggered
the second fucking encounter yeah as I
just wanna celebrate knock about its
order from Felix shut up just me not
just children Wow
I don't I don't even talk what's
happening for the things that I clearly
do not know about yeah I just have to
get ready
what so what do you wanna do now
difference you moved over here doing it
yeah this one next to Justin and then I
want to use blockade again yeah okay try
it like have just have a meat shield
well please don't be something shitty oh
god all right Ellie so this is the
second two so I'll give you one more
role but if it's anything over than five
you're not getting a blockade because
this is twice in a row you try to do
something all right you can have your
blockade just barely for this turn
alright just for the anthem dead bones
this turn mm-hmm I'm gonna link here
right oh you're gonna for a double turn
here alright this is the second time you
use blank this encounter if you roll you
know even average this plinkus is going
to fail just letting you know
oh okay okay sorry I don't mean to jump
the gun there no no it's fine I'm just
letting you know
alright so guess what you blinked over
here or facing the wrong way but I will
let you take a let you use your turn
because your
like slightly confused I'll let you use
your turn to do something else
you can have your bonus turn but this
turn you're going to be very confused
while casting spells so be careful if
you want I'll just not use the turn and
I'm gonna try to Life Drain the boss
okay
what's that builds that alright Devils
can take it okay good so I may have
blockaded I'm good you get confused uh
you're you're gonna Life Drain dead
bones but he's blockading so it does
nothing so all you do is use your one
stamina to cast it alright so what the
hell man I should take one more from ko
thought we were cool I'm sorry alright
Roman it no now this is just announced
your turn now your dad is infused you're
like oh macha now you can move up and do
shit cool alright yeah I'm gonna move up
I guess I'm kind of leaning on him yeah
I'm gonna go on their face I'm gonna go
for a nice blast okay can he attack him
since he casted blink and then give his
melee attack then was ice blast he was I
wasn't close to none wasn't close to me
I would have had to do it trying to get
all the help we can I know
thirteen no you're gonna have to use
your potion room and that's what it's
looking like
so thirteen you have four seven one two
three five six seven
and you're free attack alright free TAC
via tech is so broken six and you with
you don't hit them now right so broke it
huh
alright alright and uh at the end so
quite sure mm-hmm
I'm go I know no I'm not I know more you
get it I was gonna blink behind you but
oh my god you don't try to use another
prime not oh yeah don't worry action
your turn it stopped yeah things what is
with you guys I'm fucking clicking
you're just always moving things around
just all to zoom in if you need to read
something know left click E okay no
quick all right
have you guys didn't hit by enough
meteors Oh God all right meteor time
Roman you're in a range of the meteors
ah you'll act as bridge thing you guys
could take a dodge roll this turn to
dodge the meteors denhams your
blockading Justin you can just absorb it
if you like I want to punch the meteor
but you totally lavage last time you'll
just say aunt Justin wait I do stop the
roll yeah if you want it yet if you want
to absorb it yourself to roll is the
same is the same in real life yeah okay
so you're only gonna take to damage
Justin Co all right oh that was not a
roll I'm sorry I'm gonna pick up and
drop it all right go you dodge out of
the way do you want to go forward or
backward on this dodge um I'll go
forward okay you're gonna jump right
back into your tent
I can't over the tent this you do the
trick for me nice a tent nice soft
landing all right well uh chat has got
the last event I wish they had a lot
sooner
we incited to mind oh just what its
brain looks like he reigns he spawned
ten fire spirits and uses something that
the Chad didn't know or they would have
got this earlier is he now controls all
spirits of all kind oh oh four five six
okay
seven eight there you go nine man may I
ask what's the range on that
oh it's taken thirsty it's huge it's
huge
what do you mean you're hungry and
thirsty well I'm you know I don't have
to control these spirits over here no no
no they have to be like the immediate
radius but there are no spirits alive
for him to control I was so happy when
you guys started summoning all these air
spirits I was like oh oh oh it's gonna
be so bad it's gonna be so bad but you
kill them all um so we're gonna have
these start to swarm you guys these ones
are all fresh spawn this one come over
here there's a new one over here that's
gonna spawn and come this way all right
um he's gonna go for a flame lash he's
never used this one on Justin he's just
gonna take a swipe at you Justin all
right 15 listen you take five damage and
that's after your armor of God oh whoa
all right I don't want to learn you guys
but you're about to be knocked out like
all of you at once nobody has more than
ten health um so just you know keep that
keep that in mind go over over here um
um your dead bones the leader of the
party is looking at this spirit and you
can tell that for using all of this
power and stuff the spirit is getting
smaller that the giant spirit he sick
he's actually shrunk a little bit how
much smaller
that is not but I mean you know that
sizes and everything
maybe it's an indication you know that a
DS he signed up our yeah huh you're
gonna have to think of something crafty
to deal with all these spirits that are
around you though
so I mean Justin's already said just the
kitchen yeah just in can ice glass the
next turn if he doesn't move and just so
yeah if if the fire spirit gets the main
one you think if it gets dissipated what
happens to the the sub spirits they
iTunes addict row are they part of it
would they we don't get to know that we
don't know you got to wait and find out
okay thought I'd ask
you know Roman oh I'm sorry there's one
more thing before goblin turn the goblin
attacks Roman I forgot about that one oh
you're so fucking lucky the Goblin the
Goblin pops up and swipes at Roman Roman
sees the Goblin it pushes him into the
water doesn't do any damage just pushes
into the water
no Goblin not right now cannot deal with
this right now get back in the water
fight honorably yeah alright Roman it's
your turn
you're just as low as all these other
guys and I'm unlike a character last
week I don't think your character
necessarily is gonna leave all of his
you know oh no no no all right not gonna
move you do about here that you'll have
to use your move and your Ruby so if you
want to move shoot yeah I'm okay with
that
okay you're not gonna move shoot back up
uh now okay wait hold on let me think
this through point so from here because
you can probably do one you can probably
like one two three four five the what
see one two three four five and then
yeah you if you went like right here you
could hit him and then you could get
behind cover if you really wanted to
okay way to go with that alright um
I'm going to
this sucks I'm gonna live strain on the
fire elemental okay really it 20 yeah 20
be really nice 20 would be phenomenal
right now it's not as funny is that what
is that but if I don't have made this
big it's a fake hey dice can we go back
to your home Oh dice is cool man drink
it I lost right no there you go
shrinking a girl it's a lie now it's a
new regulation do you roll I'll give you
a rear old yeah I should have never
changed I changed it to be big and now I
don't know what the like its original
size is that roll proper all right 10
that's neutral so one to do it then you
gain four one two three four
I'm gonna use my quickness elixir oh
okay so you're quickly flick sir will
give you two free actions but it's used
up so OOP yeah right you can spam like
drinks though we're doing here Owen okay
so I'll do one more lap - mm-hmm on the
on the big guy this would have been so
easy if you didn't kill those allies by
the way just wanna let you guys know all
right and you life train but you don't
successfully like hit it so you're only
gonna hit him for two and so you'll only
gain effectively one okay we got one
more action Kanaya
way after that hit the roman you he's
got Eve okay here you might be able to
him what a big dude all right I mean
cope up next look oh my be able to do it
too but yeah you have enough damage
Roman to survive a meteor or like a beam
so you're seven health yeah but not both
if you get it if you get anything you
get another life train so oh if I get a
20 keep if he turns into a hug elemental
worth 500 yeah it was absolutely uh
alright so I see him getting noticeably
smaller
come on bro take the big plane the wind
blaster life Deb I believe in you up
I'll go for the wind blast I already
regret this Rolla 100 my god this
doesn't say yes I hate this die you know
what we're just we're gonna have to go
back where's the pink Dyke give us back
the pink dye 100 percent that's this is
that thing is honestly it's the worst
ice in the world it's shiny and nice but
whatever yeah I know
those are 19 right no it was there's 20
roll we roll
Oh damned rolled 14 whoo all right you
know for 9 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9
he gets even smaller God
I'm so this is gonna be so bad jet all
right hi oh go ahead Co it's your turn
right I'm gonna move over here what we
could reach and uh I'm gonna go for
another wind raven or grande ravenclaw
Oh have we got an update on the pizza
though like aren't we a little bond yeah
what the pointer it's a straight Tommy
hundred yeah oh okay okay yes Joe no I
want to know maybe the pizza was it like
it's in sight
he would be like uplifted he's like oh
okay
you can have your rent grande Ravenclaw
and the rampaging spear is dead and
you're so lucky
Justin was about to screw you guys over
Wow when when each of these spirits die
it heals this for ten oh thank you good
all right as you die all the fire
spirits start to move back into the
forest thanks Josh oh yeah I thought if
Roman had gone for the life tap Justin
would have done the AE
and I think I would have just let him
kill it but if it got to the point if
Justin to the AE and it didn't kill him
you guys were gonna you guys were gonna
be knocked out you guys are really odd I
mean I balanced this fight around the
idea that there was potentially three
extra guys helping you and you killed
them all do cut his head whoa whoa we
killed one
oh no you able to you life drilled
everyone through life drains this one oh
yeah but then Roman did the kiss of
unconsciousness Roman did the kiss about
yet all right so we're gonna take we're
going to take a break here and when we
come back we're gonna do some loot yeah
after this Thanks well we're gonna take
a quick let's just let's say like a
five-minute break because I need a good
breather so we'll be back here in five
minutes and then we're gonna do some
bonus loop stuff so save actually just
save your donation just roll off hold on
you won't be able to see it while we're
on a break here and when we come back
where you live and then we're going to
play some more I've read of realms live
see you guys in a minute
see you guys
[Music]