ring-ring ring-ring but not before I
make you higher up
yeah uh I'm sorry I can't change your
name you're gonna have to speak to the
higher-ups oh bloody Puma bum burden
it's not your nickname it's your
official office man oh ah very well I
will do so but not before I make you
higher up alright yeah oh yeah I love
you oh you're such a sexy girl sort of
Whiting really quite not okay great yeah
give me a bit though
oh nana how I miss you I respect and
love you so much
but when you went away to Turkey on that
holiday I always thought that you would
come home Nana my Nana
I'm born for you every single day
oh gosh on this fifth anniversary of
your death justice hey Ethel oh hey
thank you real really hot oh thanks so
much
justice and action man brakes were fine
don't mess with me
all
uh-huh
hahaha
Oh
ah man post ah
ah yes Bagon I'll trust you not the way
hello you missed me because I'm little
and wet like a penis little wet penis
I'll trust you not the way ah you missed
me because of little and wet like a tuna
fish ha ha you missed me because I'm
little like a leprechaun oh ah you
missed me because I'm little and greasy
like a WoG some of the Bloods gone from
the nose the back of my throat and out
my mouth cool that looks great climb
your way to the top it's sell High buy
low and then you make a beach sorry
I'll work you like I'm a regular Steven
and I just gonna fuck it fuck it
sorry it's 1999 what what's ass not what
to see Scoob - what's new - shoot uh
what's your reference number other
reference not as easy as some hike Italy
that's a letter that's not numbered
all's it say yeah say here it is ok so
well here we go oh oh here oh oh oh here
it is fantastic great work Zach you got
the trust of the co-workers and the
secret file now the slip out of here
real quiet-like and sell it for top
dollar
oh look what sorry the quarterly sales
report is what I need from you shopping
I'm sorry I'm so sorry I'm a sales
research assistant I give the cliff
great work Zack proud of you not only
did you gain that work of the Travis
look at the trumpets boom I said and I
didn't meant it
you like this done ship
you're a big fan of asunción
1999 coming soon to channel 7 just prior
turn it off fucking try you really like
this fuck you sketch comedy on an on
YouTube this is pretty fucked you really
like this