Nanni's some once I feel titus a let me
walk into the office it'll be your train
facsimile here printer there do you play
Nintendo
action
bigoted bill is a nasty man I don't know
why he works here he's key just keeps
waving at me like like this dog don't
look at him he's really evil and I don't
like him
you know I'm Jewish but you're not mad
you're Sicilian oh that's right yeah
yeah oh God bigoted bills now steaming
bigoted bills now steaming this right Oh
about that oh you're on his back
no what's tiny to get is it the back Oh
No yeah yeah is it I know same face oh
I'm fine same face
why just let me do this okay you're good
yeah just gonna go on your lower back a
bit is that a guy yeah yeah you buzz
enjoy horses yes but not that Oh oui oui
is it or is it a role-playing thing
yummy Magoo teeny chicken
you filthy cunt check it out check it
out my chicken check it
ah I'm hungry boy hungry boys always
you're both fucked the same pigeon
remember that when that pigeon came in
you both did you both fuck it or was
that just okay
regular the same guard or the workplace
Raleigh yeah what same same amount of
hairs on your balls
oh think ah
all right let's blue okay let's blue
more blue all right same curves I'm
Rachel I need a broom okay yeah I mean I
could help you with some of your grammar
as well it's fine
would have been better with a full-stop
rather than a I'll know that is a
full-stop you just sort of angrily
lunched me what's that blood even oh my
lord oh my lord oh my god
did he do mark
what do you think of this is that a dead
bird
yep you like that yeah take a closer
look
doesn't it make you think you know we
think life is beauty but it's a lot more
complicated than that you're getting the
horn be honest yeah I got the horn
I always bear up when I look at this do
you yeah I'm bear up when I look at
pretty people which this yeah just watch
here soft boom soft boom soft boom and
if I keep looking Aldo come okay do it
alright just do another one cool well I
was gone
well I was got mark you look up I was
got yep but hey I got a little question
for you my little beauty man shoot him
away Oh Zack that was pretty dang good
that pretty dang go down leg no name but
one in the minimum on just a little bit
in someone it really I like you I really
like it yeah cool what do you think of
this that's pretty cool Zack
what do you think of this Wow is that a
dead bird sure is I really do want more
really up into really down yeah what do
you think of this that's pretty cool but
Zack what do you think of this is that a
dead bird yeah yeah
let me kuma that's pretty cool mark but
I've got a question for you you can okay
hello that's pretty cool mark but I've
got a question for you why are you
buggin er that's really good mark that
is so strong but hey I've got a question
for you what do you think it is another
really strong mug really good what I got
question why it was swallow yeah I kind
of got a bourbon
oh my god it's one of those sweet skills