you want my jacket DJ lucky - yeah
boob alright bubble wrap a double-sided
tape a bubble wrap up oh oh oh this is
way more fun than cocaine oh oh
huh pop we found this earlier never done
cocaine you know you don't actually need
drugs to have fun I mean look at us
well just having a good time now and
it's just a couple of boys with some
bubble wrap and that's all it takes to
just have you know fun
get the endorphins run it and you know
what I think I'll be a little bit
happier tomorrow how about that ha ha
Brighton don't ever talk to me again I
do help feeding sir
that's nice that's clever you all crazy
man you're not hahaha
oh man either came him away from the
drugs lehem who happens you're fucked
he put his tie on his noggin
he put his tie your his noggin fucking
crazy yeah who's gonna start yet alright
hey hey I broke up with you cuz you
never respected me do you understand
that and you never wonder what was good
for me and then you stole money from me
you little twat house and you stole
money from me what again cuz I've moved
on I've moved on see you later
shit I love jelly beans I just want a
second was shit but however you two were
great thanks I there's a great cast is
this a little bit too much cocaine boys
yeah I think it's time to sing a little
song my mammy taught me back in 1920 and
take it away Zach three a two a one two
three
when you take cocaine with friends
everyone will know it's the end of the
day and we cocaine on a Friday been
shooting Clive Dane on a fried dough
Barry time we are 90s businessmen doing
cocaine because we have no friends like
okay now I get a guy I don't yeah of
course oh is this gonna take me it is oh
I'm on a summer holiday at the beach in
the Caribbean with my baby she's such a
good baby
we just roll around in the sand thinking
about how good it is to be on holiday on
our piano cruise I love beagle whore day
with my wife and babe
she's such a good baby I really love
guys bury me in the sin the cocaine okay
I got one more bit as well after that
goodbye Broden goodbye knowing you long
are you oh it's really getting in my
ears I'm sorry you had to go this way
but you know what the end comes for us
all my time has come
hey guys we just want to do some
engagement right now how much do you
think this amount of cocaine would cost
let us know in the comment section below
there are two certainties in life death
and puse death and puse two certainties
in life death and boom beam is much like
the much like the alcohol haven't you
done well this is a comment on
masculinity and how fucked it is but
you're just gonna think it's about doing
fun cocaine so please don't take this
the wrong way cuz it's not we're smarter
than that all right I just want to do
one more thing Yeah right in Brighton
this isn't the one thing but Brighton
yeah how I'm good what day is it
it's cocaine day and Friday do we get up
nah call you yeah any other bit
this is ladies and gentlemen a stop
bigger sketch for me we shot this on a
warm day we didn't mention the time I
don't know how I've shot this on a warm
day hey Zack imagine if your dick look
like this oh fuck Oh that'd be fucked up
hey guys guys there's something in my
cocaine come on
well is it something in my cocaine
burnin running to you all right man
our man is really these really tough for
me for six it's pretty for long
we wanna the whole crew was just
standing right there waiting for you man
but you agree get a shot of that then we
keep going can we please keep going or
you daisy
are you for real or I'll just sit up for
a bit ah should we call cut I don't
think we should I prefer it if we could
just keep going did you have two
different enemy ghosts
I don't yeah I also just want to do one
little thing really quick very humble
thing and then we'll pretend to be guys
that joke yeah hi
look they made a slight top because we
hired the office for the web series and
then the sound guy made us wear sakis
cuz' way too much noise look they made
us lake top because we hired the office
for the web series and they notice we're
Sookie's cuz we made too much noise well
guys I'm done I'm heading home I'll see
you guys later see you later mine
oh I began to lose oh I'm a spooky ghost
filled with ghost stories and calm oh
I'm a spooky cocaine ghost Oh dolla
dolla bills y'all
oh oh melih dolla bills y'all
oh I am the ghost of cocaine past this
just happened oh you like that is this
what you want is this what you want I
studied acting for three years
Shakespeare Edison I could do it all but
this is what you want