I want to talk a bit about creators
rights and specifically a publisher's
relationship with our artists and how a
character like spawn really changed that
conversation for a new generation of
creators spawn launched in May of 1992
written and penciled by Todd McFarlane
one of the premier comic artists of the
90s and probably the most influential
but those first few issues he along with
writers like Frank Miller new gay men
Alan Moore and Dave sim all shaped spawn
and something truly unique it kept the
capes cowls and powers but took the
superhero trope in a radically different
direction fighting the forces of good
and evil
simultaneously angels child killers
cyborgs and demons all in the same
antagonistic plane along with
introducing things like the necrochasm
timer giving a seemingly omnipotent
character a finite amount of power which
made him resort to using weapons guns
chains and spikes they gave a practical
reasoning for that 90s excess aesthetic
spawn was dominating and comics
popularity at that time he was
outselling Superman he had his own film
along with an emmy-winning animated
series on HBO
but before creating his own character
MacFarlane made his name in comics over
at Marvel with the amazing spider-man
where he would permanently reshape that
universe helping create characters like
venom and giving spider-man is now
iconic spaghetti webbing design adding a
flexibility and an elegance to his
movement posing by putting more emphasis
on the spider rather than the man you
could shed all the formal conventions of
anatomy and perspective and focus on
giving the images
image Spiderman had been in the 60s for
three decades and Todd wanted to bring a
modernity to those colleagues and of
course the result was hugely successful
and it wasn't long until he was handed
his own book both writing and penciling
the adjective was spider-man we sold
over 2.5 million units in its first
issue but that level of popularity meant
more money and more money meant less
creative control from McFarlane it was
sort of interesting that when they gave
you the book when it was floundering
they said here do whatever you want
creatively because it's not working and
then you take it to the top and all of a
sudden they want to jump back on as the
conductor so now they're going on taught
it it's too popular now you can't do
that you can't do this because there's a
lot of eyeballs on it you don't want to
offend anybody and and and so I I just
sort of got wore out of those
conversations and eventually decided
that we were going to go off on our own
and in December of 1991 he Rob Liefeld
and Jim Lee three of the biggest names
in comics walked out on Marvel feeling
that they weren't being appropriately
compensated for the success of their
work and you have to remember in 1990
McFarlane had already set the record for
best-selling comic of all time
spider-man then barely a year later I
fell broke that record with x-force
number one I want to be beating out two
months later by Jim Lee's x-men number
one selling over 8.1 million copies
still the highest selling comic book
ever published these weren't just
hot-headed kids rebelling against the
system these are the driving forces of
the entire industry comics were picking
up steam and the creator's wanted equal
compensation but then Marvel president
Terry Stewart famously stated the
importance of the creative people must
always be secondary to the characters
and it's that kind of backwards thinking
that left Bill Finger out of the credits
of every Batman comic film and video
game from 1939 all the way up until just
a few years ago comic book artists and
writers have historically been taken
advantage of Jack Kirby's Steve Ditko
Siegel and Shuster are getting only one
hundred and thirty dollars split between
the two of them for creating Superman
this is the actual check from that
action so MacFarlane Lee and Liefeld
along with Eric Larsen will support a
CEO Marc Silvestri and Jim Valentino all
abandoned the big two to create a bigger
third Image Comics the hub for creative
independence or the artists own a
hundred percent of their work image oh
nothing but the name and the logo and
was actually six separate creator owned
companies all allied under the image ban
with each artists imprint having its own
flagship type spawn being the highest
selling of the bunch as well as the
best-selling independent comic of all
time selling over 1.7 million copies
that's an independent comic featuring a
creator own character by publisher still
in its infancy now to put that into
perspective let's look at Marvel's
latest big crossover event civil war - a
book that was strategically released
alongside of Captain America Civil War
to capitalize on its success it sold
only 380,000 copies in its first issue
and only 148 thousand in its second you
can see now why comic book artists were
considered rockstars in the 90s there
was a general excitement and enthusiasm
around comics that just didn't exist
prior to or even after that period for
just a short time what was popular with
the books and the creators not just the
characters image was a gateway for
millions of new fans to get into comics
and it also served as a jumping-off
point for people too intimidated by the
four or five decades of history and
continuity of Marvel and DC Comics and
the success of spawn allowed McFarlane
to pursue other ventures like McFarlane
Toys which had a new standard for action
figures in merchandise showing that toys
didn't just have to be cheap minimally
detailed pieces of plastic they could be
high quality miniatures sculptures real
works of art image opened up a lot of
opportunities for artists with works
like Chu saga and Walking Dead it's been
a home for some comics most creative
voices and it's allowed them to showcase
their talents without restriction Todd
McFarlane was only 16 years old when he
first created spawn just a kid with
dreams that one day his own character
can stand shoulder-to-shoulder with the
legends and he just happened to
revolutionize the entire industry in the
process so take a chance and go make
some stuff
[Music]
14:20 he's our man if he can't kill him
nor gay Bonnie ash this week to the age
lost 10 to the D to the ages are both
morning