with great science-fiction the world of
tomorrow should always shed some light
on the issues of today a story told from
the perspective of the future can be
humorous and satirical but it can also
be uplifting and inspirational and it's
rare to get a perfect blend of
everything which is what makes a show
like Futurama so significant
Futurama premiered on March 28th 1999
created by Matt Groening
and written and developed by David X
Cohen and it tells the story of Philip J
fry the 20th century pizza delivery boy
was cryogenically frozen and thrust into
the retro futuristic world of the year
3000 it's the future my parents and
corkers my girlfriend I'll never see any
of them again yeah and it took that
grand sci-fi adventure concept and
weaved it into a heartwarming
character-driven sitcom Futurama could
have very easily been a formulaic
workplace comedy set in the future but
with its incredible world building
interesting somatic exploration and all
the mean potential you could ask for it
was able to subvert the expectations of
being just the 31st century Simpsons
clause I love the American family and so
with the Simpsons that was my take on
the American family so what I've done to
the American family with the Simpsons
we're going to do two science fiction
with Futurama we poke fun at all the
other ridiculousness new trivia science
fiction and it's the same time be
honored Futurama has a genuine love of
science and science fiction and that's
no surprise coming from a creative staff
that's been dubbed the most overeducated
cartoon writers in history with three
PhDs seven master's degrees and over 50
collective years and Harvard University
we had several actual scientists in our
writing staff I was a mere master's
degree in computer science but we had a
Ken Keeler PhD in applied math bill
Odenkirk PhD in chemistry and Jeff
Westbrook PhD in computer science so if
those guys couldn't answer it we then we
made something up bringing science and
mathematics into the writing as a
stronger logical structure but the
stories being told
take the episode prison
benda for example when writer Kim Kela
was given a check to design and prove
his own mathematical theorem to solve a
body swapping scenario in which no two
characters could swap minds more than
once the episode was unanimously
acclaimed for its intricate plot and
complex writing and in turn killer is
second WGA award the first as well as
the first for any animated project went
to the 2003 episode god felis in which
bender becomes his own microcosmic god
much like the famous sci-fi novella by
Theodore sturgeon yo I was God once yes
I saw you were doing well until everyone
died
- drama offered so many interesting
insights into life and he used more than
just humor to entertain its audience I
don't laugh as hard watching Futurama as
I do when watching something like South
Park which had an episode similar to God
fellas where Cartman is worshiped by a
race of seamen
I mean people and where South Park use
that premise as a catalyst for the humor
Futurama took a more philosophical
approach exploring theology and the
relationships between men and whenever
we consider gods wow that's pretty deep
Futurama has always been the master of
hiding brilliance in plain sight
bridging the gap between comedy and
arithmetic while bringing humanity into
the science there's not a lot of things
in that category comedy science or
comedy science fiction so there weren't
a lot of role models I think it took us
a little while to figure out how to do
that but I think what ultimately
happened is the more seriously we took
the math and the science and the end of
science fiction element the better the
comedy worked - because we had sort of
this serious set-up site and then the
characters petty concerns play very well
as comedy against you know the fate of
the universe and billions of years of
history and that kind of stuff so so
really what we found to our surprise is
take the science seriously take the
science fiction seriously and the whole
show where it's better that way it's got
a broad toolbox at its disposal when
constructing a narrative and that allows
it to tackle meaningful issues like
global warming multiculturalism and
racial prejudice and explored through
the lens of a cartoon it doesn't have to
sacrifice its comedic identity Futurama
understood that the future shapes a
lesson for the present the satire
doesn't always need to be steeped in
underneath that zany space adventure is
an incredibly intimate story about love
friendship and the significance of one
person's role in the universe
you're a pimple on society's ass and
you'll never amount to anything
Futurama had a hell of a ride and after
14 years and seven seasons it's gonna be
dearly missed it's a show that touched
millions of people by respecting the
intelligence of its audience and somehow
found humor in academia it may be gone
for now but after four different
cancellations you never know what the
future may hold to this legendary piece
of animation