[Music]
it's interesting how our perception of
history shaped by very specific cultural
imagery never the full story just the
raw emotion single frames can capture
the attitudes of an entire era and those
images very often appear in fiction like
with the atmosphere of a post-war Japan
perfectly captured in 1954 Gojira one of
the boldest political statements ever
put to film masquerading as a creature
feature directed by Ishiro Honda with
special effects by eg Tsuburaya the man
responsible for pioneering suit Meishan
techniques and the tokusatsu style
filmmaking together with Tomoyuki Tanaka
and Toho studios they were able to give
form to this persistent fear of nuclear
destruction a fear that was still very
much alive in Japan given the recent
events in the Marshall Islands the crew
of a boat called the diag of Fukui you
Maru or lucky dragon 5 had been fishing
off the string of atolls in the Northern
Pacific which also happened to be the
testing location for the United States
new 15 Megaton hydrogen bomb and that
incident is mirrored in the opening
sequence of Gojira the events of
Hiroshima and Nagasaki left an empire in
ruin and during the post-war occupation
of Japan the United States tried to
sculpt a new foundation of democracy but
with that came a very strict censorship
policy criminalizing the production of
propaganda films and banning military
imagery and even though Gojira was
released two years after that occupation
ended Toho was still under immense
pressure by the new media regulations
imposed by the Japanese government which
had been influenced a great deal by the
American censorship policies and the
wounds of war were still fresh so Honda
and super riah's use of suggestion and
visual metaphor made for a much more
tasteful interpretation of those events
Godzilla may seem like just an oversized
lizard but there was a lot of thought
and care put into his design if you look
here you'll see that Godzilla doesn't
have scales like a normal reptile
grooved hide was meant to evoke the
keloid scarring of the survivors of the
nuclear blast and the blast itself was
represented in Godzilla's mushroom cloud
shaped head
Gojira was about perspective building a
window into the post-war fears and
anxieties of the ordinary people
involved in these tragedies and that's
something that wasn't taken into
consideration when the transworld
releasing corporation acquired the
distribution rights in 1956 the foreign
political messages were deemed
unsuitable for American audiences and
many of the scenes were cut in the plot
heavily restructured to include an
American lead with the idea that a film
with a Japanese perspective wouldn't be
commercially successful in the US
because Americans weren't ready to look
at the destruction of Japan to the eyes
of its victims so the film was retitled
Godzilla king of the monsters and scenes
were reshot to include actor Raymond
Burr as an American reporter covering
the destruction of Tokyo alongside
Japanese American actor standing ins
look-alikes to make it seem as though he
was part of the original production
while references to the dangers of
nuclear weapons and American testing are
either distorted or outright removed and
a lot of those subtextual elements were
lost in translation or just not
translated at all on top of the 20
minutes cut out of the film and the 30
minutes added the majority of the
original Japanese dialogue wasn't dubbed
or subtitled and the scenes that were
done very poorly I'll give you an
example with one of my favorite scenes
in film
it's a quiet moment in the middle of the
destruction a mother comforting her
children as the city burns around
it's one of the most poignant moments in
the film there's no musical cue just the
crackling of fire and this woman's
beautiful performance now let's take a
look at that same scene as it occurs in
the American release
[Music]
the added score muffles or delivery she
wasn't dubbed and I didn't remove the
subtitles that's just how the scene was
originally screened and you can really
see the difference in emotional
performance when comparing the coverage
of the Japanese reported to the monotone
monologue of Raymond Berg this is my
record as it happens a prehistoric
monster the Japanese called Godzilla has
just walked out of Tokyo Bay
unsurprisingly when the film premiered
it was critically panned Bosley Crowther
of the New York Times calling it
incredibly awful saying the same could
be accomplished with a dinosaur made of
gum shoes and $20 worth of toy buildings
and electric trains and that may be
harsh but I understand his
disappointment it's just a shame that he
along with most people never got the
opportunity to see the film as it was
originally intended
Gojira was a product of in a response to
oppression and tragedy and censorship
and what this version did was censor the
oppression trivialize the tragedy and
introduce an American perspective to an
experience that is very specifically
Japanese without understanding it the
film was designed to be a nuclear
allegory so when it's stripped of its
message all that's left is a dinosaur
stomping on buildings but despite the
criticism Godzilla found his success in
drive-in theaters and on late-night
television its popularity completely
obscuring the original film for decades
the original wasn't even available to
American audiences until The Criterion
Collection remaster in 2004 fifty years
after its initial release and over those
50 years Godzilla's significance within
the context of the man-made disaster and
war has shifted in favor of kaiju
battles he's embraced his Americanized
title as king of the monsters becoming
the defender of Japan as well as the
official Japanese tourism ambassador and
his domestication is due in part to the
American sanitization of that first film
the Godzilla we know today is as much a
product of America as he is of Japan
he's a product of the bomb product of
the censorship and a product of
Hollywood marketing part of coping with
the atrocities of
war is twisting them into entertainment
which seems distasteful and strange but
it's something that every culture does
and gojira was meant to be a cathartic
release for Japanese citizens something
that allowed them to reimagine their
history and learn from a tragic wartime
experience but the war was over now and
it was time to move on
Toho had accomplished its goal in 1954
but saw a potential market and American
audiences with a more lighthearted campy
er direction and with improving
relations between the United States and
Japan Godzilla was able to reflect the
changing demographic but it's telling
that in his current incarnation he's
much more natural disaster than an ally
so if you only know Godzilla by
reputation
a look back at his origins will give a
unique perspective into a very
complicated time in Japanese and
American history
[Music]