before the early 2000s if you heard the
term virtual band something like alvin
and the chipmunks or the Archies would
come to mind that comic pop fusion has
been around since the 50s but the
potential of that creative concept
wouldn't be fully explored until 2001 in
former blur frontman Damon Albarn and
tank girl comic book artist Jamie
Hewlett would collaborate and release
their debut self-titled album guerrillas
the idea to put together this animated
band arose from their frustration with
the MTB generation the phases of the
music industry becoming the celebrity
without substance so if the music was
going to be manufactured they wanted to
do it properly from the ground up and
with these four characters 2d Russell
Murdock and noodle they could strip away
the celebrity of it making the face of
the music into these characters parodies
of what they were seeing so much of
within the industry there's a quote from
Roger Morton in their book rise of the
ogre which he says in a world where
everything is a virtual copy of itself
where there's nothing but immature
publicists have publicists and where
celebrity is Bleakley industrial it's
inevitable that image starts to collapse
on itself guerrillas set out to shatter
that myopic idea of what pop was it is
or should be
it became this experiment to deconstruct
genre using these for musical archetypes
as a conduit to explore everything from
hip-hop trip-hop Britpop j-rock to
orchestral electronic jazz folk and
opera there's always a higher conceptual
theme to each Gorillaz album the
individual songs themselves a radically
different tone atmosphere
instrumentation and lyrics I'll give you
an example from their album Plastic
Beach something a bit folksy ethereal
and comb
and now at the complete opposite end of
the spectrum
and those were both part of the same
song those constant musical shifts drive
the album's momentum and keep you on
your toes
you never expect what's coming next this
need to over categorize music putting
everything in neatly labeled boxes is
detrimental to the exploration factor
when acquiring your musical tastes and
this happens mostly when you're young
you find a few genres you like and you
get stuck in that labeling truck one of
the most common things I hear when
discussing music with people is oh I
don't listen a country or I listen
everything but rap and that's a result
of constraining their tastes to a vacuum
they wrestle with monitors to try to
describe every detail you can't
discredit an entire spectrum of music
because you weren't into a bit of it
genre and sub-genre categorization allow
for more refined searching and trying to
find music with specific characteristics
or artists and similar fields and
categorization is just part of human
nature but it's also human nature to
combine and merge and collaborate
sometimes adulterate but that's all part
of the experimentation process and we
need more cross-pollination between
musical styles and cultures I grew up
listening degrees and that erosion and
genre boundaries opened me up to
appreciating so much more music and
that's something very important to learn
young the quote from Liam Gallagher in
the press was Meg enough who knows are
saying is for kids
it's fucking kids band and I thought
that was before the coolest thing ever
said about goodness because I want it to
be for kids the sort of 8 to 15 year
olds because they're the ones who don't
care who's behind it don't fit in there
who I am today
Damon is they think it's gorillas and so
they buy into it the way they should be
knit when kinase wood came out he went
in the top 5 and it was in there amongst
all this sort of teeny bot crap and yet
the kids are listening to that so they
were listened to sort of music
influenced by dub and reggae and hip hop
and thinking it was cool I think that it
worked
Jamie and Damon label completely
disappear by the artifice of this
animated band and the music took full
advantage of that free utilizing a
constantly rotating roster of guest
performers anyone from Snoop Dogg and
Bobby Womack to Lou Reed and the Syrian
National Orchestra the music is
constantly evolving even within the
album's and the animated element of the
band isn't just a gimmick or a
distraction those visuals can live on
their own and so can the music but the
marriage of those two together opens a
whole new world of narrative driven
songwriting so is this a film is this is
a movie well gondol it might be a bit
like the cinema doesn't have to be Ned
would his eggs because we give them
enough visuals enough sound enough music
to make a stable goal and see this in
some artists like Kanye and Beyonce have
experimented with visualizing an entire
album with music videos and these large
performances but that doesn't have the
same reach as something like gorillas
when you hear Damon Albarn's vocals the
fact that you picture 2d singing them is
something uniquely special and that's
what makes grill is so deserving with a
double platinum selling album nine
Grammy nominations and a GQ band of the
Year award to a band that doesn't
actually exist