there have been hundreds if not
thousands of different incarnations of
Superman in the nearly 80 years of his
existence he was the first superhero the
Hercules of American culture and why was
created on the page
who wouldn't become fully realized until
a cinematic debut when I say cinematic
debut one of these probably comes to
mind but Superman actually made his leap
to the silver screen in cartoon helmed
by this guy Max Fleischer and if the
name seems familiar is because he's also
the creator does into characters like
Popeye and Betty Boop he and his brother
Dave were approached by Paramount to
create a show for Superman who was
surging in popularity at the time with a
budget of about half a million per
episode they were able to create one of
the greatest achievements in animation
history they produced 17 single reel
films and by the Fleischer's themselves
the remaining eight by famous studios so
what makes this show so significant for
the character well for one it
established everything from the look of
the Daily Planet by the way to
Superman's ability to fly Superman
couldn't fly before 1941 it's why the
leap tall buildings in a single bound
comes from because the limitations of
animation at the time it was difficult
to have them bouncing around everywhere
Fleischer put in a request to have him
fly to lighten the workload on the
animators Wow unknowingly creating a
staple of comic-book superpowers flanks
the second most popular superpower
behind maybe super-strength everybody
flies yeah I can fly hey you fly in a
plane are you freaking kidding me
the show didn't just build on the
Superman mythos it also helped push
innovation in every facet of animation
and filmmaking in general it was the
first of its kind it was an
action-adventure series which no one in
animation was doing at the time
animation was for comedy it was
something for the kids to watch Superman
elevated the medium took it to places
nobody thought I could go and it
inspired multiple generations of artists
when we started doing the Batman
animated series I was actually going to
go with something a little bit brighter
gaudier a little bit more weird and
stylized but my boss at the time
suggested that we look at the Flash's
Superman cartoons again every element in
these films from the movement to the
color sound design everything worked so
synergistically that sometimes you
forget these cartoons were made in the
40s
even though lighting is realistic it
looks almost like an oil painting being
dark and shadowy well maintaining that
beautifully saturated color that's a
heightened sense of drama to the
cartoons
it actually anticipates the look of film
noir now I was compared to something
like the New Adventures of Superman
series from 1966 so 25 years
holy shit that is terrible
Max's approach to animation was less
about putting pencil to paper and more
about adapting the mechanics of
filmmaking to bring these drawings to
life cartoons don't move like this
anymore there's so much life in the
action it's fluid it's poetic every
frame is a wholly new drawing my father
was pioneer in animation a great
innovator great artist and really gave
cartoons the movement and flexibility
that we see today now what you just take
a close look at this shot from an
episode called the bullet tears did you
catch it
alright let's reverse time real quick
take it back right there so you can see
how after he catches his balance he
positions his foot on the ledge for
leverage to kick back off that may seem
like a really small detail but it's
difficult to capture that kind of nuance
and character movement and to do it Max
Fleischer developed an entirely new
method of animation they invented a
machine called the rotoscope
which is still in use in every
special-effects house in the world that
night up complete change in the look of
animation it was a process of filming
the movement in live action and then
matching it to the characters by drawing
directly onto the celluloid and just
remember without the rotoscope
lightsaber fights would still look like
this
the light servers weren't the only thing
Superman had a hand in take a look at
this episode it's called the Arctic
giant and responsible for inspiring one
of the biggest icons in pop culture in
stream
I noticed while modern portrayals of
characters like Batman are constantly
updating and becoming bigger and more
grandiose Superman at least in his
current incarnation seems to be trying
to get back to his roots
Dease even went so far stripping him of
most of his powers and reverting back to
the classic black and red insignia Max
Fleischer designed in 1941 and one think
most people are just beginning to
understand is that Superman when
over-explained becomes uninteresting and
you take a look at this scene from Man
of Steel this opening sequence lasts
nearly 25 minutes and while being very
visually engaging ultimately has nothing
to the narrative other than telling us
two things one Krypton was a place and
two baby kale leaves Krypton Krypton's
no longer a place now comparatively the
Fleischer's get that same origin in
about 25 seconds and Grant Morrison
famously did it in just four panels the
original Comics Superman sorghum's told
her just the first page origins stories
are boring as hell which is why the
second film in the franchise trilogy
usually works the best it's the
simplicity of Superman that makes him
such a compelling character
is a heroin perspicuity and it's
motivations we always know what Superman
will do because he'll always do what's
right the clearer the motivations the
more distinct the character becomes it's
the stories around him that should be
complex and while these cartoons and
their 10 minute runtime are necessarily
the most complicated narratives they
present Superman is the most fundamental
attributes if you strip away all the
faff and plot and continuity and just
look at the core of the character if you
had to explain to a five-year-old who
Superman was this would be your
description someone who's never read a
comic in their life can hop onto the
show and have a real understanding of
who Superman is who truly is he's not an
alien he's not a god he's just a dude
from Kansas doing the right thing