it'd be tough to find a piece of DC
Comics media after 1992 that hasn't been
majorly influenced by Batman the
Animated Series it went well beyond its
generation because it took the best
elements of every era of Batman and
brought it all under one banner giving
something accessible and familiar to
anyone who is a fan of the character
Batman premiered on Fox kids in
September 1992 created by artist Bruce
Timm and writer Paul Dini who were both
heavily involved in bringing to life the
entire DC Animated universe along with
the various games and comic book
offshoots those demand within Warner
Brothers for a darker serialized Batman
cartoon to capitalize on the success of
Burton's Batman film and since shows
like GI Joe and transformers were the
standard for action-adventure cartoons
at the time it was a somewhat radical
idea to do something more mature and
tone with the darker atmosphere and more
sophisticated writing the animated
series was airing in his time with the
films were becoming progressively more
and more cartoony and over-the-top
while ironically the cartoon took a
grounded more serious approach to the
material but it didn't just rely on
those adult themes
Batman's versatility allows the
character to be campy light and
adventurous or this dark vengeful
creature of the night and the animated
series circuit healthy balance between
both it covered the full spectrum of
potential with that character it was an
amalgam of everything people loved with
in Batman's history the camp and fun at
the 50s and 60s the swashbuckling
adventures of the 70s in the gritty
maturity of the late 80s and that's what
helped it inform the next two decades of
Batman stories it gave everything else a
template to follow and a solid
foundation build on that's why Batman so
consistent as a character it rooted
itself so deeply into the lore that it
significantly changed the source
material more than any other adaptation
before or any to come after
it didn't just add to the mythos
reshaped introducing characters like
Harley Quinn into the universe it was
conceived as just a throw away henchman
character but garnered popularity
through her original design and
interesting dynamic with the Joker and
of course the incredible voice acting by
our lean sorter and now she's one of the
most prominent characters in the DC
Universe it's also responsible for
reinventing former d-list villains like
Clayface with feats of clay and Mr
Freeze with the Emmy winning episode
heart of ice which to this day is the
greatest example of a sympathetic
villain in flight this is how I'll
always remember you
surrounded by winter of a young forever
beautiful rest well my love the monster
who took you from me will soon learn
that revenge is a dish best served cold
explored those hidden shades of gray
between the strict good and evil lines
of cartoons of that era it challenged
your empathy you didn't just get to see
Batman kick mr. Freeze's ass you had to
experience that heartbreak and that cold
sorrow understanding the Rogues gave you
a greater insight into Batman's psyche
and you realize he's not just trying to
beat supervillains he's trying to save
these victims of mental illness and
obsession heart of ice works so well
that it became an integral part of
friezes character across the comics the
games and even Joel Schumacher took a
crack at adapting it with Batman and
Robin
with the Batman films that man himself
is always the aspect least focused on he
has the best rogues gallery so it's easy
for him to be overshadowed by his
villains there the main event they get
the best lines best scenes most of them
even get top billing
but the animated series was able to take
its time and really delve deep in a
Batman and the life of Bruce Wayne and a
big part of the exploration was done
through the performances the voices of
Kevin Conroy Batman and Mark Hamill's
Joker have become the default voices in
my head
any time I read dialogue from those
characters they gave life to that text
like no one else could Conroy's Batman
is commanding and authoritative he's not
some snarling psychopath losing a cow
and his transition to the more subdued
Bruce Wayne voice is subtle and
incredibly effective it's a great way to
highlight that dichotomy between Batman
and his true mask he's got to disguise
himself somehow so I thought you know I
come up with this voice that was more
mysterious and you know it was just
another sound that would disguise him
and I thought in order to make that
distinct Bruce Wayne had to have a very
different sound so I just made him a lot
lighter a lot um there was a lot of
irony in it a lot of sarcasm it I played
up the humor a lot in the early episodes
and as his foil Hamill's Joker was both
charismatic and utterly terrifying he
was able to bring that character to a
whole new level that's what I wanted and
[Music]
big smile they went to great lengths to
incorporate that essence of Batman into
the visual aesthetic of the show knowing
how dark everything needed to be they
started on blackboard and airbrushed in
the color of the backgrounds gave the
images these rich authentic shadows that
complemented the themes of the
storytelling everything seemed to emerge
from the darkness there's very little
detail which lended more to the
imagination
it gave Gotham a sense of scale being
this endless black and void that
minimalism also carried over to the
character designs there was a tendency
with the early Filmation cartoons like
the Superfriends to try and emulate the
look of the comics of that era the
anatomy the articulation of the muscles
which works great for stills but not so
much in limited animation everything
ends up looking stiff and artificial Tim
took a much more simplified approach to
the character designs allowing for more
fluidity in the movement prioritizing
expression over realism but two years
after Batman ended its original run on
Fox the style was changed significantly
when the show began airing on The WB as
the new Batman adventures they tried out
more streamlined designs for the
characters that closely resembled what
was being done on the adventures of
superman' show which is airing
simultaneously Tim didn't want his
characters to be bound to the model ship
and redesigning the universe every few
years helped keep it fresh and reflected
the house style of the rest of the
animated universe these cartoons are
over 20 years old now there's an a hint
of anachronism to them there is
timelessness to fleischer superman
serials this was a show that truly
respected the source material and had a
great love and understanding of the
characters in that world and it's not
just one of the best portrayals of
Batman it's one of the best pieces of
animation of all time
[Music]