there are a few things in this world
more badass than this intro to the 1992
x-men animated series it's vibrant and
bold and exciting and it says everything
there is to say about the x-men but it
wouldn't hold that same visual energy if
it looked like this with comics and
superhero comics in particular color is
a key component in making the characters
iconic and recognizable in a universe of
thousands of characters you need every
available design element to
differentiate between them but color is
the most important if you distill these
characters and adjust their specific
color palettes you'd still have a pretty
good idea of who's who but in this era
of bland muted lifeless costume design
and film
you strip that layer of identity away so
if you can guess who this costume
belongs to we've had 16 years of x-men
films some great and some not so much
and apocalypse isn't out yet so I can
only speculate but why does it seem like
the x-men franchise is almost
embarrassed by the x-men actually go
outside what would you prefer yellow
spandex that line isn't directed towards
Wolverine it's directed at the audience
that was my response to a lot of
internet complaining about the the lack
of spandex multicolored costumes which
we tried in 2012 we even got
confirmation from singer himself that
there would be no more black leather
costumes in future x-men films finally
we've upgraded to black paintball gear
it's not an issue with the limitations
of costume design that's been proven in
Deadpool and partially in x-men first
class except for whatever the hell this
was about it's an issue with the
filmmakers and their faith in the
material because how is full-body black
leather any more practical than spandex
now this right now this this is the
first time the actors wore the suits
that is true and they could not climb
over that concrete divider they just
couldn't do it they kept a Hugh slip
this pan
they fell over and when the first time
they wore them everyone felt like they
were sort of in a body cast yeah and
could not hop over that wall without
practically falling over say no they
have the footage of it
we like tripped in like fall we fell
flat on our faces and because we can get
our legs high enough with these suits so
you couldn't feel less like a superhero
in these costumes the x-men have a very
complicated role in the Marvel Universe
they aren't celebrated like other heroes
they're misfits and outcasts and kids on
the run and a lot of them don't have
families and that costume that the
students wear is sometimes the only
thing that gives them any sense of
belonging it's not just a uniform it's a
symbol of the unification of the group
while also being a representation of
individuality because that's what being
an x-man is about it's a celebration of
self-identity take Nightcrawler for
example he's a circus performer and his
costume should reflect that it should be
vaudevillian and acrobatic and full of
color
there's nothing acrobatic about khakis
or a leather trench coat a costume can
say a lot about a character if you look
at Cyclops and Wolverines classic
costumes they have inverted color
schemes to visually represent their
opposing roles on the team and the
relationship is foils it's a subtle and
clever way to show their conflicting
ideologies and you get all that from
just two colors in some ways wearing a
flashy costume is a tool to battle
segregation and the discrimination the
mutants are facing by the public and
what is proud stand for if not
self-expression Xavier is goal when
designing the original uniforms is to
promote cooperation and project a
positive public image you wanted to
students to inspire people like
superheroes did it's the same concept
behind police uniforms or firefighters
black isn't the only serious color and
the x-men should do more than represent
a dated interpretation of cool this is
going to be about tights sorry Logan
superheroes wear costumes and quite
frankly all the black leather is making
people nervous here's a quote from James
Mangold the director of the Wolverine on
why the character doesn't wear his
costume he says that the flesh and blood
of the character is loyal to that iconic
elastic rebel who doesn't seem to be the
first to Don spandex and that by
removing the costume there
trying to stay true to the character
staying true to a character doesn't mean
stripping away the one design element
that he's always had since his first
appearance 40 years ago
Wolverine wearing his costume as a sign
of his loyalty to Xavier vision and his
respect for cyclopses leadership the two
may butt heads and be at constant odds
but at the end of the day Logan knows
who's in charge every now and then
summers I remember what you're still in
charge
because throughout history Wolverine is
a soldier and a soldier knows the
importance of a uniform so if you think
that blue and yellow spandex or capes
and tall boots are too silly for your
film then you don't take the property
seriously and a true fan takes their
interests seriously if you want to do a
darker real world spin on these
characters that's fine by all means
fulfill your vision but don't say it's
because it wouldn't work on film because
it does and it has and it will continue
to these characters should stay
authentic because they mean a lot to a
lot of people and I think there should
be a certain level of responsibility
when adapting these properties because
these characters are a result of decades
of work from creators who've shaped and
molded them into the icons that we know
today when people have been doing things
like this in cosplay for years there's
no excuse not to do it fulfilling but
overall I'm excited for the future of
the x-men franchise because they've
learned anything from Deadpool it's the
costumes can be comic accurate without
looking like they came from a Halloween
store
No
you