it's usually pretty easy to trace back
the origins of a character you just flip
through history till you find their
first appearance but for Bugs Bunny that
history is a little more complicated bus
doesn't have a specific creator he's a
character created by committee you see
unlike the rest of the Looney Tunes
characters Bugs Bunny doesn't have any
one definitive origin you have to break
up the roots of the character in the
stages one of the earliest instances of
a Bugs Bunny like character appearance
was in the 1938 short Porky's hair
remake of Tex Avery's Porky's duck hunt
which first introduced Daffy Duck here
the Bugs Bunny prototype is more or less
insane due to him being a reskin Daffy
the name came about in 1939 scrupled on
a model sheet by Charlie Thorson as Bugs
is bunny note the possessive apostrophe
in reference to bin bugs Hardaway the
director of Porky's hare hunt and one of
the several artists involved in the
creation effects money then in 1940 the
character was handed over to Tex Avery
Bob Gibbons and Mel Blanc who together
would shape the attitude and personality
of the Bugs Bunny we know today's bugs
represented the collective talents of
some of the best creators in the
business and throughout the years who
would be passed around an incredible
roster of artists like Fritz Freeling
Bob Clampett and Chuck Jones each
tweaking and refining the traits of what
would become one of the most iconic
cartoon characters of all time he's up
there with characters like Superman in
terms of sheer longevity and pop
cultural endurance but he doesn't seem
like a character from the 1940s his
anarchic gender-bending wiseass
personality is pretty progressive even
by today's standards and he's aged so
well because he isn't locked into any
one specific pool of relatability
something like The Flintstones can be
revived again and again but that
honeymooners era sitcom approach doesn't
really gel well with a modern audience
bugs on the other hand can work in any
situation because he's incredibly
versatile and that's why he's appeared
in more films than any other cartoon
character in history he's about as
frequently used in film as Sherlock
Holmes Hitler or God and bugs his
adaptability comes from his personality
which is a mishmash of traits from Jane
in Rex Harrison Dorothy Parker but he
isn't an imitation of anyone else like
how Yogi Bear is a very blatant
imitation about karna and that's
important when trying to make a
character stand out a kid mimicking Bugs
Bunny is mimicking Bugs Bunny not Clark
Gable or Groucho Marx because those
influences ever turn into caricature
bugs is immediately identifiable because
of his attitude his voice but most
importantly his movement characters
don't move like Bugs Bunny there's very
little expression in modern animation
the same budgetary tears Looney Tunes
hands at the waist feet together static
posing there are a lot of limiting
factors to blame for that certain
character designs don't even allow for
that sort of dynamic expression but it's
that movement that really brings out the
personality to define character
animation you have to go to the Three
Little Pigs which is the first cartoon
that was made and it was made in 1933 in
which three characters that looked alike
acted differently and you can define
them by the way they move rather by what
they look like and all of a sudden we
realize that we had on our hands a
method of communication which could
establish character and rather than
animating on ones like Disney Wonder
Brothers just animate on twos to get
fluid motion while keeping the budget
relatively low ones meaning one frame
per image twos meaning two frames
burnish animating on twos makes the
images less smooth that's snappier which
benefits that fast-paced slapstick stop
call me and chuck jones very often use a
technique called smear Posey using a
series of abstract smeared shapes for
the in-betweens to get from one keyframe
to another to simulate that smooth
motion the movement wasn't always
realistic but it was believable that's
why the ballet moves and what's opera
doc are so well executed as caricatured
and as absurd as it is when Bugs does
his fish dive into Elmer's arms he lands
with perfect Port de bras limb placement
is all impeccable there's an elegance in
that animation that's accentuated by the
live orchestra and Looney Tunes use of
classical music
Rossini's William Tell Overture
bugs as Leopold Stokowski conducting
tenor through his aria
[Music]
and to this day I still here right of
the valkyries has killed around all your
knowledge of high culture comes from
Bugs Bunny cartoons Bugs Bunny was a
very important figure in my childhood
and despite bugs being the corporate
mascot for Warner Brothers
he didn't fade into that role he's
always very much been a character of his
own Disney and Mickey are synonymous
with each other
Mickey's a more recognizable icon it is
dissolved into that logo he's put up on
a pedestal to be tamed inoffensive which
gives him that element of international
appeal while bugs is a hard-line New
Yorker brash rude defiant unmistakably
American which adds another layer to
that cultural barrier
Mickey's the better t-shirt but bugs
makes you laugh he's an entertaining
character not just the face of the
corporation
he's effortlessly cool always in command
in the face of all danger yet somehow
still the underdog you always root for
him even though you know he's gonna win
because he can kick your ass dress as
Scarlett O'Hara bugs is who you want to
be nobody wants to be Mickey Mouse
[Music]