this is the age of the multi - an artist
and no one exemplifies that philosophy
better than rapper writer producer actor
sketch comic and standup
Donald Glover aka childish gambino a
moniker he was given by Wu Tang Clan
name generator' during his time at NYU's
Tisch School of the Arts there he made
his name in improv with The Upright
Citizens Brigade
along with gaining early YouTube
notoriety as a member of the sketch
troupe derek comedy before launching his
career in television as a staff writer
for both 30 rock and The Daily Show and
then eventually being cast in a lead
role in NBC's community not bad for a
former Jehovah's Witness who grew up
prohibited from watching television but
that restrictive upbringing is what
really brought out his creative ambition
and I think that's what allowed him to
hop from project to project so
effortlessly like leaving community in
its fifth season to pursue a career in
music a move that was met with deeply
enthusiastic fans but also incredibly
harsh critics Jarmusch Gambino becoming
one of the most polarizing names in
hip-hop the infamous one-point-six
pitchfork review for his debut studio
album calling it one of the most
unlikable rap records of the year as
well as Time magazine claiming Gambino
just isn't cool enough for hip hop and
why exactly can't you rap about friends
I don't know childish gambino gets
people mad how can this comedian think
he's in the running for hip hop stop 5
he's not a real rapper right I don't
consider myself a rapper I don't I don't
think I'm a rapper I'm I'm I can rap but
I don't think I'm a rapper I want to do
a bunch of stuff but Donald Glover
represents a new archetype of
entertainment one that isn't bound by
classification someone who can easily
balance the self-deprecating nature of
being a comedian with the boastful
ego-driven persona of a rapper is a
multi-faceted artist that can use all
mediums for self-expression you're just
hurting yourself when you're like I'm of
this I'm of that and he's by no means
the first to do so there are hundreds of
artists with their hands and multiple
careers but typically they're very
distinct contained work
straik the actor Drake the rapper Tom
Ford the director Tom Ford the fashion
design but what I find so appealing
about Gambino and his work is
ability to thread all those elements
together shaping a bigger picture using
those various artistic tools and you can
see that in the album because the
internet a project that took full
advantage of all of Glauber standards
the two short films in the accompanying
72 page screenplay the visual show
during the live performance Donald even
started dressing like the story's main
character during press junkets and talk
shows further blurring the lines between
art and artists he's building a world an
immersive experience with the music just
being the soundtrack to that Troy the
boy earned Gambino they're all the same
character in a way the person on stage
when I do stand-up is the exact same
person who's doing rap like it'd be
different if I was doing jokes felt like
oh they're just made with love lemma and
then I'm like alright now to talk about
killing babies and smoke and we like it
sway it they're the same dude it's a
narrative that tells the story of donald
glover not necessarily in the
biographical sense but in a way that
allows him to translate his perspective
viewing the experiences that shaped him
through a fictionalized lens that can't
be achieved to its fullest potential
when it's limited to one medium and
that's what Atlanta's about filling in
the gaps left by the comedy and the
albums and scripts but everything is
interconnected and that's what makes it
feel whole it's all their structure it's
real you got to build a bigger world I'm
not gonna make an album I'm gonna make
like album I'm gonna make the rollout
dope I'm gonna make the movie with it
though I'm gonna make everything don't
make a world because the thing is like
album it doesn't mean anything music
doesn't mean it means as much as you put
into it and we don't have time to put
anything into it so hopefully I don't
see the point of making albums you
cannot like his stand up his music is
acting but you have to admire his output
his him bitch
he's in my mind what every artist should
strive to be unsatisfied Jorge Gambino
represents authenticity and subversion
disrupting the established that's
hip-hop personified and right now he's
one of the most important figures in
that feat and this new crop of artists
that have followed in his wake
had me excited for the future not just
the music but the culture I want to see
experimentation vulnerability I want to
see rap do what it was designed to do
keep it real
[Music]
you