Pixar sets the standard for 3d animation
they created a new medium for filmmaking
and continually raised the bars the
artistry and innovation but Pixar's true
success comes from their ability to go
beyond the technical and focus on the
most important element of film and
that's story they have 22 rules for
great storytelling that they adhere to
in all their films but I want to focus
on just one and that's the why must you
tell this story why does this story need
to exist and what greater purpose does
it serve whether it's to teach the
virtues of cooperation over pridefulness
coming to terms with the death of a
loved one or pursuing your passion
despite your background all themes and
ideas central to socio-emotional
development
these aren't superficial love stories or
fairy tales they focus on family and
respect friendship and compassion things
kids should be learning about in their
most impressionable years I grew up on
the classic Disney animated films I
loved those movies as a child and I
still do to this day
but even at a young age I was curious
why so many of them focused on love
stories or stories about a young girl
giving up everything for a guy that they
barely know in the Little Mermaid Ariel
leaves her Kingdom her family and gives
up her own voice to be with some dude
she saw through the water and there's
nothing wrong with stories about an
ill-treated girl being swept away by a
prince but they aren't really applicable
to younger kids and it makes sense
considering all these stories or
adaptations of hundred-year-old novels
there's a tendency and animation to
oversimplify a message and boil down the
central conflict into one megalomaniacal
villain with no real subtlety or context
for being evil Disney films are
notorious for making their antagonist
fairly paper-thin scar has no motivation
other than wanting to rule Gaston is
little more than a thug and even frozen
which is a great story about sisterhood
and independence as a cliche mustache
twirling villain revealed toward the
third act this isn't by any means
add storytelling these are all fantastic
films but these characters have so much
more potential in the incredibles
syndrome may be evil but you see that
characters aren't wanted and what did
you say to me fly home buddy I work
alone he's layered and you understand
his motivation very clearly and
ultimately it makes him more sympathetic
even Sid who arguably isn't even a
villain he's a curious kid who likes to
experiment with his toys sure he's a
punk but we all were when we were that
age
the real antagonist of Toy Story is
woody his selfishness and fear of being
replaced sets the conflict in motion and
he's challenged with accepting change as
a natural part of life and from an
emotional perspective that's much more
relatable than facing your nemesis Pixar
understands that the most important
stories resonate with people because
they appeal to some core truth about the
human condition regardless of whether
those stories are told to the eyes of
toys or monsters or robots they're able
to really empathize with their audience
as if to say we know that you're feeling
this way and I want to show you why
you're feeling this way and they do it
in a manner that doesn't feel preachy or
condescending they strive to teach
emotional understanding something I've
always admired about Pixar is that for
the most part they tackle subject matter
that would only work as a 3d animated
film you can't adapt Toy Story into any
other medium it just doesn't work the
same you can do cars and live-action or
inside out as a play Cinderella has been
a novel a film a cartoon a play and a TV
series with Pixar you're not going to
get these stories anywhere else look at
Finding Nemo it's a film that took full
advantage of a fresh unique setting and
told the story you could only do in the
ocean and now let's look at a similar
film shark tale
it came out a year later and it's just a
weird mafia gangster movie with
restaurants and car washes and all the
fish are racist stereotypes you're not
Stephanie oh hey don't sweat it a lot of
white fish can't do it didn't embrace
the medium animation has the ability to
simplify or exaggerate an abstract
clarify
it's the perfect vehicle for
storytelling and character development
it has the capacity to explore truly
meaningful subject matter and should be
more than bright colors and catchy songs
there's this connotation of childishness
that comes along with animation because
the audience is typically skewed young
and people have a tendency to take the
term family film to mean kid-friendly
and that's just not the case with Pixar
films these are stories for everyone
fathers mothers teenagers children
anyone with a beating heart and a hunger
for great storytelling