we've come a long way since the early
days of computer-generated visual
effects creating entire planets
resurrecting deceased actors but one of
the biggest innovative leaps came when
CG was still in its relative infancy
Jurassic Park released in the summer of
1993 directed by Steven Spielberg and
adapted to screen by David Koepp and
Michael Crichton who also wrote the
original novel Jurassic Park set a new
standard for visual effects and film and
it fundamentally changed the DNA of the
modern blockbuster CG is no longer just
another brush in a filmmakers toolkit
sometimes it's the entire canvas and
that flip in the industry only occurred
when Jurassic Park showcase the
capabilities of the computer solidifying
its role in the creative side of the
process not just the Technic and despite
its massive influence Jurassic Park
didn't actually mark any visual effects
milestones it wasn't the first to use CG
or the first to use it well it didn't
use the first entirely CG character or
even the first animal but it was the
first to successfully hide its effects
seamlessly blending the digital work
with the practical alternatives they
originally intended on using initially
on Jurassic Park
everything was intended to be done
somewhat more conventionally between the
full-scale live-action pieces and we
were going to do miniatures but ILM had
been working with computer graphics and
they put together a dinosaur transfer
that looks pretty convincing and we took
it down to Stephen England that's how
we're gonna make the movie but they
didn't fully rely on CG to create those
effects the stop-motion animation team
was repurposed to animate armature rigs
equipped with motion incomers
essentially translating the stop-motion
movement into digital data that could
then be applied to the CG skeletal
models there was an awareness of the
strengths and weaknesses of each method
and the bridging of those technologies
was a significant factor in making the
animation so convincing and whatever
level of detail was too complex for the
CG
would be achieved with the full-scale
animatronics or bigoted Jers as they
called them he gave the animators a
real-life reference for weight and
dimension something physical to occupy
the space in the frame that'd be
difficult to create from scratch the
goal wasn't spectacles to recreate
reality and the key to believable
effects is the way they're integrated
into the physical world
so you've couched the digital images
with close-ups of skin and eyes and
teeth and by the time you see the CG
t-rex in motion the practical image has
already been pieced together in your
mind the visual effects have to be
grounded in some semblance of reality
and you can see that in the
cinematography as well even when the CG
is implemented you're still witnessing
the events from a human's point of view
it gives the dinosaurs a sense of scale
and verticality and allows you to relate
to the characters fear all because it's
presented through their perspective but
whose perspective is this from or this
there's an incredible amount of research
that went into making accurate
depictions of these dinosaurs studying
behavioural patterns of alligators and
giraffes muscular movements and walking
patterns of elephants there's a reason
no other dinosaur can compared to the
t-rex in Jurassic Park and that's
because it was shaped over thousands of
man-hours a paleontological resources
and later iterations of dinosaurs and
films haven't used what we've learned
through paleontology and phylogenetic
bracketing there for the most part
Jurassic Park clones there's been no
further innovation even though science
has discovered so much since 1993 you
stood on the shoulders of geniuses to
accomplish something as fast as you
could you know you're read what others
had done and you and you took the next
step you didn't turn the knowledge for
yourselves so you don't take any
responsibility for it there are a total
of 14 minutes of dinosaur visual effects
in Jurassic park's 127 minute run time
only six of which use CGI that's 63
individual visual effects shots by
comparison
Jurassic world has over 2,000 and that's
not necessarily a bad thing but when CG
is plan a and plan B C and D are all
digital effects solutions you're
probably confusing convenience with
laziness people like to argue that CG is
somehow gotten worse over the years and
that's simply not true
but there should never be an
over-reliance on one specific tool and
that's what a computer is a tool I'm
going to use it to strip away all
elements of reality that's exactly what
you'll fail to recreate
you