the most meaningful art is able to be
enjoyed and understood at every stage in
life with Calvin and Hobbes you're
always discovering something new read
them when you're six and fall in love
with the colorful Adventures of a boy
and his Tiger but revisit them when
you're 16 or 26 and they take on an
entirely different but equally impactful
meaning Calvin and Hobbes launched
November 1985 written drawn colored and
lettered by this man Bill Watterson
Watterson was only 27 years old when
Calvin and Hobbes was picked up for
syndication and he had gone through
several rejected projects before finally
landing on the one strip that would
reshape the way people looked at
newspaper comics they weren't just
throwaway cartoons he firmly believed
that an artists work shouldn't be judged
by the medium for which it was created
there's no such thing as low and high
art his creations that either speak to
people or don't part of what makes the
strip so timeless is that you don't need
to understand the pop culture or
political context of late 80s and early
90s in order to enjoy it there was a
focus on asking questions and exploring
ideas rather than commenting on current
topics as comic strips often did
Watterson challenged readers on issues
of gender inequality religious identity
education environmentalism philosophy
and so much more he didn't let those 2
inch panels restrict them to cheap gags
or sloppy artwork he used it as an
opportunity to get people think outside
the box or at the very least rethink how
they thought inside it
reading Calvin and Hobbes makes you want
to be an artist and Explorer philosopher
a simple 4 panel strip can occupy your
mind for an entire day it perfectly
captures the complexities of a
six-year-olds imagination from the
infinite possibilities of a cardboard
box to their heroic aspirations we all
had as children as the comic evolved
Watterson rendered the world inside
Calvin's mind and an increasingly hyper
realistic style all the mundane retained
a more traditional comic strip look
Calvin's fantasies are always more vivid
and more real than his own reality that
contrast added a unique and visually
engaging dimension to the strip and it's
the details like those that set it so
far ahead of its contemporaries
Watterson was constantly pushing the
artistic and conceptual limits of the
form drawing comic strips comes with
heavy constraints chief among them is
drawing space early newspaper editors
developed a system that would maximize
the number of strips on a page and with
the dying print industry those spaces
slowly became smaller and smaller
Watterson fought with the syndicates for
more artistic freedom to explore
alternative panel layouts and page
designs he often even experimented with
throwing out the format completely
making for some incredibly dynamic
artwork but it wasn't just water since
draftsmanship
that made the comics so exceptional the
strips have substance too often with
short form storytelling characters
become dull interchangeable props for
the humor and comic strips can be more
than a three panel build up to a bad
pulling governor and hobbes both have
genuine personalities and it makes them
incredibly elastic in terms of story
possibilities they share a broad
imagination and appreciation for art and
a disdain for authority not unlike the
two 16th and 17th century philosophers
for which they were named Thomas Hobbes
and John Calvin so many strips rely on
the pun
which makes their characters plastic and
predictable Garfield's a lazy cat who
loves eating and being an asshole and
that's every Garfield stray it's lazy
writing in the most literal sense and
Garfield's lack of quality comes from
Jim Davis barely being involved in the
creative process with ghost writers and
assistant artists penciling coloring
nearly every strip since the mid 90s
Garfield has become a hollow brand for
merchandise there's no passion in work
Calvin and Hobbes massive cultural
footprint derives solely through great
artwork and storytelling not a flood of
merchandise and constant film and
television adaptations Watterson felt
that turning his characters in the
merchandise would violate the spirit of
the strip and contradict his message
he's protective of the form newspaper
comics are a dying medium so it's
understandable that he'd want to
preserve what he believed made his work
unique there's always a risk of
bastardization having something special
turned into mass-produced
uncharacteristic garbage like this
everyone's first exposure to Calvin and
Hobbes will always be these strips if
you want Calvin and Hobbes you have to
seek it out it's not going to be shoved
down your throat and that makes the
experience most intimate it becomes
personal it becomes valuable art before
Commerce that's how it should be and
that simply cannot exist in an industry
built on spending millions of dollars
but when it's just one man one voice
with a pencil and a sheet of paper a
truly unique perspective can be
expressed one of the best things to come
out of water since refusal to licenses
characters is the rise in artists
creating their own tributes to Calvin
and Hobbes
he's forced people to embrace their
creativity and make their own movies
characters knitted plushies and
animations short films the best thing a
creator can do for his fans is inspire
them to create themselves there won't
ever be any more Calvin and Hobbes after
ten years of creating that world
Watterson has said everything he wanted
with those characters and outside of
appearing in a few panels of pearls
before swine and this oil painting of PD
otterloop he did for Parkinson's charity
Watterson seems to be done with comics
but that doesn't mean it's over I see
kids today reading Calvin and Hobbes at
the same enthusiasm I had as a child art
is never done as long as it has an
audience even in a few panels you can
develop characters and express an
outlook on life as the months go by and
before you know it
readers are seriously invested in the
world that you've created