[Music]
South Park has come a long way since its
days of construction paper and Elmer's
glue and over the years we've been able
to see its growth from the profane to
the profound this is Matt Stone and Trey
Parker the creators of South Park as
well as the two animated short films
that preceded it both titled the spirit
of Christmas the first in 1992 featured
four boys witnessing a fight between
Frosty the Snowman
and an infant Jesus and second in 95
featured a fully grown Jesus this time
battling Santa Claus a video that became
one of the earliest pre YouTube viral
hits after being passed around Hollywood
by former Fox executive Brian Graydon
who had originally commissioned the
video as a Christmas card and with the
success of the spirit of Christmas they
were able to secure a six-episode series
deal with Comedy Central a dying network
mostly known for showing reruns of the
Benny Hill show and absolutely fabulous
South Park was a foundational part in
making it the basic cable giant it is
today debuting on August 13th 1997 with
the episode Cartman gets an anal probe
the only episode to be made with the
stop-motion cutout techniques of those
first two short films the rest of the
series was done in Maya using 3d
animation with the original construction
paper textures scanned in and plastered
on the models it gave the series its
signature style setting it apart from
its contemporaries like The Simpsons or
Family Guy it made it to perceived
cheapness of virtue and they didn't just
create a show they reworked the entire
animation process putting a system in a
place that would allow them to produce
content hours afterwards written than
average turnaround time of just six days
given the content fresh and topical a
time capsule of the current week and
while most satire pretty heavily focuses
on just one side of an issue
South Park tends to criticize every
angle Matt and Tracy the world for what
it is and presented as such they don't
take sides and they have no agenda but
honesty and humor they don't just target
conservatives they go after liberals
liberal positions left-right and
everything in between what we've always
said and I think
you say with the show is not anything
new but I think it is something that is
great put out there which is you know
the people screaming on this side and
the people screaming on that side are
the same people and it's okay to be
someone in the middle if laughing at the
South Park set up to dismantle any
symbol of self-importance
it isn't escapism it rubs our noses in
the ugliness of our world while
simplifying current events into a less
complicated more easily understood
format and viewed through the lens of
these four kids made it more relatable
to younger audiences but South Park
debuted just as the newly formed TV
parental guidelines went into effect the
series being the first to earn the tv-ma
rating by the FCC and people typically
like to point fingers at the FCC when
the topic of censorship comes up
particularly with South Park but the
FCC's authorizing legislation doesn't
allow it to regulate subscription-based
content that includes cable satellite
and pay-per-view services those are all
self regulated under their own standards
and practices Department which is why
the rules are so vague and varied
between network's standards and
practices only censor when pressured by
advertisers you're less likely to secure
an ad spot from McDonald's when your
content is laden with profanity which is
also the basis for the do monetization
ruling here on YouTube advertisers
typically operate under the assumption
that family-friendly content is their
biggest revenue source but that's not
always the case in fact ad space on
South Park has always been some of the
network's most valuable in the spring of
97 Comedy Central's highest selling ad
spot went for just $7,500 and after only
a few months of South Park being on the
air those prime time slots skyrocketed
to 30,000 or more although in the 90s
and early 2000s a lot of the material
was only suggestive Matt and Trey were
masters of planning a joke in your head
and then subverting it with an odd joke
there I didn't miss these days the
vulgarity is a bit more blunt you go
look at season two or season one and
it's so tame it's like Yo Gabba Gabba by
comparison to what we do now and even
though the material was significantly
tamer in those early seasons they still
push the boundaries of what was
acceptable on television quite a bit
take a look at the word pussy yeah I
know that some of you think this is very
funny words like penis and the Jannah
we're gonna get through this by being
mature and grownup people often accredit
Amy Schumer for getting the word pussy
uncensored on Comedy Central
but South Park was airing pussy
uncensored all the way back in 1998 at
the episode no or in 2001 with here
comes the neighborhood and now we hear
50 year old lady say it on CNN because
it's palpable
today we saw him boasting laughing about
grabbing a woman's pussy our cultural
sensitivities to language have evolved
there been a lot of swear word related
innovations over the years and South
Park has really blazed the trail for
social acceptability and obscene content
like with the episode it hits the fan
which serves as a great lesson on the
diminishing returns of empty profanity
by having the character speak or write
the word shit nearly 200 times stripping
it of its potency in the episode you can
really see the fluctuation in the
severity of swearing over time starting
with Kyle saying goddamn being one of
televisions biggest taboos just a few
decades ago shit being the centerpiece
of the episode as well as a word unable
to be broadcast on censored before 1999
just two years before this episode aired
and it's closed out with a censored it's
interesting to see where we are now in
terms of language tolerance and how far
we still have to go South Park's not
only the most aware but also one of the
most important shows on television which
really matured its audience through its
own immaturity helping to sensitize the
mainstream to vulgarity a common
criticism of South Park lately is that
it's lost its edge yet two weeks ago we
saw classroom of ten-year-old boys pull
out their dicks in protest on basic
cable
and it wasn't a big deal South Park
hasn't softened we as a society I've
just grown up in 1952 Lucille Ball was
prohibited from using the word pregnant
on television because it was considered
indecent and now equipment our standards
for what's offensive has radically
changed and maybe sometime in the future
we'll do away together as you can see
here the number of FCC complaints over
the past decade and a half has decreased
quite a bit that brief uptick in 2004
was the Janet Jackson's nipple incident
broadcast during the Superbowl and with
South Park there's definitely more
leniency on visual obscenities than
verbal ones for example in the episode
where is my country gone where the
Canadian Donald Trump equivalent is
shown being fucked to death by mr.
garrison but when the act is referred to
by the Canadians hey did you hear the
news but it the Canadian president's
been dad it's bleeped and that has a lot
to do with the crudeness of the
animation in the uncanny valley south
parks really just one step removed from
stick figures so they're able to get
away with a lot more depictions of
sexual acts involving construction paper
was pretty far removed from the actual
thing but the word fuck is the same
across the board but these words are
only bad because we let them be
censorship is really just preserving the
negativity of language the word
pregnancy being deemed too vulgar to air
in retrospect seems goofy and backwards
as hell but it didn't at the time and
think about how we'll look back at the
word cunts or get censorship does not
protect children as a former child
myself I can tell you that awareness
overpowers ignorance know about
something without knowing what it is and
you'll be more compelled to investigate
censorship won't keep a child from
swearing it'd only make them more
curious which is the entire foundation
of the show a perfect metaphor for what
happens to children when their language
is restricted claiming that words by
themselves somehow corrupt or degrade
the people that use them is not only
ridiculous but it's also what gives
shows like South Park a platform to be
offensive by pushing those artificial
boundaries with no boundaries there's no
one to offend but that would probably
make life a lot more boring and a lot
less funny so I guess if that means
dealing with censored fucks on
television for the next decade or so
it's probably worth it to see just how
far South Park can push the envelope
within those limits
every one from now I got to try and
watch your language go fuck yourself
[Music]
you