there are a lot of polarizing opinions
regarding adaptations specifically comic
book adaptations and even more
specifically Watchmen a story that for
over two decades was said to be
unfilmable published in September 1986
Watchmen ran for two years as a 12 issue
miniseries created by Alan Moore and
Dave Gibbons and they designed Watchmen
from its foundation to highlight
everything that the comics medium was
capable of and what film television and
literature couldn't do Alan Moore said
in the past that if we only see comics
in relation to movies then the best that
will ever be are films that don't move
Alan Moore's goal in the mid 80s was to
focus on those elements that make comics
a distinctly unique art form
things like structuring the entire book
around the nine panel layout three rows
of three it gave the page as a sinner
which allowed more precision in its
narrative flow and the few times that
structure is interrupted or broken it's
done for a very specific reason it gave
more in Gibbons a level of control that
wouldn't have been possible with a more
fluid layout and you can see that use of
control with issue five fateful symmetry
where each page is mirrored front to
back converging in the centerfold with
Adrian foiling his attempted
assassination and with the film Snyder
tried emulating that control through his
use of slow motion
but the design of those panels is part
and parcel to the storytelling in that
book even the lettering is used as a
storytelling device Rorschach's word
balloons before his psychiatric break
are solid and fixed while after the
incident with the little girl the
dialogue is jagged and uneasy much like
his mental state it's an easily
unnoticed detail but it adds so much
weight to that character another easily
unnoticed detail is watchman's use of
color done by John Higgins where
traditionally in comics a primary color
palette would be used reds blues and
yellows Higgins proposed using a
secondary palette purples greens and
oranges and when they did use the
primaries they would use them boldly to
punctuate a moment something that's lost
in the film watchman's less about the
story being told and more about the way
it's being told it's a comic about
comics no matter how visually faithful
and adaptation film can't articulate
that intent but that doesn't mean it
shouldn't be adapted Alan Moore himself
has dabbled an adapted material with his
own work characters in Lost Girls and
League of Extraordinary Gentlemen and to
a degree the characters and Watchmen are
loose adaptations of the classic
Charlton characters noir shack Nite Owl
dr. Manhattan the comedian Ozymandias
and Silk Spectre were all based on the
question Blue Beetle captain Adam the
peacemaker
Peter cannon Thunderbolt and nightshade
respectively Watchmen was originally
going to be a team book comprised of
those pre-existing characters but more
didn't want to be encumbered by
continuity and all the baggage that
comes with writing in an established
universe he wanted his characters to be
damaged and to generate a complete 180
subversion of the known superhero mold
and these days everything's a grim
reimagining or a gritty deconstruction
but before 1986 that didn't really exist
outside of The Dark Knight Returns it
took the realism that Marvel introduced
with characters like spider-man and made
it actually real not just money troubles
or alcoholism Watchmen dealt with
paranoia insanity rape war nuclear
holocaust what would happen if these
characters were real but not just real
within the context of comic
real characters in the real world
dealing with real issues using the
tropes of comic book storytelling but it
did it in a way that wasn't exploitative
however the film almost glorifies
violence knight alan Silk Spectre
snapping bones and half murdering thugs
arm sawed off every one of dr.
Manhattan's victims explodes into a
bloody pulp so a single panel like this
in the comic escalates to this yet the
destruction of New York is completely
bloodless seemingly inconsequential
which is the exact opposite approach of
the comic there's no real graphic
violence in that sequence with Dan and
Laurie Rorschach doesn't butcher a man
with a meat cleaver that one moment of
unimaginable horrific violence is in
those six splash pages surveying the
destruction of Manhattan the entire book
builds to that single moment and it's
incredibly powerful but by the time that
moment happens in the film you've almost
become desensitized to the violence and
there isn't really much to see other
than a flash of light
it doesn't elicit the same emotional
reaction as those brutally detailed
pages there are quite a few moments like
that throughout the film it strips away
the context but retains the payoff so
there's that emotional disconnect I'm
not saying there isn't a great deal of
respect given to the source material
because there is I am looking at the
stars they're so far away and their
light takes so long to reach us
all we ever see of stars are their old
photographs but it's selective and it's
seen in minor things like Ozymandias his
wardrobe his purple robes and gold
accents in the comic are meant to allude
to his infatuation with Egyptian myths
while also giving him a regal
authoritative silhouette but in the film
Zack Snyder wanted his costume to be a
parody of the rubber bat suit from Joel
Schumacher's 1992 film Batman and Robin
bat nipples and all so there's a
sacrifice of authenticity for an inside
joke it's frustrating because when a
property is adapted it's typically the
adaptation people are most familiar with
like with Watchmen and the Charlton
characters it doesn't affect the source
material but it does remove a potential
portion of an audience that could have
been introduced to it through its
original form although you could say
there's another portion of an audience
that would have never explored their
material had it not been adapted good or
bad faithful or not an adaptation should
only be seen as supplementary material
never a substitute for the original and
that's what I think people are
forgetting what I've said is that I'm
not trying to replace a graphic novel
with the movie as a matter of fact I
think in every opportunity I have I say
you know you need to read the graphic
novel yeah like if this gets people
interested in reading the graphic novel
then I've done my job as a filmmaker a
film a motion comic a videogame they all
exist to complement the original work if
you want a voice to read Rorschach's
dialogue in a sound effect for John's
teleportation it isn't necessarily
needed but it's there to draw from this
scene from the film is more emotionally
impactful for me than those five panels
in the book but only because I've read
those five pins I've had that experience
with the book and it's been visually
enhanced through the film those two
moments exist independently of one
another but ultimately they work
together to shape a more vivid image of
the overall story
[Music]
you