there's a beauty in horror the seductive
nature of something terrifying and
nowhere is that more present than in the
design of HR Geiger's alien a film icon
is influential is dracula that brought
an elegance to the grotesque and
reshaped the way we think of movie
monsters this is hans rudolf keegan
known simply as HR a swiss surrealist
painter whose roots are in architecture
and industrial design and his work has
been described as a twisted combination
of the surreal the mechanical the sexual
and the McCobb and even if you're not
familiar with his work you certainly
know his influence an aesthetics so
unique its aren't its own adjectives
it's rare for something so disturbing
and darkly sensual to also be
commercially appealing so what's the
story well in 1977 director Ridley Scott
and screenwriter Dan O'Bannon approached
Gieger after seeing his work in his book
Necronomicon a collection of gears
airbrush paintings
this is Necron number four it along with
its companion piece Necron five were
used as the basis for the xenomorph
design Scott was so impressed with
diggers work insisted on keeping the
design faithful to the original painting
interfering as little as possible
his distorted blend of sci-fi and
abstract industrialism was perfect for
that used future atmosphere they were
attempting with the film and gigglers
designs became such an integral part of
the production that he was also brought
on to shape the entirety of lv-426 and
everything within gradually down the
line I realized it made a lot of sense
how giga designed everything that was to
do with the alien that includes the
landscape and the space craft that
everything that was earthly that it
would be Michael Seymour his team right
and so that made a lot of sense you know
to separate brains working on to Tiffany
walls up until 1979 horror movie
creatures were typically earthbound
entities spiders sharks lizard man fish
man Wolfman but Gieger as an outsider to
the film industry wasn't bound by the
common design tropes of the
he was able to create something
genuinely ailing a distorted
biomechanical reflection man everything
we fear about ourselves exaggerated to
the point of surrealism it's very
difficult to interpret those airbrush
paintings in three dimensions which is
why they had Gieger himself fabricate
the majority of the alien sets and
costumes they couldn't just tear apart a
jet engine and construct a set out of
scrap metal like they did within the
stroma gigas vision is very specific and
very uniform a replication of the
painting this accurate could only come
from the mind who created and Gieger
coming from background an industrial
design crafted everything with a
practicality mind the aliens elongated
head housing the secondary mouth the
breathing apparatus on its back and
place of a nose and of course something
with acidic blood would be encased in an
exoskeleton which by the way was made
with real bones along with condoms first
articulating lips and a human skull in
the tip of its head yes a real human
skull and coupled with the idea that it
wouldn't only take on the
characteristics of its host but also its
environment allowed it to blend
perfectly into the interior of the
Nostromo adding to that claustrophobic
terror but even outside its design one
of the greatest aspects of the alien is
the logic in its mechanics you as an
audience member can understand
everything there is to know about the
Xenomorphs parasitic lifestyle without
the need for exposition of dialogue
there's no expert that comes in to
explain the origins and motivations of
the creature
these symbol is associated with a pagan
deity named
he consumed the souls of human children
you learn the process visually through
the experience of the characters and
every stage of its evolution drives the
narrative and unlike your typical
slasher movie antagonist the alien isn't
supernaturally invulnerable it's just as
fragile as anyone else on the ship but
killing it can open a whole new series
of life-threatening problems for the
characters so brilliantly the objective
becomes escape it was jaws that
perfected the art of hiding its creature
for dramatic tension but that was done
out of a necessity given that the shark
was fairly unrealistic and closely but
the xenomorph
works in bright light or in darkness and
at every angle it's only seen any
glimpses to accentuate its ability to
disturb and seduce because the aliens a
monster that you want to sing and
honestly at a certain point it becomes
almost too intriguing to be scary visual
demon I say it and antunes alien hum is
a design and a state dishes and monsters
in each time five it was v delicious
something I launched cancellation height
and harmless as can see elegant the
vagueness come say in exile kickers
alien is one of the most influential
creature designs of the 20th century
it's become the crux of an empire of
games movies comics and merchandise and
somehow nearly forty years later it
still has the power to terrify excite
and arouse and equal measures it's a
creature that to this day has seen no
equal and it's one of the most
beautifully haunting nightmares ever put
to film when the work was finished an
alien I thought it will be something
special but that it never know that it
will be so important that and and I
remember God Carol saying
you know you will get famous with this
film oh my god I wouldn't be so
successful probably as with the alien
Phil Noah studying of the people is
known as the father of this alien it's
okay
[Music]