what is fully coolie at a distance it's
rock-and-roll and sex and fighting
robots evil corporations and space
pirates everything we love about anime
but it's not really any of those things
fully Cooley has a lot on its mind but
at its heart it's a story about a young
boy learning about maturity and the
increasingly complex emotions and
responsibilities that comes with fooly
cooly stylized FLCL was created in the
year 2000 by director Kazuya tsurumaki
and screenwriter yogi in Aikido in
collaboration with studio Gainax and
production i.g
and it was created as a stylistic
experiment of sorts an attempt to break
the conventional structure of anime at
the time Japanese animation is an
industry built on perpetual
serialization some shows running for a
decade or longer and that can sometimes
result in an end product that's bloated
or overbaked
but fooly cooly was designed to feel
almost like a music video or a Japanese
commercial from the late 90s short and
accessible but densely packed with
character it's a teracle and chaotic and
heavily heavily stylized but it's all
contained within six half-hour
installments it never gets lost in its
own absurdity there's always an
emotional through line to keep the
narrative on track it's focused on
exploring the anxieties and sexual
confusion and frustrations a young boy
has been experiencing puberty the
phallic imagery and violence and
sexuality isn't just there for
titillation it's used as a lens to shape
a bigger picture around growing up it's
less to show containing sex and violence
and more a show about those sexual and
violent urges and were anchored in the
perspective of mountain Indaba
a twelve-year-old boy was caught in a
messy relationship involving a rogue
alien police officer how do how - Haruko
and his older brother's ex-girlfriend
sama Jima mommy me as well as a
classmate his jealous father and a
seven-foot robot that emerged from a
portal in his head that appeared after
being hit in the skull with a bass
guitar by an alien whose goal is to free
a space pirate from an evil corporation
who intended on smoothing the wrinkles
of the planet with a giant clothing iron
but like I said it's not about any of
that it's about adulthood and how that
means absolutely nothing
all the adults and nafta's life were
child
incompetent a stupid adult who doesn't
know how to grow up and they each
represent a different aspect of his
immaturity insecurity abandonment issues
auto call we've been calling herself an
illusion of his youth the manifestation
of the feelings in his adolescent heart
anime Alta has this idealized vision of
adulthood that it conduct himself by
stoic removed uncaring he's always
focused on appearing cool like this
scene from episode 5 notice classmates
are chatting about the rumors that he
saved the city unless that admiration go
to his head feeding his ego he's
convinced everyone that he's the pilot
of this robot Conti when in reality he's
just a bullet he doesn't really
understand maturity and he's too afraid
to take a chance at expressing himself
emotionally which is what keeps him from
maturing nothing can happen till you
swing
he's a kid that's constantly trying to
shove his problems back in his head
rather than confronting and those themes
are represented in the show through
different flavors just being a kid it's
an adult taste
he isn't fond of exploring anything new
you like the spicy curry or sour drinks
you know I don't like salad drinks the
friends stick with the sweetness and
familiarity of his childhood which
contradicts that false identity that he
constructed for us but we see his growth
as he learns to understand his youth
realizing that age and wisdom aren't
always synonymous fooly cooly isn't
about manhood it's not a coming-of-age
story it's a story about embracing
individuality and having the strength to
stay true to yourself and it's the
insanity of a world where no one knows
what the hell's going on fully Cooley
was a show that I never understood when
I was younger but I felt like it was one
of the few things that understood me and
what I was going through in that period
of my life it perfectly articulated that
sense of discomfort and confusion that's
unique to puberty and that's what made
it so accessible both in and outside of
Japanese audiences so it fully Cooley
seems to you like an incoherent mess
just remember how you saw the world when
you were 12
ah
you