this year marks the 20th anniversary of
Pokemon a property that over the years
became as much a social movement as it
was a gaming experience this platform
for players to connect with each other
exploring and discovering together while
transcending language age and culture
creating this global community beginning
in Japan with pokemon red and pokemon
green and later pokemon blue when it was
imported into the West in 98 work found
a massive audience in American consumers
who proved quickly that this wasn't just
another fad like Tamagotchi but it all
started in 1996 with Game Freak a small
team of developers led by Pokemon
creator Satoshi Tajiri and just to clear
up a bit of widespread misinformation
this is not Satoshi Tajiri this is
current Pokemon company CEO suni Kazuya
Shehata
this is Satoshi Tajiri the founder of
Game Freak a company that started as a
small self-published gaming magazine
where Tajiri could express his
admiration for games and game developers
but on April 26 1989 just 5 days after
the release of the Gameboy
Tajiri with the help of Ken Sugimori the
magazine's artist turned Game Freak into
a video game production company what
drew to jury to the platform was the
potential he saw in the game boys
linking functionality that data transfer
system inspired a dream in which he saw
little creatures crawling along the
cable from one game to another and
Tajiri was also a big fan of the
Japanese series ultraseven a show in
which the protagonist would fight with
monsters hidden inside little capsules
and out of those two concepts the idea
for Pokemon was born with production
beginning in 1990 and taking nearly six
years to complete then by that point the
game boid hit a major lull in popularity
but despite the hardware being nearly
out of date by the time of its release
Pokemon went on to become one of the
game boys most profitable titles
boosting its sales over two hundred and
fifty percent after launch and his
popularity spread across the globe with
the still ongoing anime series in the
trading card game each of which
simultaneously contributed to and
borrowed from one another shaping
Pokemon into this international
multimedia phenomenon with every kid in
the world wanted to catch them all as a
child diagnosed with autism - Gerry
spent most of his free time collecting
bugs and that played a major role when
developing the mechanics of the game the
concept of collectability really
resonates with gamers trophies and gamer
score every game has come
and jury collecting some games like
Sonic and Mario but those rings and
coins don't really mean anything if
you've ever played 52 car pickups you
know that this is not a game it's a
chore but these collectibles were
special they were yours
something could show off to your friends
and they could show off to you and
that's where the social hook came in
because Pokemon games come in pairs each
with their own version exclusive pokemon
so with red and blue each game had 11
Pokemon that were only available on one
of the two games in addition to four
pokemon that would only evolve when
traded which meant out of 151 pokemon a
tenth of them were only accessible by
trading so to the game's design alone a
community was built from the ground up
it's brilliant marketing because not
only does it promote sales but it also
encourages collaboration which is
required to achieve the main goal of the
game gaming typically gets a bad rap
with marketing especially with pre-order
exclusives and bundle exclusives but
with pokemons open barter system as long
as you have one game every piece is
there for the taking the exclusivity
only extends your ability to interact
with other players and that's laid out
for you right at the beginning with the
starter Pokemon players are immediately
broken up into three categories and
introduced to these three pokemon two of
which you cannot obtain in your own game
at least not alone and that kick-starts
the sociability aspect you have one safe
you pick Charmander you got to go hunt
for Bulbasaur and squirt but not out in
the tall grass in the real world you got
to socialize you got to participate they
gave a lot of shy kids myself included a
foundation for conversation young
introverted people didn't have
difficulties with icebreakers and
Pokemon served as a sort of blanketed
interest for most of us which made it a
lot easier to make friends so why people
go to the movies on a first date it
gives you a topic of conversation the
starting point for the relationship to
evolve Pokemon was designed to be a
social experience even though the
gameboy is very much a device to escape
social interaction it isn't just built
on the connection with a player and
their Pokemon or a player in the game
but with a player and other players if
two games share data with one another
there
forever when a Pokemon is traded it
remembers the original trainer that
captured and raised it the stat sheet is
branded with that players name and of
course that alone won't create lasting
bonds between people but pokemons
encouragement of cooperation and
competition will for me growing up with
these games played an important part in
learning the merits of sharing and
sportsmanship and you can get that from
athletics or summer camp or church but
for a lot of people it came out of this
little 353 byte cartridge I grew up in
the first Pokemon generation but now
every generation has their pokemons
every game will be someone's first and
every kid will grow up with these
characters that 8-bit journey we started
two decades ago isn't over because there
are still so many new people to connect
with and so much more to discover