there's a structure to language we all
learn when we're young a flow to the
words that could almost be sung
something most of us learned from the
great dr. Seuss with his chartreuse
villains rhythm reminiscent of Mother
Goose in his imaginative world so
perplexingly abstruse told with the
simplified language even a kid could
deduce his name was Theodore Geisel the
man who coined the word nerds and wrote
green eggs and ham with just 49 words he
made reading a tool kids could finally
enjoy not like Dick and Jane books which
would bore and annoy in much of his work
he used this literary trick it's a
rhyming tetrameter it's anapestic it's
that signature style that's always
greeted with laughs it's just two
unstressed syllables and one stressed
syllable actor and today the great
Yertle that marvel is he is king of the
mud that is all he concedes that he
showed that that rhythm helps with core
memorization and builds children's
confidence with classroom dictation some
constraints on a canvases language
design gives a structure to reading and
a writing guide you can see all these
kids were finally reading by choice
these stories told to the voice of dr.
Theodore sois and yes sois is correct
he's of German descent it's just harder
to say with an American accent and the
semblance to goose helps skyrocket his
fame kids preferred saying Seuss so he
stuck with that but his acclaim wasn't
bound to just one single nation his
stories exported to the gift of
translation books phrasing and language
in which they were written works
perfectly fine in the US or Britain but
to reach out to the world and all of its
culture hellos not enough you need hola
and bonjour and not just the words but
the rhyme patterns too like Poisson on +
on du plus all woosh + on blue with
designs in the hundreds of with distinct
features translators work hard to rename
all these creatures translating them all
with their essence intact while
preserving the fun at a major impact on
the habits of reading of kids at young
ages there's so many lessons in the
words on these pages
[Music]
you