hey Michael here
and here I am the real Michael this
Michael was created by a brilliant young
man named Mitchell who brought it to me
at a meet-and-greet after brain candy
live it is phenomenal and obviously the
most handsome jack-in-the-box ever
Everest is a mountain that's eight point
eight four eight kilometers tall its
size is impressive or is it let's cut
earth the entire planet write an app
straight through Everest and then start
zooming out as you can see
Everest monumentality quickly disappears
against Earth's planetary ginormous
Atene compared to Earth's diameter
Everest in fact all of Earth's
ruggedness barely registers now that can
seem surprising since we're often
surrounded by diagrams and maps and
globes that exaggerate Earth's
topography now there's a good reason to
do that but it leads to a misconception
about just how smooth Earth is here's a
typical example a cross-section of the
United States that I found on reddit the
vertical axis spans about 10,000 feet
but the horizontal axis represents
nearly 14 million stretched to the same
scale so as to mirror reality the actual
smoothness of the earth becomes apparent
on this one foot diameter globe
Everest is a bump about two millimeters
high
good but if the earth was actually this
small Everest would be a bump only 1/5
of a millimeter high it's 10 times
taller than it should be only 24 people
have seen the earth with their own eyes
as a circle small enough to be looked
right at not as the whole world but as a
little thing suspended alone in space
the further away you are from a ball the
more of its surface you can see now we
don't always notice this because in our
day-to-day lives most of the balls we
deal with are so small they're almost
always many of their own radii away from
us and the available amount of their
surface visible is near a maximum or
they're so big like the earth that we
rarely get far enough away fast enough
to notice this property but the next
time you're near a ball get close to it
you'll see that as you get nearer more
of its surface disappears behind the
horizon but moving back up will make it
available again for most of us stuck our
whole lives on Earth's surface such an
experience is impossible with nothing
around to block your review 5 kilometers
about 3 miles is about the furthest you
can see now haze can limit your view an
atmospheric refraction can slightly
extend it but for the most part
everything you can see happens within an
area of just 80 square kilometers that's
not bad but it's tiny compared with what
there is to see the higher up you go of
course the further away you'll be able
to see that's why it's great to be a
satellite here's the International Space
Station yes look at that nice big
portion of the surface in view
unfortunately this isn't to scale if the
earth were the size of an apple how far
away with the International Space
Station orbit like this far away maybe
this far away maybe this far away
actually it orbits
here 2.7 millimeters above the certain
that's how far the stem of this Apple
sticks up it's not very far oh here's
another fun little to scale fact if the
earth were the size of an apple your
eyeball would be about the size of the
moon we often imagine that from the
International Space Station astronauts
see the earth like this but they're just
not that far away from where they
actually orbit International Space
Station residents only see about 3% of
Earth's surface at any one time and that
3% is too wide to all fit within a
window when I was in Pittsburgh their
science museum had a mock-up of part of
the ISS and as you can see out of the
window earth is still quite expansive
using special lenses images can be taken
from the ISS that look like circular
discs Earth's but the lenses distorting
things here it's fitting much more into
the picture in order to truly witness
Earth's entire shape with your own eyes
you would need to either smash your face
right up against a window or just be
floating outside the station and even
then you would have to move your head to
see from edge to edge so how high up do
you have to go to see the edges of Earth
all at once
and even if you did that how much would
you actually see how much is there to
see earth is made of stuff lots of stuff
water and dirt and rocks and air all of
which are composed of atoms tiny things
so team that a single drop of water
contains not a million atoms not a
billion atoms or a trillion or a
quadrillion or a quintillion but five
sextillion atoms earth is made of even
more stuff not a septillion atoms not an
octillion non-alien Basilian undecillion
duo de silient Redis iliyan not even a
quarter Rhoda Cillian but 100 Quin de
Cillian atoms but since we live only on
the surface of our
planet we unfortunately can't see most
of those atoms if the earth was shaped
like a disk or an icosahedron or say a
cube or a rectangular prism or two
stellated rhombic dodecahedron we could
see more of the earth than we normally
can but as things are we actually see
nearly the least of Earth's matter
possible because of all solids a sphere
which the earth approximately is has the
smallest surface area to volume ratio
the most stuff inside and the least
stuff outside so how many of these ten
to the fifty atoms that make up earth
are on the surface for us to see that's
not an easy question for one thing
technically atoms on the surfaces of
opaque things like rocks and dirt aren't
the only parts involved in their
appearances subsurface scattering can
and does happen regardless attempting
even a rough approximation is
illuminating
I asked grant from the YouTube channel
three blue one brown for some help and
he pointed out that if you calculate the
number of circles with atom-sized radii
that could packed optimally cover a
sphere with the surface area of Earth
you get about one point five times ten
to the 34th that's a lot of atoms but
then he pointed out that the Earth's
surface isn't smooth its roughness
provides extra surface area for atoms to
occupy without a complete description of
the shape of Earth's surface every
mountain and valley every bump on every
rock this is just going to be hopeless
right well here's the thing Earth is
made of little rugged shapes that from
far away make big rugged shapes in other
words Earth's surface can be described
as a fractal there's a regularity to its
roughness in fact mathematicians have
even assigned a fractal dimension to
Earth's surface
two-point-three now to see what that
means I highly recommend grants video on
fractal dimensions it's fascinating
using two point three and assuming that
it applies from the scale of a human
hair up to that of a mountain grant
found at the number of atoms on Earth's
surface changes significantly up from a
power of 34 to a power of 37 that's a
thousand times more atoms so maybe we
shouldn't count Earth's roughness out
just yet it's smooth but not perfectly
to put that number in perspective the
human body contains about 10 to the 27
atoms that's 10 powers of 10 less than
the surface of the earth 10 powers of 10
is 10 billion there are about seven and
a half billion humans so more or less it
can be said that there are the same
number of atoms in every human body
right now as there are on the surface of
the earth as I've shown before all human
bodies piled into one place would barely
even fill the Grand Canyon but all human
atoms spread across the earth would
almost perfectly cover it just one atom
deep fun back the mass of the atmosphere
is about 2.5 percent less than what you
would get by multiplying sea level
pressure 14.7 pounds per square inch by
the surface area of the earth because
Earth's terrain displaces about that
much air Earth's surface is pretty cool
obviously I mean it's got lichen and
monster trucks and an island in a lake
on an island in a lake on an island but
from down here on its surface we just
can't see that much of it
your view of Earth is obstructed by lots
of opaque things walls buildings trees
rocks terrain if earth was flat you
could see further
but sorry it's a rough world out there
or is it if you could hold the earth in
your hands like this how bumpy would it
actually feel we already saw that even
our planets biggest bumps barely
register relative to Earth's size let's
go somewhere famously flat where
relative to our size terrain rarely gets
in the way of seeing lots of the planet
the US state of Kansas I grew up here
and took this footage while driving
across the state last year you can
probably see why Kansas is often called
flatter than a pancake however although
it is famously flat Kansas is not the
flattest u.s. state in a fantastic piece
of research
Jerome Dobson and Joshua Campbell
defined looks flat like this if from a
given point any part of the terrain
within the horizon Rises more than 0.32
degrees up about the height of a 30
meter hill at the horizon a typical
person would say well hey that part's
not flat by cleverly applying this rule
to topographical data they were able to
give every state a flatness score West
Virginia was the least flat Kansas was
only the seventh flattest Delaware
Minnesota Louisiana and North Dakota and
Illinois are all by this method flatter
than Kansas as was the number one
flattest state Florida
Adam Savage and I had the pleasure of
visiting Florida with our brain candy
live show this year and as this footage
from a top to King Center in Melbourne
Florida shows it's pretty gosh dang flat
now even though Kansas is not the
flattest it is the state most often
ranked flattest when the general
population is asked it is truly
scientifically flatter than a pancake
it's been demonstrated but there's more
to the story than that
in 2003 researchers took a 130
millimeter wide
cake procured from IHOP and analyzed
it's local relief they found the
difference between high and low points
was on the order of about two
millimeters if a typical pancake like
this was the size of Kansas five million
times larger two millimeter high peaks
would be ten kilometer high mountains in
comparison Mount Everest is only about
eight point eight kilometers tall and
Earth's deepest scar the Marianas Trench
is thought to be just under 11
kilometers deep so not only is Kansas
about as smooth as a pancake but so is
every other state in the Union and so is
the entire world if you were a giant
holding the planet in your hands like
this you and it would be torn apart by
the immense tidal forces created by your
gravities if somehow you could avoid
that though the planet would feel not
much rougher than running your hands
over a pancake but a soggy one right I
mean most of Earth's surface is covered
in water your hands would get wet or
would they yes
earth is covered in liquid but the depth
of that liquid like the mountains above
just doesn't compare to the total size
of the planet as it turns out if the
earth was the size of a typical
classroom globe like this one one foot
in diameter the volume of water
contained in above and on it would only
be about 14 milliliters that's this much
water kind of hard to believe because of
this scale spreading this much water
across all of the ocean surfaces would
be pretty much impossible due to surface
tension but this is it all of Earth's
water compared to all of Earth 90% of
the space on our planet life can live in
is in here the other 10% is dry land so
no you wouldn't get wrinkly fingers
playing with an earth like this you
could stop it dry just with a paper
towel despite the incredible area oceans
hover on our planet their depth is just
nothing compared to the size of our
entire planet now you may have heard it
said that if the entire planet were
shrunk down to the size of a billiard
ball it would be smoother than a
billiard ball after all we've seen so
far that seems believable but as it
turns out it's not true the
misconception stems from the
interpretation of the world pool
billiard Association's rule now
according to them a ball must have a
diameter of 2.25 inches plus or minus 5
thousandths of an inch
now some writers have taken this to mean
that pits and bumps of five thousandths
of an inch are allowed proportionately
on earth that would mean a mountain that
was 28 kilometers high so since Earth
has none of those earth must be smoother
than a billiard ball except if bumps
that high were actually allowed on a
pool ball a ball covered with 120 grit
sandpaper would be within regulation
clearly the 5,000th rule is more about
roundness deviation from a sphere and
not texture in fact as microscopic
photography has shown imperfections on
regulation balls are only 1/100
thousandth of an inch or about half a
micrometer deep and high scale down to
the size of a billiard ball Earth's
Marianas Trench would be 49 micrometer
speed so earth is smoother than a
pancake but not smoother than a billiard
ball nor as xkcd wonderfully showed is
earth
smoother than a bowling ball but hold on
earlier we were using the word flat now
we're using the word smooth that
distinction is important you see the
earth isn't flat like a plane instead it
curves it's a ball pieces of earth light
Kansa might be quite smooth but they
curve along with earth if you were to
stand in the middle of Kansas people on
the eastern or western
Edge's of the state would appear to be
not level with you but about 8.1
kilometers below you that's nearly the
height of Everest and if they stood
straight up they'd be tilted nearly 2
degrees relative to where you thought up
was now here's an interesting
coincidence generally speaking one mile
from where you are
earth curves down about 8 inches one
kilometer from where you stand it curves
down about 8 centimeters now the rate of
drop due to curvature isn't a linear one
you can't just multiply any distance by
eight to get the drop due to curvature
instead use an online calculator like
the one I've linked down in this video's
description you can put in any distance
you want anyway the visibility limit
caused by Earth's curvature is your
horizon it encircles you like a visual
cage but it's a cage whose radius is
determined by how high up your eyes are
Conan O'Brien at 6 foot 4 inches tall
can see up to 5 kilometers in any
direction but Snooki at 4 foot 8 can
only see about 4.3 to find out how far
away your horizon is geometrically just
use the online tools like put down in
the description below Earth's texture
can get in the way of your horizon but
can also cause things beyond the horizon
to peek into view hey what's that com
factors all of this in now if earth was
a smooth sphere the view from atop been
nevus the highest mountain in the
British Isles would end at the horizon
131 km/h would look like this but
factoring in Earth's ups and downs
here's a more precise boundary of what
you can see locked rate Scottish Gaelic
for Lake of death is only about 10 miles
from the peak that's within an 80 mile
radius but it can't be seen because
terrain in the way blocks it parts of
the Atlantic Ocean and the North Sea a
times further away can be seen they lie
at the limit of Earth's curvature just
before it bends the surface out of sight
these spikes extending beyond the
geometric horizon are caused by things
beyond it that are tall enough to peak
above Earth's curvature and the case has
been nevus this includes high elevation
parts of Northern Ireland ok enough
about the surface and what it's like
close up let's go further away and see
more this will be fun but there will be
a trade-off the further away you are
from something the smaller it will
appear to be moving away from Earth will
make more area available to see but that
area will take up less of your field of
view it can be difficult to illustrate
this in a YouTube video because your
field of view the shape and size of what
you can see with your head still just by
moving your eyes around is about 120
degrees up and down and more than a
hundred and eighty degrees horizontal a
screen is just a window of that space
nowhere close to filling it unless you
get uncomfortably close to help us
visualize large apparent sizes let's
replace the spherical earth with a flat
disk that's always the same distance
from the observer this disk can be given
an apparent size equal to Earth's from
any altitude and the disk can contain on
it everything that would fit within your
horizons from any altitude ok so
standing on the surface looking straight
down earth will take up nearly a full
180 degrees of your field of view with
your arms extended straight out parallel
to earth your fingers will point to the
edges of the planet your horizon from
400 kilometres up about where the ISS
orbits 3 percent of the Earth's surface
is within your horizon but the earth
will only take up about a hundred and 40
degrees of your vision your fingers
would point to Earth's edges if you
narrowed your arms angles each by the
width of two outstretched fists one fist
is about ten degrees across at arm's
length now you can move your eyes from
edge-to-edge horizontally here but you
can't quite take in the full-width
vertically but for more than twice this
altitude 1,000 kilometers away earth is
only 120 degrees across that's one less
fist-width each this is perfect that
fits within our narrower vertical field
of view so from a thousand kilometers up
about 620 miles you can just start to
see earth as a complete disc right in
front of you at once
however only 7% of Earth fits within the
horizon from up here images of Earth
taken by satellites this far up like the
Suomi NPP look kind of weird
I mean North America doesn't actually
take up this much of the globe Earth's
120 degree width has been compressed to
fit in an image much narrower compared
Africa from its height to the famous
blue marble picture taken from 45,000
kilometers away
the latter looks more realistic like
looking at a globe on your desk
geosynchronous satellites are about
35,000 kilometers high from their
altitude 43.4% nearly a whole half of
Earth's surface is visible but the earth
only takes up a meager 17 degrees you
could completely cover it with two
outstretched palms that's incredible but
what about from the moon well from that
far away earth is only about two degrees
across you could block it out with your
outstretched thumb however you can see
more of Earth you can see further around
its curvature from the moon 49% of
Earth's surface is visible just 49 if
you want to see 50 half of Earth's
surface at once you have to go even
further away in fact you have to go
infinitely far away
which you can't the most of us fear you
can see at once your own eyes is just
half but in the real world way before
you were actually infinitely far away
the amount of light reaching you from
Earth's surface would become so small
and infrequent that you wouldn't be able
to see anything at all stars like our
Sun are much brighter and better than
the earth but only a handful have even
with our best technology been resolved
as anything larger than just a single
point from one thousandth of a light
year away our own Sun would look like
every other star in the sky a single
point to the naked eye only about as
wide as our gyrados the widest star in
our sky from 91 light-years away the
point of our Sun would dim to a level
undetectable by the naked eye it would
disappear most of the stars in the night
sky you can see with your naked eye are
further away than that we can see them
though because they're brighter and
bigger than our own Sun which means if
there's life out there living in systems
around the Stars we've marvel that and
written stories about since humanity
began chances are we are not part of
their constellations or folklore we're a
dark patch in the sky to them and ignore
ball emptiness framing other stars the
ones they marvel at while not knowing
we're here or that there's anything here
and as always thanks for watching
[Music]
if you don't follow me on Twitter or
Instagram you are missing out on a
treasure trove of premium content so
check that out and know this I love you
oh and this vsauce shirt is only
available to curiosity box subscribers
this shirt comes in the latest box if
you sign up now you will get this shirt
so long as you sign up before it sells
out
the curiosity box is good for all brains
it comes to your door four times a year
full of science gear and toys that I
want you to have I want you to hold and
learn from also a portion of the
proceeds from every box goes to
Alzheimer's research I'm incredibly
proud of it but what's going on on this
shirt well it's modular multiplication
around a circle we have the numbers 1 to
40 around the outside of a circle
connected to their product with the
number 4 so 1 is connected to 4 2 is
connected to 8 3 is connected to 12 and
so on even past 40 you can keep
imagining the numbers continuing for
instance one can become 41 2 can become
42 and this emerges the Vsauce be many
other shapes can be made by using
different multipliers or different
numbers around the circle math a logger
has a fantastic video on this topic
which you should check out if linked
down in the description thank you for
being curious and as always thanks for
watching