hey Vsauce Michael here the eye is a
mirror when you look into an eye you can
see a small tiny version of yourself
that kind of looks like a doll version
of yourself the latin word for a little
doll is a few pilla that's where we get
the word pupil for a young student and
the word pupil for the dark hole in the
middle of your eye
it's a pupil because when you look into
it you see the pupil of yourself
the tiny doll version of you and you are
in for a treat today something a little
bit different than usual but I think
you'll like it I've been working with
Adam Savage on our tour brain candy live
and I decided to give him a tour of my
brain candy the little things I have on
my desk the desk I work at every day
that are sweet to the noggin but before
that here is a sneak peek at brain candy
live but not really this is this is
brain candy right here we've been
literally yeah this is the show we've
been the last couple of days here and
all the little colored pieces of paper
right for you it's blurred because we
don't want to give it away yeah well
maybe give that one away fight you've
got to come to the show oh yeah let's
not mess it up this is how I think
through a narrative it's either like
this or on a whiteboard yeah I can't
actually type it out linearly yeah and
you can see how dense parts are you can
see by colors where the audience is
involved where there's going to be
something dangerous and how they'll
maybe spread those out properly okay but
wait this is a lot while we're here
we're here because we're in Michael's
amazing Vsauce space in Los Angeles and
I happen to notice that your desk is
awesomely messy and yet covered with
stuff that I wanted to get my hands on
and we realized we should just shoot
that so a little bit of a concern yeah
let me I wanted to clean it up but I
don't kind of convinced me no the way it
is is the way we're going to film it so
this is just pure unadulterated truth
that's really what I'm about what's
going look all right why are you feel
like a little bit reticent to show off
your awesome by the way
you're deaf you couldn't set design this
with this much chaos so let's you like a
photo to go off of I'm nervous because I
mean I don't know there could be
something here that I'm like all that's
embarrassing yeah like you know okay
here's a half drink energy drink from
yesterday I'm gonna finish this today I
like them up flat I like a low
temperature I really want to show you
this
Stirling engine this is so precisely
made it is powered just trying to give
your hand
so put your palm out and then we'll let
that warm up for just a second meanwhile
yes yeah see all that blood in your hand
but the thing is it doesn't need a lot
of heat underneath it it just leaves a
temperature difference between the
surface on top here the disk on top and
the disk that's touching your hand so
while you're holding that because I'm
gonna get that bottom warmed up a little
bit plenty brave I hear
let's admire some Indian Indian Indian
it is the only element in the universe
you can chew like bubblegum
what it's a soft metal it gets softer
when warm but it's also non-toxic and
it's quite rare
I heard it's on the endangered elements
list and 100 years there might not be
really any found in the ground so is
this a particularly large chunk of India
then in a hundred years it might be or
it might not be I mean this is there's
some guesswork involved in knowing what
the earth has and what
going to run out of I'm dancing it with
my fingernail exactly and you can take a
bite out of it I wouldn't recommend it
because it's quite cold in here and it
could be a little firmer than your teeth
once haha but I took a piece off and I
melted it in this speaker because you
can make awesome mirrors with it this is
like a wonderful wish list for me other
things to play with because I think if
we went to if we went through my desk
and my space with my shop there'd be a
whole bunch of stuff you'd be like oh I
didn't know those existed we gotta go
vote yeah I'm going to give it just a
little turn alright but as you'll notice
even though I didn't put that much
energy in it won't slow down wow it's
going to keep going how does this engine
work well it's all about temperature a
kinetic approach to define the
temperature the air is made of molecules
moving and shaken around their
collisions produce what we call air
pressure now we say that warm air
expands but really it just has more
energy when a gas warms up its kinetic
energy increases it's molecules
literally move faster translationally
rotationally and vibrationally as a
result the average force say all exert
when colliding increases if the
container they're in isn't perfectly
rigid these collisions stronger on
average than those coming from the other
side will push the containers walls out
expanding the space within now that's
what happens in our engine our engine
has two Pistons a power piston
responsible for moving the big wheel and
a displacer piston that shuttles around
the air inside your hand warms the air
inside giving it more kinetic energy
enough to push the power piston up
turning the wheel the wheel motion then
pushes the displacer down moving the air
away from the warmer bottom plate
causing it to rapidly cool and collide
with the containers walls and the power
piston less often and with less force so
the piston falls turning the wheel with
it the wheels momentum now drags the
displacer piston up pushing air down to
the warm plate where it gains energy
collides with the power piston more
powerfully again sending it back up
beginning the cycle again it's
surprising just how quickly air can cool
and warm enough to move the piston it's
fast a classic example of this is the
old egg sucking trick put something's
burning in a bottle and stick a peeled
boiled egg on top
then suddenly OOP the egg pops into the
bottle this is often explained as being
caused by a vacuum forming in the bottle
because the oxygen inside got used up
leaving fewer molecules within to combat
the pressure coming from without but
that's not true the oxygen used by the
fire doesn't disappear from the universe
that would violate the laws of physics
instead the flame turns it into things
like water vapor and carbon dioxide
there are however fewer molecules in the
bottle when the egg is placed on top but
not because they were destroyed by a
fire instead it's because the heat of
the flame gave them enough energy to
push their way out air pushing against
the egg can get out because the egg is
shaped in such a way that lifting it
opens this seal but once the flame burns
out the air inside starts to cool right
away and well there's less of it inside
now external atmospheric pressure is
stronger but the shape of the egg is
such that pushing this way only tightens
the seal the air inside continues
cooling pushing less and less until the
pressure difference is enough that the
entire egg gets pushed in and that's a
piece of brain candy if you ask me the
egg isn't sucked into the bottle so much
as it's just pushed in by the atmosphere
because the pressure inside which would
normally be pushing back equally has
become weaker likewise you don't really
suck liquid up through a straw you just
cause the air in your mouth to push
against it through the straw less than
usual so the air outside can win against
you and push the liquid into your mouth
so make sure the haters know
scientifically nothing sucks anyway back
to how messy my desk is I think it does
give a good sense of what's in my mind
and how FS ODEs look to
it's like the kind of openness this is
what absolute looks like in your head
before it yeah and my tolerance for mess
is really high
okay so if I need you to work I wouldn't
even move anything I'd be like look the
trackpad and keyboard are accessible
yeah yeah yeah
but if also inspiring to have little
things around to fidget with for
instance these cast puzzles
but that one is called spiral oh wow
the craftsmanship was on some of these
puzzles it's just I didn't realize it
was a puzzle I just don't recognize it's
not all those pieces come apart they do
yeah exactly
and what they do is they I think
exercise the part of my brain that deals
with three-dimensional realizations I
don't think I'm very good at that it
takes me weeks to see something in my
head so try to like you know what the
all really good for is finger strength
because they're heavy and if you toilet
out of one for a whole day you're like
oh my gosh I'm giving some some uh nice
tone so what you said about the seeing
something in your head that's the same
way I build stuff I can't start building
unless I can see the structure in my
head do you think you're really good at
visualizing things in your mind
yeah no actually there's a there's a
term that happens and as a maker where
you start being able to just build stuff
in your head Wow and turning it over
directly after did practice make it a
better feel totally practice makes it a
better skill and every time I detect new
material it's the same thing this is
another point that's another one and
that one is really fascinating because
as you pull it apart you don't really
what's catching right how come it's not
coming apart all right no matter which
way you hold it and they're going to
lock itself these are like really modern
Appalachians like wire puzzles
now watch watch this I don't know if we
can get a close-up of this but if you've
got pins that are falling because of
gravity this way and this way there's no
way to unlock it on
you get some little centripetal force
happening or more precisely their
inertia will cause them to move out and
if I give it a little spin it just falls
apart Wow or sick it just wants to fall
apart when you find that beautiful so
you have got a lot of stuff here what
I'm picking up all the pump okay nullify
the delay
most yeah Oh sweetie please I must have
oil assumptions for those out there
watching who should really get into my
love topology stuff at the moment these
are Spears that dissect into a bunch of
pieces I bought at the dollar store
three for a dollar but yet these the
mechanism or the or the design behind it
is so clever and so easy to put back
together right I actually Instagram that
I was so like excited about the
simplicity because how it comes apart
and goes together this is from we when
we finish Mythbusters we packed up my
desk and it was exactly like this like a
couple hundred pounds of this stuff yes
the desk is super heavy for a few
reasons one is the tungsten cube ah
there it is
isn't that surprising ah fabulous this
is larger but not as heavy then that
solid steel that's a long ball it's a
plumb bob and i use that in d what if
you earth stop spinning video it was so
heavy I said it's like actually tape a
camera to it and you have a camera on a
pendulum so I'm noticing you've got a
lot of a lot of materials different
materials and the I saw you holding this
one early oh I think they opened down
this is a density cube set each cube is
one inch by one inch by one
and it gives you a really good idea
density how different things feel one of
my favorite things to do is because
different metals have different thermal
conductivity I will like pull some at
once copper ones with a catalyst to iron
copper and I'll mix them up I don't know
which one is which more than put them on
my forehead and I'll try to guess which
is which by which one feels cooler and
the one that feels cooler should be
copper it has a hybrid on the two they
feel cooler the question is which one is
coming I feel like the cooler one is
it's my high school that's where all the
cruel is but between these two the
cooler is I can't get this wrong I think
you actually can't get it home oh yeah I
should can but I'm thinking that this
one's copper you got it hey hey I can't
raise our little anxiety about that
pretty work I knew I could do it if I
didn't get it right on camera I'd look
like a fool my desk by the way happens
to be littered with pens that you can't
really see in the video they are pins
that are erasable because the ink inside
of them becomes invisible when heated
you can erase the ink in this pen by
just rubbing the other end of the pen
over the ink heating it up to the
invisible point a really fun way to
erase a lot of stuff at once is to just
use a flame
also I'm just going to go for the other
this is more these are is also a density
set but in this case every cylinder is
100 grams that's a hundred grams of
aluminum and this is led and that's led
and they've got brass copper
I think Lincoln and he'll it set a
standard tarnish on LED I don't know
because it's tarnished the part that
that's the finish in the wood
the reason I'm adding one oyster or
something one of the original Maltese
Falcon two of the original departments
were made out of lead and they now have
this very dark brown patina on them and
I have wondered and never wondered aloud
but I have wondered if Brown patina is
something that happened it must but why
did it not happen on the part that was
close to being I'm actually noticing a
interesting pitting on the brass and the
copper as well from the contact with the
wood yes could be boiled in the wood the
multi talking could be brown from many
people handling yeah it could be alright
so what do you think is the worst thing
someone could conclude from looking at
your desk I wouldn't be static included
that I was disorganized because that's
true
well disorganization others
disorganization you're not inhibited
from getting your work done money
exactly that is a piece of calcite that
has that birefringence property right
where if you look good out here
the supposition it does double vision
yeah see unless it's organized I can
find a legal pad in a second so let's
just draw like a circle yeah that's not
a great circle and then you rotate it
Oh No Lanie yeah okay so what is the
most recent object to tiny step yeah
thanks for parking I will do that what
are the most recent thing you've you've
brought into the space the most recent I
guess was also really cool isn't it cool
that's a call the TV Rock it's a piece
of us ice the fiber-optic property oh
cool I found out that a famous fact
about a polar bear first supposed to be
fiber optic is not true oh is it not
true apparently it's not so I didn't
even know that fact but if you were to
tell me I would believe it yeah I know
it's a total it's one of those feelings
oh yeah totally I buy a newest object
newest object if stuff in a speaker oh I
saw this yesterday yeah that came in the
in the curiosity box this third one and
it's it looks like a laboratory beaker
but it's a you know double wall thing
with the handle you drink coffee out of
and it has milliliter measurements on it
but I was like no leaders we've heard
about those we'll see you some crazy
unit right so what would evolve blood in
your brain the amount of saliva produced
every three hours during the day if you
fill it all the way up to 300
milliliters it also tells you to build
to here the beaker contains
approximately 10 septal and water
molecule I should of course point out
the spit error I misspelled saliva on
the Beger on every beaker in fact it's
completely my fault I take full blame
and spit if you are out there watching
please know that I respect you even
though I'm not perfect
I'm going to move past this because I
just did a rack focus on the glow
and am i right that that is one of those
bespoke gloves made by that company in
England yes that would be gloves
yeah okay yeah won't you go get it it's
not really a surprise that I love globes
I've done a lot of videos about where's
the earth look like how our map
projections made and this is a gift from
my wife on our wedding day well in
flattery if you look up at the top of
the globe it has written the company
that made it oh man it says our name our
nido Judith Wright and then it's got the
place of our wedding in the days and in
the base which is over there and it has
a plaque that says to my husband on our
wedding day
so these globes are the most accurate I
know I'm very familiar with these below
other hand I go to their website every
few weeks and think it's better as they
make them really large they make what's
called the Churchill yeah and you
couldn't even hug it I I think this is a
reasonable place to stop the desk or I'm
just going to go up into a corner and
look at this for a couple sure of course
look at some work done they use not
metal here so there you go brain candy
live hits the road on February 21st
traveling to 40 cities around the United
States check brain candy live.com to see
which cities were coming to we're
probably coming to one near you the rest
of our global viewers please don't worry
we are considering and looking at tours
and the rest of this beautiful glow but
for right now it's just the United
States see you out there on the road and
as always thanks for watching
but wait there's more let's talk about
the I specifically blinking we all do it
it's good for our eyes to blink but is
there a chance that at some point in the
future there will come a moment during
which every single pair of eyes on earth
every single human is blinking at the
exact same time a moment we will all
miss do tube linkage you blink your eyes
anywhere from 30 times a minute
all the way down to well just three or
four times a minute if you're fixated on
something like when reading that can
actually explain partially why your eyes
might become dry or fatigued while
reading also a typical blink lasts about
100 to 300 milliseconds which means if
you are awake for 16 hours a day and you
blink say 10 times the minute on average
and your blinks are just to be
conservative here only a hundred
milliseconds long in a waking day you
spend about 16 minutes of your life in
blink mode with your eyes closed that's
a lot of minutes to miss every day but
what about all of us blinking together
well the math has been done on Reddit
and the chances aren't good there is a
zero point zero zero zero zero zero four
billion more zeros 1% chance that today
every single human will blink their eyes
at the same time or have them close
because they're asleep that is a very
small chance even given the number of
days in the universe's life so far you
just wouldn't expect to have ever seen
it happen or to ever see it happen so
remember earth we are always watching
and as always thanks for watching
cool I'll just play it back for a move
yeah I can you cut on the audio