[Music]
hey Vsauce Michael here if every single
one of us held hands together in a chain
of unity around Earth would there be
enough of us to go all the way around
the planet there are about seven and a
half billion of them that's a lot but
remember that that many human bodies
thrown together into one big pile would
barely fill the Grand Canyon this is all
of us in one place the physical bulk of
all living human flesh on earth today
would only make a cone about 7,000
people tall and 2,000 across that's it
but that's a three-dimensional shape
what if we made a one-dimensional
single-file line of people each would
say one meter of room and we stretched
that around the planet well we would
make it all the way around and still
have 99.5 percent of the human
population left if we made a circle that
included everyone the ring of people
would be more than 2.4 million
kilometers in diameter dwarfing the
orbit of our own moon now that's not
just a circle that is a sir cool but
let's talk about circles today
specifically something that they do roll
but what is rolling what rolling occurs
whenever something moves with respect to
something else and is always in contact
with that something else and the contact
points have instantaneous velocities of
zero that is there's no sliding in
mathematics the path traced by a point
on a rolling object is called a rillette
French four little wheel the center of a
disk produces a roulette that's just a
smooth straight line while rolling on
one and this
disks are good wheels a square on the
other hand would be bumpy but square
centers can make straight through
roulette across the right surfaces this
is the principle behind square wheel
which I recently had the pleasure of
enjoying at the Museum of mathematics in
New York City Stan wagon wrote a
fantastic and famous article about
wheels which I've linked down in the
description below it's a great lead he
also contributed a fantastic interactive
tool to the Wolfram demonstration
project that allows you to build a wheel
and then finds a corresponding road
shape that allows it to roll smoothly
the roulette traced by a point on a disc
as it rolls on a straight line has a
special name it's called a trochoidal
reak word for wheel Pro code now throw
coins can be curtayne or prolate
depending on whether the tracing point
is inside or outside the circumference
if the point is on the circumference the
resulting curve is called a cycloid
cycloids are very special and they are
the star of this episode now I've been
working with Adam Savage a lot lately as
we gear up for brain candy live our 40
city tour that I hope to see you at
recently I asked Adam for some help with
roulette
Adams
give a favorite polygon um the whole
group I just literally an actual bit you
can't is there like your children yeah
the favorite I I don't have a favorite
either I do have a favorite thing that
you can do with punk okay
make a cyclic on a cyclic cyclic on is
an actual planet so actually it's an
actual thing doing a polygon around here
here's this this here's a squid right
right say this is a square yeah if I
take one of the vertexes of this square
and I start rolling this square and you
follow where that vertex oh shoot let me
roll this better egg you ready alright
the actual path that describes the curve
described here yeah that curve is called
cycling on and as you pick polygons with
more and more sides you get closer and
closer to what I want from you today
okay that's a cycloid cycle now I I
could have just done this in Photoshop
and done like an animation like I
normally do but you have a shop we can
actually build and you can build okay
why do I want to build a cycloid well
let me ask you this with only gravity to
move you what's the fastest way to roll
or slide from a point to some other
point below but not directly below would
it be a straight line well that would
certainly be the shortest path but when
you fall gravity accelerates you and
falling vertically a lot right away
would mean having a higher top speed
during more of the journey and that can
more than make up for the fact that a
path like this is much longer than a
straight line but of these two
considerations accelerate quickly and
don't have to long as a path what's the
optimal combination finding the answer
the path of least time is called vibra
Kista Crone problem and it's been around
for a while
Galileo thought the answer was a path
that's just a piece of a circle but he
was wrong there's a better one and in
1697 Johann Bernoulli came up with the
answer using a very clever approach to
see how he solved it let's start with a
similar
problem you are standing in some mud and
you want to run to a ball in the street
as quickly as possible now a straight
line would be the path of shortest
distance but if you can run on pavement
much faster than you can run in mud the
path of shortest time would be one in
which you spend less time moving slowly
and mud and more time on the surface
here fast on the angle you should enter
the pavement at depends on how fast you
lose on both surfaces as it turns out
when the ratio between the signs of
these two angles equals the ratio
between your speeds across both surfaces
the resulting path will be the optimal
quickest route this is called Snell's
law light always obeys AML's law when it
changes speed like when it leaves a
material in which it moves more slowly
like water and enters one in which it
moves more quickly like air it always
refract according to Snell's law in
other words light always follows the
route that is the fastest for it to take
Bernoulli used this fact to tackle the
brick eve de Crone problem light
changing in speed is analogous to a
falling object changing speed but of
course a falling object doesn't just
speed up once its speed is always
increasing its accelerating to mimic
this using light which Bernoulli knew
would always show him the fastest
possible route all he had to do was add
more and more thinner and thinner layers
in which the speed of light was faster
and faster and faster and well what do
you know there it is the brick East a
chrome curve the path of least time roll
down a track like this and you will beat
anything rolling down any other paths
every time Bernoulli was clever enough
to realize that this curve can be
described in another way as a roulette
specifically he noticed that it was a
cycloid the path traced by a point on a
circle rolling along a line a cycloid
satisfies Snell's law everywhere
to see why I highly recommend watching
this video on the bridge Easter Crone
problem
this channel is fantastic by the way I'm
a huge fan the visuals and explanation
are top-notch anyway a cycloid provides
the perfect balance between keeping the
journey distance short and picking up
speed early now I told Adam all of this
and I told him that it would be really
fun to have a cycloid curve we could
roll things down and he said clearly we
should start building would you just
start building it what we need is a
circle okay that's a height that we want
and then we're going to use that circle
to trace a mount cycloid curve I want to
do a race right so here look if we're
going to do like if you have point a
here and point B here and you say that
there's some kind of curve that's better
than a straight line in terms of
something traveling between those two
then I want to also make a straight line
from A to B yeah and maybe also a really
extreme curve like that right okay
got some protractors there I can't give
a compass again I do I have all sorts of
I've never seen such things that area
that connects to that and that connects
to that
give or take I almost am I feel guilty
that this is like a dream of mine coming
true oh really but it's such a nerdy
dream - it's not like I want this you
know Red Ryder BB gun it's like I just
want to curve that thing's roll down
okay so then clearly when we're done
with this this is this is like Christmas
recipe this I think I'm currently like
working out a way to do this in my head
that actually makes it fairly compact
and not super not super complicated yeah
take a blade and cut out like an inch
around the whole thing how are you going
to give the finishing I'm going to cut
this how much you would like to on the
band you can start okay here we go
[Music]
okay now that's a little bit rough so
we're going to finish it on my disc
sander oh wow
that's close enough it's pretty good
yeah so now you want to use this to draw
us like a cycloid yeah so you'll need a
little hole that's what yeah so that the
point of our drawing implement is on the
rim not above it I'm doing this right
inside let's set up I don't think so
you know yeah I'm sorry yeah that's even
better than having the rim hole because
we want the line to be right on the edge
okay so what we're going to do is we're
going to create a pattern for the
cycloid curve that I'm then going to
transfer to acrylic to clear acrylic
rather white allow us to see things
really clearly yeah
this allows you right roller spike for
representing it is literally like that
right oh yeah it's perfect yeah pushed
against here I shouldn't slip like a
Ouija board for geometry nerd
it is a Ouija board for geometry nerds
okay there we go that is so about Rakesh
the Krone that's that's at the curve
that we're talking about yeah that's the
beginning that's the end and this is our
pattern yeah Michael that's cool
okay so I'm going to end up with with a
piece of plywood let's say 3/4 of an
inch thick but it's going to have
channels table saw out of it reduce the
travel of slang and in those channels
will fit my clear acrylic acrylic curves
and it'll also have an upright that also
will have the channels milled out of it
on the table saw and that will allow the
curve to fit and be supported yeah a
little backstop here usually at the
bottom metal allows us to hear that they
all hit the same
there's a couple things going on one is
that we've got a cycloid straight line
and then we've got extreme curve right
and are these you had mentioned bending
the acrylic so we could adjust the known
actually I have this is real like this
everything krill ik will just be a sin
of acrylic this is the thin sheet of it
traveling on that will be and I have
material for this some Delrin or acetyl
rollers that look like this so from the
side they'll look like this they'll look
like an H uh-huh in which the acrylic
sits in there and the roller is
self-supporting on the acrylic but rolls
down
ah that it's tolerance love it
I like those curves while Adam and I
build a real-life spy coy track let's
take some time to appreciate other kinds
of roulette
as mentioned before trochoidal anon
straight lines but an epic row Koide is
made when a disc rolls around the
outside of a circle roll a disk inside a
circle and what you've made is a hypo
trochoidal names for the curves you make
when using a spirograph toy
notice that the holes don't lie on the
circumference of the disks though some
do come close there's a special name for
epic Rockwoods and hypo trochoidal I
went on circumference --is analogous to
disks rolling on straight lines they are
at both cycloids and hypo cycloids now
if two circles have the same radius a
point on the rolling one will touch the
stationary one exactly once always in
the same spot
creating a cut this cute heart-shaped
epicycle is also known as a cardioid if
the rolling circle has half the largers
radius you'll get a two cusp of a
cycloid the shape of which is called a
network because it apparently looks like
a kidney
I guess one-third the radius gives you
three cusps one fourth four cusps and so
on as for hypo cycloids if the inner
circles radius is one-quarter of the
larger the resulting roulette curve is
called an asteroid because it looks like
a star which the ancients also thought
about asteroids one-third the radius and
you've got a deltoid named after its
resemblance to the street letter Delta
1/2 the radius and well you get a
straight line
this fun relationship is called a
two-seat coupled rotational motion
turned into linear motion follow a
number of points on the rolling circle
and you'll get the famous illusion where
every individual point moves in a
straight line but the whole thing
describes a rolling circle put a handle
on it and you've built a trammel of
Archimedes aka
an ellipse a graph when used to make
ellipses aka a hillbilly entertainment
center when bought in Osceola Missouri
anyway let's get back to Adam a nice
curve comparison build I have a finish
line Oh beautiful
okay okay there's your finish line you
ready I'm ready
all right I'll count us down three two
one go okay here we go 3 2 1 go 1 2 3
with the the strength was second
straight was last great was last the
shortest distance between two points
what a blast and slowest way to get
there yeah it certainly was let's try it
one more time
yep because it was super close the brick
East a Crone curve was by far the winner
yeah what a mouthful of a name by the
way Britt Britt Easterbrook teesta Crum
but keeps Brook east across not related
to the Brachiosaurus different everyone
that's I once looked up the difference
between ingenious and ingenuity and they
don't have been they're not related no
all right all right I'm ready
okay then three two one go yeah same
results same result
one two these are so close it's hard to
tell
[Music]
well we're answering the main question
which is to save your keister chrome
curve is the fastest way to get there
well a brick isa chrome curve is also
known as a tata chrome curve it has
another property that's that we should
test which and that is it's not even
hold it before you get to this we've
established between these three curves
that the cycloid made brick easter
chrome curve is by far the fastest it's
by far the fat okay great you get steep
and unfortunately you pick up a lot of
speed right away but then you've got a
lot of this with little television yep
you go straight down and you know funny
enough you what you want is that perfect
balance of gravities acceleration but
also moving to where you need to be and
that is asked that specially to me that
a geometry which is the cycloid curve
would yield such an efficient
exploitation of the forces involved yeah
exactly because if there was no
acceleration if there was just one force
in the beginning straight-line would
probably be the fastest right okay what
is the other quality of the Tata chrome
curve you just said it
Tata chrome means same time so as the
geometry and math tells us no matter
where you start an object yeah what's
the clamp that was your fault City it
was my fault but also come on clamp go
exactly you know how to do these cables
are a pain in the ass because they have
these lips on them in they actually oh
that's looking and yeah they drive me
much it's actually my fault
good I'm glad we got that result okay so
I'm going to remove the straight line
guy as well so we're left with a cycloid
which is called a Retief to Krone curve
but it also has a bizarre property where
no matter where I start an object on it
when I let go they always reach the
bottom right in the same amount of time
wait a second so if I start it here the
amount of time it takes for the
to get to the end is the same amount of
time it takes for it to get to the end
from here yeah and the same from right
here well the extent Wow okay so
starting from here it's going to be
tough because of friction yeah now if
you do this in software it's perfect but
that's boring yeah this is the real
world and maybe we won't start them that
way I mean if we do one two and three
yeah or we actually I feel a good
problem we could probably get one to
work from here like that there might be
a lot of friction involved but look at
always see we can always see we've got
enough of them that up here I we made
three curves so to test this property
and these were all cut and sanded plants
together so they are incredibly soon I
will have to tamper the edge as I did on
this one yeah Pat I'm worried it was
just right and what's remove it steel
wool a little note fact that once you've
torn paper off of Plexiglas it crumples
it's a really nice ball to be thrown
long distances eh how did it get this
paper on the Plexiglas in the first
place good question I've never seen it
happen because it doesn't really feel
glued so they're good friends of Librium
gluons right yeah I think this is really
cool I hope it's cool because in theory
and practice theory in theory theory and
practice for the same thing but in
practice I went to the University of
Chicago where one of their changes that
sounds good in practice how is it in
theory ha ha ha ha
life of the mind there so let us see if
you do if I do one up here and you do
one there and ok yeah so this has got to
be without this I think the same person
should release them because then ok I'm
it better so here put that one here ok
all right so three different positions 3
this one has longer to go yep this one
has the shortest path
so who's gonna reach the bottom first
okay here we go let's see we'll be wish
everyday the one in might this one yeah
go first ready yeah good pretty good
that was awesome that was all I kept
they lined right up all right let's do
let's switch it up okay even I think
you're gonna be the one to release them
yeah otherwise it won't be the guitar we
go three two one
I'd be Gotham lining up yeah they line
up like they're waiting for each other
I'm gonna stand further away cuz I want
to see the full path okay ready yeah
three two one how cool is that they
totally line up to hit at about the same
periodicity they would for here so given
the vagaries of some extra frictions
here and there there they're actually
hitting this at the same sort of
periodicity that they are when they
start at the same point so there's that
and then
[Music]
it's the sub judice the Tata chrome
curve demonstration rig of your dream it
really is it really is it's also the
brook Easter Kron rig of my dreams and
the cycloid rig of my dream so check
that out you're doing that yeah that is
really cool
another one yeah that was yeah exactly
on point Wow
raesha see in this game no matter where
you start no matter who you are you're
always a winner that's a pretty cylinder
there's always a tie so this is brain
candy for me Adam Totalus this is
something that was previously abstract
and only seen in animations and in text
made real now I can put these wherever I
want I'm not stuck with what someone
else did I can physically hold it Matt's
that's what makes brain candy exciting
for this it is like that I love taking
the theoretical and making it physical
and actually honestly we've always had
what seemed to me like sister
enterprises yeah and it's nice to join
them together yeah this is is this
little child of ours isn't it is maybe
maybe one of us wasn't so good at
standing and maybe the other of us kind
of saved the day but it's real now
yeah and it's alive and I think it's
love in its life that was fun Eames
really fun yes had come true Adams thank
you so much for your help
working with you is always amazing I
hope to see all of you out there
watching at brain candy live it's going
to be incredible and in your daily lives
may you always find the Tata chrome the
solution that brings you and others
together even if you started in
different places and evolved
[Music]