hey Vsauce Michael here
if you pour a spear that is remove a
cylinder from it you'll be left with a
shape called a napkin ring because well
it looks like a napkin ring it's a
bizarre shape because if two napkin
rings have the same height well they'll
have the same volume regardless of the
size of the spheres they came from this
means that if you cut equally tall
napkin rings from an orange and from the
earth well one could be held in your
hand the other would have the
circumference of our entire planet but
both would have the same volume
I mentioned this counterintuitive fact
while making a kendama with Adam Savage
check that video out if you have it or
better yet just come see us we're
bringing brain candy live to 24 new
cities this fall it's going to be busy
but right now we're talking about balls
and coring them I have here two napkin
rings from very differently sized Spears
one is from a tiny ball just a little
tomato that I've cord so it's got a
little hole in it right there the other
napkin ring is made from an orange but
both napkin rings have the same height a
tomato has a smaller circumference than
the orange which means less volume but
its ring is thicker which means more
volume both of those effects exactly
cancel out so these two napkin rings
have identical volumes they take up the
same amount of space by the way orange
oil is flammable to see why the napkin
ring problem is true let's discuss
cavalries principle it states that for
any two solids like these two cylinders
I've built here sandwiched between
parallel planes if any other parallel
plane intersects both in regions of
equal area no matter where it's taken
from well then the solids have the same
volume that's clearly true here these
cylinders are built out of stacks of
vsauce stickers 100 in each stack so
their volumes are the same
if I skew one of them like this if shape
will change but it's volume hasn't it's
still contained between amount of stuff
I haven't added or subtracted stickers
and capillaries principle ensures that
they still have the same volume because
any cross-section taken from down here
up here in the middle anywhere
will always give us a region of the same
area as the other because those regions
are always equal area circles now let's
apply kelgarries principle to napkin
ring we can see that two napkin rings
with similar Heights have identical
volumes by showing that when cut by a
plane the area of one's cross section
always equals the area of the others now
to do this notice that the area of the
spheres cross section minus the area of
the cylinders cross section gives us the
area of the napkin rings cross section
depending on where we slice the napkin
ring the cross sections will have
different areas but they will always be
the same as each other let's calculate
the areas of these blue rings first of
all let's call the height of the napkin
ring H and the radius of the sphere
they're cut from capital R and perfect
now a cross section of a sphere like
this and a cross section of a cylinder
like this are both circles so their
areas can be determined by using pi
times the radius squared so if we want
to find the area of the spheres cross
section and subtract the area of the
cylinders cross section draw a picture
of a cylinder here all we need to do is
take pi multiply it by the radius of the
sphere cross section square that and
then subtract PI times the radius of the
cylinder squared but what are their
radii well if this is the center of the
sphere we can draw a line straight up to
the corner of the cylinder down the side
of the cylinder and then connect to form
a right triangle the Pythagorean theorem
will really help us here it tells us
that the length of one side squared plus
the length of the other side squared
equals the length of the hypotenuse
squared now this distance right here
this side of the triangle
what we want it's the radius of the
cylinder so we'll call this the little R
radius of the cylinder beautiful little
picture there so the radius of the
cylinder squared plus this side length
which is just half the height of the
cylinder so the height of the cylinder
divided by 2 squared equals the
hypotenuse squared the hypotenuse
happens to be the radius of the sphere
itself which is capital R perfect now
let's solve for the radius of the
cylinder which is what we want we'll
just subtract H over 2 squared from both
sides that'll give us the radius of the
cylinder squared equaling the radius of
the sphere squared minus cap the height
of the cylinder squared we can take the
square root of both sides so that we
wind up with the radius of the cylinder
equaling the square root of the radius
of the sphere minus 1/2 the height of
the cylinder squared perfect ok now
let's take a look at the area of a
cross-section of the sphere now for this
let's draw a straight line from the
center out to the edge of the spheres
cross-sections and we'll go straight
down and connect back up a look another
right triangle let's call this height Y
and notice that this distance now the
side of the triangle down here is
actually the radius of the circle
cross-section of here they're both equal
so we even want to solve for this the
radius of the circle that is the spheres
cross-section okay so we know that the
radius of the spheres cross-section
squared plus this distance squared which
is y equals the hypotenuse squared well
what do you know the hypotenuse is the
radius of the sphere again capital R ok
let's subtract Y squared from both sides
the radius of the spheres cross-section
squared equals the radius of the sphere
squared minus
I squared will take the square root of
both sides and end up learning that the
radius of the spheres cross-section
equals the square root of the radius of
the sphere squared minus y squared y is
the height that this cross-section is
taken from above the equator the higher
up we take these cross sections of the
sphere the smaller their radii will be
whereas the cylinders radius is always
the same no matter where we cut from Oh
anyway let's take these two radii and
plug them into our formula
okay the area of the cross section of
the sphere is what we want first okay
that's just the square root of R squared
minus y squared not too bad
now the radius of the cylinder is the
square root of R squared minus half the
height of the cylinder squared now what
you might notice is that we're taking
the square root of something and then
squaring it these actually cancel each
other out perfect much more simple
looking but now let's distribute PI to
the terms inside the parentheses so PI
times R squared gives us PI R squared pi
times negative Y squared gives us
negative pi Y squared then a negative pi
times R squared is negative PI R squared
negative pi times negative H over 2
squared is positive pi H over 2 squared
great now we can keep simplifying but
what you might notice is that we have a
PI R squared and a minus PI R squared
what is equal 0 so these completely
cancel each other out
but what we're left with are terms
containing no mention of the spheres
radius whether the radius is large or
small doesn't matter all you need to
know to find the area of the cross
section of a napkin ring is the height
of the napkin ring why of course is
bounded by the height of a napkin ring
these blue areas have the same area as
each other and this will be true no
matter where we cut the cross section
across the napkin ring meaning by
cavalries principle that both napkin
rings have the same
onion yay with you
but what is this mean for you for life
in the universe well as we know if you
like it you should put a ring but if you
like it don't know it's finger width and
only want to offer it a predetermined
amount of material you should put a
napkin ring on it and as always on
August 21st 2017 there will be a total
solar eclipse the shadow of the moon
will race across the contiguous United
States it's going to be incredible and a
little bit scary I'm sure I will be
viewing it from Oregon with my friends
at atlas obscura
I can't wait but keep your eyes safe if
you want to view the Eclipse you have to
have special eye protection the
Curiosity box comes with such gladdens
these block 99.999% of visible light
that's what it takes to be able to look
right at the Sun as actually what I love
about these glasses there's no eclipse
going on you can still just look at the
Sun notice that it's a ball maybe
imagine what kind of napkin ring you'd
like to make it into the current
curiosity box is my favorite the one
that you'll get if you subscribe right
now comes with all kinds of cool stuff
that comes with a poster showing that
all the planets and Pluto can fit
between the earth and the moon
it also comes with science gadgets like
these levitating magnetic rings pretty
cool also a portion of all proceeds go
to Alzheimer's research so it's good for
your brain and everyone else's brain
check it out I hope to see you at brain
candy live and as always
[Music]
thanks for watching