ah
Zach you're a tech-savvy dude do you
know if we can use the internet to help
send this letter to my dad it's so
simple Matt all you need to do is use
electronic mail or email what we've got
to do is scan it upload it click attach
and we're off
Wow email I think that's pretty cool
Zach but let me ask you something what
do you think of this well that's pretty
good mark it's really impressive but
mark I've got a question for you okay
what do you think of this not bad not
bad that that's not bad Zach but let me
ask you what do you think of this holy
shit yeah that was impressive am I right
or am i right
but mark yeah here's my question for you
okay what do you think of it that was
great if I could be honest for a second
that was great it was pretty good not
you know what it was spectacular but
Zach let me ask you what do you think in
this mark it was really strong but I've
got a question for you shoot what do you
think of this red gun single piece yeah
that's pretty good what else you got
what do you think of this is that a dead
bird yeah
those are all fantastic I've got an idea
let's show Broden oh I don't know I
don't think it's Broden sort of thing no
come on give him a chance he'll love it
Oh a my ears burning Rhoda what are you
doing was like your recive in the web oh
you Broden settle a bet for us Zack and
I have been goofing around and Zack
thinks you won't like it
come on boys I'm not some bloody prude
give us a look are you sure Brodin it's
pretty out there
but of course come on alright Broden
picture this what do you think of this
come here gun of a bitch brother chill
mark
why that was just a jar down around down
right
Oh God I'm come Oh what the fuck were
you thinking like I don't know to think
I would like that
I would never like that mug I never
liked that okay I made a mistake it
won't happen again
good good I mean if anything I'd
probably like something a bit more like
this
oh the telephone hello fingered there's
no way Phantom Menace is gonna be bad
I've seen the trailer Susan I looked at
that file you sent me but it was just
full of pictures of dead cats was that
the one another one you wanted me to
look at and my two o'clock is with Jane
at 3 o'clock I cut my fucking throat at
4 o'clock I get my asshole pumped with a
Swiffer pump