oh it's my friend Zack hellos shh-shh
I'm just making myself a cup of tea I
know what's going on here are you having
yourself a cheeky little Tea Party ayah
you bet your bottom I'm having a tea
party come on join in
I you don't want me to join in you're
just having a girl tea party on your own
robot Bernardo just ruin the whole thing
don't be such a fucking wet blanket the
Holden's are up your Tea Party get
yourself a mug da come on grab yourself
a teabag I'm good I'm good and get a
party hat from the party hat draw cuz
it's party time I got it I got it
possibly grab yourself a mug and get on
in here
all right you bloody convinced me yes
yes a mug all this talk of tea is
getting me thirsty shall I pop the
kettle on I'm so hot
yes all right let's do it right now a
watched pot never boils
a watched pot never boils I think the
thing they say is a watched pot never
boils water and what is the world's my
Royal Club a watch Paul never there are
tales of the Box the watched pot never
boils and it is sex talk among little
bagels watch upon the $90.00 boil
watched pot never boils
hi boys I think you're missing something
for your tea huh what do you mean you
made a big omelet slickster salt on a
pecky chili dickyvicky
Scotch finger oh and the best thing
about a scotch biscuit is it's for
sharing Oh time for naughty chalky
ripple he's a naughty boy
Oh No here comes the Anzac biggie for
those who fought in Gallup or is it
commemorate all our boys forensic biggie
oh how do you like your teammate I have
my tea with a little bit of it
how's that little bit okay sure
how's that take it back pip hmm
oh no I've lost half my Bicky in my tea
don't worry sack I'll get it for you
ah hello mark fetching a piece kit ba
sure AM who are you mr. Ned Kelly
Australia's most notorious bushranger
hold up banks and seek revenge for me ma
locked away in a prison cell and by me
word I'll have my vengeance oh yeah cool
yeah okay bye-bye
see ya yeah yeah thanks for getting the
other half of my biscuit mark its hole
again oh well this T's making me tired
for bed boys I might turn it in you just
got here
I don't want to hear another word out of
you two boys and I want nothing more
lipping Stouffer Matty have my team bid
the guys some loose tea leaves in my mug
do you know what my tea reading says it
says you're gonna get a big cuddle
cuddling is so much fun all right then
boys naughty naughty troops naughty nice
Shh boys good night I was pull the light
I've done
haha could all the teddy bears look at
all the teddy bears oh look at all the
teddy bears off to work off to work
can't have a teddy bear boys Oh more
bicky's for me