well I love being a big office
businessman I've whittled my chair I've
got my expensive collection of fine
china bowls and plates I finished
watching my movie Space Jam with Michael
Jordan what frightened a new IT
consultant is here the new IT consultant
who's that his name is mr. bowl oh yeah
cool man
hello I am a boon stompy stompy stompy
stompy stompy but first things first I
am a bull stompy stompy stop but I am
also a graduate of Cambridge University
with a master's in information
technology also in big nutball stompy
stompy stop oh yeah cool man
but first bring me some yummy
hey stompy stompy stompy stompy susan
could you bring us some yummy hay for
mr. bull please now mr. bull first
things first I'm a business man business
later first libations stompy stompy
stomp stomp yummy yummy in my ball tummy
good ah and what is your name Susan
Susan Oh son stompy stompy stompy t as
well as pretty Susan did you know that I
am a bull yes
Oh No suspend the mortal enemy of any
ball I get you a drink
a long black early crowd with love and
orange juice come hold my clothes steel
bosom span hidden for I am dying
Oh blood I suppose that blood ism I'm
and so I go to a land of twisties now
please remember me and tell my tale for
I was a bull a big bull who ate hey and
sometimes twisties
they were a little emoji Dorma well it's
the 90s so it's time for lunch
a VHS yum-yum-yum it's the 90s I hope
this isn't poison now time for some
classic 90s drink film from a VCR well