and then I said in the bum oh my god
good joke hey oh you're right uh
dividends yeah abs divid um I don't
hello all right I'm sorry who are you
he said rural way the poor words by the
greatest golfers pie in the hall I will
a corporate spy is someone who uses
covert and illegal means to steal trade
secrets such as a proprietary products
Minh specification or formula or
information about business plan
and what was that song uh in inelastic
markings
you gotta climb a climb away the top are
climbing all the way to top oh I went to
a Catholic High School and graduate like
left at sixteen I said you'll know Magus
of boy and you got a cell low and by a
high and that's how you do it and hello
and I'm Josiah Greenfield I'm a sales
research assistant hello I'm Zachary
fuck
I mean I'm - sy Greenfield I'm a sales
research in Sisson first rule of
corporate spying give a fake name to the
enemy so they can't search for you on
ask Jeeves why don't you turn over there
and start talking about Ask Jeeves and
fake no um I need the quarterly sales
report is what I need from you is that
what you could just as well be a
corporate spot I don't even I work here
just like you like just like a regular
Steven is what I I don't know let a snap
I know why I don't do that don't know
photos where we keep the quarterly sales
report dingus
well this isn't a this isn't a some
photo that I'm just taking the snapchats
snapchats with my friend snapper I'm
sorry it's 1999 I don't know what
snapchat is unless he's one of the
planeteers so what I need to find from
you guys right now is that quartile
sales report and a bit you wondering why
well I'll tell you why cuz I need it for
the CEO that's my job I make Excel
spreads for CEO Jimmy Oh Jimmy is your
core CEO Jimmy you better go is coming
right so hello happy and a genuine live
as well what a fancy maritime file just
fine holy shit I said up in here then
send me up oh here it is okay great Zack
proud of you not only did you gain the
trust of the workers you also got the
top secret file talking to you now to
slip out of here real quiet-like and
sell it for top dollar on the world
market come on oh sorry
before I forget what's your reference
number
what well anyone retrieving a document
for the CEO has a reference number that
correlates with the request so I was
just wondering what's your reference
number a reference I don't even
I mean hey snapshot something totally
fishy about you Josiah from sales you
know if I didn't know any better I'd say
you were some sort of corporate spot cup
cooler yeah through a song chorus my the
better couple dividend horn sound recall
a trade secret such a professor
preterius I'm sorry I don't be more
advantageous oh hey let's go get my
awful shaky
Oh 1999 I'm not sure what snapchat is
add a new sort of shoe yeah it's a shoe
where you put an iPhone in it so uh it's
1999 I'm not sure what snapchat is that
a new breed of potato yeah it's a potato
looks a bit like like an iPhone so my
point is all right
go I'm not sure what snapchat is is that
a new shrek sequel yeah it's a shrek
seagull about an iPhone so I'll get it
it's 1999 I'm not sure what snapchat is
yeah is that is that a new type of
prophylactic um yeah it's like a
prophylactic but with an iPhone in it um
Josh you've got away with it