my name is Sammy on a sandwich boy I'll
make you a Sanger that's filled with joy
I take two bits a bread and a lovely
filling put it all together and make a
killing ball of white bread
Gillibrand bread wow I love Strasburg I
love broke bread with stress butter on a
slice of cop ham and cheese get that in
you jobs
knowing them no no thank you Sam Nami
nom nom I love ham eat it up Pasha
put it away a gobble gobble gobble have
a great day
junior sandwich with a hint of child
thank you Sam well it's still alive and
you are French transparency's why that's
the sandwich that you ordered today cuz
they're goddamn it semi that's four
Strasberg with sauce on wholemeal just
get a three thick head mate sorry to be
fair though I have ordered this every
single fucking day I've worked here how
do you get a wrong chair brought it down
handing out 150 of these things kill him
kill him now oh no oh great if that
demon again the one that tells me to
murder my friend come on just do it
ain't nothing to it cut off his ear and
wear it as a shoe take his elbow and use
it as a bell ring a ding dong ding it
did you don't go mr. Damon Sammy the
gate your black magic can't get to me
not to mention the source makes the
bread go something what did you say
about my sauce oh my god
I've killed instead of putting yummy
things inside of bread hey Sammy my
question please don't push me not today
just let it go go away oh no it's just
that I think you've given me Sandra
sandwich from the second it's not a good
wall a curve and use it as a toothbrush
slice off a head and use it as a gas
mmmm you'll get me on the MPL oh yes
must catch me I'll be up here
Sammy you're talking to your sandwiches
again what are you that sheet is that
blood and there's no deadline sandwich
I'm assumed Oh killed everyone again
can i Sam is something wrong dad wanna
play Nintendo stop killing everyone
hi i'm sami care to join me in my office
no wait mr. Peterson I can explain ah
look Sammy all of your friends from the
office of gathered for a little party
we're going to count down to the new
year and we've decided that you're going
to cut the millennium cake here use this
knife it'll also be perfect for cutting
the cake Hey
well that's $19.99 done and dusted
not just the year but also the web
series
it looks like y2k wasn't so much of a
problem and this murderous person is
gonna kill everyone no people