ding-dong yes frightened hello little
girl there is a problem with my office
lanyard
oh yes my name is misspelled I deemed it
appropriate to resolve the issue before
a conflict arose of course sure so how
do you spell your name Brendon M I in BA
for biking on eggy's hey I yes
- pardon it's not a nickname it's your
official office line oh I know what it
is Susanna
it is you who doth not know what is for
Ironman beast hunter of elk lover of
women sovereign of the moon Oh cat got
your tongue will cook that cat and a
salty broth man we can't change your
name I'm sorry you're gonna have to
speak to the highroad huh
very well I will do so but not before I
make you higher up high like that
waiting miss friend now to find justice
for my office one yeah oh you're a hot
Nana one wrong one kissy kissy Kissy
justice oh hi Brian how can I help you
place my London at once key glyph now
Broden well that attitude it just won't
fly I'll make you fly unwashed popinjay
oh yeah yeah this is in my department
I'm just head of HR h yeah man that's
what you get
Brydon please surely this is something
we can discuss Oh Frank you like a
discus you piece of shit
prick smile on your fuck
Loden he'll easy now you're big dickhead
don't you see tossing peoples not the
way I'll toss you not the way no no we
can't catch me because I'm little and
Italian now I know it's hard trying to
make it in the big world of business
sometimes it feels like you just don't
matter it
all but you can't go around tossing
people like that I'm afraid you hear me
I'm afraid Marc banana we're Frei
debating and adequate I'm afraid of
being alone just afraid well you don't
have to be afraid anymore wait come into
this warm basket of goodies afraid I
will have to throw do got him madly
man-beast
hmm this is your new office lanyard
sorry about the mix-up thank you thank
you all I shall now cease my tossing hi
ah that's better justice with my new
lanyard
Leonard for me man-beast yummy man-beast
now I can recommence my work under my
correct title of good ol man bossed typo
Oh
but for biking and eggy's e for the egg
is in bacon and egg ease I for a good
time eating bacon and egg ease with
friends s4 so on some bacon and egg ease
and t4 tummy where I put my bacon and
egg ease