their DNA evidence guys brace yourself
touchy Tim from upper management we
joining us today not touchy Tim he's a
piece of shit and he's all touchy-feely
on me
hi guys it's me touchy Tim hi di Brodin
good to save him hello lovely to see
Marc
always a pleasure and I can touch it in
oh not again oh yes excuse me buddy
could you please pass the Bulldog hello
no I can't talk now I'm just about to
try these new blue M&amp;Ms it's impossible
tried everything
never mind I'll do it myself
he's got low armies and M&amp;Ms are you
it's interesting how I enjoy business
it's interesting but oh jeez Louise I
want help touch me I'll Amy - oh my god
and bloody Polamalu touch your other
hand him touch stop it oh yeah oh geez
Louise got it again did somebody say
long arms hmm I thinks I might have an
idea
allow me
ah ah
okay uh oh okay all right all right not
fun
sorry I know this fucking fucking sorry
mmm-hmm I'm fingering someone how far
the night Hey lotta chops chicken sorry
baby
fuckin drink bunch of mmm yummy
cigarette ha ha ha
Tachi Tim you don't touchy-feely at all
you just have really long arms that's
right and up how do you do ha ha ha I
think it's fair to say that you've
touched all our hearts is there anything
you haven't touched oh oh let me see
yeah I've touched roofs and umbrellas
and kids of time - oh listen it's really
it's all about context you really got to
hear the whole song looks like a touchy
Tim has finally had his first taste of
the long arm of the law you know what
I'd like a taste of those blue M&amp;Ms
Oh touchy tim-mah luncheon you don't you
do touch cheater cheater cheater cheater
I've touched roofs and umbrellas and
kids I've touched lots of things that
you can see I've touched adults and
friends and everyone all of course
accidentally I've got big long arms big
long absorb Russian and Russian and it
mad that big long arms it can be quite
hard let me get rid of these proper
things cuz I cuz I I'm touchy TVs I'm
outside she Tim hidden