oh he won't walk you okay hello Rachel
how do you do I'm good bro Tim well
that's real good and just walking down
the hall I wish I was dead uh-hmm
what a delicious mega Cheney and great
with a focaccia Messiah tires me you are
joking of you hey boy hey ah
joking Oh Susan was this will that see
that one so this one oh my god what are
you two boys goping and giggling about
did another pigeon get into the
boardroom now I might have a look is
anything tying us together and yes that
pun was intended well it'll only have a
look oh gee I'm not sure certain oh
you've been there okay this is what the
difference all right I'll bit a bit of
spot of similarities are we fighting all
right gee I'm sure Oh Gino
wait a minute are you two boys wearin
the same everyone something mildly
interesting is happening for workplace
today two people one the same fuckin
tighter work and I'm gonna take a
fucking photo on this camera I'm gonna
get into village and a fucking cave
not since that pigeon flew through the
window in 95 has such a wonderful thing
occurred in this year office yes come on
you there the boy what's the meaning of
this hullabaloo sad George lip nice and
employment mother of say whatever broom
hey pigeons just got into the boardroom
Oh
you
and so it came to pass that the pigeon
was let out of the window and order was
restored to the office plus I think
there's a little Zach along the way join
us next time as we think from same
haircut no not same here I'm got long
hair and he's is a lot shorter biggest
to same same cock no not same or similar
but different I've got a little cock
okay I'm saying but no no so have a look
mate have a look
I got booty same breasts no I have a
look Lance have a look wait wait
way to see him you two are wearing the
same tire yep