yes very good oh very good we're good
very good to both of you right Jill yeah
get out of here
Wow Wow oh great meetings so fantastic
great job
hey bro great job they're so good man
you nailed it
mmm when's that next meeting oh shit my
dad it's five minutes mmm can I tell you
something brighter job right you know
you can speak to me about anything you
know I'm your best friend we can talk
about anything I'm feeling a little bit
tired you tired well let me ask you a
question are you hip to it yeah are you
a cool dude yeah do you have an
addictive personality you know I do well
then maybe you should have a little
drink of this ah she get off your hands
hundreds of dollars right here oh right
let me have a go
write it yeah kind of a hunch baby ah
that's better
hey guys what's going on we ride the
drugs just act like nothing has happened
oh how do you do gentlemen sir
sir good to see you good to say good to
see you mark banana wait a minute
something seems to be a little bit fishy
going on here right oh we've been doing
a lot of cocaine what we're look you can
tell you better get outta here you
nervous little Nelly cuz we're the cool
kids come on I'm cool now you ain't cool
you got to do the drags the drags I
don't give a dang what you boys gonna
put out there I ain't taking it because
me I don't give in the peer pressure
that's way too big kids it's it it's it
it's oh go for that one Oh baby
all right let's do this okay
Zach boys just saving some for later
oh yeah put it Marshall Zach take the
funnel try no one any cocaine around the
rim I just thought you might want some
suck a toes come on here we go
I don't know about you boys but caffeine
is the only high I need that in cocaine
yeah yeah I just thought you might want
some sucker towels
hey Zach did you want another hit I'd
love another hit my brother could I have
another hit my dear
party yeah actually got a little bit of
a blood knows mine oh shit well I just
just on your nostril there we're here I
know just sort of know a little bit yeah
that night is still a little bit more
there and you've got a little bit on you
are they go got it oh yeah great hold it
ah that's our dolla dolla bills y'all
I lost my T all these drugs have ruined
my septum in my nose but don't worry I
have a spare nose for friends Germany
only three two one
now have you both in my icing sugar
oh it's icy oh you boys I just like
sandwiches like I was made but I knew I
could say tober at your boy so I made up
my special egg sandwiches the trick is
you use the vegan mayonnaise cuz you
don't want none of that
eagle egg shit you like egg sandwiches
Brighton yeah I know you do
glow and boy like yourself you need some
good egg sandwiches they get tally how
old are you now brothers 26 cheese and
sucka but your mother huh yeah you know
for my boy hi Brian
I'm not your mother