you
all right welcome guys
I hope you guys liked that quick little
animation so what we're doing today is
we're playing tabletop role play you
guys mostly you're probably already
familiar we've already done character
creation we're pretty much ready to go
here Roman today is you are the leader
of the group okay you're going to be the
leader of the band of thieves what was
your character's name again character's
name you me right so all our characters
have character names but this is mostly
just for documentation just so it's not
complicated on the stream we're going to
be just calling everybody by roman dead
bones Justin Cohen Rob that's just the
names we're going to be using I'm going
to be playing the part of all the bad
guys and NPC's in the show and these
guys are gonna be playing our
adventurers dead bones what was your
character named Skoll squink the gnome
squink no and you enroll me your second
command to Roman and you are also the
little Kean McKean and I was throwing
that Jam back and forth back and forth
Roman what sets Keynes apart from normal
gnomes what makes them you know that
your go-to gnome
so here's the thing about the King Kings
are about sharing which the sounds weird
in the band of thieves because you'd
figure you know we don't care about
helping each other but because we're
greedy we get to use other people's
stuff why would we not want to do that
so me and dead bones are gonna be
flinging stuff back and forth know that
that gem is gonna be passing back and
forth well now people have pointed out
that you could you know let someone like
Justin hold on to the gym and you guys
could still use it ya know
okay I don't think he deserves any me
yeah look at it
seedez doesn't deserve it there's
there's a couple people who will watch
and they will they will say like like
why don't they do this in this sea there
is an element of role play around and
you have to do things that are in
character and I won't let you do things
that are out of your character and you
guys haven't really established much but
for example if Roman establishes itself
as this greedy go-getter
you know later down the Rhine it's not
going to make sense if he's just like
here Justin have
of my items you know it's yeah I'd have
to pick a character and stick with it
so Co you're also known but you're not
you're not a keen or rate we're raised
for you I'm a no kinoma you're an oaken
omikuji use the treasures like the other
two guys but you can trade out your
things now you really wanted to do it do
you still want to trade up with
blunderbusses right now or do you want
to hold on to them for a while I'm gonna
see I'm gonna sit on them for a little
bit yeah
we'll see how so you know I need them
okay mm-hmm and Justin finally we got
you by the way everything everything
we're doing today guys as you're
watching there may be technical
difficulties there's so many things
going on I can break you you for just I
can't actually watch chat if there's if
there's like five muted for seven hours
make sure one of you is checking I'm on
it oh yeah yes trust me is rock okay uh
and then finally we have the last a
party who is not a gnome he is a simple
dwarf just yes a hill dwarf your Hill
dwarf yeah and in your serving as like
the pseudo warrior tank for these the
band of Thrones band of thieves
mm-hmm I'm super eager I'm I'm the first
dwarf ever named dwarf number three I
mean as far as you know well read into
those oh if ever
well uh so the submissive in has has
given you the guys you guys can see you
have you can see everything because you
have a map you know that you need to
basically go up and write to an extent
so you have two current paths to get
towards the town you can go through the
mountain through the canyon to the north
or you can go never eat east and go go
buy some cottage and some dockyards to
also get there it's your it's your
choice which way you guys want to go and
I meet you mean it's it's Romans it's
Romeo say like 100 percent Roman well
actually you know what this woman has
keys come he's gonna come drop you off
so uh which which was where you guys at
Roman oh hey oh hey hey hey there Roman
so this is a camp this is where uh you
know you you I would I would recommend
you probably go north but you know you
can go east to you know they're both
they're both good directions just if you
see any elves just you know try to stay
hidden you might want to avoid any
battles of the elves they're pretty
strong they're spell blades do you wanna
do even know what a spell blade is Roman
uh it's a blade that's made completely
out of spells no no I mean that the the
the the elves call the spell boys you
know what they are you know what we look
special about them why not fight them
know what's oh oh the ones we throw
water on a beach no no no really
yeah yeah no no they can attack and use
spells in the same turn so they're very
very dangerous cuz they they can do that
you know how you get to use free ray of
Frost's yeah they could use a free ray
of frost and an attack and another spell
so you know they're pretty scary
I wouldn't recommend fighting them but
you know so you're saying they're like a
bunch of meat yeah yeah they're else
yeah so which so so I mean are you
confident in your other band of thieves
like are you confident with these other
guys that are gonna be able to keep up
with you in combat because if so that
I'm sure you'll be fine but you know I
know some of your recruits are new oh
hey there mr. Koester Robin we got the
water excellent but I I don't I don't
believe in the water plan wait wait wait
why are the two are you here whose water
washed number three I mean he's kind of
easy he's doing his own thing you know
did you tie them to a tree at least why
these guys all cover me in water
ah look it's uh it's a it's a hazing
ritual all right okay you mean all right
so we're gonna say no to the spell elves
or whatever they are well just for just
be careful now I'm just to remind you
guys if you get if you get close you're
looking for this key it's orange Scott
may be a little emblem of a Sun it's
part of the Sun key you really
can't miss it it might actually be
physically on the keeper of the elves
you might want to go in there at night
when they're sleeping or something
that's your guy's choice
but that's when we can pour water the
best way to Sonic into the city is
through the cave if you even can make it
to the city I'm I don't really have a
lot of faith in you guys are there any
wonders in this cave oh yes there's the
great monkey fish he's great we played
to him he's but he's a generally good
guy he's pretty wonderful can't can you
eat monkey fish I just wondering um I
mean you could try but I've never done
it all right sounds pretty good I do
know what happens if you put water on
them because they don't want you do who
happens flat tell us nothing they just
live in the water they're in City
oh well that's disappointing good well
anyway I need to get going cuz you know
I don't actually do things I just pay
people to do yeah you're pretty useless
I got it yeah yeah you guys have a good
adventure okay and um go to a barbecue I
think yeah yeah try not to run into
these spell elves what else
something spell I don't know spelling
bee bow me it's a boy they've blades
made completely out of span I don't even
know I think it's a I think it's a spell
spell rate if they're made of a spell
spells are written on paper so they
attack us with paper so they made a
neighbor do Patel's I like horrible
elves are any hey hey elves can Elmo
automatically can a like multi class so
they can have a why they can have two
different sources of spells like they
can have some spells from lumberjack
class and some spells from a sorcerer
some guys just see you guys voice coming
from right action don't know it's creepy
right yeah oh yeah this we can always
talk to you through your minds that's
character trainee has I was just gonna
say that a female elves can be pretty
hot as well as gonna say yeah
alright so okay Bernadine say to knock
oh uh he said so well he did not go to
the cave he says samba throw
water on something yeah he's like okay
there's gonna be spells and caves and
treasure so wait treasure
wait okay not in the cave no we're going
to the docks so we don't want to go to
the cave we're going to the docks look
man I I think we should go to the cave
I like the cave idea see I I think by
him saying we should not go to the cave
we should probably go okay what you
think you're trying to pull one on us I
think he's trying to pull he doesn't
want us to know the shortcut it was a
really ship do you looking no man I mean
yeah
I know I know my shifty-looking gnomes I
mean come on right come on hmm no come
on
it's Romans Kyle I think Greg I think
all right okay okay I don't trust this
guy
I think he's gonna screw us over so if
he's telling us to not go to the caves
we got to go to the caves
exactly all right let's go to the caves
that's all guys let's do this
party all right we're let's get those
caves okay so you guys want to go north
into this cave here yes ye all right
Rowan so which way was it left or right
I never actually got the old left
all right after going left kay did not
actually matter what why wouldn't it
mattered yeah they're both the same way
all the books Anna okay so you guys
wanna start moving up here move up yeah
right so I didn't enter the beginning of
the cave okay
uh you know I still don't help hold on
do I see the cave uh not yet because
Rob's getting his notes cuz he had to
Wow I so Jack dude to do this show man I
have three desktop windows just max like
I can't even look at stream and stuff
like that okay
what a pity hold on I have three
monitors uh you have three mothers -
right okay you can look at you can look
into the cave and you see you see three
coal bowls okay - wearing different
armor and hats and things and they all
seem to be your there's tons of
gemstones in the cave and they're all
just sitting down like having a nice
conversation they seem to just be like
chat
it up like they're telling stories with
each other in the talking just having a
nice conversation eating some lunch
which apparently is the Diamonds of this
mine
they're eating diamonds see I was about
to ask day we eat it they are sewing
diamonds
Wow Wow Wow terrifying bite strength is
it was jaws I mean come on good there I
have been other diamonds
alright we're not in combat or anything
so you know I'm not in combat nope they
have not even they haven't even noticed
you guys yet so okay but I see a good
talk you know if you wanted yeah hey hey
hey are you the leader of this band Ames
I'm just sayin just sayin man boss I'm
just sayin all right I'm gonna move
forward and approach them I'm gonna have
my hands empty your hands boss what do
we do
my hands are empty I think they're
suppose what does it say bout you with
the water this thing Beck who the woman
I want you to cover me but plate be cool
okay so you're gonna walk up to Goebbels
hey Cobalts come on uh no hello goat
gobble gobble gobble gum oh no no no no
let me speak cobalt go go uh this this
car oh he's going he's come please come
right up to you he's giving you a hug
I'm gonna return the hug go on my god
like a Lena Lena part hug not like oh so
you're not actually gonna like getting
close and we're not like you know you
know yeah touch yeah when he hugged
Allen good when he of you he went for
the full squeeze like the bear he went
for the full squeeze like like full body
you know what I mean
yeah and plus you know you're a supple
little gnome so you know he's got up all
in your business like he's he's he's a
he's a he's a wily little gnome you know
he's handsy
he's a you know to the type of people
that touch just too much like very
grabbing
yeah okay okay I don't realize it was
that kind of hug yeah chopper sitting in
the must face and me make him a little a
little quick slap on the butt
just to let him know hey you know what
you don't scare me off okay that's good
bro man this is looking bad do you need
water this is all wonderful leave all
the water crack you I I can actually
speak other languages I just really
appreciated the fact that you know you
just said you spoke like us nobody does
that
every time I have a conversation with
anyone they just start talking in their
Elvis languages or the Dwarven late that
dwarf language but but man you just came
up and you just knew what to do that's
an impressive I did I didn't expect that
hey guys this guy's pretty okay you know
I wasn't gonna let him pass but I'm
almost considering it no that's good
Nick well no no the other guys the other
guys they don't want to let you play you
can't pass though this is a large white
why not we just want to go through uh
yeah it's not happening this is our cave
we were here first
and you know I don't want you stealing
any of my gems than my gems I fought for
them I lost the knife trying to get
these gems so I want to tie it's a nice
looking eyepatch though I think you
really pull it off not everyone can wear
an eyepatch like that thanks I guess I
just told you I lost my eye and then I'm
said hey you got a really nice no I no
no not no I nice eye patch you gotta
think of it like an accessory now hey
what are you just i just saying uh offer
him and i we can give the dwarf side we
come across i mean he doesn't need it
yeah think about it think about it come
on think about oh ooh check the dwarfs
pockets he's weird maybe he has an eye
in there is this alright really
oh this is does yeah this sounds like
yes rule yes just am i the one real
quick yeah just your a role to see what
in your pocket okay all right what's
what's in my pockets
oh it's in the fog it's a 67 to 16 so
justin has nothing in his pockets Roman
and dead poem's earlier in the day
removed everything from his fly so oh
yeah yeah yes that makes sense I guess I
wanna put the I in there but it would
have been like dead bullets put it in
there - Stuart for God anyway oh I got
an idea cobalt hold on I know you your
little sensitive about the eye let me
introduce you to someone who has no eyes
oh okay that bones now you know that I
both came up here the puppet is just a
representation you don't have I I think
I was he talking he's got two eyes I've
got I got two eyes you got yeah he's got
two eyes two good eyes I got got a eyes
nose beard mouth everything yeah but you
always told me you had no eyes I don't
worry Sam
I mean that was no no no no I just know
he's he's a keep your key gnome right
I've know your type Joe yeah you're
blind aren't you you like use
echolocation to navigate around the
world yeah that's that's just an urban
legend I have no ice okay yeah he's he's
got no eyes who doesn't have eyes who's
Rick that guy yeah hey I know you have
eyes behind those goggles no I mean I
just I really don't have eyes the guy I
know the truth I don't don't believe you
take those goggles off and prove you
have no eyes I can't take them off me
guess I have no eyes Oh take them off
for you and get back here take these no
don't touch me okay the cobalt is going
to try where's Kelly you're like right
here the baboon is here Justin's just in
the back area okay uh the kobolds I
wonder girl my cobble is going to try
and reach up and grab for your glasses
code are you gonna resist this so you're
just gonna be okay with it I'm gonna
resist man okay don't punch him I'm not
gonna gonna dodge okay so yeah you're
just you're just darted back and forth
he's like come on if you have no eyes
and let me see him he wasn't able to
nope - grab him
nope all right you know you guys seem
like you're good fellows but again like
I said you can't come through their cave
this is our cave nobody comes through
this cave it's just for us so I'm gonna
need you to just you know back on up go
on just back on the way wait wait wait
wait we we can offer you things shiny
things
hmm very funny what do you got to offer
yeah it all is a tent actually you know
what I'll handle the deals let me let me
go get the boss a box yeah what do we
got off I don't have no idea I'm just
I was just bit bawling I like at 47 bows
Robin Hood's just give on what good get
out of here what get out don't keep an
eye on the water man exactly fine good
swear to God
tie him to a tree when you leave him
alone yeah come on right wait are you
talking to me yeah we're talking to you
oh I'm sorry
you're the last one the song okay I'll
do it next time all right all right
there you guys want to come into my cave
you okay this is cobalt come on Kobol
come on go up yes yeah you go you go
help you guys know that that doesn't
actually mean anything we just we just
like to say it come on come on
yeah yeah I can i I came up to you
speaking yo this language that we all
speak the common tongue is you don't
evolve all hope a couple okay couple all
right we're not cut we want passage
through this cave but we don't want your
gems and I think we can come to scale
yeah I bet you want the big giant gem
that's worth thousands of thousands of
gold I know your type a little bit even
gnomes but I am that guy wish that he's
whispering about the gem his eyes lit up
he was not he that have no I want to
talk about
I said not you don't know what I'm
talking about look we absolutely do not
want this gem and there's certainly you
know this gem that might be located
where so we can make sure that we avoid
it you know I know you guys you think I
don't see that dwarf I hey hey you dwarf
get up here you think I don't know I
hate dogs man they kiss kill coal those
are the
time and look at ya just try to smuggle
one through my cave oh oh he's a he's a
new hire that's all it's like a it's
like a meat shield no girl imma talk
this to a bus you get over there right
thing move are you a miner dwarf do you
like to mine
I hate mining the worst right now you
look like the kind of dwarf that likes
to mind gems
my gems steal all my gems aren't you I
don't even know what a gem is it's
actually actually true he's not bad at
all
nothing right not very bright ya know
his weed he fought back with virus is he
liked you and thought they were rocks is
he even really a dwarf then like uh yeah
I mean it's questionable it might just
be a word he heard once and just you
know I I hate Wars but you guys seem to
be nice but mm okay I mean I guess if
he's not really a dwarf he's cuz I mean
why would a drop here now with gnomes
whats your name nan dwarf uh Wharf
number three okay comet is started the
goal is going to punch just to get again
right in the face we're gonna move
Justin's the composition it's gonna say
this okay so because this is the first
time we've ever done this uh you guys
will be able to donate to trigger events
trigger events also cause movies and
stuff so you guys can go go nuts and
could make us let me pull the notes
alright so this is mr. blue kobold he is
going to immediately so the kobolds are
taking are going to be going first for
their attacks so he's going to be trying
to hit Justin now kobolds are special if
they these are trenton guard Cobalts let
me show you
is for chat did you do these are trained
guard kobolds which means if they really
critical they get to a free turn again
so anytime they roll 20 you get hit
again okay man
somehow Justin you he doesn't hit you
you reacted that's amazing
yellow Coble is also going to come up
he's also going to take a swing at
Justin sixteenths Justin you're gonna
take the girl now you damage there don't
I have a spell blade or something late
for ya later elves for anti spells but
this is just him hitting you with a clay
wait now isn't blades from the first
melee attack of the turn yeah oh yes I'm
sorry yeah wait legend is the first man
for things like that is we're gonna go
with the rule of you've got to remind me
every time and if you if you ever miss
it that's just tough luck you know it's
one of those type of games all right
shit outta luck buddy last kobold they
really hate wharves they're gonna come
and beat the dwarves up Oh take a swing
oh oh and miss alright so we're gonna go
in the order just cuz it's here in the
tabletop we're gonna go Roman code dead
bones Justin for the game alright so
Roman it is your turn you were back at
the back of the pack you can definitely
shimmy through your allies because
you're just small little quines
alright rolling I have a suggestion
punch the dwarf and make them think
we're on this side just a suggestion
make some bleep were allies suggestions
okay I gotta see gonna stop you guys I
gotta stop you guys because it's time
Wow okay I messed up the hell I'm gonna
do that hold on oh I'm gonna do that
again okay
I don't think I can get hype again
though chat is fun
Teddy I know chata spawn 10 gem links
throughout the cave these things are
randomly going to attack know what yeah
why do that check four five six
it's horrible are you kidding me what
the hell then okay don't know it may be
the doubles now gem wings they only do
one damage they will attack Coble's
cause colds eat them um they only have
one health and they only do one damage
but again there is ten of them okay
trying to all us right out of the gate
Ally um so you guys Lauria shut the
dwarf out in front so it was your tongue
who are you doing okay I am seeing all
this crap spawn in front of me I am
going to quickly peruse my you alright
uh yet my Cod's Oh God I'm gonna move
back I'll say crap what's the range on
and large it's five I know what five do
five it's five are you coming to do all
right I'm gonna move back for and then
I'm a captain large on Justin mmm-hmm
right here like right here uh more to
the left so I obviously would have a
line of sight or line of sight
okay do i well okay sorry does this so
just for reference for chat because chat
because it's the start of the stream and
they're really excited have already made
all our donation goals for this I'm only
ever going to do one per round of combat
so the next one I'm going to activate
will be on the monsters turn or else
because knowing you guys you might
sometimes spawn all three movies but you
guys are already awesome all right so
you're casting enlarge so
tu-tu-tu-tu-tu-tu so dramatically size
before times that's a few minutes and
you're doing Justin I'm doing just this
is going to be really weird go ahead and
roll this is gonna do weird things it's
gonna be really weird I'm dead bones I'm
worried for us okay
so you're gonna get a good old two times
and large here nice and big
I need I'm going to do one role for the
coal Baldy one rule for each kobold
because he's this is pushing people in
the way so he's getting hit well he's
getting oak he's getting all the way the
roles all roles not he's getting hit so
good doing it after all we just wait
wait uh you you might you can roll now
yeah yeah all right I'm gonna I'm gonna
roll this dice yeah oh wow that's
terrible
it's okay again I can deal with it okay
so dead bones you're gonna hit for one
damage know how much you didn't largest
three yeah one two three four Romans cos
oh I'm sorry Roman but you have the the
one armor I - yes so dead bones you're
going flying over here you land on your
butt uh was that a melee attacks Deb
concept later oh it's not it's not it's
not necessarily that it's a melee attack
it's that it's cuz cuz it's pelipper
it's kind of like a spit cuz he's got
he's he's gonna be enlarging here right
well what exactly hit me over there was
it his ass I'm gonna be suing - yes yeah
you gotta you definitely hit by his ass
from just in behind these cobbles this
could've been like it's like this cool
incoming wish and this one jumped out
okay oh did they bouncing entities
kremlings
uh yes they did but but none of them
chuckles alright so it is a coaster no
well yeah coast twisting yeah and after
Roman okay um
Roman what do i do what should I do
I brought you along for your expertise
in this if you're gonna ask me every
time there's a simple decision on what
to do I may have to reevaluate your
status and Steve's guilt I just need to
know you're playin man
alright I'm just gonna I'm gonna move
out of the way we're gonna move exactly
five isn't it fine
my plan is to let a bit little cobalt
agro yeah over there that's why there's
no what I answer the question what is
your name alright I'm going to do I'm
going to move back to here and
let's see like desktop is so complicated
something oh okay I want to uh are you
doing it see range five okay so I'm
gonna cast rolling fog right okay thank
you yes one two three four five so like
right in front of Justin I guess I can
cast the fog right that's five I don't
have anything to indicate fog so I'm
going to use what can we use I'll just
use this guy so the rolling fog will be
these purple squares okay that's where
it's going to start
I can't meditate guys that was thanks so
what is rolling frog do it created dense
fog returns under the flag expands to
nearby spaces each turn until it's
expanded twelve spaces that's each turn
so every turn it's it's just gonna be by
the way yeah yeah it's gonna get bigger
bigger
it can't encompass a certain space and
anyone trying to move through it or
attack through it it's going to be slow
except for Co Co I will what are you
trying to where do you want this fog to
kind of roll out though
what director how do you want it to go
because you can kind of I wanted to go
but I'm but you're gonna try and tell me
where what you wanted to do I want to
cast it directly in front of Justin and
I want it to roll into the cave okay
there we go
well tis amusing night alright um roll
uh yeah huge roll just a case I failed
and I don't even need to do any of this
okay
good excellent I use the fog all right
okay so fog the fog moves dead bones
it's your turn all right
is this gem leaned close enough for me
to attack yeah you can always attack
diagonally like that alright I'm gonna
hit it with my walk blade should I roll
for that bugger off set oh alright the
Gimli is dead good job did don't do that
whew I'm going to use the blank to
teleport back five spaces okay - all
right what is it they're the only one in
there who the kid well still on dead
bones turn since I'm a hill dwarf I'm
enraged that he killed that right I'm a
better free AK yeah
so you got a few do I got that time yep
just so give me a roll and you can do
five damage so the only thing in range
of you is going to be that cold drink oh
bolt yeah I'm I'm addled aren't you in
the face
and you miss okay punch him in the face
uh doesn't that emerge dozen large
actually say it increases your damage no
it just makes a big abet nosy creases is
our strength
so I would just get I would do no no
it's not at times to I just give them a
small buff on top of it okay
times 1.5 depending 20 it was 20 it
might be times 2 right it would be
depending on goal so so now all right so
now it is your turn just in the fog
rolls all right I'm gonna attempt to
toss green cobalt in the yellow okay
come on big money big money here okay so
you're gonna miss your only gonna throw
up green kobold and you're gonna land on
this gym right here and you gotta kill
it nice all right
am I still in range to attack green
cobalt no you're not anymore
you know even though you're big you're
not so big that you're like you can't do
like more than one space attack so
alright see I'm gonna yell over my party
members what the hell you guys want me
to do everything
punch punch everything fuck everything
before we have walkie-talkies
alright so it is now the monster
horrible it's now the monsters turn
which means I can surround a bit
spawning event
so my ears sweet unless they're half I
told four names to do the thing
yeah I know I got turned that shit out
no they're as very a devil they are
Coble's that are that can that use
whirlwind every turn and they've just
come down from the mountain to back up
their buddies here oh my so they're all
might be nice what do they exactly do
yeah they it's a you know you're now
fighting five Cobalts and these kobolds
specialize in whirlwind all right set
out as uh let's go through the turns of
green kobold here he's going to again
walk up towards Justin and hug him and
he's going to try and attack so glad we
product Wars I know right I'm not like
the best up there if he was annulled
that's when it happened hey no well
she's handling this we all go to the
bridge take three Justin Oh Blake turn
your play-doh blades our blade turn
stops huh yeah it's opted we roll again
rolling for what's going on yellow is
going to try to heal so yellow is going
to heal dude his green cobalt friend
with Holy Light so whatever the dice
roll is how much he gets healed oh good
see thanks Oh fifteen so he's back up
the full health basically good good
that's great that's good
need to redefine good here oh it's good
relative okay um holy light costume
three though I'm legit this time I not
just make it up numbers you know
something what you made up numbers
lesser sounds I had to make up numbers
because there's too much but I'll okay I
almost blew cool we'll do blue Coble is
casting blessing of strength on green
cobalt so cussing and I grant will
double attack I use it wait what'd you
say guess what the phrase is
it's gonna be coupled hey the phrase is
actually cold yes yeah to attack yeah
she'd done that different order but I
know it's great really yeah great cobalt
Thanks
all right these gem wings are going to
try to attack yellow Kobol dear these
gems are going to come in and try to
attack our whirlwind be buddies here I'm
going to do just one role to see gem
Ling's just that they're doing well this
turn or if they're derp sister they're
doing well this turn so we're going to
do one damage here three damage here
three damage here to these guys one two
three and then one two three one and
finally these two Coble's are going to
start casting whirlwind so red cobalt is
go ending and it's good purple cobalt
world ending they like killing all the
gem links yep that's exactly what's
gonna happen
alright and all these gem Ling's die
oh no now remember this is the warrior
whirlwind ability that Justin could have
had so after every turn now of your
guys's term um they're going to be
moving and whirlwind ting okay wait a
minute are they subject to the confuse
yes
sure absolutely after they're done
whirlwind thing they're gonna try to see
if they can do it again and again and
again and again these are this is the
first encounter right these guys just
the foot just go yes that's smart oh I
need to move your fog one more time
alright Roy yeah I'll get up okay I'm
going to move forward let's see how far
back I I don't want to be a nerd but
shouldn't the fog be um like spreading
in a wave like getting bigger and bigger
or just doing it one at a time I'm just
I'm just oh oh you mean doubling it's
true I think that you know what I'll do
that from now on that's that's way
better in the way I was doing it no I
like that I'll do that next time this
time I'm just gonna keep doing it cuz I
started it but yeah it's cool
alright Israel frost like a target
ability or is it like slide ability
targeted I mean its line of sight but
although Justin's big you're going to be
look at that kobold keep in mind though
you're gonna have to keep him
through the fog so you have a high
chance to miss oh okay
I'm actually I'm moving up so I can go
for the green guy he's bust through
Justin through Justin I mean you need
like a sight I mean this so there's a
high chance to hits Justin cuz it's
through just casualties afore I feel
like it's a chance I gotta take
you got it cuz here's the thing worst
case I can still book it out of here
alright Wow a crappy recruit maybe I
mean yeah we're doing horse display a
divorce
yeah can I like creep can I make like a
good guy so we like to go I'm huge
you're just shooter under my legs
alright Justin is about to lose the
ability to father children you better
lose his golden inherit just this is a
good point
if you lose your manhood you do not get
to roll your treasurer because it is an
inheritance
so in Froman hits you in the dick with
this red cross you have children anymore
buddy now that's only three shifts
that's only if he shoots his dad in the
dick before he's born you said no time
travels come on well Justin do you have
any kids
oh yeah any kids yet towards number four
nine he doesn't have any kids yet so why
is it no yeah but I do yeah your stud
you already said no it's you're
committed to this you can tell father
your child
oh if you shot in the dick for this rare
frost nothing wrong playing
no all right Roman he going for it
oh I'm gonna yeah I'm shooting through
the legs come on say my joke before or
after you can say it before okay
I'm trembling in anticipation well I'm
I'm trying to like break my nose here
all right two two
the cobalt I'm putting you on ice all
right
we're all putting you on ice in putting
you on ice all right you don't hit
Justin just barely Oh fine you're not
gonna hit the green kobold he hit the
shambling behind him he's dead all right
and now that he died I'm gonna take a
quick attack Oh hold on whoa all right
all right
wait wait wait is he bleeding yeah cuz
he's is reactive anytime it's miraculous
anything he gets to get a free attack so
he's gonna so I'm just doing a quick
roll on green yeah and you miss all
right
well all right where do I get my freak
back um why do you get a free attack oh
yes
so you can you into a free action as
long as it's not a class ability so you
can do like an attack or use a treasure
item if you had something like that you
have a bow go wrap up I have a bow yeah
all right uh all right so you don't want
to chance it twice I'm gonna try and
shoot blue cobalt with my bow okay not
gonna try to shoot that arrow to me
Justin's legs look frozen nuts feel a
lot you know better than you know no
nuts arrow through nuts arrow through
nuts
Oh Nuri all right well you you
completely miss and somehow you hit
Justin but it's one damage the fog
really confused him okay the fog really
confused Roman and he just let that
arrow fly and it just didn't write in it
let's say the nuts no no a grace a grace
his leg okay he was aiming this way but
somehow the arrow went this way okay
graced your big old leg you got right
now all right
oh wow um did you hear a Ross you shot
your arrow okay so the fog all right Co
you're up all right I'm gonna move one
two three four five he's just running
manic oh no no I planned that the second
weekend so far
hey are you gonna fill us in on your
plan he's just gonna run yeah hey you
know he's talking about your plan to
trees you only be sneaky about it unless
you're trying to none touchchat
let's just make oh no no no I'm trying
to go going around the hedge here it'll
go around I'm gonna flank these these
Cobalts okay I guess that's my turn then
uh really uh I can't well if you're if
you're going to use your whole turn for
movement I've always let people you go
farther so you can all come further go
another like five spaces or so hey great
hey oh yeah you didn't sprint turn oh
sweet alright so do I get to use an
action or is that just but that's that's
you because I I'll let you do it for
your action okay cool thank you alright
a fog rolled out dead bones it's your
turn
alright so I am within ten spaces of
Roman so I'm gonna be all like hey pass
me the jib I'm gonna get I'm gonna get
to get the Ruby yeah yeah I'm gonna move
I'm gonna move ten spaces whoa whoa whoa
us assuming I'm giving this to you I
mean it's fast Mike you can't stop it
you can't you can't stop it
so I'm gonna I guess you know here's
Jimmy the thing so going through the
maybe on the same place as the fog like
I want to begin you can't but you have
to roll to go through the fog okay okay
I'll roll to go through the fuckin like
a barrel roll cut over like a barrel
roll yeah oh all right you you try to go
through the fog but you think you're
facing the right way you're facing that
oh okay so I can't actually see anything
in the fog as my turn you're not gonna
do any actions I mean I can I take a
wild swing with my ward blade yeah you
can you can wild swing in the fog with
your work plate but you have no idea
where you are you going to pause oh no
and I got oh man oh my god honey
way to go eight did it hit that is not
no that is not a hit so you just is you
take your here's likewise
hmm does do I have to hit to use the
blink yeah isn't it safe why do damage
yeah ah we're good
uh uh anytime you do leave any time you
feel damaged I'm sure sure would you
like to teleport somewhere were you
trying to avoid tempo it back five
spaces you
we're trapped oh you're just reeling in
that okay roll cuz you're reeling the
fog time to see if you know the right
way to roll buddy
oh what a shy that ball ashamed Devils
you seem to have teleported in the wrong
way
oh hey guys this is an unfortunate
accident good thing good thing you went
into the fog it use your turn fair
changes worked in boats by the waves the
fog expands all right Justin it's your
turn
Oh God alright um that's guys I think
dead bones is dead uh oh I have no one's
doing oh man you know what I've been
missing whirlwind turns on these kobolds
I'm gonna take them all right now so no
yeah so on Romans turn well they could
just whirl with it in place they didn't
move that coast turn the world into
place because they would have hit their
allies but I'm dead bones turn Devlin
you get whirlwind did twice by these two
kobolds um how much damage just
whirlwind to see me remember those eight
cubes it three or two and it's lower
come damn it wrong so you're taking oh I
think it's a UH you have do you have a
blade turn you don't do you I don't know
I don't know what I got some literacy
for you get your plate armor you know
it's not pretty Tallmadge pretty strong