[Music]
uh justin is now your turn all right
it's my turn
uh all right so uh as olives Co sucking
done anything we don't know yet like he
hugged yellow COBOL but the monsters
haven't edited since then it did sorry -
Justin he'll the one for the Frog totem
on Romans turn III heal it I've just
been healing it on their turn it's
easier on their area it's not what the
card says that's how I've been doing
just make sure all right oh I'm gonna go
ahead and toss blue kobolds heap into
yellow cobalt yep all right uh you pick
up blue cobalt you miss when you throw
my yellow Kobol when he lands over here
but blue cobalt takes five damage all
right and now is blue kobold stunned
from the toss four or five major Lee's
for next turn let me see does it say
that in the card yeah yeah well it's
both targets - yeah so blue cobalt will
be stunned next turn so put them like
that okay all right and uh now can I
move it all I gotta move a few spaces
right yes you can move move up to four
move right on here okay and I'm done
does the whirlwind cobbled move I
suppose uh whirling Coble moves he takes
one damage because of fire and can't hit
all right so now it is the kobolds turn
red cobalt is dizzy red cobalt though is
going to try and bite dead bones space
but there's a space distant Manchester
is gonna try that really wants these
dueling rings I got on Jeanette you mean
I gotta give them my opposite oh you're
so he moves he moves in he's too
confused he tries to bite something he
likes he bites the bite so it is double
rabies yeah he bites his arm bubbles are
actually great immune to rabies because
they're Coble's um let's see so blue
cobalt is tons we're gonna pass his turn
man yellow cobalt who should you heal
God is he not done from the hug obvious
um yell actually that's right about the
hug yellow copal decides not to he
decided to go back here
and he's just gonna heal himself he's
gotta wash up he's a little bit used
yeah I really won over five like to do
something I really wanted to do
something okay then the gem Ling moves
into the fog of war I think I think I'm
even more intimidated by that just
manages all right a purple kobold is
gonna move up to KO and dingo Channel
try another bite
woo gently finds the key break to back
because he goes the bite yet again he
bites himself man that was a not a good
turn for the golf balls oh man do I have
anything I can really do here oh my god
now this is playing out beautifully
alright it's like I got no cards to
really put pressure on you guys couple
to loose in this fight
alright Roman you're up okay we're gonna
ray it okay actually bro move my plan is
working
I think it's worse your plan he's trying
to befriending them he's trying to
perforate almost dead let's just an idea
process isn't like an instant thing no
way man I'm breaking through the
eyepatch guy plus oh good I got yellow
leaf patch you alone for now yellow
remember his heel bail Stockholm
Syndrome Justin kiss his heel Roman cost
three stamina so yellow kobolds not
feeling too well cuz he's been spamming
it every turn on other people so no yeah
so it's creating an issue yeah right I'm
gonna move fall he rolled a ten so he
healed himself for five and it cost
three so he healed himself for two he
ain't doing that
well yeah alright what are you trying to
Roman
let's do oh my god in a row okay oh wait
I'll get you to roll to see if you get
dizzy mister using oh really Jimmy
usually read your turn blink using this
ability a chance of making you very
dizzy I put that on the card for people
who try to play I forgot a Jagger and
well the blink that is you don't really
use it for movement you use it for all
right you don't get to be dizzy you can
take your turn okay in fact the feeling
refract you feel a little bit for fresh
yeah hey maybe it healed you for a
little bit okay yeah I'm gonna hug him
role for the hug okay you don't have a
scenario for what to do with her hugging
the monsters hahaha carefully if you
didn't consider that one
you know what yellow kobolds uh he's a
little happy he's a little happy little
happy you know hey buddy you're alright
you too man yo mother I've just received
gems I don't know why you couldn't pass
no I thought I was done yo great if you
could if you guys kept a scuzzy didn't
look like you needed gems nah man we
don't need gems this is all a big
misunderstanding you what you wanted to
sit this out and just watch them fight
yeah that sounds good that's good yeah
you can have some of my diamonds I might
cool man
alright the co and yellow Koval are
gonna sit off on the sidelines and
really would you like to try eating one
of the diamonds ko na na okay
if you pass again just you're just gonna
relax OCO will not be taking any more
turns for the rest of this compact
unless you decide to jump in yeah um
dead bones it is your turn
my turn woah woah woah woah woah oh oh
I'm sorry that's right I it's cold
oh yeah it's actually it's actually
Roman then coded me Roman conjugates in
the turn it hasn't yeah I'm well he's
out now Zelly on that matter
Romans your turn though see ok you um
first I'm gonna yell at Coe
wait wait hold on did you heal us I
healed you now Co okay okay go ahead
Roman all right
I'm gonna yell at Co first mm-hmm cuz I
do I see him Jerry you can see him is
over there just sitting in the sidelines
god dammit Co what I see you over there
yeah this is all right man we're just
chillin check him out he's eating some
diamonds he's really cute
no no this is not cool look we were to
talk about this no no you're bad
influence on Co you go but you know what
we'll sit we'll talk about this later
yo buddy don't worry about him he's got
kind of like I said later
hope he doesn't screw this up for us man
all right that's a good trend Roman uh
Devlin's a sorry
I'll get coach gets it so I'm gonna I'm
gonna take I'm gonna take a page out of
Coast Arcos book I'm gonna be like so
the lo of fact I'm actually just
stalling for time while I upload this
so squid so scripts is actually a
world-renowned artist but only for
self-portraits how are you doing so he
actually just quickly dashes up a
picture hands it to the fire bro I'm
using charm Oh using charm I'm using
charm
farbros every time doubles more charm he
has to take a sauna tea oh it's up so
you guys home enjoy didn't sell hairs
they get better as it goes along I
actually did they escalate wildly so the
more I use the better this gets all
right go ahead and roll to see if you
can churn red kobold what it's not
instant the photo isn't a no after roll
for everything man I was just not rule
Jame of 20s and one's buddy Ted all
right red coal bulb is charmed yeah this
is a fire bro man I'm like a relax it's
a red cobalt it's just like yeah you
know what that boats you're a pretty
good guy
yeah yo you just sit there don't don't
let the fire though just wait are you
dead boys let it let it burn news he
doesn't have marble monitors who doesn't
realize what's going on
okay so uh so yeah so he's just talking
and he's there he's befriended you he
kind of likes you and then uh he takes
damage from burning great um so now it
is audio track well there's an audio
crackle apparently on my dream from
Isaac who is it I mean I wouldn't be my
microphone so I don't know I will just
ignore it
unless it's yeah huge pretend it never
happened yeah let's that's the whole
chat saying your mic is muted when it's
not muted then you spent ten minutes
checking to see if your mics muted thing
right if it's if it's true they'll keep
telling us all right Justin it is your
turn all right uh why someone have a wet
re so that charmed kobold
don't touch him he's gunfighter guy
well he's is he charmed to just dead
bones which he just charmed in general
is like relax no he's trying to just
dead but she's my fire bro
he's my fire bro can you tell him to
give me my weapon back man I mean look
we just wait Wayne it out all right all
right welcome back
he left yeah Justin's turn okay I'm glad
you guys remember this stuff yeah I
heart my little fire bro and he's just
he's cool but I told Justin not to come
here cuz okay so uh let's recap so Co in
yellow Coble over here are hugging it
out blue Coble just got thrown over here
by Justin a purple mist nice hanging out
and and you just charmed a guy so whose
turn is it
it's Meyer yelled at Co so it's Justin's
term justice justice mitered and I
believe Eliza guy said was what the hell
do I do
that's I don't have a weapon well wasn't
well we weren't you trying to talk to a
kobold who's I was I was coming down
here to talk to this Cobalt but he's not
friendly okay well he's friendly to you
yeah but that's not means he's gonna be
friendly to you so tell him to be my
timing we're not friendly to you that's
a good point I mean that's okay so you
so what are you gonna save this cold
ma'am wait this is a no head he's a fire
easel fire he's on fire
pretend to pretend I'm on fire please
get a little close all right
hey so uh so I saw that that my sword
got thrown by you and uh I hope just can
i attack can I counter attack will he
tries to talk to me yeah I'm gonna do
that what way to counter-attack wait hey
wait hey oh oh oh hey hey hey bull's eye
bro lit hey I'm gonna counter attack
well the city of Transtech you just Worf
I mean uh is that all right my turn
first off you you want the sword yeah
I'd like the sword please okay you're
gonna have a sword I thank you okay now
you can do it BAM I'm happy now can't
fight him okay on Justin's turn I'm
gonna bite him what's the day have you
wasted turn for role play oh my god and
counter-attack come in it's y'all fuck
fucking start talking to guys in the
middle of compact he's not really go
that's your calling you know you ease
into it uh eight so you don't get bit
Justin who like I'll give you a sword
next turn
okay you think you've seen a long way
dude it was all right um did you do
so that was Justin's turn Bri I guess
okay I guess it is sir
we'll make that kobold Reds turn as well
cuz that was dead bones controlling his
turn do you wanted to do anything else
he gave you the sword on his turn now
he's gonna take one damage from the fire
though I know the fires want his bus
gone up on fire went out all right
that's okay I'm still gonna calm fire
bro okay no mass yeah yeah
suppose introduced to ads um I really to
make computer so it's just like I keep
four
I need to like load things um especially
because it's the mobs turn and I need to
have like I actually like have lists of
like what the mobs are supposed to do
feeble attack lights alright so let's
see what do we got yellow cobos decided
to sit this out that's not gonna make
blue cold happy wait wait who Colby's
just stunned did he get it back what was
that go can can can me and you yellow
cobalt have a chat about that yeah maybe
like turn yeah yeah well let's say it's
his turn yeah I'm not a combat man yes
turn hey buddy how's it going oh whoa
whoa Trading Places haha
yeah his fights pretty good huh oh yeah
man hey uh what's up with your blue
buddy he seems kind of angry he's got
rabies oh man that sucks dude mmm do you
want rabies
I'll give you rabies if you want just
give me your arm nah rabies is bad for
no no it's not it's great what do you
not trust me not I trust all my friends
I thought we were you know you're gonna
get it eventually if we hang out all the
time all right I'll make you a deal
yeah you do cuz I I do want to trust you
so I'll let you bite me
give me rabies if you go and you talk to
your blue buddy after that and you know
kind of maybe try to calm him down he
seems like he's a little stressed out
okay how about I give you rabies and
then we continue sitting here and join
the show and so I don't have to go back
and fight while I watch all of my
friends potentially die I'm trying to
save your friends man yeah they're not
gonna listen to me man
that's the boss Cobell okay the kobold
hierarchy is pretty it's pretty
complicated actually man that's rough
yeah hey can I just join you guys I can
follow you guys around dude totally that
would be awesome
my name my name is um Pete
I'm Peter Kobo but I need you my name is
grass I'm only joining you if I'm only
joining you if you let me bite your arm
yeah totally you go hey you go okay come
on
twenty god damn it all right double
bites the arm does not give in fact go
with rabies oh yeah yeah you know what I
think you're gonna like those rabies I
just gave you
well yeah man I'm excited well so let's
watch the rest this fight
alright cool dude let's do that do not
try and chat I'm trying
yeah I'm trying to give him rabies I've
bit like four turns in a row it's not
even worth my time to do how I've let
him bite I know that's not happening
right purple Cole bulb man I mean Roma's
animals got a deal with anything right
now so it's yeah yeah then they don't
see the dwarf he's this general other
option he's gonna walk up and he's just
gonna start whirlwind ding dude chat I'm
getting so lucky right now that I'm uh
I'm gonna pay later it's gonna shitty
it's a shitty ass whirlwind though it's
only gonna do one damage each turn one
takes one know exact fall hello wait
what is that your first nail eat damage
yep
that's not like this entire thing
alright ah mister was really hoping
there'll be 0 damn it feels like man
want to use this on a crappy thing but
I'll have to use it oh my god okay here
we go blue cold is going to try and what
can blue colder he's a leader
blue Clairol is going to it's just gonna
just gonna attack you with his wooden
club does this club have rabies yeah
lick it 14 romantics 3c that's the one
the plate I need to take
yeah but how do I then explained he
can't yeah is like well you remember
when I cheated to not accept it may lead
a minute.what turn I totally want to eat
in the one day was like a cool alright
uh so this guy's whirlwind ding so hits
his buddy
and then he hits Roman for one um
ruined it's your turn you get healed for
one erratic data saying that the sound
effects might be a little loud hey yeah
I'm sorry every boot in my computer so
all my sound levels are off I'll take
them down a notch fees well Roman does
his turn Rob will fix everything
uh yeah I'm already got fixed alright if
I were true hmm no if you take those two
out we're pretty good
oh if I do all the work we're good Roman
get all the kobolds look pretty and
rotate even blue :
you could probably kill the buff with
your free father guys still think Roman
stole he's all range attacks there's no
point for Roman to not back up well yeah
that's like not like fight cuz he can
back up you know it was real don't no
don't hit fire bro don't hit fire yeah
okay fire bro we're gonna frost attack
we're rare frost oh god which one you
forgot to bring the Frog you can't move
it it stays I can't uh I can't
yeah if I pick it up then that's a
connection yeah memory after you're
gonna heal them soon or something
alright
I am an array of frost to be fair
there's the whole whirlwind thing has
not been nearly as intimidating as it
sounded ah I is going first think
they're just Colton caveman and they are
looks this is one of the two boards I
prepared but they're scrappy okay okay
take your really underestimate of that
part not very combat focused okay oh
yeah I know it's fine
that's good okay uh rare frosting
blue cobalt okay alright sting not rare
for us
rheya frosty here's my jokes covering it
kcals here the Joe and tonight's
forecast a frost is coming that's not a
joke it's a fun so what's a pun suppose
you miss blue Coble then you hit purple
Coble purple cobalt is defeated just X
we'll have a free Aston you get attacked
you want to attack and go blue yes I'm
gonna hit weapon don't hit him
yeah you don't even have much shot good
punch him don't punch it I know it works
cool man I mean he's hot that's cool
dude Justin right by the buckets of
water but a room enroll for your boat
actually co our buckets of water burned
down and our consensus 255 it would but
it's Co you miss with your bow attack
and you hit your little frog on the
stick oh that's why whose frog on the
stick card was it that was mine yeah he
just Roman just shot it she just killed
my frog and special God where's your
taser card you know how you could have
forgot of that from happening dead bones
there's you stole it so no I don't you
had a second one hidden underneath it
what sweetie no no I didn't God alright
um so
whirlwind oh he died so it's KO stern KO
is relaxing dead bones your turn
hey Dad miles give aways assort I'm dead
just ate just hold on all right
am i unlike the others last time you had
this you threw it away so I'm not giving
it back to you just yet how does this yo
you don't deserve it just yet uh how has
been done you may attempt to charm
charge it successfully you controlled
their actions on their turn so yeah your
you controlled him in the sense that we
had a little Oropeza
yeah we had a thing uh what what's his
health looking like what's the bus fire
Bros was he looking legs he little beat
up is he I mean fire bro is looking at
you and he's like in love with you oh
yeah I get like what is when you charm
someone you juice yeah
I think it's like sexual animal
magnetism they thought that they have
the sexual feeling is that it's like the
he looks at you and you're like the most
perfect person to this so you're saying
I'm a sexual Tyrannosaurus
so he's like he's dead bones like like
if you try to do something sexual to
kobold he would let it happen but he
doesn't see you in a sexual like okay is
a oh he idolizes you
you know you're the MC he sees with cows
yeah you're khaleesies down Mesa right
so but all right so how is he looking
like is he looking to beat up or what oh
so his actual facial expression he looks
like he's already dead he's already dead
he's like on fire and he's like
breathing him all right right right fire
bro fire bro we go way wet yeah buddy
fire bro is now he's got an eye patch no
yeah you go hey buddy
hey hey capons how you doing hey hey so
cub oh yeah I want you to do something
for me
yeah kit right you see that guy over
there doesn't come in here I see that
guy yeah Nick he's he's a big juicy
dwarf any okay yeah I want you to bite
him okay all right that's you chip
that's gonna be a 19 no matter what it's
a 14 you can have all right he bites
right justin justin is now infected with
rabies
oh I'm sorry I'll teach you to throw
away your cowboy at the start of a
return until you cure this you will be
taking stamina damage Oh Oh Rios shit
really oh yeah yeah okay bones
ah all right as a show of good faith the
cold then turns to also by his master
because he thinks this is a good thing
then we roll to try and not get bit
let's try not get yeah oh wait on the
rate yeah he's gone
all on the rabies oh yeah that those
doesn't get hit all right so that cow
doesn't move are an act that's your
whole turn you just as much man you're
connected this guy on his turns you just
control them on your turn
that's a straight that's all you get to
do well I mean your science right I mean
no no II know what happens you gave me
my sword you gave me rabies yeah we'll
talk about it hey kind of sordid I have
a sword back did once and maybe laid it
all right it is now
Justin's turn so we actually walked over
here together for some reason Thanks uh
is rabies infectious hey uh you keep I
know Judy's gonna be like I'll take some
rabies damage at the start of your turn
now Oh God you won't die from this like
when you get to zero you would just like
pass out so you were saying kobold bro
was hurt right yeah he's dead he
wouldn't I when him in dead bones walked
away he walked off with like a really
bad limp and you could tell that like
one of his arms is broken I'm gonna walk
up and toss him into the fire is it like
Old Yeller is he putting them down oh
all right you pick up you pick up the
kobold you throw them into the fire the
Cobell just screams of horror pains as
he's a dad
up till now all the other kobolds they
really haven't died I always say death
but why should be saying they fainted I
shouldn't have been knocking off the
boards that's the first time you guys
deck that guy's dead dead okay oh yes to
the other the one that Justin split in
half he's just oh yeah oh I'm sorry no
justice guild tickle I feel bad for him
when he wakes up like how the purple one
died purple and died - Rafe Rossi he
just passed out Roman he just passed out
over here he's after after Justin does
uh it's kind of late huh all right
that's what you do I'm just gonna say
Justin you can use an attack you know
just
whatever you want to do with that
information what spice I'm gonna wrestle
dead those are my sword oh okay hey
that's fine um sure I'll let you do this
is like a move action is just trying to
get back you this can be the move that's
fine
15 dead bone just this this yeah this is
you guys competing big I mean I don't
really care so it's like a half-hearted
role what whatever okay you're not a lot
of effort yeah
oh he for sham yeah alright you get your
sword back Justin good thank you you can
assume you have your sword back now
yeah that's into my third you should
bite your sword
okay so man it's just blue kobold he's
feeling quite defeated he sees as he
sees his friend his friend just died so
he's gonna he's gonna try to uh worth it
to charge blue coals got no choice so
he's just gonna he's gonna blindly go
for the charge hey blue we could totally
be proud yeah he doesn't he's not having
any of that and Roman takes Wow is he
fighting hymns well now we charge I'm
sure I don't get charged okay so that
wasn't paying attention sorry alright it
is now Roman Stern let's kill him
you've got wait you have more spells
than Frost right yeah alright okay well
no I've enlarged oh okay UNK you enlarge
the frost ray do that can i enlarge your
smell eyes of a target or object no I
mean one large fount of years well
technically if I had two actions I could
cast the Ray of frost and then cam is
like a lard in my other hand you can't
do them at the same time that's that's
alright that's a multiplication spell
which is hard that we definitely need to
make okay
oh okay here we go
or never a frost wait let me go up thank
you Miss French eat of puns he has
I just like pulling these on your foot
okay oh yeah bye spreadsheet Bobby
wikiquote for brought Batman and Robin
right uh first of all they're not all
from that okay let's oh yeah I branched
out a little bit like that Frost one
that was a gym you know come on Roland
say you're chill okay okay alright well
I'm looking first of all I have a list
here okay all right uh to the kobold uh
you don't look well is it too chilly for
you
are these really puns about you you
blast the kobold for three damage he
falls to the ground and passes out oh
all right you guys are now effectively
out of combat so pirata we why don't we
bring you guys up to over group with Co
Oh Weiss Kona come on all right no you
go whichever way you want I'm just
bringing you guys let me wait we go
you're at a combat so you guys yeah you
can okay okay we're having a group
meeting here guys everyone get over here
yeah you guys need to meet Pete it Pete
Pete is the shit with Pete this is a
dwarf move - PA yeah nope get go back
daddy-o
Dorf get behind me all right the order
dude so like Pete's gonna join our crew
is that cool uh easy I don't want exec
lights is is he like yeah yeah yeah you
bro oh oh oh oh you want to see the big
gym what yeah yeah like what - lets come
here it for eating wait wait just just
hold relax
I'm really sorry but your red friend
kind of burned up oh he wasn't my friend
no I just hung out with those guys we
weren't really his bite right we were
really close though he was my friend
no but there's a great cave but the boss
will don't worry boss will never let me
go near the big gym and I heard it's the
most
let's just Jim I mean we don't eat gems
do we do eat cheese guys this totally
sounds like a side quest oh I heard of
those I have a problem here your friend
just wanted to bite all of us well yeah
no no it's the boss that made me do that
remember I was obvious guy was cool
I thought you cute murmuring I should
watch you guys uh I let the dwarf get
bit yeah did you get that doubles no I
didn't get bit but the dwarf got okay
rocket yeah I see hey science h by AP if
you ever feeling bitey
just bite me man all right Pete the
other guys they might not like that
hold on he's gonna plate co he's feeling
bitey right now well you didn't the
offer and I roll the three I'm trying
okay Chad I'm trouble so hard get effect
these guys with rabies it's just they've
happenin but hey he still gets to bite
me so that I got to bite you so I'm
really happy I just again I guess what's
what's yellow Cobos health looking like
oh uh okay he'll be good yeah your
friend do you want some healing okay
yeah I need he'll really ignore him
I need I need healing come on hey here
you go buddy boo boo baby thank you oh
wow stupid nice nice
hey where's Cody hi Pete do you want to
buy Chucky
you want me to bite you yeah yeah
where's your bike uh uh that cowboy I
pick a bite of it he's already in fact
dammit I was gonna double infect him all
right no confections I mean if you're
okay with it you can you can I guess
I'll try to help you guys what well
nobody else anybody else want some
healing meet some leader that's th hey
the ceiling actually looks pretty good
uh give me top off healing without the
bite okay okay heals Roman
there you go Roman you're all better
okay Co so when we came in here your it
was your job to watch Justin over there
he's not the brightest huh
now you're introducing another person so
who's gonna watch Justin okay I know
peeking watch Justin yeah yeah I was
just yeah
Oh excellent okay okay well just listing
real quick Pete yeah you mind you key me
- I'm Kyle he'll all you guys have I
don't cut just don't want any yeah what
none of us are around uh you take orders
from Pete okay
that is awesome also we need to have a
discussion if there's a group of people
and they say they hate Dwarfs maybe you
don't say hey guys I'm a dwarf hi I just
said your name yeah you named me you're
the one you're the one you can go to
just erase free you could just you know
abbreviate it yeah last name three mmm
number ranges I guess numbers is metal
me you know that's a good point
hey you know the guys named me - my name
used to be something completely
different than Pete but if you guys want
you can name me as well
yeah hmm can we call him - what let's
call him dwarf number four doors number
two I guess Oh funny I don't like tours
you guys are gonna really like I have
the whole fucking story like that is how
much we hated dwarves are you guys are
gonna call me - ro - we're not called of
dwarf number four okay come on look Pete
we don't want you to lose your entire
identity so what we're gonna call you is
Felipe that's pretty good okay
yeah like that I believe that defillippo
let's let's rename dwarf number three is
something else too while we're at it how
about cool no he's not a peep no I don't
honk uh not well I was gonna say we name
a couple
so we avoided a future beep oh
stop we run into a bunch of dwarves that
don't like Cobalt well then we're fucked
Co I got this that's true you've ever
helmet that's true you have a helmet
congratulate AAB confit you have a sword
now we have to start checking on that
from now on okay
that back yeah butterfingers all right
okay talk to me what's the plan Roman
dwarf number three is now kobold number
four color fuck okay okay okay
P is now Felipe hey Polly but yeah Co is
gracias all right I think we're think
we're in good shape yeah all right
ah Felipe uh where's that big gym at
he's further than the cave all right I'm
game oh oh hold on quick idea guys uh
these couples were eating diamonds right
yeah yeah hello gems and gems you're
right yeah I don't know why they're
eating them but those are worth money to
us yeah thinking what I'm thinking
but I mean have you ever tried eating a
diamond wanna pick through my feces I'm
I'm thinking about the slice open some
stomachs and grab some diamonds wait
we're gonna cut up and Felipe whoa whoa
whoa I don't mean Oh guys we are was a
dead coal there's one here where lines a
global slew and then what there was one
more dead coconut the deck all boats
I mean called the Cobra basically
walking around naked with a club but you
know gonna tell morbid guys yeah I mean
do you want to go next little miss do
you want to go next
I mean that Justin Khalifa is gonna take
us to oh yeah a giant yeah my guess we
don't this is great oh good news Davos
we'd have to share our split of these
diamonds with coke I don't really want
to cut open a couple I'm game
I mean are you making me do this or is
this an order her where'd your disco do
it just do it I'm digging through
cobol's I don't like anything I'm a hat
sorry Lee Hey all right which go both of
you just we'll just say you're going
through all of them Roman you're gonna
take a look through all the dead Cobell
I'm jiggling he'll roll Baylor okay yeah
I'm I'm gonna go I'm lazy I'm gonna go
for the one already cut all right let's
see what you find Roman good and roll
all right uh you find a wooden club
rumen it went inside of the cobalt even
know like this is this couples not dead
this kobolds like unconscious on the
ground got the one cut in half oh look
one kaki why you have oh yeah yeah ain't
nothing you just find a puddle of blood
and a wooden stick next to the ground
they eat gems and there's nothing inside
I mean the gems everywhere on the ground
but when on closer inspection you
realize that they're basically just
there the fake gems you know they're not
the high quality gems that you come to
buy that type of gems that Cobell to eat
that are very common this caves lived
with them you could just cooked any wall
and pick them can't you look to the body
or made me like instead of picking
through the blood you're like wait a
second this isn't no fancy diamond okay
guys good news feathers uh good news is
getting through the remains of the
Cobalts not nearly as bad as I thought
it would be bad news is apparently the
gems that align around are all fake
that's good though like babies is good
for Felipe it's the wrong word I should
say uh not high quality not worth
anything the other fake yeah if you
watch I near ox start here very shiny
rocks oh my god like cools goal yeah
it's a Gwen's gold I'm gonna wait right
shut up about como Felipe talk to me I
have a question before we go up on this
side quest yeah
is that big gem the same kind of gem or
do you not know I've never seen to go
try it I mean I've seen it it's pretty
quick it holidays I'll have you win it
with or with your I that's missing or
your I that you have oh I don't actually
have a real missing I that was just
that's a bit now I take this off well
after you got an iPad yeah there we go
oh you nuts it's kind of like Paul
Simon's just so you know that's I was
not acting I think you look better with
the patch on to be honest yeah me too
meets you see the boss they didn't say
so he said I looked like a stupid pirate
but I mean I think I look cooler yeah
rugged appeal it helps with mine with
like I don't have night vision
like other kobolds so like when I'm just
Lina cave and I come out into the light
I just switched the eye patch from one
line to the other and then you know if
you my eyes already dilated saying it's
awesome dilated always thinking ahead
yes that's my logic we go with come on
we can ask belief be a very important
question Roman what can ask okay
Felipe yeah hey what's up what happens
when we get a cobble wet you don't want
to get called whatever Oh animation so
this is my idea I thought you'll have a
guess I time again I have to make one
we're like your mouth is trauma
saturated solid phospholipids we're
gonna ran through space watch more on
him later on you already tried throwing
water on kobolds remember that's what
Cody he's just still bucking at someone
no no the water came at the water came
out but co threw the bucket with the
water and the bucket Abby's just hit a
hit the gentling that's really cool the
tables got wet and do it what happens
nothing actually happens so he's lying
oh he's just like he gets angry when he
gets wet oh he's like a cat yeah you
can't squirt a cold why yeah I get it
yeah yeah don't make him don't make him
angry yeah my skin's all muddy and ok so
you're getting off topic here ok hold on
now
we're moving in this cave Felipe you
take the lead ah Co since Easley you
have to watch Justin dead bones you'll
be in the back and I'll be in the middle
hey wait you're putting me the melee guy
in the back why teleport in with your GG
run anyway so you want me to stab kobold
number 4 in order to move up ok I can do
that that's not yeah we're good let's go
guys
this sounds normal it's pretty ok wait
am i cobalt number 4 that's whose dog a
signal or maybe I'll go away
alright
so this next room has gem Ling's the gem
wings are going to be passive until you
attack them if you attack one there
you're going to enter combat we know
this yes the affiliate they okay
we made no loop it on the way was was
telling my yeah he sees told you that
the gem Ling's are fine just you know
just don't bug him they don't bug you so
is is the one that's right next to us
legged that's the one that was you ran
away traffic the one that you guys want
to see the flag war he just ran in here
to go like hang out so okay inside so
this is a big room inside of it is it
giant gem wait like a gem or a giant gem
Lee it's it's no it's a giant gem kind
of like stuck into the ground it's got
it's all veiny it's pulsing and all
Philippe knows is that the boss said to
never touch it hmm alright well let's
move on in there and chat out or let's
Felipe's just always gonna stay you you
can move yeah I now Koh treat him as
your pet okay treat Philippe as your pet
all right Felipe so this looks like the
gem you're talking about yeah this is it
man what do you think we should do you
want to try and lick it yeah maybe it's
your jam yes that's I want to try
licking that Jim that's exactly what
that's exactly what I want to do and
we're we allowed my boss would let think
you I think you should go for it man
your boss ain't here dude you are free
now I'm so excited obviously give it a
go Felipe is gonna walk up and he's
gonna lick the gym
[Music]