[Music]
was on guard and he's telling you guys
guys his elves coming oh shit okay we're
in this cave it looks like there's a
there's a way through this cave this is
a small choke point let's go let's throw
down some fog and let's book it to the
back of the cave dead bones is on his
own where are you yeah over there really
good at hiding
yeah sure of a thieves kill yeah with
you mountains it's true let's do ICO you
ready throw down some fog and let's book
it's alright let's do it okay any ideas
my ass break so codes gonna roll for fog
and so which way is the back of the cave
you mean back here like this out Cove or
you got the rewritten yeah cuz we can
see this is just an alcove so that's
just a dead end yeah there's ya know
right running in this is like a place to
wait and die just seems like it kind of
sucks okay who's gonna cuss
cast the fog slow down the elves toons
alright go cast the fog but he was not
paying attention brought anything oh we
should we should move that because you
no longer the little girl anymore right
yeah I've no longer the tiny little elf
girl
well it snows that'll grow your
following Roman Roma's leader Roman
Roman has seen that fatha that Coast
messed up the fog was the plan to keep
going deeper into the cave Roman or
Roman I fucked up okay bye yeah no wait
okay I missed here's what we'll do
they'll think were hiding behind that
fog wall so we're gonna move further
into the cave I hope you're right oh I
am right you guys gave you we don't know
where these are cuz you can't really see
them you just saw them coming
as you walk closer to this lake though
the giant the giant monster fish comes
out of the water
it is the great monkey fish he he walks
up and he says in an echoey voice that
is really loud halt who disturbs the
great monkey fish interrupt this this
echoes I wanna interrupt him we're not
even in combat but yeah oh we don't okay
oh no you're not even in combat because
the elves haven't found you they're on
their way
you don't even well you know that now
but okay and the elves have probably
heard this like you're gonna be like oh
shit can we just like keep moving good
yeah do you want to respond do you want
to respond to him or not like no I want
to respond to him okay Melissa talk to
the monkey you're in charge bus anyway
wouldn't need a little monkey fish we're
just some weary travelers who are trying
to avoid being tracked down by these
evil elves oh I'm Way too big for a
puppet this actually works for open
people see it has I'm talking I'm the
great monkey fish ruler of this cave
who are you we're just some travelers
we've we've been on our feet for a while
we're looking for a safe place where may
we can rest up ah you're trying to hide
from those devilish elves aren't you oh
yeah you know whether they are quickly
coming to my swamp
you can hide underneath my buttocks okay
doesn't have to be under your foot ox it
is the safest place and the only place
where you'll be able to breathe when I
push you under the lake to hide from the
elves my fur is specially enchanted so
that my little mug monkey fish hoard
Ling's can breathe and feed off of mine
plentiful nipples I've always heard that
monkey fish are only tell the truth so
let's do it guys let's get on under some
money fish okay so Roman looks really
happy about this the elves come into the
cave they heard the great monkey fishes
plea she comes they comes up and when
that comes up and she's talking to the
the great monkey fish here and she's
there we go he was like hey monkey fish
what was that you just said it's gonna
go oh
[Music]
that hot key it's good to see you again
nothing in here I was just talking to my
monkey fish friends we we heard there
was some weird there with some elves or
no some gnomes and Keynes in this cave
nope no gnomes and kids in this cave
just the great mucky fish have you come
to pay tribute to me no no we haven't
all right is that there's nothing here
boys and said back so after that she
starts walking back go talk to that girl
oh they're moving fast it smells like
buttered popcorn in here so then you
guys can come back on
sure above the great monkey fishes bum
man not you know what yeah you think
it'd be way right people are like Oh mad
man once you've been under a monkey fish
but like it's just gonna be just you see
you're gonna can't get that stink off ya
know it's nice it's quite pleasant
what brings you gnomes and dwarves to my
cave um well I mean you know now it was
the health no yeah but why are they
chasing you why are you here what great
quest are you on who sent you
oh we're looking for tang you know Roman
a bi let you talk yeah let's maybe you
could be a little more specific ah okay
so have you heard of the wizard miss
oven Kombat has started miss Irving I
was coming to my cave room cuz of miss
oven no no wait wait wait that what you
think that what you think so right right
okay you have a chance before Hesiod x
okay so here's the deal we we know Nissa
van wants a special object so what we
wanted to do before he got it we wanted
to make sure we can get it and then so
he couldn't have it fee really Hoarders
yet again that's all that this have been
sends into my cave trying to steal my
great red gem but you'll never get it
you little bandits all right here we go
can I hug your butt
well dang oh you know you know what you
know what you know I don't have to be
this mean to you guys this is cuz I
wanted to do the monkey fish but you
know not to be that mean to him all
right I guess I could excuse mr. Finn
for sending them here as long as you
promise you're not here to steal my red
gem if you can say that I will help you
on your quest since dead ones fucked it
up that's great it's great to hear I
know we do not want to touch your red
gem at all only here to take something
back from the else what is it you've
come to steal from the arrows well we
wouldn't okay yeah it's stealing um it's
it's a key Lisa Finn wants the sunfury
key I should have known he for many of
years he's had his eye on that key and
many a times he's tried to steal from
Gweneth but every group of adventurers
descends into here ends up either in the
great silver mine mountain prison or
dead tell me have you killed any elves
on your way here it we know thank you
tonight
good Gweneth may spare you you love your
life should you lose a battle to her cuz
as if you want if you had slain any
elves she would have she would have done
justice by them by taking your head oh I
got a kobold than half of like Wow I was
pretty sweet I know where this key is
when it keeps it around her neck if you
want to get this key you'll have to do
battle with her or you know like if
she's sleeping or something or if she's
sleeping aside you know no you should be
the great Monkey King that's pretty
clever I never thought of that before
that's pretty good I like that yeah well
I am the leader
oh well yours almost night
yeah you guys should just wait a couple
hours ago steal from her Wow hmm you
don't need we have anything that might
assist us yes I have one thing that will
assist you one of my sons his name is
Albert take him with you I'm sure in a
moment of crisis Albert will prove his
worth and with that he's just gonna jump
into the water go deep down and then
he's all you're gonna see is some lips
poked up like just break the surface now
you can hear this and he's gonna spit
out his son Albert Albert is a little
special as you can tell if you scroll it
exhume dead bones now you don't ya know
you can suspect they're coming back you
guys know that the key isn't here you
don't know the keys here so so the first
thing I'm gonna be like so I guess it's
me it's you and the charm thing means no
charm guy where's he at one little add a
character thing what are we again you're
Kings and gnomes right eats thieves yeah
thieves what the thieves do they're
always out for them Simon your Romans
number two I would have assumed I was
but you know Roman always had the same
plan Oh a disguise oh I just got I'm
just telling this to this elf oh yeah
this guy's always like oh it's disguise
he's scum does whatever you want now
he's like yes yeah oh yeah yeah it's
around Gwyneth's neck you kidding me no
I would never kill you you're my master
I must always listen to you I will do
anything you say
alright alright alright I can fix this I
can fix this I can fix this okay here's
the new plan I am going to turn back
into a little girl and you are going to
say I'm your niece and you're going to
bring me through
the village okay and where are we going
hey I don't you know I just want to get
out check it out yes that was good that
would be good turn into disguise and we
can escape charge of your three stamina
roll yeah
I hope you roll Oh that'll be fun if you
do excited you're gonna pick the clock
Oh dial this guy's that you okay not
what I had in mind don't think it worked
master master I'm not sure okay new plan
alright you come sneaking in take me to
the lady that lead lady okay take you to
Gwyneth yeah we're gonna wait here for
her to come back and you're gonna you're
gonna be all brave and say that oh I
caught him and look at his gnome and
then I'm gonna I'm gonna I know I'm
gonna rat people out I guess what if I
just took you and locked you in the
prison oh and then I could help you
escape at a later time master see you
man why is everyone I follow me follow
me master we must go before she returns
alright moving back around here you guys
know your mission he got good old Albert
fall along with you so Albert can't talk
no he just he makes sounds like this can
I hug Albert I don't actually have an
Albert for you he was not playing played
puppet but yes you can here you go
gay when Albert hugs you he leaves a lot
of like ooze off his skin all over you
so
dude this was the best day all over you
I know all over I need a new shirt
so let's this guy was the plan bus
okay so monkey fish says the sun's gonna
be useful so we're gonna have to take
him at his word I don't know what he can
do we can't really talk to him
but we're we're just gonna trust him ah
well if the assumed dead bones has been
taken captive but we've escaped the
first round so they probably wouldn't
suspect anything yeah we know we have to
find Gwendolyn Gweneth when she's a slim
when she's asleep yeah I mean Master I
feel like worst-case scenario she's
awake the hell out of her take that
necklace
we're badasses fourth what just just
chill it down fourth okay those ideas in
that helmet there yeah once they get me
there justin has no one to back up his
stupid claims take a four and I'll be
happy all right fourth
for so the plan is you're gonna try and
sneak in the city as well yes yes so
we're gonna wait till or since kind
okay so we're let's wait till it's you
know past the you know the witching hour
mm-hmm and we will stealthily make our
way through the town and try to identify
our house and you know break in do our
thing I'm looking at my watch but I
can't find witching hour okay hey uh
where's uh Philippe okay yeah what's up
we forgot you in the anus all right good
news we got ourselves a plan we're gonna
sneak in we're gonna find the lady with
the key around her neck we're gonna wait
till she's asleep and we're gonna take
it and possibly kill her but we got
ourselves a plus the planes not gonna
work what why not
they're elves okay I almost don't sleep
stages what yeah they just like meditate
really well fuck I mean this would be
really easy if they slept what are they
here we go again boss you and your plans
they're all a solid plan oh you didn't
even check to see whether elf sleeper is
a wikipedia I'm going to Texas oh wait I
don't know where Texas is never mind
okay hey for
hey buddy I know we've been a little
rough on you it's been a you know tough
little adventure I just want to let you
talking to gonna be six Kasich sounds
better than capable come on let's go all
right Roman which way do you want to
sneak around this down do you want to go
through the building do you want to go
around how do you want to do it uh we're
gonna go to Eagle or above this building
so I want to go up this way okay
it seems too obvious that people would
of course sneak around the edges really
a deduction rope Hey
you don't see anything look at the coast
looks clear is there ready to just keep
moving wait hold on when we talk to fish
monkey boy can does it look like he
understands us oh yeah okay oh he
doesn't nod he just makes sounds okay
uh-oh let's do this uh hey fish monkey
boy yeah we're we're looking for this
key that's around Gwendolyn when when
when what the elf leaders necklace we
need to find her house do you know where
it is after he spit up he starts hopping
so he makes little excellent lettuces
okay all right okay here's what you do I
want you to be sneaky but let's kind of
go in that direction
he's so long he's leaving you forward
you look keep looking around the corners
when you get to this building the door
is open and a Sun blade sees you right
away as as the like the monkey walks by
but you see him Roman and you you make
complete eye contact with the Sun blade
Oh combat has started I gave him the
horn who this guy yeah okay Commodus
started Roman you have initiative
you ain't know a frost okay yeah also
you don't know that he is charmed
still and guarding the door so nobody
sees dead buttons okay okay
you cast a rear Frost where's the
Cassandra frost no joke okay Oh yelling
yep one hmm
two days oh sure oh just yeah yes I
didn't realize we hit a second it's
getting well yes I think we lost one I
do this it's uh ten so you hit him he's
frozen in a block of ice okay I'm gonna
move into the room okay move to the room
okay all right what do I see um calm as
combat is now over because he's still
charmed okay so you guys are gonna walk
in you're gonna walk up this guy's just
frozen in a block of ice and by that
before like you're getting ready to
attack or as a group when you guys see
dead ones behind the bars I wait yeah
wait haha hi hey buddy
oh man we were really worried about you
we you know smell came by and it was
like can I ask something
what why did you freeze my guy what do
you mean he's your guy he's my guy I
gotta go okay I mean that's cool but
like he's not like he's wearing a sign
that says you know yeah I mean you could
have just waited and I couldn't see your
guy yeah why are you in there because
it's a brilliant plan that I have
devised myself yeah well you can't
possibly know that he's done it right
yeah but he said something suspicious
right okay what that he's my guy well
yeah you're my guy and I am in jail will
give us explanation of how this happened
how why were you locked in a jail cell
with a guy you charmed guarding the Bell
I fucked up as as I do and he caught me
put me in jail then I charmed him and
then you guys came and you froze him and
now he's a block of ice oh that's so a
block ice that's pretty reasonable
that's so what's the big deal let's
skate you out of there oh hey Deb bones
good news by now so we got ourselves you
know we met a great fish monk what is
that thing he knows where the key is
yeah it's around gwendolyn's neck
exactly all right but you need weight
you can understand that thing we were we
were in a dad's butthole not the kid yes
let's not make this weird guys okay bye
you were just Thunder Neath him sucking
on his you know nipples nipples
yeah his nipples we're his children he
had a lot of them you like you couldn't
be under there and not do it like what
it's okay right
what's up before oh it's not good
wait this is way better than you'd
expect
oh my god I don't I don't really want to
hear about your monkey butt
you wanna know I mean I wanted to know
about the thing smell me
we want to tell you that's buttered
probably you'd never know that was it a
monkey fishbowl no you yeah no here here
I get it yeah get that yet compare yeah
perfect is he in frozen the the it's
unfreezing we're gonna see if he's still
charmed after all no oh yeah he is not
charmed anymore wait oh that's annoyed
no it's yeah I'm sorry I was I was doing
it as if you're rolling for me around
yeah yeah all right he's still charmed
hey Dave how you doing buddy yeah chilly
good hey Dave I need you to do me a big
solid sure sure what is it master I want
you to go into town go into young tents
put this full elves right yep yep yep I
want you to go on a murderous rampage I
want you to kill every elf you see
that's not yourself what what's the I
mean I might be able to get like one or
two sure one or two get as many you can
get a high score get a prize if you
manage to survive hey boss I got an idea
what if instead of killing the elves hmm
he just goes somewhere and blows the
full horn which was your job originally
and you didn't do whatever I thought
you're gonna happen to that yeah why why
that guy of the horn Oh
because took me in jail but no that's
not true master you gave me the horn
that's actually that's actually true why
don't you give him the warmth why did
you lie what's going on here hey Dave
why did I why why'd your master give you
a home I don't know you just ain't now
let's talk to them anymore stop talking
to them Dave let's talk to him let's
man I got I got some news miss oven he's
playing you guys what yeah true there's
no you were coming they blow the horn
God that explains all those elves that
we've seen Dave Dave is reaching to blow
the horn we're gonna see how swiftly you
can do it to see if you guys can
interrupt it you guys Kate was saying
something bed asleep what you guys were
yelling and shit yeah we gotta go we
gotta get out of here
yeah enjoy jail what's we should kill
Dave while we leave oh yeah where's Dave
probably leave Dave alone oh good I get
out yeah gonna be so ripped
yeah no you guys are all just gonna duck
into the forest a little bit just gonna
have you run out Oh God all right so a
bunch of elves are gonna come into your
place dead bones and debo unless you
have a plan here you I think you just
you've written yourself out of the story
this is Rosen's band of thieves and I
tried to set you up but you got to get a
plan for how you can join Roma's beta
thieves again there is your story just
you got like in a jail cell I think this
is the part where I become an informant
for the other that's pretty much it
okay what do what are you gonna tell the
elf's a it's gonna hear that horn - they
are okay this is nine but at this point
your charm has worn off Oh Dave starts
telling the Sun blades that he was under
this guy's illusion
yep too light in that I admit it I admit
to it they closed a little plate door
and dead bones just locked in the cell
do you guys want to hear wait wait
before you go about the gnomes that are
here you want to hear they they don't
even listen in to you but not even they
killed a bunch of people bunch elves
kill so many else well there's a good
job betraying your party did dead bones
the rest of the game you can play as oh
I know you can play as what's his name
the bat eats Philippe Philippe Philippe
has he has he's got heal and he's got
the heal one blessing strength and he is
a blunderbuss at a club that hits for
three he has 20 stamina so we're gonna
change your stamina well be wait elite
bait not to pose okay so there could
have been all sorts of talks with
Gwyneth and stuff you guys kind of
ducked into the forest and then you
can't kind of popped out once you
thought it was once it was open so once
you thought it was safe to pop out again
man that was fucked up bro dude he
totally just bent us over on that I told
you about that guy yeah I told you I
told you I always hated you guys yeah I
don't know why you were hanging out with
him honestly I know he did these awesome
disguises yeah I mean yeah you really
seemed to like his disguises a lot maybe
that was just compensating for not a
person he did actually you know out of
all these guys he at least called uk4
but fuck him still call me a couple like
that guy Felipe you seem a little more
hostile oh man I got the snakes fish
monkey we need to find we need to find
guedes house oh he's trying to tell us
something you say that and the fish
monkey starts hopping but we have to be
sneaky fetch monkey he's gotten a mint
when he gets to the building he just
starts ramming his head against the wall
over and over to indicate wow he is
proving his word he's proving it hard
yes mom he's proving it really hard
someone's watching them
yeah yeah I think we did okay we should
probably stop what we're gonna have so
because he's knocking on the thing a son
cleric is gonna come out I need you guys
to roll to duck into the forest to not
get seen oh no oh shit
oh no everybody take a roll here okay
see how thievery you guys can be today
this is my role Roman is thievery he
sneaks right back into the forest to be
not seen Co good dead bones calm
Philippe Philippe isn't speakest yeah
but I tend to that's a bear pass but you
take just in the spot when you're trying
to it you're new to this thing
fully made your job harder here roll
into the okay Justin rolls into Philippe
and they they're just like on top of
each other they both take one damage but
you're not spotted son Claire comes out
sees the little monkey fish banging
against the table pulse ever blade
slices it in half clunky fish is dead
what's Clark do it she then she walks
back indoors like it was like a rodent
you know like these monkey fish do this
all the time like come around the town
just that's why the the grid the great
monkey fish hates them all his return
just keep getting killed man dude guys I
have a new great plan yeah okay boss
what's the new plan
so like daddy monkey fish is well you
can't call him boss dead bones hold on
sorry ko wait I can't call him no
because no he still respects Rob right
the boss right ko is his friend but that
was a confusion yeah pal whoops to
angling okay right yeah so monkey fish
dad is real big and they just killed
monkey fish son so maybe we tell daddy
what happened and maybe he'll drive
maybe yeah maybe he'll come with us
right mad at us you might get mad at us
yeah he was kind of on our watch and now
he's kind of did you really have a
chance though I mean that was just like
instantaneous yeah sure I know what he
dieded noble noble would you use sliced
up into I'll give you shit how you felt
I felt no I'm so sorry it's okay I
didn't really like that guy but you know
all right okay so what are we gonna do
uh all right here's the thing we've
tried this whole sneaky thing okay um it
does not quite seem to be working
we only saw him chop apart a retarded
fish monkey
so how tough could that really be yes
sure he comes against us let's you know
let's go in there guns blazing so that's
where that's where the keys at yes yeah
I say we just we just go gangbusters go
in there and we could do this top people
in half shoot shit yeah yeah it'll fire
[Music]
yeah is it that way or this way
wait oh it's this way okay so your plan
is to just bust down the door and just
go in guns blazing we know it's in there
see it's not working we gotta try
different testing in first side-by-side
like Justin okay am i sense who's going
in this long side with Justin Phillippe
just going in with the three of us
behind Oh three of us so Justin's gonna
be the first one through the door yes
like Tetris actually you know what no no
you know what I'm man I'm gonna go in
next door
oh yeah wait wait wait wait yeah Justin
should toss Roman in this dumbass plan
that's why against Authority man you're
not tossing me in okay I don't want to
talk to you all right
so Justin's gonna go in first
so we'll have Justin go in with Roman
here okay
combat has started all of you can see
what's going on so you're gonna walk in
the room and you're gonna see three
clerics okay and Gwyneth at the table
and the second you walk into the room
they all stand up okay they're all on
hundred here also combat has started so
Roman it is your turn this is going to
be the last encounter of the night guys
I hope you guys have enjoyed our first
stream is a little bit bumpy but it's
turned out great you guys are awesome
for staying up super late especially you
guys in the UK hopefully next week we
can have a nice and good stream for you
guys but I hope you guys have had a ton
of fun tonight all right here you go
all right to the Sun clerics which one's
Gwyneth Greta del Sol Gwyneth is this
one the one that looks different she's
the green one okay all right okay I'm
going after though I'm gonna Brea Frost
the red one okay go ahead okay chill out
you just completely whip it lets you
have another action but so you came in
busting down the door trying to be all
cool like a Gwyneth chill though you
shoot your beam and you hit this this
pillar let's just completely miss
Jenny's a warning shot playing it cool
alright I'm taking a bow I'm lining up
at at the red one still it's the closest
one to me okay are you sorry too so you
line up and throw the red one you hit
the same pillar to spot back-to-back
demoralising your party everybody feels
pretty shitty Oh karma revenge for
earlier Jim lording out dudes
alright Co it's your turn you can shimmy
past these guys
Shammi my asset here all right and a
cast fog okay right right and when it's
face I like I hear okay yeah right there
we're gonna do fog the new way and good
old new well just the way where it's
gonna expand every round it's gonna
double I'm the fog we don't know what
that I already saw it
okay boom baby it's a good fog it's
gonna spread twice as fast cuz when I
started from 2 so it'll 2 4 6 8
whatever okay
dead bones Phillips turn very deep yeah
all right he can move the same as
everybody else right yes and this one's
Gweneth isn't it yeah as he is a cobalt
he is the the Triton guard variant so
you get there's two passives associated
just so you'll know them because you're
gonna need every help you can get since
you can't get the bustling yeah
if you roll oh yes you're cold you will
always roll two dice okay yeah you're
right your roll two dice and you're
always you can always take whichever one
you want but if you roll one it's gonna
count so now I okay I need two dice you
do need the two dice alright well you
just roll one twice rollin twice
probably just remember the number it's
so anytime you have to roll a dice
you're gonna roll 2 2 as well as you are
a trained guard kobold which means if
you roll a 20 you get to have an
additional action okay so action yeah
okay all right now Phillipe he's got the
blood rage and this is Gweneth right
yeah okay so I can probably get up in
her face right yeah he wants to do is
his friends justice he wants to do his
friends win it Gweneth is the green one
oh can I get would I be able to hit get
up to Gweneth now I know it was 2 3 4 5
really yeah this is fine here this is
fine here okay you're gonna pull out
KO's trusty blunderbuss
okay oh sorry hit both yep yeah yeah I'm
just gonna shoot them mmm without ignite
the fall okay that's good
boo okay as well okay that didn't roll
that's the first one it's gonna go go
fog relax you know take it easy and 15
I'll take the 15 thank you and a good
job playing Felipe so far so you hit
both so we're due to damage to red one
to two damage to Gwyneth
one to the fog explodes boom boom
destroying the fog but you're gonna do
again to 2 and 2 and the Reds gonna take
4 from this when it takes 1 to 30 turns
just it's 32 nothing has died what okay
Justin's turn alright uh so what what's
what's going on here right now so you
guys to catch up you got three minions
and you gotta you got the Gwyneth the
boss who's got the key around her neck
is this one froze or is anyone frozen
when nobody stunned or anything you guys
are as the initiative you run in guns
blazing everybody else is doing stuff
Roman just shot two things that a pillar
all right I'm gonna get up here next to
the blue yeah I think this is as far as
I can go yeah okay and I'm just like
you're pushing a chair out of the way to
do this right this is a table so keep
yeah yeah you have to jump on top of the
table oh man yeah I'm jumping up on this
chair and I'm taking a huge swing at red
you go ahead and give me a roll
eleven so you get the hitter four five
one two three four five
[Music]