[Music]
oh poor Philippe
so we enraged the boss and we managed to
have dead bones just question what's the
range on on chivalry is that what it's
called yeah use that one's over like
it's five five five you're gonna use
that plenty of times you want to get bit
yeah having fun times with the doggy in
there yeah all right Justin it's your
turn all right at this point you've seen
all your all your buddies making a run
for it
I feel like all right so I'm back I'm
pinned in a corner I know I'm abandoned
the gnomes screwed mm-hmm can I try to
slam this elf through the wall through
this pillar sure yeah I just I'm just
kool-aid man my way out of here wall
wall so you're gonna like maybe with
toss yeah yeah no I'm gonna try it with
toast okay I I thought it's just
desperation roof you're just letting all
your inner frustration out saying oh
yeah you guys are celebrating over 15 s
gonna be oh yeah you grab her you
slammed her against the wall the wood
begins to break and you slant her like
into it like you just threw her into the
wall so she takes five damage which
kills her so yeah so you get another
action from that oh wow but she didn't
make a hole or anything and that your
plan of like throwing her through the
wall to escape is not a thing you kind
of just slammed her into the wall but
she's just indented it so yeah and now
she's she's not dead she's just fucking
passed out like stuck in the wall you
know I'm dragon ball when they do like
they throw them onto the mountain and
they're just like stuck in the mountain
like the shape of their body that's what
you've done
alright pressive well I got another
action what you got another action guy
just run for it you have a user move so
yeah yeah you put right away you can
shimmy pass the dog now how far can I
get well are you gonna use your action
as well to sprint yeah yeah bail out
here five six seven eight unless you go
here alright
The Great Escape before what's up
alright so first off I'm gonna do one
two three four catch up here spawn these
behind him and then he's gonna try to
bite you and toss you back into the room
Shh
cuz that's what that's what Fenris likes
to do that's what he does he likes to
play toss so he's just gonna bite you
but you managed to not actually let him
throw you so you're gonna just take the
damage alright um this cleric is fainted
this cleric is still alive she's gonna
walk she's gonna walk up into range
she'll walk right over here and when
she's gonna yes it does she's gonna try
to shoot you dead bones but you're in
the fog no there's no guarantees come on
Philippe can i yeah you can take the
arrow okay yep in a blink right there
now that so for lift for this reference
the Sun bolt is already in route you can
do whatever you want but if nothing
takes that Sun bolt you know it's just
gonna end up hitting ya Philippe right
yeah can I can I blink right there and
then it's a full-term bush right well
this is alright use your action to push
you can leave action to pass yeah push
them out of the way yeah yeah yeah okay
see user action to push them out of the
way
and I think blinky also gets a move it's
just a full car you fucking that for
dices curse okay her skateboard does
that what a box movie you blink but
you're disoriented and you meant to push
them outside but you only just kind of
push them right next to Gweneth so and
co you are so tired after that you can
move now you can and remember you can
move unhindered through the fog so you
can run it oh wait the function have
never affected him yeah that shouldn't
matter no you're good
yeah you can go there because the fog
doesn't affect you yeah even even a for
you all he's trying to do is push yeah
by the way is the fog expanded lately or
is it just like this quarter yeah the
floor looks like this it's chasing Roman
remember your yearly report you could
light the fuse I don't know why you guys
think you guys could still get away as a
team though yeah I know well the book is
it makes it hard pretty see you can you
could go out one side now all these this
fog is blocked this way if you go out
this way these Elvis can't see which way
yeah but he's gonna have to get through
the fog first right I'm waiting for
Roman to run back into the Mucky church
so I'm gonna use my move right yeah you
can you can move the the Sun both will
then miss everyone because everyone's
out of the way I'm gonna I'm gonna move
into my one lonely remaining piece of
fog right here and just died you can
just move like into Roman though like
you can leave Liana alright no it's a
fine loose yeah I suppose do you came
for or yeah you can be right there and
then the Sun boat would have just hit
the wall because basically you blinked
push them out of the way and then you
ran out of the way to that's fine
fucking hell epic died all right uh that
makes it dead bones his turn was like no
no I think that was a roughing oh yeah
still monsters turn oh yeah yeah yeah
Gwyneth hasn't attacked right this this
cleric over here I think it was name was
Dave it's moving up closer this one's
moving up closer these guys are
basically all getting close up to the
fog poor Dave it's kind of bad for the
guy all right
Gweneth man now this is the best thing I
can do so Gwyneth is just gonna use her
duskblade right here to detonate and
basically kill fleep kforce massive
sacrifice Wow
give me a roll to make sure your ship
really goes well there first time you
use this is gonna be almost like it's a
really good skill 12 do you find him
attractive by the way are you attracted
kobolds that fur is just your resistible
okay give us cheesy pick-up line then
just Acosta this isn't gonna cost the
standard them cheesy pick-up line so
yeah oh no sorry a creepy creepy two
dead bones to get this cost removed it's
creepy to the Cobble not to me do a
cobalt yeah hey could I kind of on you
and give you some rabies like that like
Phillips already established that he
likes he likes it right yeah what's the
treat yeah but I don't think you liked
the way I asked creeped out by dorbz
right yeah
and so because this is a Chevrolet I
won't actually detonate these Stiles I'm
just gonna have you get hit by the blunt
of the blade so you take five well it's
I mean the best time to use it is when
you're preventing someone from dying
we're like really why else would you
really use it you know unless he's got
way more stamina everyone else so she
has a second turn so for her second turn
[Music]
okay for a second turn she's actually
gonna try and hit Justin but she's gonna
move here and she's gonna use a desk
blade and detonate these two tiles on
Justin Oh safe in the fog well yeah but
the fogs not gonna protect you from like
an exploit before no no no okay okay it
looks way cooler than it is it's more
like an energy sapping explosion just
like not like an actual cuz that would
have been amazing so just not have been
amazing you take five two tiles are
detonated each of them do for you take
another eight one two five six Justin
you are now at the point where one more
hit and you're gonna be knocked
unconscious any bit any critical attacks
used against you would will kill you
don't have your death your mu little
bones anymore that got ya yeah
creative that out so that gets keep this
in mind you can't use using any stamina
abilities you can use them but if you
roll low you'll pass out using them okay
mm-hmm so just keep this in mind you're
at the current point Oh God all right um
I think so because the fog is actually
Casey you guys I'm not gonna have the
Sun cleric attack into the fog that's
gone that's gone I've tried shooting
okay Roman it's your turn
all right I want to try and get out of
the fog and I want to come south well
sorry guys I think there's only one shot
here before you run off Roman Road
Runner buddy
you should we might be able go go he
might be able to dive into that well
don't know what else to do go live with
monkey fish yeah we're surrounded we're
dying I don't know what else we can do
so we're thinking the wells gonna
connect to some kind of other like
underground aquifer
well could you meet a dozen I mean what
else are we gonna do least the well
might like protect us sort of until you
tell you keep casting fog and just you
know live here well I think I can only
cast fog like one more time no we can
fill it with fog and maybe they'll
forget we were if they never see us get
in the well oh you know the fog is
almost over there already and it for
some reason seems like it's following me
your throws any connection yeah it's
weird that's probably just you know your
mind playing tricks on you
so weird what do you want to do cast
some more fog and I guess I'll just pass
that on the ground wherever I do that at
okay okay that's acceptable trips right
really I'm really gonna tune with me now
yeah okay well there's only a couple of
dudes below us mm-hmm we bust out I
freeze one I freeze the other one and I
freeze the other one
how many turns to you okay I'm freezing
17 what what's happening the room and
disconnect stop doing that look I didn't
hear half your plan all you did was just
move so it's just it might have might
have locked up on me love it all of a
sudden Romi can see a glimpse coming
from the well Oh children is it is it a
real one or is it another retarded
indicating that the well plan is a solid
plan okay I just saw something what's
wrong oh nothing
okay good all right so your idea with
the well yeah I like it
cool yeah let's uh one last hurrah all
right Felipe's I think this might be our
last chance that room and it's your turn
oh okay I'm gonna try and get out now so
the creator of the fog is with me to see
is he able to kind of guide me in the
right direction well sure yeah I think I
can be a little better you need to take
my hand if you're put out here you go
okay sorry I got too excited here how
you whoops
charted multi-child you know you still
see one of those all the time twice a
game two three four five six seven eight
nine
I mean this his fog is still gonna
expand for three more tiles when you run
for that well that's gonna happen yeah
okay you like this over and as long as
you don't get stuck in the fog
you could effectively get in the well
and escape on your own I mean mind you
Roman you're a full
stamina if you want to keep some of your
party memories you may want to help them
get into the well but it's your call
uh here's the thing if I die then Romans
thieves team yeah it just disappears so
listen right so really self survival I
mean come on alright so I'm gonna try
and get to the well okay give it a rule
go such a team player to get so first
Roman shit yeah
you walked back into this way go okay
okay
I'm gonna use my thingy my Rubin you can
use your Ruby you're lost in the fog
right now see if you can escape do I
know that I'm lost in the fog no you
thought you were running towards the
well you don't know how much fire is I
got a trust and I'm gonna power through
don't have any other options alright
you're not out of the fog but you just
come to the brink so now you can see the
well fully clearly and the monkey my
filter well he still has an action if
you wanted to roll right but you're
stuck in the fog you can kind of see
like hazy you know elves and stuff
rings and boats uh is the monkey looking
at me
yeah like is he like at the top of the
well yeah he's at the top of the well
like just I'm a cast and large on the
monkey crane the bigger target for them
to go after is he like on the edge or he
like just straight up like I could see
it with you guys intentionally this is
what you can expect for people who burn
down buckets of water
we didn't put it down it just happened
to burned down and we were there do you
want if you did it shut the hell up I
mean like have some large on the well
itself and make it bigger
would that make just the stone don't
figure yeah you can try sure wait so
wait what can I still have an action
yeah you've used your right you're going
to freeze the closest guy then okay
you're shooting through the fog shooting
through the fog well I could see it so I
you can only eat a Z though it's hazy
you're not go but yeah you don't kill
the dinosaurs did you freeze the green
guy he takes change all right I'm gonna
shoot the the guy to his left
okay we try to scare him yeah you can
try to scare one of Gwen's son clerics
didn't bow yeah I mean right it was a
good shot you you use three damage to
her but you know she's long emanated
he's not intimidated I'm sorry
I should have been like me would you
like to move to the well like that the
elves are English alright it is co stern
Co so much you got Coco you got to like
so doing a fog like if you get a low
roll I have a plan
you'll pass out trying to cast it so no
not check out check out my sweet plan
alright okay I have I can move five ish
right you can get to the well this turn
and escape if you like because you can
see through the fog so so I want to do
basically a series of three things one
is I want to move to the well and I want
to stand on the edge of it
okay okay I'm gonna do that yeah I'm
standing on the edge standing on the
monkey ducked down with Co got close
yeah okay now I'm gonna shout Philippe
go towards the well what do you want to
say Philippe follow my voice cuz you
know the elves will all hear you going
with my will yeah I mean then jumped up
on the well like exploded a puff of
smoke
so as I'm leaning forward no way I'm not
gonna fall into the well wait I'm going
to no way I'm on the edge the edge of
the well right so you want to fall in if
you pass out exactly yeah he's fine I'm
saying I want that to be like a gear I
got shit out a final fog here out of my
ass okay so you're gonna like this is I
near this is all of it do you want to
guarantee you pass out I want a
guarantee that I well Rhian your role if
you get if you if you if you could have
passed out from this I'll give you a
plus C so a seventeen RI is critical s
out and fall down the Wow
alright there you go this is my
last-ditch effort to try to save the
remaining party yeah yeah alright here
we go
this could be a man looking for again I
guarantee it okay for nurse can't curse
the K 4 7 10 K step alright you you you
fall down the well you pass out and a
fog starts worried on the well okay
thanks Felipe yeah you believe it's a
Felipe heard that I'm gonna try and head
towards the well but I mean yeah the Fox
you need to get out but you know where
the voices so it should help you get out
of the fog so I should do I just worked
doing rolling out of the fog and this
fog looks a little bit yep alright
double roll for the car bones come on
Philippe
you run as fast as you can but before
you know it you've run right back into
the room just you just dashed in just
let oh so do I get an action still sure
absolutely
MacLeod on fire no no that'd be to kill
you and just I mean he doesn't like
justice but he like you know he likes me
he's called just in case like dwarfs
he's kind of grown on him I mean just
give a for a while ago yeah he wouldn't
he wouldn't kill him he hated dwarves
because his friends hated dwarfs you
know he's learned to not be ignorant in
height so an 11 hey Bobo yep and come on
come on all right
you blast the Sun cleric for two or
three one two three I'll even let you do
four cuz it's that's how much that's not
gonna matter and that's your turn Justin
you're wrong all right I'm gonna try to
run for the well yeah does your name
ever repay you have no stamina okay
yeah keep that in mind you need a high
roll to break through this fog yeah it's
getting pretty dense too I mean everyone
have any other options yep
all right could have played dead yeah I
mean there was still the option to give
up Oh Dean that's Justin you make it
right to the well you are home safe yeah
okay pour out one two three four yeah
that's fine you're out all right it is
mob turn thin wrist walks up oh if he
gets a one it might be okay and you need
Gweneth rule ones yeah
that's not a one okay that's 1 2 3
finish throws you across the room r.i.p
this son cleric is gonna try to shoot to
bolt at you Oh gonna chase you too you
know yeah he likes to chase mind you got
double stacks this this room is just son
clerics I really wished you set that
room off at some point but it didn't
happen well these these things really I
do
they don't and once they're enraged you
just take the damage every time they
don't go well that's what I'm saying
they detonate but now they don't picnic
before cuz they goes raised yeah see so
now the room is just Gweneth swings your
sword
Boombah Boombah boom you die so yeah
like if you're here and gwennyth swings
at you you're gonna take two day you're
gonna sleep for damage for each Sun tile
so 816 plus or sword damage wolf I don't
generally have Gwyneth's swinger
duskblade but it's this twenty plus two
image that's insane
so the Sun clicks I'm also gonna try and
shoot a stumble that you is here the
only one chicken aimed at see oh she
misses look at the alien he's so lucky
Gweneth is gonna try to go into the fog
to chase after these guys she's she's
pretty confident Penrice is gonna kill
that stupid little coal bulb we need to
have gay like one two three four five
Gwyneth is no one to fuck with Roman she
has cut off your escape and she's gonna
hit you with her duskblade that's what
you get three she does miss con the
duskblade though these elves are moving
into position
they have seen people jump in the wells
they don't want anyone escaping they're
coming in this guy's actually coming
into the fog these guys are closing in
this one's coming into the fog this one
is actually gonna try to attack you
through the fog oh my god
you can totally see 18 kills you and the
Sun tile spawns or that kills you it
does do you know just this spell blade
the spell blade is going to attack you
spell blades can both attack and cast a
spell each turn
so he's going is he green oh well I
guess yeah do not do that green greens
the green spell blade has one spell and
it is flare
you know what the fog knows
so you know the fog I guess he's just
not gonna use a spell blade ability
because it just wouldn't make sense he'd
he'd dead maybe hurt more of his friends
would make sense though I know the fog
detonates he's he's he's a source / - he
knows his flare right five he tries to
swing it Roman he misses um I think
that's my turn yeah alright Roman can
you roll 20 Roman has a lot of stamina
is the thing okay done so you can
probably last but he's got I can't last
another one you can get out
he's just a mile and a half away
obviously the goal is to get to the well
are you just gonna try to like bull rush
through them uh here's the thing I'm
gonna try and go around them I can i
okay so you're really rolling to get out
of the fog and not come yes it again
yeah man you took that fog ability come
on wrong-o sixteen all right you're out
of the fog I'm not gonna let you run to
the well but I guess you've got that
Ruby but if you're gonna try it yeah
you're to use the Ruby just jump in
right that's the devil I'm gonna try to
have yellow block you okay but if this
fails to escape
Oh Oh yellow is gonna come in for the
block so you can still do your actions
Roman but you you're not cleaning out
also the floor yes like this well he
knows where it is
yeah he's fine he knows where the well
is it's just it's covered in fog now
right yeah you want to hit the spell
brave Roman you wanna you want to do
with your action okay so I can't move I
can only have an action yeah because he
has gone to block you he's impeded you
from trying to do him another move this
turn I love room and that this turned
around on you it's so round on me demos
is what aperture 8 o/w you started yeah
but he's dead but the thing is you yet
you sounded the escape alarm cuz like
you guys don't know how much health they
have like I'll tell you how much bender
says header says 5 10 15 20 25 30 or 32
fender still has 32 hit points when it
has 510 Gwyneth has over 50 claims still
like well years haven't even attacked
twineth so it probably would have been
impossible to kill quentin unless you
were like if there was no way I really
killed one a at that point Roman Roman
is is uh remember that ring it fire oh
wait I don't know if you still have it
or not doesn't know you Roman has it no
because in the past back room and took
it oh yeah the ring fire you could shoot
it like outta line you can hit okay you
hit these getting elves and go at night
crazy
oh the gate is open yeah you can just
blow and run you'd be split up from the
party
but what I mean this is the show right
no no I can't do that no you don't want
to go for the Ring of Fire
I'm not I'm not going for the Ring of
Fire okay Wow I think you might have
time wait you actually you know what
Sorry Sorry Sorry
I'm gonna I'm gonna get down on my knees
and put my hands on my head okay okay so
Ruby's still gonna do the blowing run
okay so the elf is just gonna knock
romanette unconscious
do you like Romans just gonna be knocked
out unconscious and Roman will be
escorted into the jail so now they have
one turn left final moment it keeps them
alive and actually it keeps dead bones
and Roman together those Romans
characters together cuz I'm not gonna go
to jail so okay
Katelyn yeah Felipe let's pick up Felipe
first so we get two Saudis to move five
spaces right sure move as close to the
door as you can I don't want to see your
action or not using your action no just
moving just move one two three four we
can put you here would be Jeff can you
see outside with that if all you see is
fog okay with the fall you how do you
like this at this point how far does the
blunderbuss reach never you can you can
make a movie style and just go don't
miss your roles yeah oh you've been
rolling ones though he can hit the fog
though and I'll let him hit the fog
animate one two three all right so let's
figure out how this detonation is gonna
work so
the thing is Roman is still unconfident
really think like I was just playing out
the end of the game Roma still here but
you don't know that so this wouldn't
change anything
everyone's left you're shooting that was
gone so I mean you still had a ton of
health anyway you're gonna live this
explosion actually really this is going
out like this is gonna change things
this is gonna change the story I think
okay
good old fleet is gonna ignite this fog
so just looking at this these elves are
all going to die like all of you didn't
win it NACA winneth but like this son
cleric won't this one won't
this guy will cuz he's touching one two
three four five which is gonna be ten
damage he won't die now I guess like
none of them die they're just gonna take
em when we manage to have a young fire
is it gonna blow up the well so this is
this is 10 this is 1 2 3 4 5 that's 10 1
2 3 4 5 that's 10 1 2 3 there's probably
no well no that can't replace what's
untitled 1 2 was a fog there 1 2 3 4
that's the new cleric so she's alive
everybody's alive but they're gonna be
all on the flame on fire the well just
explodes like all the walks come caming
it in but now there's their fog where
this guy stood yeah does it take at this
wall does it take out them yeah yeah it
does yes yeah do we even have you still
know do we even have the dead bones oh
wait he's the fog all right if you if
you flip the fog over to Kelly yeah so
dead bones jail cell just got exploded
all of these elves are on fire Roman
you're gonna only take I gotta bring you
back a small amount of damage for this
but I would he's gonna get blasted back
this guy's can I blast the back this
guy's gonna get blasted back this guy's
gonna get blasted back Glennis on her
ass
this is my blasted back this this guy
this guy got blasted into your jail cell
is what happened oh nice oh this guy
could just get blessed back he's not
taking - no I was at full health when I
went back into jail I didn't actually
fight anything yeah I know hold on
Felipe here though is going to pass out
because he's gonna end his turn on a Sun
tile so he's unconscious okay fucking
asshole I gotta bring you in with 30
health all right
actual dead bones who has full health
into the combat I mean this is
disclosure shit dead bone so you know
what you could do Rowland was ready to
surrender okay does the reason why I was
saying Rome was going to jail because I
thought Philippe was dead and we were
down but Roman went to go surrender
because he had given up and then an
explosion happened and all these elves
are currently days.you this is a 1 turn
stun for these two elves aren't late
Felipe has passed out so we're doing so
he's just gone and she's still alive
Fenris is still alive and so he's gonna
be busting through this door ok um so
dead bones it is your turn again you may
take a turn here and then it'll go
Romans turn then your turn and then the
NPC's will resume cuz though ok so first
is turn gonna use my as W as gets close
to Roman as I can I guess okay so you're
gonna go one two three four five one two
three four five all part of the plan a
and skip a lot as well because that's
not an action or a movie right yeah you
know you can pass the decision yeah yep
so I can move an extra five that was
that was five or were you do you yeah
you were attacked twice usually motion
yeah but I used the actual prison pass
back just a thing I can do yeah yeah so
oh so so I yeah I thought you were using
pass back to get here no no I was just
using my two actions my moving my action
to get there okay give me a role then to
make sure you don't fucking roll you're
using an action
oh all right you're fine
you can pass back you can grab from
action he's on the gem yeah five spaces
out this way okay five Rohingya within
ten of me we can do this all right so it
is the npc's turn but most of them are
stunned these are gonna move up one two
three I hate that one two three four
five they're moving in she comes outside
the Moondoggie is coming outside
spawning tiles that won't have no
purpose gonna tie you just keep trampled
poor little Philippe he's just not dead
he's not dead he's just trampled he's
just he's gonna become a prisoner for
these elves there's nothing to say
there's no way to save fuel future tales
of fully personal possibility yeah
goddamn turd
I like how you totally blew off the
opportunity while Gwyneth was on her ass
to try to steal the key upper neck turn
there no she was on her ass she's all of
this all of these characters were in the
middle of the fog like it wasn't like
they were touching it they were all
around the fog I get some explosion
there they're gonna be stunned that's
fine all right
Julio's last act to save his party is
man total we have our differences but
the rest of the guys are gone fuck I
just say I just saved your fucking life
well Philippe saved us all you yeah I
just saved your life no no to carry on
if anything I'm Philippe still right I
saved his life you were locked in the
jail for being an asshole and you know
what you did you ran outside ran to him
took his gem and kept running you didn't
offer to help him up or anything you
stow is he down yeah well he's got
knocked at the wall I'm not gonna
confidently oh okay all right you can
just do it what we did before pass
here okay it's our thing first of all
you're a dick
I know I know I've yeah you're a dick I
know so here's what I'm gonna do I'm
gonna move or worse than that was here
so three four one two three four five
mm-hmm don't make me regret this
I'm gonna rheya frost this dude okay
yeah I got it I've got a bias time oh
that's smart
I don't I don't care we're running out
of town into a bigger town look you ran
out of jail you could have stayed there
oh god no I mean it's a way to get out
of town you guys are clear five okay you
miss your ray of frost you're really
Jay's from the explosion you bet you had
an action and you can still use your gym
all right you some pass back to whatever
yeah yeah those turn dead ones is the
same all right you guys hold you guys
are good it's the way out yeah you guys
you guys are gone at this point are you
kidding let's recap so CO and K for
probably assume that everybody else is
either dead or captured escaped down a
well that's a obviously gonna go back
into the mountain or though I'm gonna
tell the news about the other monkey
fish who died right and that's Han and
they're off they're just off on their
own and good old Roman and his
co-captain dead bones for the band of
thieves
somehow estate and the poor makeshift
companion Phillippe no no no
Phillippe was 100% executed liar like
murderers and well I don't think any
some clerics died
this you he kind of blew up their whole
base no this this was this is no prison
sentence for after August after all this
Phillippe was in a jail cell he lived
there for a couple months until he was
eventually decapitated by Gwyneth or
herself taken it into capitate of him
can I went out like the badass he was
real quick how my life was definitely
killed hey what who's I just want to say
I would I just wanna let you guys know I
had the biggest smile on my face when I
saw COEs fucking fog get to here I was
planning this shit I gotta make the leap
good but I gotta get me out luckily for
you you it wasn't character it was yeah
fucking master this game
what's up Co Co are you muted or are you
just you just sad
are you mouth whispering you just you
miss Philippe could you uh could you set
up the the monkey guy next to me okay so
you escaped back into the well found The
Monkey King and he's uh what's that
noise okay yep that's for Kate for when
to go all right it is super super late I
want to thank everyone for coming this
was a great show even with the technical
difficulties I hope you guys had a lot
of fun we're gonna be doing this every
Saturday this is why we want to start at
3:00 so if ever we want to go late cuz
it's just a lot of fun we can so
hopefully next week if our schedules
line up we're gonna be starting at 3:00
p.m. Eastern again you guys have been
great you've been an awesome audience
thank you everybody for coming
this was one of the greatest days of my
life this was so much fun
I'm glad with that we got to do this and
I can't wait to do it more so thank you
Roman Justin dead bones echo at Megan's
or for doing the maps map for helping us
with the website's missive in for
helping us with some behind the scene
tech honorary and all the editing Nick
for doing the animations I'm going down
the list don't forget people anyway
like there's so many people involved in
trying to just make this funny stupid
little internet show and you guys have
just shown that this is something we
definitely can do and we can probably do
for a long time and we can build this
whole world and all these characters and
all these cards and just give them away
to you guys because you guys just are so
supportive us so yeah thank you guys
make me all teary rob on borderline if I
wasn't like perpetually jovial like I
think here's like my face my face hurts
from smiling so fun very fucking long
time no I can't wait to do this next
weekend like this was absolutely fun so
anyway thanks for everybody coming this
was this was great and we hope to see
you all again at the next show next
Saturday see you guys thanks everybody
[Music]