[Music]
okay
it is now gwenna stern so first off got
about that yeah fiendish the wolf come
on rub comes running it comes running in
oh man co just got disconnected yeah
yeah I'm coming back yeah yeah I might
have to fix that for you to come back in
though right
oh nope that is so Fenris just comes
running in he smashes you guys out to
the side because he's come to help out
Gweneth he just comes comes running in
and he's gonna be taking his turns he's
actually bigger than that oh there we go
no no I thought I'd changed it he's dead
sighs yeah he's big he's big okay Fenris
has come in he's a giant Sun hound the
thing is with Fenris when Fenris walks
he makes these little sun tiles the sun
tiles cannot kill you but if you end
your turn
standing on a sun tile it detonates
dealing damage to you so they have a dog
that makes dent like literally lease
agreement on fire just roll it around
town anything around yeah it lands these
it makes these sun-tap tiles that will
basically blow up if they land on you
some of the world a favor roman it is
your turn
holy shit okay like next week i'm gonna
make these today should go so much
harder because these guys just get them
in the first round of comment every
single time you guys are doing awesome
like it's this absolutely amazing
response to this show
oh i'm sorry so that so that was Fenriz
coming in i got a deal my turns
alright so son
no chapter so some clerks get to shoot
Sun bolts which have five range they do
two damage and it'll spawn a Sun tile
next to the person they're shooting at
so red red is gonna shoot at fleep a
here whoa all right mrs. Felipe hits the
side of the wall some tile goes over
there blue is gonna shoot at Justin oh
man blue blue getting out of her chair
false the ground flat on her face all
right yellow is gonna shoot a co-star 17
hits co-star for two now and son tells
bonds the Sun style spawns that never
spawn on your space but always next you
know I'm surrounded yeah you can so you
can walk through you can walk them
there's just a thing on the ground
these don't kill you they just drain
your strength you should think of it
okay they're not little explosions
they're just like they think they're
gonna make you pass out do they only
trigger when you sland on them and stay
on them right you can pass over them and
they're okay yeah you can pass over then
yeah okay yeah yeah they're not supposed
to be scary yet you guys are so fuck
just so it's Gwen Stern Gwyneth is gonna
come up to you and she's going to swing
her elven dagger at you Gweneth gets to
take two actions every turn
damn so she's gonna attack you twice
with her elven dagger okay take for
damage out and hit you're gonna take
eight damage okay philippe MVP okay
Roman now it is your turn okay I have a
giant dog in front of me
get it get a rare frost okay all right
you act like you have decisions to make
both used enlarged like twice we had to
keep clearing things like constantly so
there's a reason all right
hey Fenris tonight hell freezes over
alright you hit Fenris Fenris takes two
damage one two and he is frozen for his
next turn
alright I'm gonna move you could walk in
with friendless yeah move I'm moving
therefore my movement then I'm gonna go
to my Ruby or use my Ruby to move
further back in the room I'm going to
shoot at yellow guy okay roll dice
feeling I'm feeling it feeling it I'm
not feeling it damnit you miss you just
Nick him you do one damage to the yellow
guy's ticket so now it is who's turncoat
go it's my turn alright so I need to ask
you about trading treasures in is that
my action no no the actual act of
trading treasures in costs nothing so
you can do the thing it's a racial
alright I want to throw my range when
you trade treasures in you can use that
as a free action it doesn't cost you a
goof or anything so you do as many times
as you want
sweet yeah no I just keep lending
treasures yeah that's cool I want to
trade in my blunderbuss and my blade
turn
Oh super excited see cuz he hadn't
better get a ram also he also has
another thing let's see what other thing
no I don't have that throat a debt bomb
so catalyst doesn't exist doesn't exist
did this did you have your blade turns
still Justin I don't think you know I
got armor is gone for dead booms I mean
like one of my blunderbuss when your
colleague at dippin's your whole put it
under my guy yeah your whole Road just
doesn't make sense we'll just put this
down here des what you're holding yeah
everything else so you're trading what
the blunderbuss plate the blunderbuss
and the blade turn okay alright random I
know I'm so hoping for a blunt it's a
freebie like I my fingers are crossed
for a blunderbuss that would be what if
he gets the potion no give on three
potions no it gives me three is it oh
okay alright you got Ring of Fire
against a bunch of fire people great
they're not fire they don't think they
shoot the Sun things they're not gonna
be it's like they also this builder
attack they're very tax drain your
stamina okay all the second tiles and
their son bolts some boats don't do
damage to you they just like SAP your
energy right cool then I will take it
keep that in mind that Roman can use
this if he really wanted to so right and
Roman it's in a line and it's ten long
so you know you could line up multiple
guys but it's like having a stamina for
cost and it's really not good for you
because you give the King armor and that
doesn't get applied so oh now is dead
bones still technically part of my like
my pet no no no because because dead
bones has written himself out
Philip is now
be his own but you can still you know
influence yes he is yeah he suggested
like he he like oh right because I want
to what I want to do is I want to move
here and I want to use the Ring of Fire
which is a line train and I wanted yeah
dead let's could roll out of the Dodge
alright and I get two rolls because
kobold sir all right roll free in the
fire
oh my god that's phenomenal
also shouldn't the 14 okay so that's
gonna cost co 4 cuz he's gonna take them
to himself - yeah but he's doing for in
a line deadlines I need you to roll to
try and dodge out of the way
Rose we got ourselves - it's not a one
it's not a one still clenched room whoo
I'm gonna I'm gonna give it to you just
because I believe is I don't want you to
guys just die in the next turn now does
the Ring of Fire have a bonus to frozen
targets I don't think the dog is frozen
I think he just you only damaged them
cuz Rob didn't say anything about him
did you no did he just do the freeze I
hit him
you know why don't know why I would do
damage you would understand him but
you're not gonna be able to stun in
multiple times anyway like I'm not gonna
let you chain this guy completely oh no
this is the first time he's gonna be
stunned yeah this plan wasn't thought
out he's gonna thaw from this he's not
gonna be it's still four damaged it
still damaged total that killer worth
that hmm look he's just B's farm farm of
those damaged meters right deep dead
bones it is now your turn
oh yeah Philippe well I guess after six
probably after seeing Co attack the dog
maybe divert attention from Gweneth to
dog I don't know
I think Philippe looks towards Co just
who should I get who should they get I'm
just gonna tell you guys now just
because if you don't realize this you've
not gonna stand a chance remember she's
just fallen on the ground this turn the
clerics can heal is it if you don't deal
with the ads they're gonna you're like
if you start focusing on these these
guys you 100% lose because you guys are
already the way low on resources to even
stand a chance of winning this
especially since chat has bought in rage
which is dollars and it means that you
guys really like the show that honestly
I am so pumped to be able to do this
every Saturday for you guys I like I'm
ecstatic right now but it does mean
after up after the next turn I'm doing
the one event and then enrage happens me
does less things on the board is
possible by enrage so I would do this
littlest to biggest yeah can I make it
past big
doggy here yeah okay so I can get low no
but you can walk past this okay and then
I can get up on her yeah just
blunderbusses I gotta give him some
chance champion they're not gonna make
it anyway it's gonna be a wife
I can have to rule a lot of one one's on
this when it actually yeah yeah yeah do
those two ones come on
all right it's an 11 you still hit what
do you would you is attacking right the
blunderbuss it's the blunderbuss
oh the blunderbuss yeah the blunderbuss
only does 3 damage yep so tickets it
hits the wolf - yeah eight area one two
three one two damn hard she's been
applying your dot dead bones that's what
I you should have been telling me tell
me a buddy buddy yeah yeah maybe on the
bosses yeah I don't think I didn't once
narrative like the dog I thought that
would be like I know chats doing that
but one stamina per turn guys I don't
know how many turns you think these guys
are gonna live that's kind of you know
maybe we'll die but they'll eventually
die themselves all right it was Justin's
turn then all right
is uh is this lady up here who's waking
up is she a healer - yes she is
all right wait Justin gets an attack he
would nothing in woodson range that's
why I get up yeah uh unless he had a
blunderbuss he could all right yeah it's
red died though yeah but uh how far can
I toss um I think it says on the card
let me pull it up for you
he was in intensity yeah it's five so
five spaces
I can only toss someone five space so if
you pick this up you could hit Gwyneth
you probably could want one too you
could hit Gwyneth of the dog you
wouldn't hit yellow cleric though which
is yeah might within range to run up to
you and start beating on yellow cleric
one two three four yeah I can let you
shimmy by yeah that's right I'm gonna
I'm gonna be buying getting up on yellow
cleric yeah okay team up attack you
swing you whiff and I wish Wow Wow zero
missing there all right it's it's a
winning works turns
the board it is a duskblade it it
detonates sun tiles when she swings it
so what so when she swings this blade it
puts out the light
so when she swings it she can detonate
light swords all of these clerics do not
take damage from light tiles heard the
sword also does more damage so there's
there's that too
duska blade is a 2x2 radius that does
five damage so Granite's gonna move over
here so doc doggy is not stunned we're
gonna do this first since doggies in a
hard place doggy likes to bite dwarves
and gnomes and throw them across the
room so he's going to use his version of
toss on Justin here
Oh God he likes to play play fetch with
himself all right so it's Margiela and
takes three damage just then you go
flying over to that side of the room and
now dog he's gonna walk towards you to
chase you two three four five that's
what well he'll have to learn there as
well as that's gonna do this where he
was oh good when it's gonna she wants to
do a silly thing she can't believe ass
laughs laughs laughs I wouldn't be
against that right now yeah she's gonna
walk up to Roman and she is going to do
her dust blade this is the first time
crash attacks twice yeah she gets
attacked twice oh my god wow wow wow
that was ten damage that you avoided
okay
yellow cleric what are you gonna want to
do you're gonna want to stall yellow
cleric is gonna heal all my job
yourselves not worth it
yellow clerics gonna move here to the
corner and shoot adjusting shoot her son
bolt do damage and a Sun tile sorry for
damage and two Sun tiles alright blue
cleric gets up starts to move up doesn't
get to do a turn and now it is Romans
turn okay
um kinda move pass one of you you can
you can shimmy past but not a full five
movements like right okay you can stop
right here for your move like right here
that's that's a pillar so you can't
stand on that
oh okay yeah so you'd have to shimmy
past the dog okay um all right I'm gonna
freeze blue cleric okay I don't I don't
even have it anymore
yep chill out
that's we're just you're you're
panicking you you hit the same pillar
those that use it the first two times
the one you're standing right in front
of to you you just you you your plan was
all right I'll look behind I look across
I'll look around the pillar and shooter
except you shot the pillar they looked
around the corner oh boy do you do I do
I get to shoot one no you get you though
Street you're both yeah okay just my
bike alright I'm gonna use my thingy yum
Ruby Johnny yeah alright move it over
here and I'm shooting yellow
we're really gonna have a problem with
blue yeah 19 all right
you do three damage into it you know
what nice guy one two three four you can
do an extra bit of damage it's got a 19
there Roman all right
it is now do choose turn is it mister
yep all right I'm gonna fire my Dragon
Skin bow at Gwyneth Paltrow okay yep
where's the dice there's the dice over
there you guys need some 20s for you
should you try to shoot Gwyneth you miss
you graze the puppy for one damage okay
can we request a new dice this one is
clearly curse there we go prepare for
all the ones just you look look we need
to just we need to try things I don't
like that that's cuz it was already on a
four I suppose how about this days we
put on a 20 and then spawn it yeah yeah
I mean I'll say 1500 done yeah yeah can
I get past wrong did you move Co yeah
did you move he moved up yeah I moved up
wrong you can move as a gnome you can
use it an actual item card so you can
ring a fire + action action every turn
and so you could just use all your
stamina aggressively try to just put as
much damage as you can on the board
wait wait wait so I didn't do an action
then last Oh No
nope using items yeah but you moved into
the position right so you use your move
and then for your action use the knight
'm what a normal person would as an ohm
though you're allowed to use items as
moves so if any turn you don't have to
move you can use that to do a ring of
fire if you want I see
so well I've already moved the shopman
if there's you wouldn't be able to move
into a plate bring your your your ring
of fire you're gonna want to hit two
people or you're really just trading for
four four against people with way more
stamina than you so oh yeah
so make sure you've got that sick ass
bow now and if you create on a bow it's
you know like 15 damage it so yeah so
can I get past Roman are you fucking my
gut no you see were tight yeah get past
Roman you can alright can I get up
doesn't he has the blunderbuss so
couldn't he move over to shoot blue
what's the ring or shoot blue yeah he'd
get a range of blue yeah okay get me a
range of blue I was gonna try and watch
out for that pillar over there by the
way it's a bitch this frozen pillar I'm
gonna I'm gonna just shoot it with the
Daedalus
why Kalina cos this suck go to anywhere
he really needs the 20s to because it
gives him another shot right so you
heard her she takes three damage on blue
Sun cleric one two three okay it is now
Justin string yeah all right so what's
the deal with these so these Sun tiles
if you're on one and you end your turn
you'll take that's right it's here
you'll take two damage so you'll you
forces you to move okay
the idea is the room fills up with them
and then you have no choice or standing
on them and gwennyth her new blade is a
2x2 area and it detonates those that
cause an explosion
that will you know deal damage in a 3x3
so you can combo them and basically all
the enemies are immune to sun tile
damage so okay they don't have to route
hitting each other alright I think I'm
gonna move up and throw yellow here into
the wolf okay so like here that yep yeah
these are so these tiles are like spaces
you could walk on think of like indeed
they are enchanting the floor gotcha
yeah okay okay think of it as the floor
like it's almost like time bombs
yeah the time bombs on the floor and by
standing on them they drain your energy
that's all they're doing they're not
hurting you they're draining your energy
because that's the thing stamina is just
energy if you run out of stamina you
pass out so you can't fight so it's all
the same resource still sounds like
you're trying to make it sound like they
don't hurt us but they right they heard
you in the sense that you will pass you
won't die from a sundial even if it'll
detonate you're not gonna die from it
we're gonna die from something else
alright though I like this plant I like
this plant Justin alright yeah next time
we will get a stun maybe kill yellow who
knows sorry I like this plan k 4 sorry
dude you that's one stamina you used to
do this and you go to grapple her but
she resists oh god no toss happening
alright I'm sorry guys chat has been too
awesome
why do they have nukes the Sun tiles now
do not go away when they detonate so
anything that would cause them to
detonate like Gweneth sword or cleric
shooting at the Sun tiles will cause
that explosion but they will stay on the
battlefield forever I can't see any Sun
tiles now deal double damage as well as
reinforcements from the city are gonna
show up every turn oh okay so basically
when this happens like a bail is being
run throughout the city and this and the
spell blades basically it's every spell
blade that you haven't beaten in the
campaign and you ran from the first four
and you haven't killed it he ever you
haven't killed any he doesn't beat any
spell blades so they will one spell
blade will enter combat each turn I hope
you want to see you don't know Dave dead
bones oh we met Dave you froze him you
didn't like him I know I wanna meet him
so I can kill him
I just one point I'm like standing and
not in my happy place right now the
stupid campaign is emotionally getting
to me all right
it's so so I'm sorry I'm sorry it's my
change mobster yeah I got so excited by
a couch I'll skip his turn
yeah I know we'll go with Fenris first
who sees a nice plump little king he's
gonna bite you and throw you across the
room uh was that nine nine all right I
turn oh then this completely negates
everything he goes to bite you and it
just bounced off the blade turn oh
that's good because his whole gimmick is
he throws people across the room that
goes who chased after them creating sons
all around the board
okay
Romans done this raid before it's okay
so Gwyneth is going to who one two three
four five and she's gonna to shoot two
son bolts at watch my collar and not a
chattered wondering why I'm not using
the whatchamacallit it's because I'm
just trying to create I'm trying to get
these Sun tiles everywhere because they
just Auto lose their key that's unlucky
so they fail right right yeah no this is
just you just shooting that the Sun bolt
at dead bones here but one one can Nick
you but you get hit by both two Sun
tiles spawned it makes one two three
that's the whole gimmick yeah all the
clerk's shoot them too but you guys have
actually be doing a good job of keeping
the block down for those oh all right
blue was not stunned yellow was not
stunned yellow is going to she win shoot
cuz your close range is she's kind of
stuck so she's just gonna swing her
elven dagger at you Justin but she just
barely hits you so you're only gonna
take one okay and then blue over here
dead bones is gonna shoot you and he's
gonna shoot you with assembled and
another eleven so you take another two
dead bones is very very weak on health
on the good old
Lipe is looking pretty rough Felipe is
alright honest in trouble right now he's
he's wasn't geared out you guys good big
ko gave him a blunderbuss cuz that's all
he's really got alright I think I've
done everything for my turn so now is
your turn Roman okay um this shit has
gotten a little too real just a little
we got a giant dog the floors
turn into lava I played that game as a
kid it never ended up
oh uh Oh God
are you sorry plenty to run is that what
you're getting that uh you bet your ass
I'm gonna run whoa shout at him good
reason with that remember how fish fish
man I will let you guys let you guys
know that because it's basically every
encounter at the end of these like the
final encounter every night is always
gonna be a battle because that's what's
really exciting for chat so while there
may have been a point to kind of talk to
her at this point you know it wasn't me
yeah but you doesn't like people I don't
think you guys didn't kill her did you
do not we killed run else dead yeah she
dead oh just you just get knocked out
straight up dead who killed her remember
it was either me or Justin I wasn't at
the fire oh yeah was the fire it was Co
so let's go yeah no I don't think she's
dead I think she just passed out oh yeah
unless Co is your the character the type
of character who he likes murdering
everyone no yeah so she just passed out
from lack of stamina all right fair
enough
I'm just bad about it I should really
just flip them over and have their body
be laying around
yeah me thinking he confusing doctor I
know yeah I should just move him to the
side she didn't die though okay which is
good cuz you know great monkey fish
talked about the whole the band room
quit it doesn't like good yeah I mean go
is surrender but but I must surrender
when you're completely out of stamina if
you're gonna do that never surrender
keep fighting until the good fight is
over look we got one person by the door
we got a dog back there we got they're
kind of scattered guy in good tail rock
break your toe yet Romans the luck let's
go all in on this come on
okay Co we're gonna go all in on this
Rob I'm not going home just shit later
you can't lead when you're dead by the
way I just gonna let you guys
Roman has yet to take damage or use
stamina in this event everyone else
basically at half health were almost
dead Roman is at full and he's the first
brother run fucking hell it makes sense
why his characters been alive for a long
time yeah he will like that's the other
thing Roman like yeah now that rage is
triggered the whole town is running it
here like I don't know that well you
heard the Bell being rung you know some
shits going down okay I can also see
what's happened in this room and he's
the writing's on the wall I'm not saying
it's gonna be great outside I'm just
saying you're gonna turn me to run for
it okay alright
interrupts what would you like to do
with your billing teleporting to do I'm
gonna teleport to right here so
basically he saw Roman making an eye for
authorities like I know fucking uh did
not again not on my talents yeah all
right and I'm gonna cast fog on myself
yeah they're trying to do is kind of
know how many things he's setting up the
escape plan okay seriously all right
well you start casting the fog and you
wanted to cast at the doorway but you
started casting this way yeah you kind
of misplaced it now the fog will move to
where you want but that was not a good
place for it initially if he cast it if
you wanted to encase this doorway and
smoke alright now it's back to Romans
turn okay alright so I'm gonna use my
move to
move me wide space on here as long as
you don't end a turn on them okay and
then I'm gonna use my necklace to get
outside good necklace
so the second you get outside here OOP
you're gonna see basically this else we
got we got these two and you grab and
you can see elves are coming at you from
all sides you still got an action
because you're crazy combo character
that can do 12 things the turn what do
you want to do okay now you guys know
that you guys can talk to the strategy
right you guys would be like hey how
about we do this you guys have this
lovely tendency to all do four different
things and it feels like if we're
talking like that's part of our action
like thinking character they probably
wouldn't be snow in screaming strategies
at each other I think Romans character
makes a lot of sense
KO's already on board with the trying to
escape plan
although Coast Guard must guard next for
you that's always but that's always been
a theme dude they've always used to as
disposable she'll take my word though by
shattering an arm-wrestling crystal
we're gonna drink we're at the pub push
that you guys didn't think that I was
not at all totally trying to trap Roman
inside here with the rest of us by me
know something that is totally what I
was doing I went down with I thought you
were right I wasn't bothered by it at
all I figure you knew how nimble I was
and it was just one of those things are
like yeah no problem we can get through
that yeah I believe I thought it was a
skate plan I thought a CO is setting up
to blow himself up no case Roman
side with us so you can leave see well
now he's probably the thing is Roman has
so many ex because he has that stupid
ring so he used to go move move move
move move as much as he wants it's an
image as well you know it's it's perfect
for his it's his character like why
would he carry this if he wasn't the
ultimate I'm just running when I went in
when I'm in real danger and he's like
and he went to this fight right and
everybody's getting their ass kicked
Philippe is about to die
justin is stuck in a corner and you're
at half stamina like you've yeah you
took your blunderbuss rigged it to be
some like makeshift Ring of Fire which
was pretty cool but this is not gonna be
enough so ah man you get that axe Roman
by the way you might want to borrow my
Ring of Fire sometime before this is all
over Oh pass back the rear fire yeah
mm-hmm ten spaces well see I'm trying to
aside how I want to play this out here
because I see that this is a shit
situation yeah well I can't freeze
anybody I can't shoot anybody
yuria fire is essentially the only thing
that I can do when you decide to jail
Ring of Fire is ten range does it stay
on the ground after I cast it no so the
ring of fire is as a make of Ring of
Fire
it shoots a big line of fire so think of
it like you you have that you have the
ability to breathe dragon fire by
holding up your hand
aiming it forward and going a big wave
you know like like Captain Planet sure
sure okay so but ill and we're outside
on grass so the grass would then be on
fire not not really nothing it's not
gonna catch anything a fire unless
you're really aiming for it no Melissa
burn this place down is that it's not
gonna make a trail fire now okay though
the trail of fire here if you're
fighting on hey yeah okay I'm writing in
a paper Factory but not just normal
normal grass
can I can I move or just I only have the
action you've already used to your move
and then your Ruby you just got the
action and shooting at ons means you
have to shoot through Co I don't think
does I don't think you have any good
plans yeah no I got nothing you got your
bow you can take a really long bow shot
and whoever you like from downtown in uh
let's do this I'm gonna borrow the Ring
of Fire I'm gonna shoot it back inside
the building just which way just like
straight forward straight back yeah
straight back for no reason you know is
the governess cape out the building
he'll hit Fenris
it's not a light things on fire though
it's just still scare people just to
scare people and singe the wolf okay do
you want to get the illusion that you're
running really fast that's good
Rovin ran so fast that he snatched the
ring man look I'm shooting it straight
back what if I get a 20 think of the
possibilities only cost three but you
you come yo mind it was a wait how much
does it does you take the damage as well
so it's inches the wolf the wolf takes
four one two three four and because of
what you were trying to do it actually
propels you one step further further
nice there you go
see already like one step closer to
being out of here guys yeah so close
psycho so you're so the fog is gonna
move Coco so I don't know what did you
want the fog to do do you wants to
actually cover your escape now or just
block the exit like what do you what was
well again I wanted the fog to confuse
Roman and hide him from bleeding okay so
they want the fog chasing after Rafi is
that wouldn't it hitting the fire that I
guess that was my intent my intent was
that it was trying to block Romans
I guess it would just sort of like this
direction
meanwhile I'm I've had it with
everything and I'm just gonna try to
shoot going into the fucking face with
the Dre no you're right upon her nuts
though I mean you can yeah I know that's
actually I gets like range nope nope
never mind yeah you you can hit her but
you're gonna gonna hit her for four okay
one two three four which I'm telling you
now is barely doing it dint like it just
it hits her and an ox or and moves her
back but the arrow bounced off her armor
is just she's a little more peeved at
you and if anything great all right
Felipe poor poor Philippe its death
throes man he's just he's got he's kind
of leaning on it looking towards Coe
well he's seen yeah he's like he's gonna
wanna he's gonna want to escape to now
because he won't go with Boston Coe so
he's gonna try and move get into the fog
that's hurting fuck I guess I get so far
the blunderbuss at her yeah the best
part is if 50v actually did that he
would have just pulled up only you guys
yeah coalition six damage from fifi mist
right yes what's the oh no no he's
inside the fog if you share the fire
from inside the fog you like it but just
the character perspective he did you see
Co try an attacker we have established
that when he sees go attack buddy boy
but we've established she's also not an
idiot
he's gay he's he's not made to be honest
more but like that's fine I'm just gonna
get clever to make it even further if I
use two moves you know you should try no
you're in the fog now yeah fucking try
to grab the key oh yeah you're in right
you're Jason
try and grab the key Oh of all times to
get a 27-piece come on come on
to rolls oh my god all right you you you
swipe to grab the key but you can't get
it man like this is right behind
Gwyneth's neck it's not that easy I'll
let you have another action though as
long as you're not trying to grab it you
can try a swing I'm gonna gonna biter
okay yeah I don't know maybe she'll die
eventually I mean you're in the fog too
is the thing 16 roll again come on 20
like I can't let you steal it off her
neck all right buddy you roll the one
when you're trying to bite you you're
gonna bite kono if you have if you get a
one on a kobold it just you know it
always fails why don't you three Co is
infected with rabies they go everybody
[Music]
you