[Music]
right
move these up move these away from now
all right so you've crossed the bridge
and you've come into a little bit of a
forest who's gonna who's gonna walk up
walk first around this corridor here who
Suzy who Justin Lee Justin Justin it was
just across first
so as Justin crosses the bridge uh whoop
Justin bumps into a beautiful girl the
zone whoa I think you'll whoa hey oh hey
there big boy you're a strong man what's
your name
it's our kobold number four that's a
really weird name there couple done
before you're a righty and strong though
I was just wondering have you seen my
brother bit necie uh yeah yeah I know
that guy oh that's okay I know this is
forward uh Cobalt but would you mind if
I gave you a little kiss yeah I guess
all right literally roll a die for this
kill weird are dice go you're the one
they could see everything oh it's off
the table here it's over touch nailed it
Justin I just want to say all right all
right
she gives him a little kiss and then she
just walks on by anyone she's walking
onto the bridge is it did anybody else
want to talk to her she's just walking
by you just gonna watch the gnome walk
by I have no interest in uh anybody have
any interest it's you just gonna sexy
Road wench okay
all right you guys can push forward then
all right it's all keep moving along
this pathway what kind of Aryan is like
a little forest path or you know I
thought I was pretty clear there Justin
what you know Messi doesn't have any
brothers or sisters I went on a real and
that kiss you got pickpocketed buddy
what oh my god what did you lose uh you
lost your Emmy little bones cuz you
traded that away and you know how to
spell word armor ah
but you just lost your blade turn whoa
oh man man got nerfed anyway but it's
okay duplicate cards underneath are you
guys trying to give me a reason fine
fuck me you feel like I've deleted this
bones like three times fine you just use
got pickpocketed by the other man Justin
just became useless crew I'm just he's
just you're useless treasures right
trade trade some treasure for kiss as
soon as you come across into the next as
you come out of this little forest you
see a big encampment filled with elves
oh no there's fire there's tents why are
you flipping things over room I'm gonna
do anything yeah you're if you if you're
in the fog of war oh if you can still
flip yeah they need that they tabletop
simulator need some more better fog
awards for stuff so you can see elves
all over none of them have noticed you
and the path that you guys know you need
to take is right around this corner
going down this bleeding hallway so but
it's up to you guys what you want to do
next Roman you're you're safe where you
are you could you could have a little
chat and sneaky eats it's a dark part of
the forest they're not going to see you
coming out but once you start moving
forward you're there's a chance that you
could start getting detected by these
guys okay Justin
Hey we're sleeping bleep oh but arias
okay everyone see I had to trade my
scarf oh okay
not sure that no you had a scarf that's
I was wait what do you you didn't even
notice that scarf my mom made me that
scarf I know all you Cabos look the same
to me I'm just gonna well we like eglee
scarves aren't kobold so that statement
doesn't even make sense
bleep place is gonna go wait over there
please he doesn't really like dead bones
right now because dead bones still looks
like a dwarf oh no he doesn't
you know I said this voice the second I
stepped in the boy said to Megan unknown
okay you just said I was just across the
bridge
yeah he just doesn't like you because
you're you that's nothing I mean that's
work that's understandable
yeah that could be fixed the power of
charm can it okay Hank
these are those spell elves that this
goes tell us about I don't have a gasp
ah what I can't guess dad really
surprise there they're the ones we're
supposed to get wet remember he said
that we're not supposed to fight them
but if we get them wet something will
happen
oh okay but we don't have any buckets
that's right they'll burn down well I
mean it's a shape maybe you might have
met in there all right no never
barking I gotta know yeah let the cop
the cobalt suit what what was your what
was your idea don't know nothing no no
come on share I was saying not what if
you met in like a like a like a
different way like like what kind of way
all right dude come on
just drop it no no no that you like
you're just confused by words I got an
idea boss boss I got an idea at what try
do you Felipe what if we use Colville's
helmet as a bucket but that's actually
not a bad idea that's pretty good idea
that's actually kind of wait what a
great idea man this this is why he's
Felipe your cobalt number four yeah this
is why he's in charge of you classes I'm
not okay with this we'll give it back
what good news
bad news I mean good news is you don't
have to be okay with it
bad news is give up your hat oh it's
just just so anything happen to it okay
oh yeah whatever but wait are we gonna
have to go back over the bridge to get
the water no there's like this other of
who signs up you know hope you
understand how this work but they it's
the guy in the elves are sneaky now
they're sneaky he's a British show it's
not a elf
no but the L maybe he's working for the
elves think about it okay hold on here's
the thing how do we get close enough to
these elves to they can water on them we
could walk there we can Walter to Pete
yeah feet during this conversation this
green one has walked over to this way
into the fog of war and you can't see
him hmm I think one just left you know
maybe we can just walk by now Nick
that's not a no Diego don't what I so I
was right what's the key right all right
is the key camera helmet back then no no
you just don't we might need it later
I mean I could carry it on my head okay
hold on you can have your helmet back
you have to carry your hands that was
just okay I was thinking well what's the
what's the plan boss what do you think
we should do I think we should walk by I
don't like okay come on what here boss
what if it was getting walking by oh
please talking to the boss are you run
by you want to write ah you mean you you
want to do the gym toss
oh yeah you bet your ass I want to just
run this bits let's do it
okay I'm just gonna watch so you're not
you're not gonna try to encode oh you're
gonna come hey you all have to really
Monday to wait all right fine I'll go
why are you wearing your hat okay all
right this if you're gonna make a run
for it these guys are gonna see you
right away
you're gonna give it weight but we're
gonna be you they're not occupied with
their sweet campfire and that's like a
really thick fire you know hang oh I
mean we can move really fast that bounce
yeah what's up I got another idea
does it involve me having to do
happening uh all right okay look you can
turn you can disguise yourself the stuff
you're really good at that
yeah I'm actually I'm really good at
that like that's oh and a few fates that
and that is he great to hear yeah yeah I
want you to change yourself into an elf
and distract him
uh I can't not really good at elves
they're kind of it's the height thing
it's weird
I get all this orientated as a vertigo
but I can I can try know that bones
you're not gonna try I'm gonna do got
the tube all right I'm gonna do see
we've had this talk many times do all
right
go you plant the way you're dead boughs
distracts them we book it alright to
distract them magic the sweet disguise
magic that is so stupid no no it's a
good idea mm why don't I just cast fog
which actually struck vision so we can
go by um okay
new idea totally unrelated to what
coaches said haha dead bones what if we
have Co cast fog huh it will restrict
vis
Asian and they spread throughout there
so we can just run right over I know
what that's that's a really you that
this is what you the boss this
experiment
yes yeah Jesus come to me it's insane
I'm just like uh idea boom and I don't
have to turn to an elf it's great
everybody wins all right go yeah so
we're gonna do we're going to do this
differently for this fog of war we're
gonna actually just tossed it all at
once
and I'm gonna try to make it like a
barrier to blocking the line of sight
okay okay roll it's a 20 hey ever
jiggets I love this game you'll be fog
like this for now so this is gonna be
the fog okay all the way over there and
it's just dead they can't write it it's
just the fog now however however you
should assume that even though they
haven't been alerted to you we're going
to treat this like combat has started
because they've seen the fog okay so
we're gonna have their turn right now
they've seen this fog and they're not
running at it but two of them are kind
of looking at it like where is fog
coming from because it's really unusual
for a fog to just roll in from a forest
you know if it came from this side it'd
be different but there's just a fog came
out of nowhere
and I mean there's dispel blades they're
all they're all aware of magic so we
should probably do the first line drop
so Roman it's your turn now all right
I'm gonna move forward and then move
into more forward okay when you run
around the corner now you're in combat
combat
all right okay ah so ii you runner just
run around the corner this guy this guy
seen him he has keys not done anything
to alert anyone only you really see him
right now
if
want you can tell the other well I don't
know how you tell the other guys without
alerting everyone else so you kind of
like stop and you turn the quarter
because you see him just kind of
blocking your path okay is he facing me
or is he facing away yeah no he's deaf
he's definitely facing you cuz of the
fog like he would've saw it in Richmond
like what's gonna walk make a sound
yeah makes it this sound was up
crackling fire I mean that would see my
coat make sense no it's like it's really
yeah it's like that
okay all right how are you okay uh
here's what we're gonna do um I'm gonna
go ahead and castrate a frost without
the jokes I'm trying to be sneaky okay
let's see rain frost um when using this
tech you may say a joke okay so yeah so
you're only doing a ray of frost okay
yes because my idea is just a stunning
okay all right smart give us a roll like
this right yeah it's hard to see ya all
uh like look if I can do so well because
we're not going to this side I can just
reveal this stuff for you yes well 17 or
6 that is 6 um so you catch your way of
frost you missed though so you go it
just it's a tree it was pretty silent
though there's no real noise but you've
missed the guy
all right Co it's you in Felipe's turn
ok also random chat concerns apparently
dead bones and I got to do stuff without
stamina loss we used we used dead bones
used his disguise no I haven't I haven't
used your fog already you correct for
dead bones but they only just as once
there's also no stamina loss at combat
right um there is when you're using
abilities like that especially if I
could lead into combat like god no hose
costs ability because it might lead into
combat if you wanted to toss
ever know yeah that would great all
right it's your turn right hmm well I
guess we don't really know what's going
on right so running that you're just
following Roman follow the leader
yeah basically okay Philips gonna follow
you then dead bones uh I'm gonna follow
Roman actually can I can I can I get the
gem from here
yeah I'm Jan and I once and you're gonna
do that wonder what's gonna happen is
you're gonna run up a hide room and see
what's happened and then enter combat
you can take an action okay I get taken
a case oh I can see it from there it's
like once you see him because he's kind
of a surprise factor you wouldn't run
around a corner cuz you just ran into
someone right okay uh I got nothing okay
just a pass yeah all right Justin you've
just playing follow leader here yeah
yeah for now okay so it's the elves turn
this elf
you know pulls out his little pocket
horn and just just calls for you guys
just just just blow wait can I interrupt
that with a oh yeah sure if you want to
blink yeah you surround out yeah so you
see him pulling out the horn you go to
you go to blink Boop
and I guess I want to try to grab the
horn grab the horn
yep go ahead oh man come on it's so
exciting
come on now um on it's good this could
be our ticket yep no I'll take it you
grab the horn out of them so you rip his
turn these guys don't really know so
they are now approaching the fog this
guy still sustained by the fire all
right Roman it's your turn okay um I'm
gonna move around of oh yeah oh oh as
you walk into the fire a sweet fire oh
sorry I'm sorry around the forest okay
Nate comes out bleeding
ripping in blood just wait what did you
do to these snakes you else live in this
forest man is this is natural habitat is
still blood wait so it's not bleeding it
just yeah no no it's naturally covered
in blood actually covered in blood
yeah that's what would make sense it's a
walk shouldn't be spreading because Rob
as Rob said earlier just came out all at
once yeah it was a different combo it
wasn't a combat dog he was trying to
like use it all at once
it shows spreading anymore he's
explosive he wanted a big wall sure yeah
okay all right I'm gonna try and attack
him with reiha frost akin okay uh and
I'm still gonna be quiet
wait no no I'm not no you're not gonna
be quite this time now I'm gonna tell
Jeff a joke yeah I think it was joke
the jokes yeah he's gotta tell the joke
he's got to say it loud enough
then when wait these are gonna hear
voices if you tell your joke oh okay not
telling the joke the whole point is to
be sneaky okay so ray of frosting the
dude come on babe money come on whoa ah
7g yeah all right you ready frost him in
the back he's frozen completely solid
just a big ice block yeah okay well done
uh dead bones and oh and I'm gonna move
over the further away but nothing is
code right Co is your tizzy interrupted
yeah mm-hmm ah now I have the sweet horn
oh my god do I have to roll to see if he
hears me say that no tell I was a good
oh my god all right I'm just gonna move
up right about here I guess okay
and I don't think I need to do anything
else right now who's Mike is getting a
buzz he has a really good very uh I
think if he goes kaatham feedback or
something um okay then dead bones it's
Oh Philippe is just gonna do the same
thing he knows you're trying to be
Enki so he's not going to try and Alert
anything he was here one two three four
five um you know I think Philippe is
gonna attack the snake but he's just
gonna try and snuff it out like just
step on he's just gonna step on it yeah
he's just gonna crush its head okay and
it's so close to be enough he he crushes
it but it goes it makes a loud
distinctive sound yeah I'm sure they're
used to hearing these things no no I
don't think it's it's not a horn being
blown all right
dad bones I'm gonna use a gem okay yours
double sprint here yeah I'm gonna get up
to in front of Roman actually one two
three so that's my move right cuz that's
the pass back oh well no that's just
that this to do that right is your mom
okay okay that's my turn to do that
would be his move and the Jim pass back
doesn't actually cost your action yeah
so you oh so I'll do an action but I
still got an action yeah what you would
do uh yeah you could try to charm the
frozen L no Barrett no I think I'm good
okay Justin all right out how far can I
move like I can move double if I dig it
yeah you can start it go double your
movement I think I'm gonna come up to
your next dead bones I'm just gonna get
past here okay um these two L's walk
into the fog
this guy's stunned um you guys are good
to go so your turn Roman alright what do
we see in front of us you see a really
really dark forest you don't see
anything in it but you can hear the
sound of tons and tons of solidity
snakes and there's just blood and guts
everywhere along the long long path
while you're looking you can just see
the shadows of snakes like going through
back and forth
I would be careful you don't want to
fight the elves in this so you need to
make sure they're not going to be
following you
is it my tour or prevent ahead from the
day when you romans turn it would be
vomiting yeah lands Romy only this L
only this elf knows you guys were here
and basically what happened is Co
teleported in snatched the horn Roman
what meanwhile Roman ran past them
turned around turned him into a block of
ice so he's not gonna defrost until all
you guys do another turn okay I have a
plan Robin
okay what's your plan a gas rolling fog
again basically I'll create a wall of
fog behind us so there there's the one
wall of fog and I guess the next fog
right on this guy and it's just gonna
surround him he's just could be all
fucked and then I could be able to get
past that right he's like a lady in the
Miss ya know uh what time of day is it
um it's a say it's like three or four
o'clock it's not dark it's pretty bright
light out sometime after dying so we
wouldn't have any torches or anything no
this is this is dark in here but only
because like the trees are kind of
casting a really big shade okay
and it's like lights not getting in but
you'd be able you're gonna be able to
see all through it you're not gonna be
blind in the dark alright um is there
any no that would be alright uh oh I
like your idea so here's what I'm gonna
do
let's try and buy us more time I'm gonna
go ahead and try and freeze this dude
again great I can't
don't yeah I'm trying to buy his time
okay hmm no joke no joke
yeah yeah okay alright uh you you can
hit him he says he's already still
stunned so even with a five I'll let you
hit him so he's now frozen again you've
just you've skis you're just like
alright keeping them stuck in that by a
block of ice and you're gonna walk into
the forest yes okay and then can I like
just be like hey guys we we need to get
out of here one SCO's fog goes down
mm-hmm eat a bougie he's working you can
be like fortune for just kind of trying
run through the stores yeah no that's
fun
okay all right what what is this role
for this is for the fog oh this is the
yeah yeah it's COEs turn now cast it
right on I'm good at my dog the sky it's
a pretty good fog okay so um we're gonna
make it you I so where you want
something just around him and it's just
gonna encompass all of this yeah it's
just gonna expand wanted to connect to
the other fog it's got me eventually I'm
gonna put into it yeah it can do that it
could just be one big fog and it just
all kind of seeps in together okay you
get a move to Co yeah all right yes your
move on move up to and I guess
Felipe's turn as well I mean thing to do
would be to move up oh yeah he's
following a leader that bones your turn
I'm just gonna pass back in Jim run
you're just gonna run ahead of everyone
I mean like that too far but now there's
a pass back if you take the gym and then
you run too far ahead of Roman he might
not be able to get it right you have to
be happy in that range ain't involved
it's a tent square where is the tents go
range so like that is to get nervous
needs to view yes yes oh that's so as
far like a far enough ahead but not like
- 1 2 3 4 5 then you're more than I be
able to move normally 3 4 5 this is as
far as you could go as that is perfect
we go yeah okay
ah just ripped ah I'm just following
along too I guess okay I'm not quite as
ambitious as dead bones would wait there
we go okay um all right so in this
forest
well I guess we're gonna do this because
Chado respond it
[Music]
hi Chad spawn the coab review at the end
of the forest is a giant Cobra who's
been alerted to your presence by
entering it he shoots a long-range
protect projectile all down hitting
everyone in its path or let's oh my god
what blood spit holy shit blood sweat
hits for three damage ok so he spawns
he's going to hit everyone luckily
you're all on a line so only dead bones
takes the brunt of this hit stop doing
it for you good one six three damage
mate armor in this forest you are going
to have how many snake spawn every turn
three snakes spawn throughout the hall
so you're gonna have one come out of you
another one come out of you and we'll
put one in front of that bones here oh
man oh my god
um this elf is lost in the fog let's see
if he can even possibly chase after oh
he doesn't he froze oh no he stand these
guys come into the fog and they're just
good like they're still not alerted they
have no idea they're not even going the
right way they're just like well what's
this is fog in fact let me do roll for
them what's that like also like slowing
fog no but they might walk out the wrong
way that's oh I'm gonna rule confusion
eight yeah this guy actually came out
this way he said he went thin and they
came out the exact same way yeah red red
guys kind of like what's going on
where's what you guys doing over here
but these you know you guys are about to
be home stretch clear from them and
we're just gonna let the fog come up
behind you and get you up guys I've
never actually seen you guys sneak past
anything but for we're just going to
you've managed to circumvent this
encounter so also Chad is saying I need
to take some stamina payment for the DNA
do that oh I think I did that for fog to
Cosette like half health well you're
only at your idiot twelve yeah you've
definitely spent your stamina doing it
EMCO cuz you did three three and yeah
yeah I wasn't sure yeah just yeah oh
yeah wow we did yeah to Fox in a blink
okay um
and like like I said like your Chad I'm
gonna I'm gonna miss things every now
and then I mean I'm not going to wrinkle
retro actively back every single time so
it's if I miss it then I miss it so
blood snakes sort of come out this
Bloods think it's going to attack dead
bones no where's that die ah he's gonna
hit dead bones for to know
and this blood stink is going to hit
Roman and that third boog snake is going
to hit no one Romans getting help or -
alright it is now Romans turn okay can I
see the king cobra oh yeah like the
second he came out he led a large roar
the elves heard him and that's just
gonna make it to the elves do not want
to go near here here you know anything
like the elves have no interest going
through is a death trap that's you know
I mean the the elves you have no
interest going this way through the
forest so you're not going to be
followed at this point that makes me
feel good yeah
alright here's will okay so we got sink
that coming out we don't know that
snakes are gonna keep spawning we just
know that some snakes happen to show up
do we hear like rustling or a little you
you don't know that snakes are coming
but you hear snakes rustling in these
things you know that they're snakes the
desert there's gonna be more sakes like
you're in a forest of snakes and now
you've realized that you're in some sort
of the the Cobra Kings den of snakes
like this is how tough do these snakes
look like Felipe was able to like stop
one outright yeah Felipe just stomped
went out and killed it
so okay um let's do this I'm gonna go
ahead I'm gonna move up uh I'm gonna
take my movement a group up here that
I'm gonna use my Ruby to move behind
dead bones yeah okay uh and then I'm
going to interrupt you as you walk past
the snake the snake latches on to you so
you can't pass him okay
I don't - yeah you were trying to run
you can still do an action but well I
was just a movement that wasn't a rut
yeah I know but but you you're you
you're not gonna be able to move anymore
this turn like he's now impeded you for
moving he's just he's living just like
like latched on to you just he's okay
yeah damage he's just ensnared you I'm
gonna rant for awesome
okay give me a roll with a joke with the
choke little snake I'm afraid my
condition has left me cold your pleas of
mercy okay that's a good one well I'll
take that one okay you blast the snake
and the snake dies excellent Justin yeah
oh yeah Justin all right beat up Ling
right Justin swings down his ex smashes
snake in the face all right I was at my
initial movement but so so that would
have been your movement and then you did
your action but then that one gives you
maybe it doesn't like it and try to use
that's okay and then also I'm trying to
show you actually is it yeah I'm gonna
use the try and shoot the snake a heaven
my dead bones yes okay double didn't
coming all right
Devils till three damage you hit Devon
to the ball yeah and it you hit him in
the back of the leg there's an edge to
the board down apparently yeah that's
where you're that sure was a all right
no no I see those bounce Oh No yeah I
wish there was an edge that'd be great
okay my tester I wish I could have a
little challenge yeah because it's yes
you're just gonna make me pick it up and
just gonna Wow I believe the testify
doesn't feel like there was a dead no we
totally felt like what a man of science
okay so that was Romans turn it is now
coastering alright
Acco Felipe looks terrified
right uh let's let's get the song he's
just a sheet full let's have it is your
turn to talk to Felipe we're just using
it that it uses a turn
let's want to find out why he's feeling
so bad I mean you're trying to run
through a force it's got to use
something if you want to actually have a
talk with him if you would if you like
he I told you he's scared but if you're
gonna actually like sit here and talk
with him it's gonna use your guys's turn
and if you're not running forward at
least in action you could talk while
moving ahead if you want
well fuck that let's get the fuck out so
I was gonna ask Felipe to maybe give me
a heel because I'm feeling pretty under
the weather
okay and then yeah so I guess we'll see
if he wants to do that
yeah nope Philippe II hear you loud and
clear okay and heels you're alive okay
that's not too bad one two three six
that costs alright three health to do
though Wow worth it totally worth notes
yeah oops maybe he's trying heal himself
next turn all right let me see what I've
got now healing himself is almost very
rarely good wash it because like if he
gets a ten a key only gets five we get
sealed for two like you have to roll
high rolling low you actually I do
stamina so it's almost never worth it so
much okay what can I do I can't really
do shit really although all the sleep
boss things have been killed so yeah
it's yeah you gotta run to kill the boss
snake you're in the wrong spot you don't
want to be where you are you want to be
with the bosses two three four with a
Korsak you uh move up to next Roman
right right there I guess and Ken can
Fleet Based I'll move up Felipe's
following you right behind you
cool all right kill the thing in front
at dead bones uh he doesn't have any uh
yeah actually his bow his bow would work
one two three four five Co has the
Dragon bow nice tree oh yeah well what
it was it but I don't know oh I still
have an action don't I yeah you did this
is just a movie
it has a range of five right what's that
anal dragon skin bow yeah damn bullshit
yeah
five of five range all right balls you
go home you go to shoot the bow and you
shoot Philippe it Philippe now has a
crippled leg oh I thought you're gonna
take it I and he's bleeding no no no
he's got a crippled leg and he's
bleeding Philippe will only be able to
move two spaces each term from here I
told ya
it's flea pea but I have a potion is
sleeping blood sink what it's bleeding
all right
it is now dead both stirred all right
poor Philippe uh so using it is using an
item comes to an action remove so you're
you're a gnome so you can use items as
your off okay okay you'll use it so
normally it's an action but because your
gnome I'm you it as okay so I'm gonna
chug a regrowth potion okay just do blue
blue blue let me go over here let's go
look at this
I really shouldn't walk these down you
guys told me that I progres today chose
the color lock so that's gonna be my
gonna regenerate one stamina as long as
ring combat yep
and I didn't approach you and your
stacks of no I had no I have two of them
yeah but you don't have that look at me
okay yeah yeah and then I'm gonna this
guy can detect ahead me right yeah
so let's say I'm gonna take a swipe with
my wart blade okay take a swipe take in
thus why cuz I can't do why I want to do
seventeen
all right you killed the snake and I
wants port forward five spaces but
diagonal two three four like not
diagonal yeah I don't want to be in the
line yet I don't be in light of spit
well again okay
no we can like you notice the spit and
going down any three lanes right yeah
but hoping it'll be like oh look those
guys look way tastier than that dude hmm
you're the waterfront
yeah it's always just gonna be dead
bones lane every time
they make sense though because dead ones
is the closest and I have a play I can
take the hit and I get a little stab
well so know it I I guess you will you
would understand it cuz you guys were I
said you're on the line it's it's
basically it's time so it's written so
he picks to wait lions and I see eyes
you have to be really spread or yeah you
know people and so it's basically
impossible to not have to look at hit
unless you're all in a row you
accidentally did the correct strategy or
did I or did you or gonna right now it
is just this turn all right uh I need to
indicator for chat to show that the
events been plated not for them so they
understand there's really nothing to do
is that move up at this visitor I'm
really you killed all this you have it
you can probably double mu if you want
yeah where was I was right here yeah you
were behind Roman yeah there you go see
could really move 10 isn't it I would
right next to you you can you can get up
next we can be giving you go through the
forest no I'm not gonna let you sprint
through ten with your action I'll let
you go seven alright not through this
thing it's like three bills I'll be
crazy that's fine as a way to my channel
alright that's your turn okay finally
why'd it have to be snakes way to go hey
so it's double Stefan
this is double snakes time so now snakes
fun come on you to this one
gonna get to make sure we have ones in
the way three and I should probably use
some snakes back here and that's one two
three four five
let's get Philippe all right kidding me
so dead bones you are being attacked by
one snake okay yeah you don't get it
so you are being attacked by one snake
up you get hit for two damage ah
Philippe you were being hit by a snake
Philippe Philippe actually grabs the
snake and uses it to kata rot like he's
at the - he wraps it around a leg so he
uses it to fix our ticket yes it has a
tourniquet Philippe may now move and
normal speed again that Killa sting yeah
well the snakes horse axles or is it
still alive sure what he did is he
stepped on the snake's head killed it
and then he just grabbed it and started
wrapping it around his leg uh he's
pretty badass about the snakes the
second one you stop somebody who didn't
want to go into this forest all right so
we're gonna blood bolt down the lane oh
whoa whoa whoa
kill oh sorry kill the snake Justin yeah
no you're spawning like 40 stings so
that's we're gonna get a little boy all
right Justin there's a 6-3 split-window
mentum killing the snake that's great
would it be like flung the stake at the
king yeah oh yeah I'm just saying that's
you know he just he did a little flip
and then he actually came up into range
Justin may now attack the snake in front
of dead bones oh hell yeah
oh okay that works too just injustice
feeling a little cocky after his quick
like little flip kill the snake he goes
and he's like I'm gonna show dead bones
and he swings the axe thinking that the
the snake is like not you know on the
ground but it's like a person boom hits
dead bones in the stomach for five
damage Oh dead limbs you also fall to
the ground you're on your ass groan huh
no you're wrong yeah you're just on your
ass so you ain't doing the whole sprinty
thing you're gonna have to get up start
running this thing is still alive - yeah
alright his blood full time he's gonna
Blood Bowl dead bones and Justin so here
comes dead bones snakes immune - uh
they're on the ground right so topic
wrapped it's like a projectile and
they're just on the ground dead bones
gets hit oh oh the Blood Bowl could Pat
mrs. Justin Roman also sees it coming he
ducks out of the way
and misses both you but devil takes to
damage and dead bones is not looking
good all right
it's Roman it's your turn oh man we got
this do you do you have it I like really
appreciate the help
okay I'm not saying I can't not gonna
help you but it's one of those I can't
get up there we got frigates take your
snakes I'll do with my snakes I mean
right um so the thing is dead bones you
kind of set the thing is you win ahead
of the group and set it all the thing is
they're gonna be stuck in the back just
like cutting through the snakes it's
okay I got my buddy Justin with me after
hit okay like mom all right I'm gonna
shoot the snake to my right okay with
very frost or shocker with ray of Frost
okay hey it's I gotta hear the joke
Roman guys I'm gonna remove the joke
after this week cuz it's just it's too
spammed to it
because yeah how do I use this that's
awesome Ellie yeah stay frosty
okay nice plastic oh oh I'll be getting
into the rule what off the table I don't
have any potions guys I don't have any
Devlin's has more potions on any
regeneration 20 I know they're good
telling me okay you you shoot an arrow
you split you see it goes right through
this snake and you can hear other snakes
die in the forest like you just shot it
I went right through the snake like in
his mouth popped up the back of his tail
and just went right to the forest and
you could succinctly hear just blasting
a bunch of other snakes with your arrow
Justin only gets one swing though okay
still let's snake I need make that not
work off a e really yeah you're wrong
swing just think it's wrecked okay um so
that I haven't done my movement so can I
move forward along this edge where you
know you can all right I'm gonna move up
as my movement and then I'm gonna use my
amulet to then move yep your Ruby
mindjustification
okay it's just for Philippe Co stuff in
the back you look for Philippe anymore
he's get us like fixer sorry yeah he's
pretty bad I forgot he killed a snake
with his voice the snake whisperer at
this point yeah really um I'm gonna let
the Philippe do whatever he thinks is
best and then I'll go hey Philippe loves
you yeah so he's gonna look he's gonna
run up and if he tries to run past the
snake he'd get grappled so he's just
gonna run up in again he's actually
gonna try and bite the snake never maybe
he's gonna give it's maybe gonna give it
uh he bites the snake it doesn't kill it
but the snake goes back into the forest
that's not awesome yeah well done
all right um I'm gonna we're gonna keep
making our way I'm going to try to
blunderbuss uh well I guess I don't need
to move up that far for that
blunderbusses snake and with a bias you
know in the direction of the forest okay
for any a OE effects
OOP oh it's a 10 so you hit the snake
boom okay I'll take that
okay so it is now that's a kill but just
that's nothing to swing at and on it um
dead bones turn mm-hmm yep those your
bone you're on your butt right now
yeah so my move is going to be standing
and moves gonna be standing up yeah I
could use my good I could use pass bag
yeah we can use the Ruby oh well I was
gonna ask is he like is thing just
taking up the entire he is that you
ain't you ain't thinking of trying to
walk there's no way to run past that
well he's he's snappy too like you can
see books slicked back and forth you
ain't gonna try to run past this guy
unless you want to Ian well you know
what I'm a risk-taker charm
it's a snake snake chart oh it's perfect
it's like you the bonus it's the one
time this should make sense
bonus selfie is up boom come on good
enough to charm Oh what selfies amazing
that's pretty good it's like three 3d
then you get regains one from your
health potion yeah that was kind of an
t-shirt I was so that wrist man a trimer
was he was starting to work cuz you know
snakes can be easily carried Dave so he
was liking it but it was not good enough
unfortunately guys I gotta do this just
like the little dance though I just need
Filipe to make me better
[Music]
you