[Music]
okay he licks the gem and nothing
happens a school can if it tastes good
yeah
so how was it never seems pretty
disappointing Michael I you know I've
been the gem I looking at for weeks and
I finally get to lick it and it's just
just pretty overall pretty the
supporting I'm sorry man
well at least there's all the regular
gems all over the walls and stuff for
you
yo Roman I think we need somebody to
appraise this big thing since Fleet
Based not gonna eat it hey was it salty
if it was it was a rocky tasted a little
bit like chicken but you know everything
kind of tastes like chicken so it wasn't
making me hungry you guys you guys want
to try and lick it it's not it's not bad
but I guess I don't eat Roxy I eat rock
so I kind of like the taste
hey Zed you looking rocks yeah I love
rocks yeah that's right rocks are great
you just put this down on this what did
you take place fine I mean I'm sorry
gobo number four yes go and tickle the
rock I want to lick it no tickle okay oh
man I think I'm gonna back up for this
one I'm gonna back up tickle on the rock
we bake all right I don't even do it
so you tickle the rock and you can heat
when you tickle it your mind like
connects with it like you can sense
something you can sense no no you're
gonna want to get off the screen for
this Justin you can sense something you
decide something emanating out of it out
of the crystal
that has started chat has awoken the gem
lord oh my god
[Music]
the gem lord has been awoken okay do I
have a Jim lortell you know I do but I'm
just an idiot I don't have it uploaded
use that it's a gem we do this you know
it's not as good though go get it I'm
good huh helmet has started uh because
Justin you roll the 20 um you're gonna
get the initiative even though the gym
was activated so uh oh man I don't have
my gym Lord tunnel huh
don't forget Justin's got rabies all
right sorry I have the initiative fever
sighs I'm not gonna rabies him on the
very first turn here though that's even
your olya tickly dude he's like way on a
tickle roll like we could use English we
can give him a break here oh man so I
get first move uh you get the first move
I'm just so quickly getting a this guy
into the thing for you I really hope you
do to to to to you yes where where is it
just dead possibly say to me thoughtful
that'll do Jonathan oh no idea I guess I
said if you're if you're tossing and
you're trying to like be friendly about
it then it's fine like you like if you
wanted to do it friendly to us you got
that oh okay I'm bringing the Jim Lord
in for you fuck you anything like oh oh
oh God
Wow alright uh so the gem wings also are
immediately aggressive as well but just
so yeah I've got the jim was awakened
key echoes he's like mom
that's the sound wait is he working Sam
is this inception yeah okay Justin what
do you want to do now I've got a
question
yep sorry let's say I attack this gym
mm-hmm and I blow it up
can I keep wait what oh you mean that's
disease
okay yeah go ahead it's Lisa we are at
the gems they have one damage or a
little generally yes
you could do it adjacent one but you you
have to do it immediately so you can't
then take a move so it's really only
good when things are surrounding you
gotcha gotcha like I can't just move
around the room being a badass busting
up gems um no no no okay okay you can't
move and do it it's like it's really
good with like combination with
whirlwind because whirlwind lets you
move and you could do one damage and I
just would it doesn't hit something else
all right well I'm gonna let's see if I
were here I'm gonna move here okay and
I'm gonna run a bus this gem oh yeah
take a swing are they even active oh
yeah you know there's everything is
active now everything's act okay alright
you blow up the gym alright can I reach
this one up here too uh no you only
mound range it's just an attack I like
so this would this is really also good
with range weapons like if you have a
range weapon then you gotta use your as
an attack thank you my god I should
change that in the future but yeah or
you know maybe you can hear it if Co
gave you a gun so you were holding on to
a gun that you could just blunderbuss
buzzer buzz bullet both buzzing turn
into a school a day well we're in combat
SoCo would after like use a pattern like
yeah at least a move like being next to
each other I'd let you have it okay but
now it is the gem Lords turn so the gem
Lord is going to use his diamond beam so
this is a piercing attack okay and it
goes in a line uh Jim Lord does not care
about anything he just zaps everything
and he's gonna shoot at Felipe and dead
bones ah oh fuck you are the worst good
thing I've got so much health uh gank
rogue four lives 15 oh that's not good
that's so much do uh it doesn't do a
little eBay it only does 4 damage Shh
thanks go just for damage that's it cool
thanks Co thirdly a what thank you yeah
ok uh the jailings are gonna come into
position jamming is a composition this
one moves over here something over here
sometimes over here food two three four
or five so we're just going to do a big
role for these are the roles against you
dead bones to see if you take three
damage from the little gem Ling's
you do sound finish and then here's one
for Justin what is that that is fun as
well listen takes one and because these
all right I got a pic which one I want
to activate like to me this one oh my
god I need to get a new token man I need
to get a new token for good old Jim Lord
here the gem Lord can now do a to melee
attacks each turn these melee attacks
are going to deal damage and knock-back
and he can use them as in addition to
his giant laser beam so oh my fuck what
hey my god this work today
Oh cuz I didn't upload it alright Roman
it is your turn though so you can start
thinking about what you want to do okay
this is look hi all right here's thing
dead bones are kind of crowded right now
don't worry I got a plan you do what you
got to do I got it I got a strategy you
got a strategy got it strategy do you
want to share
strategy no okay this is how we have
more talking to after this by the way
see I am my own gnome we're not your own
gnome
I'm my number two in his Stevie gook God
look at that thing it's so badass that's
why I change like an icebox I forgot to
make these so I could swap them out
easily last night that's what I was
saying like no we have to get the gym
suckas cuz he could have arms
alright I moved back one so I have a
clear line of shot of this gremlin um
I'm gonna rare frost them okay let's
hear this but wait Oh where's Gary
they've already given me all three
upgrades I get to like just cherry pick
which ones you see trick no it's not an
awesome cheap work the importance of Hut
all right Josh troyius hey Kremmling
you're on thin ice okay
eleven all right so he blows up Justin
you can do your Tristan alright
attacking this yeah take away 18 it
blows up you can take another role but
unless you want to hit ko there's
nothing to hit okay we're thanks Justin
Jerome's but it is now Roman Roman over
to your bow probably can do a bow oh
he's alright I want to shoot this
Kremmling over here okay
yep that's fine with my bow please don't
hit bleep look felipe's growing on me
okay thank you
good that you see he's got to heal him
he's on your best friend uh Felipe Stern
so Felipe plays for you for it's a pet
now I'll tell you what when we attend
your what you can do in cool okay so
you're gonna you're gonna be shooting
this you miss you hit Felipe oh three
damn you son of a bitch it was an
accident
see oopsie
okay it is now is that it Roman you're
doing a moves uh move let's see I moved
it you
done your crazy combo stuff uh let's see
after seeing that lion attack I do not
want to be in line with anyone Jim uh
you know what let me just let me move
back a little bit further
Roman flees the battle I'm not worried
in the battle but that call strategic
positioning Roman has abandoned the
combat you wanna see me about guys
combat but I'll be awesome I just hang
out and just you know look the wall like
you don't know hey I made us a sweet
friend and he did get you a healer Roman
yeah he did get us I didn't even know
that was gonna happen that's not even
something that's supposed to happen but
it's just like because it worked I was
like all right
and just I hope for the best it's
Felipe's like me it was in character for
Philippe okay so code is your turn so
Philippe has let me tell you what
Philippe you do so Philippe has 20 hit
points he's currently at 17 I you're not
always going to know Philippe exact
health Philippe can cast holy light and
you can do blessing of strength so holy
light is that heal and blessing of
strength is that one double damage
debuff I'll let you know that Lipe is
not very good at casting blessing of
strength so just don't don't use that
unless you really really want to he has
he has a wooden Club he swings for three
damage and you know he likes hugs hmm
okay so I have I have a thought I'm
wondering if um Ken H can I share things
with him
yeah like oh yeah right if you give my
things ya know if you give if you
upgrade his weapon or something like
that oh if you give him a bladder buzz
he'll shoot blunderbuss you can have him
do that
that's what I'm saying now also I almost
want him to just be controlled by you
like his decisions as well he'd say like
do this do that um okay
no that would I wanna do that will he no
that's fine I I was giving you pet
control but if you rather just me play
as Philippe then yeah I like him having
his own personality
kotas one who imposes himself on
Philippe yeah but yeah I want to call
the fleet and offer him a blunderbuss so
he can defend himself
okay Philippe will spend his turn
moving up accepting the blunderbuss and
if leaps going to play for yourself I'm
gonna have it so Philippe is always
trying to be helpful
and not hurt his alle hurt any of you
but at the same time he he cares about
Co way more than everyone else
yes sir basically if if you know if you
guys have a problem with Co you have a
problem with Philippe okay okay and
Philippe may take things too far their
life partners yeah
by the way Philippe I'm sorry I was
fully to ragging it you know Philippe
actually doesn't mind being called the
Philippe easy like that but but I
understand you being the leader that you
know and the neighbor Nathalie Baye
Kenton one more important question
mm-hmm can-can Philippe duel we all go
boys don't have dual wheel Co ever do
will call get drunk cause to be given
someone ablution he gave up a he gave me
so let's act if you just spend more time
hugging Coleman let's go grab your
blender place it here unlock paddles so
he's having that around this is now
Philippe has an inventory he bitches
only choice where's this blender blood
so you're doing it's his three range to
damage so Philippe is obviously just
gonna take the blunderbuss and shoot
these things so we're gonna roll he's
gonna try and kill both good job
Philippe come awfully back this shit
sixteen so bully big guy both boom boom
and then man and that was your move Co
but if you want to take an action Oh
Lillian yeah
dude we're gonna be legal undertones
Roger well I'm gonna I'm gonna try to
shoot this not okay right here yep go
ahead and roll see Justin if you were
next to the boss oh my god so many
attacks
missing them sixteen so boom that one
blows up it's three attacks II could hit
my boss just to you got away like a
coward Oh someone gave me a blunderbuss
haha okay it is now dead bones turn yeah
bones turn right I got an action and a
move and I can use my pass back as my
move right yes
okay for my action I'm gonna go look at
the gem Lord and use charm Oh Lord it's
excitement
okay go ahead and roll all right you
don't know man
yeah you I know I know it's a fine job I
know there's a 5% chance they disagree
hug him and he can hug you back let it
go fuck me is that what are you is it is
it a 2000 Lord I've already posted it I
post-op sex I said it you still think I
should told you the plan one two there's
nothing I can do now
now the faggot you know that they will
he's going to try and break free every
turn right yeah but I get to control one
he's getting a home on his turn yes okay
so I've still got my action I want to
use my action to turn to Rove an
illustration your action was term Oh
my move I want he's my move to just turn
drone to go you like bring your arms
like it down or motion across your
crotch all right man I'm just I'm
fucking you are out buddy oh my god damn
don't hit don't hit my new friend what's
up with who's up don't we hit uh same
guy oh he's a friend Justin you may not
really you may want to really consider a
really good selfie you may want to
really consider being in melee range
SPEA so Justin he's charmed but so dead
lensing the Controlman is turrent but
it's eventually going to break so you
really should use that as a form of
crowd control and start kicking his ass
yeah like that won't break the charm of
us are beating on them no okay all right
so what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna move
in
yep I'm moving here there you go
and I'm gonna bust up his little friend
first Oh cuz I heard that dice go up
here with that 20 the purpose of believe
I purposely did lead with the fog just
so you could see that it wasn't be
possible
I can I can kind of stop playing now
right I find it fit my pew you swing you
kill this you can have another turn to
swing at the gem Lord Jesus Christ
Oh Lord
alright guess that's it alright
it is the gem Lords turn and I see you
Jam Lords abilities you you know you
can't go far all you know is that Gemma
it's got these big muscly arms together
things and he's got that laser beam all
right uh Roman what should I do
I didn't expect this to work okay I
really don't know what I mean I got dead
bones do you think you can control the
gem lord I mean for like a turn or like
I'm gonna punch himself in the nuts nuts
have impressive punch punches at Jule's
have him grab his eyeballs that's good
hold on it's giving me the willies
oh yeah yeah good call charm sure what
do you want what do you want with you I
like okay a gentleman is going to punch
his own eyes with both of his hands at
once yeah Oh God does the event wait for
this by the way yes it does
just cuz Devlin's is control this
thirteen all right so he punches both of
his eyes he takes five damage I was a
sight is a sight impaired at all uh no
however
[Music]
if poop Shem bleats every time the gem
lien takes damage from now on to gem
links are going to spawn off him I have
been single time any turn hey any damage
they come off sorry cool since they
popped off of him are they charged no
yeah I know I've already made the Jim
Lord punch himself in the goddamn face
as you completely changed what I was
gonna do this turn
alright the gem Lord is going to try and
break free of the charm
this doesn't have to be hot come on come
on damn it you can have it you can have
another teryn gem gem is excite you
Jared uh Maya still mom's turn this
jumbling is gonna run up to CoStar dis
gem bling is going to stay far away from
fucking Justin one two one two three one
two three four I'll go there so this
one's going to hit ko or rather all the
ten wings are gonna try to attack this
one's hitting ko and misses alright fuck
me it is that wrong it's wrong like guys
nothing there is mad if only I used
charm at the start last time there's
been way too here oh okay so I see these
things pop off and it's like ha real
eyes open so I'm gonna move up and I'm
gonna be used my gem I want to move on
moving so far okay
yeah are you like me other Santa who's
good at summon more ah all right let's
uh ooh it's gonna be a little tight
close quarters here you know what I
believe I could do it to Justin's gonna
end up being the MVP in this fight uh
yeah I get a Tom and I got a good yeah
Oh actually move it here I'm gonna cast
enlarge on Justin
oh man okay oh god I so not so sure all
right Oh miss it's just just the fact of
the rain she's gonna get from this is
worth it oh my god maybe it's like
shriek him oh you've gotta be kidding me
yeah all right Jessica's about four
times the size he's the size of the gym
lord in this process Cheston crushes one
of the gem Ling's Justin you may have an
attack all right justice swings at the
gym Lord dealing five damage to more gem
ling spawn off him Oh God best a March
ever oh my god you guys are too lucky
all right code is your turn you want
sleeping on dirt roads
well Rose even though I'm gonna control
Felipe if there's ever something you
want Felipe to do you can always just
say it and I'll try calm and we're just
shouting blunder bros and co knows what
to do jumping on the blunderbuss and
fucking because he don't want a shot
which kills those things yeah do it do
it take a shot my friend all right he's
gonna shoot at these two in front of him
giving just an attack aramas maybe oh
geez - Justin Taylor rolls this ability
still gonna have to get nerfed
eventually I was not a roll house this
is you're on a roll
uh eight that's going to be a weak hit
and twelve that's gonna be hit so you're
gonna do a total of six damage all right
nice okay so it's your tray yep
Felipe attacked and then Felipe is also
gonna move over here yeah actually
that's crazy
Felipe because I'm thinking we've this
didn't move here but if it's actually
you're right Felipe needs to be in a
good position to shoot and I'm going to
shoot the JEM Lord wonder boss boom okay
boom so you get to hit this this is
going to be a good shot what does that
do that does three
this is going to do four one two three
four two more gems all right
Devlin's it is your turn can I use my
turn to tell him to do something - what
the gem ward
yeah but yeah - I'm gonna do the roll to
see if I can break out counter it yeah
all right so if you want to use your
whole turn to try and make him do so is
it that that would just be the action
hmm chat saying there's nothing that
would just be the action now that would
double turn to Jack probably waiting for
amplifying crystals but I've only had
two rounds of combat chat I'll leave you
one 1/4 hour well whatever I wasn't
going to use an amplifying crystal chat
knows what these abilities do okay I
wasn't buying crystals to tell you cuz
you don't even know they exist
yeah okay I'm saying because Justin hit
twice that there should be more gems or
something like that oh okay I know Chad
is right yeah every time he's doing it
okay one two three yellow Thank You Chad
so oh that okay where I was so would be
uh getting him to do something would
that be my action on my entire turn now
uh if you want to make the gym or do
anything that's your tire trick it's
usually you pissed on Heather
alright so we've been in this cave I've
seen these little gem bitches explode
right yeah but it's not like an
explosion it's like a poof of sparkle
but they say pop right yeah I'm gonna
just say gem self-destruct for it oh my
god oh fuck soul food
clunks alright uh the gem lord ignores
your suggestion he doesn't actually
understand what you mean so you're just
saying things that Jim Lordan you just
like bah just wrong
bassy should I should punch the eyeballs
if I if he blew up though magic gets
Oklahoma I wouldn't know face if that
was a 20 that would be right just enjoy
your turn it's my turn
yeah alright I don't Justin just sup uh
with your ability I'm going to restrict
it so you can't you can't roll it over
and over and over and over again because
of this exact encounter you have set it
create a situation we know I'll just
I'll just I know what
I'm just not gonna spawn them right in
front of you because I was just
realizing that you get to attack then
hit the boss and attacked the boss so
I'll just make sure I don't have
responded near you
does he have longer reach now that he's
bigger no well he does in the sense that
he's a three by three square so it just
sounds a tiny squares he's got whatever
you know could I could how many is that
like twenty squares of range around him
girl he eats up out of my room so I'm
gonna toss the gem Ward up into the air
yeah and like onto these oh yeah that's
fine yeah you guys are just gonna smoke
us you guys gonna smoke this is gonna be
like a one I mean this encounter is
supposed to be so much harder yeah would
you roll in ten all right to take your
three attacks barge that does damage so
two more spawn all right analytics five
okay you hit him two more spawn oh you
hit him two more spawn you get one more
oh oh
for this one you only slightly hit him
for one so you're gonna do a total of
eleven damage one two three four five
six seven eight nine ten eleven all
right uh it is now the gem Lords turn
gem Lord the love of God just give me
anything but a one he's gonna try and
break at a charm out of over one thank
God he's out of his fucking shop you're
not getting you're not getting control
of this fucking thing for another turn
guy yes that was it that was a very very
good turn for you guys I said amazing
idea Mike
all right the genoise now has spawned
three amplifying crystals he can control
them on his turn they can move up to ten
spaces the beam he shoots can now keep
shoots it at it and he can redirect it
through the crystals to be fair he moves
the crystals after he shoots the beam I
don't like where they're positioned
right now yes you sure because I rolled
a twenty well these are the Jim Owens
abilities anyway and I gotta take up for
I gotta make up for lost ground Justin
just did like 20 damage okay whatever
man this fucking target all right Jim
Lord try babe
but he's still under confusion of the
gym so he aims it this way towards the
lake and kills for gem Ling's
all right oh boy x4 Justin oh no no no
allies so jellies are moving into
position to attack oh fuck me
hey I'm not a huge fan of this right now
alright I'm gonna do one role for these
gem Ling's against Roman if so Ruben
takes two damage
Roman takes two damage one day damage 1
damage plate turn thank you then just in
one we're doing one role for your damage
it's a 16 you take 2 damage alright uh
then we have these two attacked Roman to
attack and ko4 to damage I'm on the
frontlines man oh you guys are just
gonna clean up the scanner all right
Roman it's your turn
all right how strong do these uh crystal
thingies that just appeared look uh so
there they're obviously they look more
durable than its gem bling but yeah you
can you can sue animage one swing items
for savage okay now remember they're
amplifying crystals and well actually
you don't even know never mind you don't
even know what they'd is the crystals
fell from the ground in the gym
it's randomly shot a beam at the lake so
you don't even know what item yeah I saw
a bunch of these little shit Birds just
kind of floating around out there
they're getting popped like Pez and then
these other things show up so clearly
these are something at least I shouldn't
even have said what they did I should
have rolled first I'm gonna get penile I
guess I bye bye revealing what they did
I've made a grave mistake
I mean was well as long as they were
different than the other ones then it
wouldn't matter he's already dead he did
the other things you would've assumed
they're so special yeah yeah alright uh
I'm gonna go I'm gonna rheya frost the
thing right below me a little amplifying
crystal stop giving me the cold shoulder
alright swear there you roll for Roman
but it doesn't matter it just doesn't
matter so you shoot this ray of Frost it
bounces from this crystal to this
crystal it bounces from this crystal to
this crystal it bounces from this
crystal to the gem Lord so dead bones
and Justin are stunned this turn from
your array of frost and they both take
what's rate of frost one damage or 300
your EF was stun oh yeah really stones I
didn't know that one - thanks Roman I
needed to get back in this fight but you
know I'm very fair that was a really
awesome shot I'm just saying the gem
Lord also takes two damage but he does
not get stunned yeah you know Justin
still proc whoa whoa hold on oh you
can't oh yes sorry Roman it's still your
turn okay
did it look like I damage the thing at
all you look like you damage the gem
Lord which reminds me like you're ruined
okay no does it look like you damaged it
with your spell that it went through it
and bounced off the other ones no
doesn't mean it can't be damaging up no
no it doesn't that's that's true but it
didn't look like you damaged it the
spell looked like you shot your spell at
it thinking like it would blast it and
instead like the crystal like absorbed
it and like propelled it through the
other amplifying gems okay
then I'm gonna try a physical attack
with my bow okay you're so like
point-blank you're just gonna shoot an
arrow into it
point-blank shoot an arrow on it if it
looks like it's only Magica it's
actually you know it resistant to then
let's give it a shot devils worst case
you get an arrow through the eye I mean
what we what's happening I was I was
actually don't take it to ya now that
Rose shutters think he's gonna try and
shoot an arrow that's yeah oh that's not
good work dead bones I'm sure it's only
spells that's not gonna work
yeah I'm good I mean how big is this
thing with this amplifying crystal yeah
it's size of a body it's like your size
yeah it's like oh he's a gnome size or
dwarf size uh it's human size like tall
Dwarfs it out big else is dirty is it
this thing looks like it's gonna weigh
like 400 500 pounds oh okay okay rock
itself all around realize I should have
asked that before but no chap would like
um me to remind you that Justin has
rabies Justin said rabies oh I'm sorry
that's right yeah but she be just the
Olympic no yes I'm not that's just a
minute of this Thank You Jett now his
rabies is four times as big rabies a lot
like herpes sometimes you know just
flares up for Justin its stamina cost is
huge
sometimes it's not that bad so by the
way you guys are not helping us it's
good then we gotta be there
we gotta take care of Chad - man yeah we
just had the gym board punch himself in
the eyeballs all about us all right -
bro not unless you get it I don't really
have anything else that I could do wait
wait uh no it's be class ability oh oh
wait I don't wanna do put this I didn't
no idea what's going worldwide up rights
on a roll and I've got lost
okay well what do I have I have a book
Oh use your book you're gonna use your
Bush else
obvious look all right give me the dice
you show me you in depth I'm gonna use
wait I don't have a book Oh OHS book to
use COEs book
yeah Mindy's coast book will something
happen this is the robot look look yeah
I'll just make something stupid so Roman
is using the book of pure spells go
ahead and roll me not worried all right
oh gosh we so used up all our luck so
excited no man did I feel it's coming
it's coming back around to our roll
power roll No
all right let's see what spell you get
the mess with divine intervention you
may force your role that's not supposed
to be there
oh well that's what the yeah it's a
spell but it's not supposed to be in
there spell book because it's not an act
yeah okay it can actually be used honor
chains
so this is the greatest honor chains
ever you can change target will not be
able to move until freeing themselves a
paladin may break the chains by
whispering the ancient word of honor
because you're not a paladin you
actually cannot do this yeah all right
be patient though we can't break it you
can drink it can you can cast it yeah
put it on all the channelings it's a
well it's so well I don't know what do
you want to do with it
then I'll tell you what happens tell me
where you're aiming to spill okay um how
high is the ceiling uh 20 foot high so
it's a big big open space the gym Lord
take Jim Lord and Justin are right now
like beefy bros like Jeff Lord has
lasers okay demon um all right well I
can't like shackle everything I could
only sell you three targets right uh
it's - its - you shackle something
something else yeah you check out
something something else so like if you
don't want the Jim Lord to move you'd
shackle them to the ground
you could shack onto a little guy but
that's just gonna make it so that you
through yeah I have an important
question takes damage this is a really
good one for a 20 if you if you shackled
the gem Lord of the ceiling is he high
enough up that any newly spawned gem
Ling's would be falling and so you is it
terminal velocity for this you can't
just fall to their death this one yes
let's a Fallot so the gem lord is kind
of floating in the sky already and the
gem wings
kind of have some sort of levitating
ability they're not touching the ground
um and while you could shackle him
you can't like fold like the shackle is
going to be as long as it needs to be to
connect to the two surfaces so it's only
really going to prevent him from moving
around you'd have to like have them
already up on the ceiling
then shackled right against it and then
the guys would spot off it but again
they kind of little floaty gems there
was a movie where we saw them float so
it's true so I'd we'd the first movie
you pull it out of the ground floated
out of the ground
so probably shadow it justice whatever
he takes damage for the rabies the thing
takes damage no that's a it doesn't do
that anymore it's not a life I don't
even know all that was so confusing so
now what you turn out with the shit out
of it well now it's just a part also we
can't break it so litter if we shackle
and adjusted we kill this thing just is
dragging the goddamn it says go around
I'm not sure if down arrows a movement
we don't know that it will blow away
dead
alright here's a thing we've been
putting a beatin on this thing we're
gonna finish it off so let's not we're
gonna shackle it and run
well you gotta use your shack on
something I understand that cuz I don't
do any damage I'll get on a hint Roman
there's something else that moves around
the room that you could shackle so it
stops moving
you could shackle these because these
are able to move each round I don't know
why I'm helping you but I just feel like
because I'm actually cuz this is it's a
20 it's a 20s like right should be in
fact many on a shitty spell like he has
the power to move these to make it so he
can hit as many people as possible
and if you shackle them then they can't
move around yeah the fact that it
doesn't do any damage we can't really
and Jacqueline him doesn't help us all
right so I'll shackle this one to this
one you want to share together
okay shackle them together god damnit
Roman okay so it's the most perfect
shackle anyone's ever seen Felipe you
know he tips his eyepatch at you feel it
raises his eyes and to the wigs he's
like that's a good that's a good auto
chain tyrosine one your natural talent
throw your natural palette uh needs me
alright oh I just not realize what I
should have done Co you shouldn't have
shackled them together um Co it's your
turn yeah alright let's move the
blunderbuss over here
um you can't really run that vet too far
well yeah you need like a path to go and
right now you got two big bruisers and
you're kind of surrounded like you can
maybe shimmy through but you're not
gonna be able to go all the way around
you're kind of stuck here
okay well let's I'm gonna I want to move
to the front of the gem Lord okay and
you know Felipe still welcome to duty
once but my game plan is we're gonna
unleash the blender the blender uh party
on the gym Lord again okay now are we
now if he shoots the gem lord let then
fall off on anything around him uh so Co
could aim like here whoopsie
coca clang for you no coking for this
I'm ready darkness one I think the best
shot like I hear be able to kill so he's
okay I'll kill this one then again
trying like Felipe could do that so I'm
just gonna sleep II take the best shot I
can okay go ahead and hit Felipe go and
then oh alright
I mean well then that sense the best
shot Felipe can do is three so Philippe
is gonna try to shoot at those three
thank god Justin stunned right nice boom
boom boom boom oh yeah forgot about that
stun alright Oh doll and hello shoot
Justin in the toe Justin takes one
damage I mean he's change is time you
just you just shoot your blunderbuss and
you kind of like lose control of it and
just clip yes poor little stunt Justin's
like frozen in ice right now just like
actually no you shot Justin these frozen
four mice Justin you're unfrozen yes oh
that's strategy co-venture yeah that's
what I meant to do strategy I thought
you weren't helping us teamwork makes
the dream work
Oh makes it like I mean I had the ray of
frost freeze these two and these frozen
a little like ice and you should have
blunderbuss out of it shatters it so
yeah Justin's okay from that make sense
alright Devlin's it's your turn your
stunt you can roll and if you roll a
particular role I thought it was just
gonna skip me no
in action all right you get your full
turn go nuts full turn okay go
pass me the dog okay there it is right
Roland I guess you're feeling lucky I'm
feeling lucky man no no all right all
right here we go you're gonna be casting
earthquake yeah um so this is six
squares in a ten-block radius okay I
want all the damage these square if you
pick a target so over here Wow
you know over here no it's it they're
squares other squares you pick squares
yeah and they tow it tiles and if
they're on it they have doughnuts you
basically dammit you can kill six things
so well just six Jim Ling's
just entering yeah so I'm gonna hit that
one over here yep that one yeah
this amplified crystal next to me yeah
and what is it ten range ten yeah but
when I put one under the gym okay you
know you never know do some damage want
some more then you kill more just need
to mark two combo one two three all
right just do just do three roles for me
Justin it's a you know it's Bartek look
all right you just Nick him all right I
just you feel get a full hit there all
right I just believe in you and you're
gonna get another Nick so you're only
gonna do seven damage on two three four
five so the second six that was just my
move cuz that was passed back yeah i
know-oh-oh Jack that is the chat is
pointing out that the gym links are
floating Oh Jim Lords floating the
general the gym of the gently but this
it's a sea propel Jim Harrison if you
select a square with a target on it the
turtle takes YouTube damage so we think
earthquakes like hurt the Earth's like
shattering so it's like a vibration yes
well no it's Earth coming out it's a
legend of avatar rock just shattering
pending is these gem things like explode
when you touch him basically so
oh just earth will smash these things
you know probably maybe you know the
seal at the least it made some Souls
fall off yeah yeah I'm just like you
know what I got a better I got a really
good idea and I'm gonna use my gem
catalyst you so will how much Oh first
off also your other earthquake you can
fit earthquake into two gem things yeah
uh so you amplified it so you've caused
like an earthquake between all four of
you again so I don't know why you guys
keep casting spells into this I don't
know what's more obviously it's fine
let's let's take a hobo this is terrible
it's fine
okay so Devils takes to damage cuz he's
got hit by the earthquake space he
caused too bad that's all right actually
I don't need to put that there put
through there boom I miss this and then
there's Felipe takes two damage so I'll
do that and then Jim's blow up no am I
gonna it's the it's the beam no you're
cuz it's in between the crystals like I
typically try to make a triangle because
the idea we're going here with and then
Justin you also took to damage all right
now is the highlands it's gonna fall
into the ocean like California think of
it think of it like as rocky terrain but
like if you were standing on that rocky
terrain at the time you took damage
would be the way I'm kind of mentally
going I think of it like rocky for yeah
rocky rocky crystals Russia yeah yeah
pretty much
alright what else you do I'm also I'm
gonna fight fire with fire so I'm going
to use my gem catalyst to summon ten
gems where is that like man I wish I
also you to use it I don't have any
abilities to help this uh I just decided
I'm sure this is helping well it's
totally helping actually it's gonna help
a lot yeah this is the attack so it's
gonna get us it's gonna get a lot of
attacks alright so these are all gonna
pop out of you okay okay and that's
right
yeah you just used to so it's like
imagine you hold this crystal and you
like squeezed it and then this happened
and one two three four five six seven
eight nine
here you go Justin Tess I popped it all
out of here it's really crowded so go I
want you to turn around and shoot me
[Music]