[Music]
right sorry
oh no yeah I'm gonna walk up I don't
know you can't really hit it in the face
of it always keeps its mouth open like
that he get in the mouth he's pretty
hard to hit right now well do you want
to give you two choices you can swing at
the body easier to hit or you can swing
at the head you swing your head you're
gonna do a lot more damage and either
way I could use an ability after this
right yeah okay some body your head yeah
I'm gonna go for that I'm feeling I'm
feeling good
don't hit it right in the Fang like my
sneaking just decapitated you swinging a
snake Justin but you miss you wear it
and I'm gonna throw up a blockade oh you
were you wait how to do the swing then
that was your action I thought I could
use a ability a kid not how can you use
abilities well you're like you don't
remember Roman uses ray of frost to do
attack and ability you so you so the
game works you have a move and you have
an action and actions are abilities okay
oh I see that's what I was asking before
oh I'm sorry if you would like I will
just let you blockade and we'll pretend
you didn't swing yeah that's that's
that's fine I mean you can have your
blockades it's pretty much better since
you you kind of had a plan there and I I
didn't really realize what you're doing
so I'm gonna take your stand the cost
for it and I'm gonna take a little extra
because you made me cheat the game but
you have can block okay it is now the
snakes turns then okay so let's have
some snake spawn you're scaring mama
snake so they're coming out above it
just in sleep a and COEs got some
problems and one for dead bones one
Roman I'm pretty sure they're afraid of
me after my impressive display Thanks
maybe I mean these this will hold on my
lift height is way too low this is for
the snakes attacking Justin Johnny it
takes one damage instead of four
this snake is attacking Roman Roman
doesn't even take damage this snake is
attacking dead bones this snake does one
damage the dead bones and then we have
one attacking KO and we'll just count us
Coen Philippe I rolled because it was
shitty not because of the number all
right a snake goes to jump at Ko and
Philippe just jumps in the way of it and
just like swatting it into the forest
just and this by doing this this snake
kind of got scared and he just ran away
he's just gone did it kill the other
sank
no there was no that well this note
there's no death okay can I just be free
based pet that's just his job alright
and then we have the blood bolt so he's
gonna shoot one bullet that blood bolt
actually should I just attack you do the
tail swipe he's gonna tell swipe Justin
but it's car could've do anything oh god
it's like back to back ones alright he
swipes the tail Justin grabs it
interrupting the rest of his turn
Justin you're now holding onto the back
of the giant you were set up
toss oh my god your turn Romek you kill
two snakes
all right again
yeah all right I'm gonna tack the snake
to the right of me with Freya Frost okay
we're waiting under joke yeah we are
Roman he's running out yeah I know Roman
this is the last time you have to do a
joke from now on all right because I'm
gonna be ready just say chill from now
on to count as it yeah you can just sit
you repeat the same one you can just
just just say freeze chill yeah whoo
laughs just as long as you remember if
you forget then we'll penalize you okay
but you don't have time for you to go to
the cooler I like that one yeah all
right 15 all right so that snake dies
Justin you take a free swing now Justin
you're good so hold on before you take
your swing you were holding this guy in
your hand so if you swing at these if
you swing at these two good like you
have them in your hand so just do this
free swing you kind of have to think
about it because you're swinging with
the snake oh wow your hands are can I
like so tonight is the snake so big that
I can't like just swing him around in a
circle sure he's heavy but you could try
yeah sure I'm gonna give it a shot let
you do that for this oh man impressive
like the other adoption would have been
like 10 up the snake is way too heavy so
you let me enlarge you try to you try to
swing one of these little things and you
just miss all right all right I'm gonna
then use my bow and I'm gonna shoot the
snake to be right actually hold on no no
I'm gonna move forward two squares I'm
gonna shoot the snake in front of that
bones yes just like you're pulling your
bow up aimed at the ground right in
front of you to shoot the snake and you
miss and the arrow just doesn't hit me
no no he just misses it's like cuz he's
cuz it's a snake like on the ground so
hard to shoot I know well yeah Roman
standing right in front of it and you
like he's pointing his bow at the ground
right to the crowd oh all right
Co you and Philippe back here but pages
I can't kill him he's just a god mode
kobold right now yeah well he sees the
boss whatever he thinks we should do all
right welcome plays just gonna gonna
head one two three four five wait for me
boss how's Philippe not just like
running through the jungle like a few
guys I'm gonna kill snakes
you got the blood list all right
something else you can do Co um I can't
really oh yeah I guess you could do that
I'm gonna keep in mind that Philippe
uses his health to heal and I'm Philippe
isn't in the position himself where he
would want to use his health to heal
yeah but I'm a real person he's nothing
not really
Oh see you're a dick get out of here not
not to Philippe though like he's not
gonna do it so so I don't think they can
do anything
Coco is a ranged attacker oh wait one
hold on one so three actually Philippe
cashews blunderbuss now that I think
about it that's right
I mean it's not a safe shot ko do you
think Philippe would care or do you
think he'd still you think he's aiming
he's DEA me he's gonna aim up here to
try and hit this four by this 2x2 space
to hit this force base was I able to
move up like I spied him like this sure
okay I don't think stew up Wonder Broz
blunderbuss special attack and neither
should feel Philippe
but Philippe is really confident right
now okay oh yeah we see what he can do
fucking like I don't know do you think
he do you think he still has the
confidence to keep going or is this just
look at that tourniquet fuck yeah steady
and
now a shooting at boss but he wouldn't
shoot at the boss there's no way if it
was like dead was adjusted maybe but
he's not gonna shoot at the boss like
this boss get it okay wait what's
happening I we were deciding if Philippe
would shoot the blunderbuss like this
basically not caring about you co can
still shoot his bow you throw me why are
you pushing that because I have
confidence in co ok come on co yeah
we're it Dragon Skin bow go you have a
single hitpoint before I go yeah wait no
my turn sex I'll have to know know why
cuz kosher through you
Philippe thinks it's okay so he's gonna
try to blunderbuss the snake after
koumei okay I want you to remember dead
bones that you asked I did look that Co
I put my faith in you and I we please
just the fucking boss though kills the
snake blasts with some sticks in the
forest just then you could take your
free turn you never watch the visible
snake that was killed Philippe for MVP
right do what it's like ever co when
when I'm playing the role for you guys
good numbers when I play myself one all
right let's uh I'm gonna attack the
snake Tamela okay okay alright go at the
boss Justice feel a little too confident
now all right uh you Swift and you miss
this miss the big guy alright alright
dead bones
and you'd healed for one yes no that was
that's not even your turn that was
[Music]
alright alright I need to let make it so
you're free racial doesn't chain like
that we see behind us snake no not
really
and even if you could well I guess you
you haven't really tried to look I know
I know there's ground behind him you can
see an opening and if you could get past
him
it's a clearing so you'd be fine like
the snake isn't probably so I see
another table in the distance I'm gonna
move up you have I'm going to hit him
with my warp blade No ah crafty till you
roll a one that's a miss but I could
stab you miss but you can link but
you're gonna I'm gonna want you to roll
for this blink I want to be blank for
you just you just swung and miss and
then think you're blinking off it until
we go with the next table and there's
like elves everywhere I'm dead fucking
arrows so now it is Justin's turn
alright
good old helpful dead boss dude I'm a
lover not a fighter
swings the charm right
alright should I I guess I just take a
swing at him right yeah alright taking a
swing at the head alright you swing and
you just we do like a little 360 and you
fall on your butt so now you're on the
ground you just did a little 360 with
your blade and you just whiffed
completely yeah you're now but
completely on the ground easy target for
him
you're you can't really move without
getting up just this is blockade still
up
no because they only last one turn so oh
alright that's it so now we're take time
so can have the snakes come out one two
three four five all right these two
snakes
Hiddink oh cool
hit me oh god they're hitting gallons
yeah three for once take you home
this guy Philippe Philippe dodges out of
the way of course one nating Roman Roman
takes to one hitting Justin oh and
there's blood Bowl time it's just by the
way chat asks why not six wasn't that
six one two three and four five oh yeah
it's right chat yeah I'd hate giving
Justin free snakes but I love really a
choice by the way chat fuck you every
Kazi snake to show up for the first
place like whoa whoa
enough of the dick things that were
doing to you guys you're missing one
yeah after this well we'll take a we'll
take a little bit of a break and then we
can go on to the next Baptist to do a
like one more good encounter or
something all right yeah let's see so
that was all the snakes so we have blood
bolt one's gonna hit Justin should be
really easy to hit just in the face all
right Oh takes four one two three four
to do to say how much I wrote for this
yeah oops I think I decided just click
somebody by accident did damage to him
it was no other blood Bowl comes down
the lane for co cuz he does too so co
takes 4 1 2 3 4 and then he's gonna tail
swipe Justin Justin for 3 1 2 3 all
right
it is now Romans turn ok how does the
kingsnake look tired or weaker I see
just going to count really even done a
lot of damage to the snake I think
Justin hit like twice doesn't see them
like once is it once a time yeah
no Justin's had a bunch of turns of
whiffs and yeah so my 20 was a lot a
little snake yeah 20 was not a little
snake and then I did something else for
it so apparently I had two HP you took
one off me even though I wasn't there
oh you did you did one damage to all of
us by accident
oh yeah that was yeah and all the guys
are taking damage from fatigue okay so
we still got the snake in front of us
hmmm I think we still gotta clear before
we can I mean Devils has proved you can
get through him with magic that's not
like a tactic that all of us can do
don't get any ideas now I don't want to
leave Felipe hanging why is even carry
him with you I don't care I doubt that
works you get some lights tickets right
Felipe you try and you can alright which
one if you want alright let's uh I'm
gonna tack this snake behind me okay
with ray of frost
I'm just gonna tell a snake chill out
damn it Roman you miss you hit Felipe
who is very annoyed that you did that's
the second time Roman so I stick with my
bow shot no cuz you failed damn it no
you can move still but I don't know
whether you really yeah I got nowhere to
go I'm just going to hang out here oh
alright so now it is crafter entropolis
can are we able to move up at all or we
like blocked in here
I think Felipe can move yeah fleepy can
move these things stop you from trying
to run by oh right so Felipe Felipe's
not really gonna move his reaction is
gonna be just to start clearing these
things out so alright I'm gonna let him
do his thing and I'll go
Felipe's gonna shuffle over one and he's
gonna blast some snakes right in front
of them no believe a blunderbuss but he
just whips and shoots a too far forward
hitting nothing oops this is looking bad
this is looking really bad so your turn
ko look really good with dead bones
what's going with the charm plan that
only somebody could like sneak back in
and charm from behind yeah but if only
someone had you know enough stamina to
do with three stamina spell well maybe
that's good ocean out there I only have
one alright I have six fucking stamina
I'm going to try to blink directly
behind the snake I'm not leaving one two
three but I got to get away from six
seven ten it's actually net you can you
can do it but I'm going directly behind
the snake you actually wants to be still
out of play Oh buddy you can blink and
you can take a turn you can still do a
turn here
so you have you technically have two
turns
because blink is an interrupt so you
have to act all right okay
can I take two blunderbuss shots at the
kingsnake yep
okay here's why so that they would call
waiting it's not a good role yeah he'd
take him so he won't miss so he can
blast this way he can blast this snake
and hit him for two damage hold on
Justin can roll because just in Kentucky
I'm sorry yeah go ahead
all right do you want me to hit the
blunderbusses three I'm gonna hit the
little guys next to me okay
thank you it's a little guy am i right
eight you miss no so let's go
you have another shot and a move
technically because it's a full turn
I love has no role for OA nother
blunderbuss shot yeah at the king snake
so you hit the snake you hear something
rattle in the forest get exploded and
you hit the king snake for three one two
three four five six total okay then it
is whose turn it would be me but I'm a
Ford curled up in a tiny little gnome
ball alright so so I can't attack and
then blockade right straight-up blockade
right now yeah you I mean you have the
most health really don't you yeah I
would be mainly doing it to try to
protect what comes not behind me but it
would really have well remember that
move that I didn't actually do and I I'm
gonna play it safe gonna throw a
blockade guess well hold on hold on um I
mean Oh anyone directly behind you okay
yeah this thing is pretty burnt up from
those blender busts but yeah it's that's
a good term for plunger busts oh man you
know what people get to approve those
terms when they're actually fighting
with this I mean
with this I said it's a good one still a
snake if Justin gets one good swing at
the head he could just kill it
yeah I'll do that it's up to you if you
want to block it if you want to play it
safe because you're right yeah if you
play it safe
basically the he he's not gonna be able
to blood bolt and it's gonna make you
immune to cleave and you guys can really
tell this forest is running out of
snakes so yeah also you need to hurt me
for for my use of blank I already did
you need to stop listening to chat no no
I remember I was at six beforehand but
are you sure no you were at nine cuz the
second you say you're blinking I've
already gone and clicked it now right
yeah bad I've nobody want to argue with
you and if I didn't do it I think I did
so I'm not gonna do it well what do you
guys behind me think go Roman what are
you gonna do what do you always like
blockade or hit the snake yep block
eight or try to kill it
fucking I say kill the snake man try
fail it all right going for it
let's go it alright for his head we need
to get out of this forest 120 come on
baby big money that's pretty good you
swing at the snake you cut off his head
literally to health free yeah the other
snakes escaping through the forest and
you guys all just jauntily run through
to catch up the dead bones oh thank fuck
that was a tough one
no kiddin like it was such a good start
that was a hard good it could have been
so much worse look how many snake tiles
there still are a lot of snakes out yeah
well you guys kind of got into the
forest and your plan was already start
running through it because the whole
idea is you might have just like peeked
in and then it started but you guys kind
of got a jump on it cuz the whole idea
was it's a gauntlet the guys guarding
you from the end you just really have
the power of the Ruby oh man quick can
you run through the spell no we're not
running through the forth
[Music]
keep going don't stop so now I want to
make sure that we can actually do an
ending tonight so we're gonna have it so
the place you come into the forest was a
shortcut and it was right into the back
of the elf town that's why they were
guarding it well the thing is you you
came in here to rest you would you were
here a while ago so you came to the cave
here like I was there's a curled up in a
ball just saw this nice place
so now this this is clearly the town
that Miss 'van had told you you need to
come to and explore or to find the key
so yes so yes you guys should meet up
with dead bones again right take us take
a breather because everybody's probably
I mean Felipe is bleeding out of his leg
you know can we dead bones yeah hey oh
look who it is
hey mister arm is gonna run from fights
hey man I don't get paid to fight
I get paid to steal shit what thieves
being dead he was kind of bleeding out
of his everywhere you've forgotten that
we're thieves man I'm not a killer I
don't kill people boss
so I cure his wound so you want them to
stay wounded oh maybe not rest yeah you
should probably not yet yeah that's what
I did oh yeah you're all better look at
that
permission to bite dead bones boss it's
up to dead ones oh you're better ask him
you know you're the boss now
hey you know you're my friend this is
boss hey boss
can I come up there bones I'll tell you
what uh you can bite dead bones but not
just yet okay
good like that but don't worry you're
gonna be able to take a nice little bite
and
that's good you really impressed me back
there bleep a Filippo is kind of a
badass uh Justin please take your hat
off you have not been received
permission take your hat off
take it off take it off all right there
we go
silly Justin yeah you really impressed
me back there you put your hat back on
yeah so my boss why are you guys
actually at the South town you guys
haven't actually told me anything
what are we doing okay can i well it
will I tell him okay Felipe we're
thieves so what do thieves do I don't
know why you guys think I'm an idiot I
proven that I'm very capable no no they
don't think you're an idiot
I just you know you're cobbled I'm
trusty Barry my look at this way I'm
just gonna pretend he's not there all
right I totally understand that's what I
do too I like you friend and gold bulls
all right give me a hug okay I'm hugging
and while that was hugging Felipe tried
to nibble on your shoulder that's fine I
don't even wanna Felipe you never get
the rules when I need them all right
Felipe fill you in
uh we're a thieving guild of course
that's what we do so we take things as
you obviously know what thieves do we
had a task from this wizard who it's
like hey we need this key and he's gonna
give us reward uh you've been such a
good member we would you know like to
have you join us and we would of course
provide a cut of the reward all right
cool so basically you can consider
yourself kobold number one now and I get
my name I got a title and my name this
bleep a kobold number one how long I was
a kobold for those other guys and
do anything man I'm just going up the
ranks adventuring days man is kobold
number four my name or my title it's
both that's not important bolos yeah so
is my name kobold kobold number four no
it's just Cold War no it's Cobalt number
for first name cobalt middle name number
third last name okay so I'm really just
go before he's happy about it just let
him be
yeah okay so we need to find this key
the key is uh it's gold that bugs what
oh hey York what the hell huh yeah what
yeah guess what I snuck around you
because I'm a thief you're pretty good I
admit okay anyway what's up what's up
boss snakes freaked me out right there
we pay here little snake think badass
yeah is he so learning that Kurt
tourniquet
hey okay does anybody remember what that
key supposed to look like yes number two
you need to go over there I'm not ready
for that position I remember what the
key looks like excellent it looks like a
key okay so it's a key so it's not like
an abstract kind of key it's not like a
token it's a key and it's blue I thought
he said it was tang yeah absolutely a
color that's well it might be it might
be a key made out of tea if you say tan
colored everyone's gonna know what
you're talking about yeah exactly
just wait if if it's made out of Tang
and we put water on it can we drink it
they never said we couldn't do that so
all right say that's on the table that's
kind of our thing all right dead bones
you've been over here for a while
not helping us fight the snake be able
to kind of scout around
no I just sounds like a dice roll the
answer okay roll you don't find anything
out sort of dead bones knows that the
best location for the key is obviously
this churchy look at building over here
the one with all the fancy designs he
knows that there are elves all over the
town lots of guards let lots of spell
blades yeah let's
okay so elves you know it's um it's a
little bit impressive is you guys
actually have not alerted elves at all
and it's sneaky I I kind of well I have
this plane like the elves are pretty
much supposed to kind of know you're
coming but they have no idea so there's
no even like I'm not even doing the
Patrol stuff right now this is just
there's elves in the city but you guys
kind of have accent and the thieving
part of this yes to where the keys I can
I think I know where it is also the
voice of the sky said we can really can
speak in a voiceless guy I totally heard
it yeah so are you mean I don't okay
here's the thing so if there's elves
everywhere hmm ah maybe if we had
somebody on our group who could make
themselves look like an elf yeah and
they can kind of you know walk around as
if they're one of them and then we can
kind of sneak along through the
buildings okay you know what for once
okay like I don't have a happy mood so
I'm happy with your plan okay if there's
any sign of trouble dead bones just go
okay you know what wait well don't you
think that's a little too loud don't
worry this is a plan I can allow
right on you're given the L for ins is
openness wait
no no this is like totally not a good
idea
give your L for know I got an idea what
if you blow the horn like somewhere you
know that we aren't and then we go
inside and get the key okay Philippe
you're your new boss oh wait a minute
sway hey it's way too great of a mother
for me careful it's even I've got a
little bit of respect for every every
toy box up with is bad I don't want to
be the Mike's I have no idea we talk
about every plant I've come up with it's
been amazing
look where are we we're on the cusp of
getting this key everybody else's plans
did that we always had to come up with a
better plan who had to come up with the
plan that we're using I did plan me to
be fair at the plan you came up with was
the plan you came up with like at the
bridge it's it's it's always the same
plan with yeah it's the same plan every
time dad turn into a thing hey awesome
plan about making fog everywhere action
that was me you that's not how I
remember it you did actually have the
same plan three times what did those
goodies disguise I think using a dimples
over here that's kind of a patsy you
making him do all right
do two things okay you only do two
things I can turn into things and I can
make people like me but not forever why
don't you just guy her self as an elf
and then go charm another elf I that's
what I was gonna do I want the horn
first new bosses best boss I mean I'm
not here a lie the new new boss but I
think k4 is growing on me you got a plan
can I have my horn hey Matt the horn no
you think about joining off with them
yeah dude k4 is his own squad over here
as ask nice get back over here now who
now ooh now I'm gonna count to three
three quarters two and 8/10 get over
here yeah I'm grabbing your horns and
dragging you out of here got the horns
okay right I know what an oaf looks like
mm-hmm
okay I'm gonna use disguise and it's
turned myself into a no rule 10 all
right it's a modest elf disguise it's
like he's not the best-looking elf no
you just look like a child is what your
child you're like a little baby oh like
a little baby out yeah all right so the
plan is is that you're gonna go
somewhere and blow the horn and draw
them over it that way this guy's work
but you didn't really gain height so you
just look like a child oh oh I can make
you big ohh last for a few minutes
though he's gonna have to be quick
yeah I wouldn't do that well that he's
gonna look like a big child isn't I
wouldn't do that room and I just look
I'm just gonna go I'm just gonna it's
gonna go in guns ablaze do I have to
move to after the midterm space
you just when you're going around
corners you're gonna have to wait to see
what you can see okay all right well I'm
gonna get to here then I'm gonna peek
around the corner peek around the corner
looks all clear you can move forward
okay you can week around the corner
looks all clear fella play over here
yeah you don't see anything up ahead
okay to here I guess okay well I see you
look around the corner it's all clear
again I know you're not over fog war but
yeah yeah in here wait you guys me
you're still good still good
you see nothing in character right like
you talking to rob this isn't character
yeah you're you're walking around to
sneak it around the edges
you're like ducking and weaving you
don't see moving until you tell me not
to okay so you're gonna stop at this
point hey let me unlock it for you so
you look right forward and you see a
really big dog oh you see it you see a
really big dog yeah I'm looking at you
though he's just like often in the
forest just gonna go back this way
and to here I guess okay so you walk out
just a little bit over here yeah you can
see the well you can see some guards by
the gate just guarding the entrance of
the city but no it's it's pretty quiet
man pretty quiet quite enough I could
probably just wander into that church
yeah you're definitely good I'm getting
wandering that I don't know where my
piece is so I can't I think I don't know
this is a trap at all so that's a good
gonna wander into this this house okay
so dead bones for this you can use the
Jill puppet okay that's the one you what
well cuz you just bump bumped into
Gwyneth
Sun sword herself okay okay so I'm going
to use the Jill Jill puppet for this
okay that's you just walked in I think
use bumped into Gweneth and her son
swords just all hanging out
okay gonna come in oh you're a bit yeah
this side come on hi well I guess it's
depends on perspective little girl hey
what are you doing in here should you be
in bed at this hour at this point we're
thinking it's it's it's nighttime
it's as Sun has set completely stop fuck
this up
you shouldn't be worrying at this time
night sorry I'm having some mic issues I
can actually hear you guys very well
apart you dancing with your mic made by
Roman Roman you will be playing the part
of dead boy wait oh it's back its back
okay we're good you have to pick your
voice now that you're doing I know I
mean just reload I need to reload the
puppets cuz it broke
oh okay yeah let me know when you're
back in yeah I like how JEWS did you
have a little disconnect or something
yeah it was like a little computer fart
alright yeah I think this girl's
retarded yeah okay
oh hello little girl you shouldn't be
out at this time of night need to talk
to the important lady you know what Dave
Dave come over here Dave's gonna walk
over here he's gonna walk up Dave I'm
gonna need you to escort this girl back
to when did you see these gnomes was
coming to this why came here cuz they
were sneaky they were talking about
doing evil things are stealing something
some blades follow me we have to check
out these gnomes
yep you Dave watch this girl okay
alright so you're gonna be in this room
with Dave and these guys are now clearly
making their way to the cave of which
they have no idea
that they're on their way oh great I
mean if you were gonna do this you
should have told them so they could plan
a trap no this is a heel turn a heel
turn yeah he'll turn yeah you go turn
you go eat backstep oh you're back
stopping the party ice ok trace the
trail all right well you're in the the
room right now with one of the spell
blades I'm just hanging out son cleric
right yeah a little girl hey guys and I
was I was told to stand here and guard
you are you not strong enough to fight
the nose where do you live I've never
seen you around this town before Quinn
the one that was it's a lot of elves in
gwyndolin also anyway kind of like a
man-child do a perception check we have
perception checks
god damn traitor little girl walked in
you know you'd still think so girl still
thinks your girl all right
hmm well let's take you home where do
you live wait I get wait wait
oh god this is really bad this oh I
found this horn
look at this horn that's a horn no no no
where did you get that that's one Vsauce
that's an alarm we use that to alert
other spell blades of trouble can I blow
it no don't blow the horn give me that
he's gonna read I'll give you the horn
but first you got to tell me why you're
too scared to go fight the gnomes I hey
I'm not scared to fight the gnomes are
you sure cuz you mean you're here
protecting a little girl whereas your
friends have gone to fight gnomes really
let's see if this works then bones we're
gonna see the lower my troll the better
the better your odds here okay
being tricked this guy to go fight for
it for you okay no I was told I was
given an order I'm not leaving and
you're not adding up here where do you
live I want to ask you again little girl
I live in the house why I guess John
your disguise is clearly broken yeah
well yeah you broke it so do a role
they're dead bones oh let's try and get
that I was trying to get the selfies
thing set up yeah here have you can have
this one I mean if I kept the kid voice
up with the charm then becomes really it
doesn't matter that's what makes it
weird
casting charm is gonna he's gonna see
there's a threat yeah and he's gonna do
another perception role this well I do
the thing 15 okay you've charmed the Sun
cleric
alright so I'd probably turn back into
myself now right at this point all that
these guys were making their way to the
cave under these other group mister
alright hmm these puppets are necessary
no these puppets are those guys off the
screen great as when it turns the table
good old feel was on guard and he he
he's telling you guys guys as elves
coming
[Music]