all right it is a food justice turn sure
turn
alright so house house is dead bones
never know he's okay right um yeah we
get your get your phones you guys I'm
equal amounts to you dwarf okay all
right you guys can our health in the air
never worry about it sorry yeah okay
just don't blow her fuck just don't
don't do that don't all right
don't fire no fire yeah blowing up the
fog may may hurt the I mean it would
deal with some of the cold problems got
there though but if my already can i I
could attack and then toss right yes uh
all right no why would you be able to do
that it'd be a move in and out that's it
that's he'd hit you to action no to
actions
yeah well I'm gonna go ahead and try to
toss screen kobold into yellow cobalt
again okay salt plan and you go to grab
the cobalt and you miss like you don't
have no like you just you like go uh
remember in this game I don't really
reward you doing the exact same thing
over and over and you've already thrown
this asshole once he's ready last time
no did you picked him up and you threw
him into a gym remember yeah you miss
miss you throwing green and you did a
ton of damage to him but you didn't
actually hit the other two right that's
right so I was confused through all that
awesome all right so that's your turn
guys I don't want to alarm you but dead
bones is it some serious trouble
it was take for me was it will it be
fine well I just realized cuz it's gonna
be it's gonna go to the monsters turn he
just took another batch of whirl winds
it will be I've got playing armor I'm
fine oh fuck Scruffy's fine it's okay we
got Co doing a flanking maneuver me guys
oh yeah well I'm gonna plan I'm gonna
save the day these two gem Ling's are
attacking that yellow Koval again
they're doing more work with you guys
but they both miss this one's gonna read
just this position
same with this one then we're going to
go to the world one buddy's there right
now they're confused let's see if red
can get through his confusion and just
start winning again and he can't he's
too confused he's going to worry he
fought he goes to sit down yeah we're
fine see purple kobold is worldly I'm
good I'm good I'm good I'm good I'm good
oh wait uh yeah this this one uh he he
can't whirlwind oh he tease he's a
little confused so he's he's good but
he's we're gonna try and make him attack
so he's gonna try and hit you with his
wooden clothes to normal attack whoa
whoa whoa yes nicely whirlwind hmm no no
he can let you know that he can here
that is whirlwind they prefer to world
they also have one more ability I
haven't used the other but yeah there
were when Koval's you know but that's
not gonna do for the shit of it there to
do them yeah and he misses you dead
bones okay yellow cold is yep secret
message on be nice if you guys should
have just said that you did I forgot
about the today's you're better I'm this
is my first time so I'm like and you
guys decided yeah Rob I want you to do
that fog every turn and sorry sad and
shadow just like look we're gonna do
everything in right away
alright that's right all kobolds get
rabies this down so Todd it's not as bad
thank you sir you know like mouthwash
okay so they just brush their teeth is
anytime you take damage if you take
damage from any of these kobolds you're
going to give you have a chance to be
infected with rabies here and you're
going to lose one stamina every turn
the only people that are immune to rape
this form of rabies kobold rabies are in
fact kobolds so if you get hit by by
kobolds you will be inflicted with
rabies
oh god for however long I decide it's
going to last that sounds really bad
probably like six shots in the stomach
all right Thank You Chad I forgot all
about that one uh yeah thank you chat so
chat so green rabies green cobalt again
is gonna yeah he's gonna still go for
Justin he's gonna go for sure he's alone
drink drink this one oh no it just keeps
going as long as I say kobold
he gets it thanks for omen I would have
forgot that oh wow
oh we're gonna camp as a 14 so you're
gonna get hit 406 Justin alright real
quick how does blockade work I press
that on my god you use it that's your
turn and then it's like a buff that last
kind of like how whirlwind gets applied
every turn gotcha
or any of these things buckle at every
turn so so we're gonna so yellow kobold
is going to try to heal himself with a
Holy Light Oh 18 come on
so holy light though it's only half of
effectiveness if you use it on yourself
so tu-tu-tu-tu-tu that's going to be
what 18 9 plus 3 or minus 3 so C's get 6
you get 6 plus cells ok so that means it
is who doesn't glade turn was their
blade turned it awesome you have an
electron he does that I do believe yeah
we haven't killed anything have we no
blue blazes is the follow you that
whatever first hit but I'd already got
used
yeah it's turned each turn turn no
characters it's so over there would be
it's why we I thought it was the first I
thought it was just the first round of
combat no no no from now on Justin it is
so I never have to remember it again
just nerfing it right here there's way
too many persistent effects right now
for me yeah I thought it was like I need
oars Titanian rid of these things I need
to do every turn cuz as DM right now I'm
just feeling it trying to run everything
alright I'll get to show the cards
either yeah alright that's that I've
been on the ball with I have been
checking hello cards si
because that's what I used to check the
cards so alright green coat the blue
cobalt is gonna try to go through the
fog and see not get lost here he's not
getting lost but he's not going to
attack either he just gets into position
and I think that's all the NPC's so
Roman it's your turn okay
there will be so there will be times
where we as players have forget certain
effects and that's just kind of the
nature of the game like that's just
gonna happen you just just write it off
like oops
so alright Roman grew up what you want
to do alright Oh God
wait vibrate be down no no you didn't
get infected okay
oh you're feel good okay it's how
affectionate keep getting beat by these
cool because I mean it's infection that
might leave on you for the entire
duration of the campaign so yeah you're
good for now but I would suggest not
taking any more Meili hits from these
goals okay is blue kobold is he still in
the fog or is he out of the fog out of
the fog he's just coming through the fog
all right I'm gonna back up a little bit
1 2 3 4 7 8 9 10 two more okay yep okay
and alright I'm the cast Raya frost on
blue cobalt okay go for it okay you get
it for free because of your Kingfisher
cloth armor alright and my joke is gonna
be so it's a style that's a bit today
hello c'mon how do you prefer your ice
crushed or cubed I can't wait till he
runs odious are we using them alright
how do you like your ice crushed or
cubed and a bit of fun and you're being
completely misses and it hits Justin
oh it's Justin in the foot so Justin you
don't take any damage from this but
you're frozen to the ground
you can't move oh great yeah I know okay
do I still get my free actress fight you
still get your free action all right I'm
gonna shoot code blue cobalt with my bow
okay oh don't you far uh
is a 15 Hey
so mobile for three damage one two three
all right uh Koh it's your turn all
right it's time to see your master plan
here comes running up here uh-huh
everyone a bucket of water on them on
whoever's in front of me the chatter
there's yelling that oh just every one
you're just every night it's not
targeting you're just going like across
your body like blew everyone's wet yeah
where's that diet over here just linky
log yeah bit so here we go so code tries
to throw the bucket of water and make
people wet but he accidentally let's go
the bucket the bucket hits this first
gym Ling kills it bounces off just going
up landing on this second djembe lling
killing it as well killing both gym
Ling's Justin you get two free attacks
because this occurred because yeah
because of your uh your dwarven racial
water board all right
going after green kobold so fast that oh
wait is it all right Justin or what
would he use your longsword Justin Cosby
flail you come flailing down the
broadsword and you slice the green
kobold down the middle
oh my god he splits in half green kobold
is dead
I'm coming dragon you have a second
attack though so now you can turn and
face the blue kobold if you like oh wait
no a third attacker just get it oh yes
he gets another one he gets the attack
Pook oval place all right it's all
totally stupid thing to bring up a time
I am I covered in rabies blood now uh
sure yeah yeah he's just look especially
yeah it's just annihilating him like he
brought that because he's he's enlarged
too so he's like I don't know like an
eight to nine foot play all dwarves his
sword enlarged to or was it just him no
it wasn't I was
orbeum the short sale of butter knife
yeah it was like yeah he it's like he
cuts some you know piece of toast
through the cold okay and he got some
bloody Jam that's what he's got alright
go ahead and roll Justin yells away from
me you can roll and I'll see you all
right okay that's Soho
roll again all right
and that's of one person so justice so
Justin your first swing you come down
swing at the blue kobold you're gonna
hit them for four damage one two three
four
you're so confident from that bloody
mess that you go to swing again ah and
you throw your sword away so your sword
which will be represented by let's just
use what can we will use a mini Justin
not only can we make a mini Justin
Justin wheels Justin's you through all
the way it's right next to dead bones
gay this is where your sword is you just
threw it right through the fog so you do
not have your weapon right now all right
great the fog expands and now it is dead
bones turn because that was COEs action
that was cut out as you know exact man
just all right I'm I'm gonna try and
warp blade this purple kobold just kind
of poking with it again hoping to blink
out I'm not alone with you ruining
Cobalts there we go grab my sword it's
just your problem sighs I hit uh what
did you try to you hit who or plane with
the purple one uh yeah it's so it does
went three damage three damage okay one
two three
good I get to blink five spaces yep I
blink through the fog we all sleep
through the fog if you want but you
gotta you gotta roll for it cuz you're
going through the fog fucking hell
alright whatever
alright alright so I you can you can
blink through the fog yeah I want to
bring to here okay yeah it's fine
you actually land here though cuz he
went okay okay you can't be accurate and
through the phone that's that's not
right if only you guys had somewhere to
ignite this fog I mean I would now
because I'm still near it I don't want
them to maybe maybe not yet
you know you get Justin you melt that
ice on this leg though you TC GB is
currently routed to the ground his
swords over here
he's mad need some help on somebody are
you doing the whirlwinds they didn't
whirlwind this turn remember they all
would have confused and one just went
for an attack right right and oh it's my
turn it's your turn let's fog all right
I'm gonna go ahead and just block it up
cuz I can't to watch what is your body
exactly do I raise your shield printing
all damage to you and they went directly
behind you this turn so anyone standing
basically behind them so which way you
want to face Justin do you want to face
towards yellow or towards blue I'm
facing towards blue okay so Roman is see
what everyone yeah if Roman if you were
here or Co you were basically here you'd
be you know basically invulnerable to
most damage because Justin would be
taking it if Justin can take the hit the
hits will just automatically get kind of
redirected towards him okay cool
all right Oh prevents all damage to me
too yeah and it prevents damage to you
too um okay so this now up sorry what'd
you say Nicholas it's it's the mobster
yes mobster okay so yellow is going to
try to back up into the cave and going
through the fog and he has no problem
doing it and then man who do we you guys
killed what green Koval green couple
just did
he's gonna try again to heal blue kobold
with his holy light and heals him for 14
oh wow what that feels like a lot a lot
he's back to normal he's back to normal
basically she's all right now
yeah what's wrong um blue Co blue cobalt
is also gonna back up through the fog
whoa whoa
and that is one okay and he comes out
exactly the same way he was and that is
his turd he basically ran through the
fog got lost ran around in a circle and
then just came out with us that's why we
went red kobold is going to pick up
Justin's weapon so he now has it damages
and he's gonna try to come through the
fog space right pushing up but like
right up to you he's gonna try and run -
the fog I have a better idea for what he
should have done delay 16 all right he
came through here and he's gonna now try
to attack you with your own weapon all
right Oh
now is this weapon like a wand where we
attuned to the user the only wouldn't be
as effective no it's just the drastic
does just as lucky no okay 20 I was
gonna say just justice blockade now
block it well see the Cobell didn't ever
see him through the blockade so I was
just rolling because I wasn't gonna do
damage anyway so did I Justin
unfortunately the Cobell did roll 20
against you with your own sword so he's
going to break your blockade you're no
longer to blockade stance and you take
five damage oh man okay guys our first
fight this time you did they have rabies
and whirlwind and little blobs that just
showed up out of nowhere no I mean whose
fault is that I give oh I'm sorry
he's a cold - he's
train guard he gets another turn fucking
right that's right I forgot about that
ability all right come on Reagan is
sword again
Justin takes another five damage because
he's no longer blockading oh my god
Justin here Justin is now under ten
hell's got nine health um so purple coal
mold is no longer diffused he's gonna
come into the fog and he's gonna start
ruining in the fog uh-huh
Oh what about suede spirit oh wait are
we now
I already got nerve weirder because I
can't remember that combat now this
one's for Tom power it's overpowered
let's change it it was super overpowered
uh so so he starts whirlwind ding um and
the fog starts getting pushed away
I can't hide when I boobies it flips
them for me it flips them over this fog
is getting also pushed but just in
you're no longer big ok few minutes have
worn off you've turned small I still
frozen the ground yeah we just just read
cold has your weapon k so we know ok no
you're no longer frozen to the ground ok
um
yellow Cola went red coupl went blue
cream will glint ok
Ruben it's your turn ok so who is still
who is still in the fog so think of the
fog as like like right now blue is
completely encompassed in it purples
encompassed in it and yellow can't
really see you guys through it ok nobody
nobody can see you Roman you should
think of it as a line of sight blocker
that trying to go through causes silly
things would be the way to put it that's
one of those cards that I probably still
need to properly rewrite like let me
pull it up the fog makes moving and
attacking through it much more difficult
for everyone except for the sorcerer so
you can just so you can see and move
through the way who cast this go Coco Co
can see through the fog and can move
through it no problem it's just
everybody else who doesn't can't see to
see and move through it
hmm okay so I am the campfire is oh man
don't forget you have the gel whoops I
in it out of my done is you oh thank you
the fug okay nothing okay
all right dead bone so you think what
I'm thinking I know I'm actually not for
once haha all right we got ourselves a
fog that's flammable
uh we got a campfire yeah okay I don't
think you should do that just oh oh yeah
yeah you shouldn't do that no boy I
already have a plan I think you should
do that I think you should wait until
I'm out of the fog before you do that
now you're oh this was gonna be a
two-parter Deb bones this wasn't gonna
be I kinda just want to get out I can't
make it I'm all right I can wait
I mean you could probably wait I don't
know I don't know this is an amazing
member purple cobalt is now whirlwind
ding so he's gonna be able to move one
and do a whirlwind each turn at the end
of this oh boy yeah there's no time
Logan a lot I mean I know I'm wearing
plate armor but hey you still vulnerable
just don't look at the explosion you'll
be just okay yeah okay if I don't look
at it it takes like half damage right
yeah okay
Rob can I can I get to the campfire to
grab a piece of wood that's on fire 1 2
3 4 5 plus your BM 1 2 3 4 5 so you
could get to the fire grab it and but
only make it back here if you want to
light it but I mean coach just said that
he can evade it on the next turn so yeah
man like so you could somehow find a way
to help me you I don't really see how
that's gonna happen I know but I just
probably it out yeah at least pull just
the net away for sure if you really
wanted to I mean that's not don't told
you that okay just so you know like this
explai
ain't gonna kill them it's I'd say each
tile is gonna be worth like to damage
okay well that's the case just wait now
he's gonna shoot me
oh yeah no don't do it all right let's
do this son
let me throw your frog on a stick hey
are we within 10 spaces
yeah we are yeah you are yeah I can see
clearly right there you get you gonna
throw it up no no put it next to me in
Justin so bad thanks thanks look I even
have to oh my god oh my god that I can
use for a fog ah well use this look you
want to get the benefit you get your
butt over here
all right where are you putting it I'm
gonna put it right there oh that's a
pretty sexy frog pretty sexy frog top
right it's a pretty sexy crotch um this
doesn't say at the beginning of your the
end of your turn Roman at the beginning
of a turn where is frog on a stick it's
over all my sides
it's beginning group okay all right it
does it it does not heal enemies it's
very nice it only heals you guys well
great that's all right Co it is your
turn
all right I'm gonna fire my blunderbuss
all right hold on one sec was that it
Roman um can I see cuz that's just like
any other action well yes because you're
those you're known you can use the totem
as your move and then you could take an
action you can still attack if you
wanted to give your drag your favorite
ignore the way a little yes a race gnome
you may use an item or treasure card
consumable or ability instead of moving
each turn so you could have used that as
your as your move and then use an
ability oh wow so you could try to like
rain frost through the thing if you want
amen gnomes ROP I mean it's it's for you
you can you might as well just do a raid
frost in a shoot right cuz it's right
like maybe just yeah he's gonna hit just
I mean that's just funny Justin smaller
now don't bad bubbles you get bad rolls
there's nothing you can do yeah not in
the way right are you doing array of
frost you got a joke
yes do you an array of for us and I got
a joke cover your neck Justin one room
let's hear Rome come on come on
everybody's weird so yeah shit you can't
even say this is it that good
it better be like you know notice these
are good shut post come on okay alright
I think it's time to just cool it with
the jokes okay that was a nine so you're
shooting through the fog so you just hit
this hill next to them you don't
actually hit him you missed all right
you just take your shot with your bow
shot with a bow okay can you roll yeah
if you have to roll into the fog it's
not a big deal because I can just show
you guys I I we see it through the fog
anyway okay this time you get the hit
so you hit blue kobold four three one
two three all right uh como it is now
your turn what would you like to do do
it go right so you know I'm going to
fire my blunderbuss and it has a range
of three so this square right here is
that if I shoot it at this square it
would do like a 2x2 this direction or
this direction it's so it's a 2x2 like
it's however you want it it's just where
you're aiming
so think I'll pick a square and then you
can have it go farther out if you dope
I'm sorry um yeah like right at this
square so I don't have to move and then
you know obviously I'm trying to hit one
of the fog's okay okay yeah like it so
it's gonna be these four I didn't sign
up for this all right
seventeen that would've been way more
fun if you hit it - all right so those
just blunderbuss
blowing up these flogs fog spaces long
spaces so I haven't been sick chain
reaction haven't been doing these
goddamn whirlwinds I'm going to change
that whirlwind ability man it's just
it's too hard to remember so you're
taking two Purple's taking two dead
bones you
do you want a barrel roll out you want
to try and barrel roll out no me
athletic give you your barrel roll
ability all right Devin says not barrel
roll
he goes to turn and cinches his butt
taking to damage and so then this is
going to chain react boom boom boom boom
boom two more on yellow two more on
purple one two one two boom boom boom
boom Justin do you want to try and roll
or just gonna take this because I'm
gonna jump out of the way if you like
yeah I'm gonna try to jump out but not
jump at me nice alright so yeah I'm
jumping back towards the totem okay
gonna jump back for the north's totem
was 16
that's fine okay so I've been doing
these whirlwind things so also rabies
check baby's check or anything going on
with rabies
has anybody got hit by rabies well may I
mean I got I took that article no yeah
but that went through blade wall so and
I didn't oh that's true like it's it's
like that's you really hit by a weapon
not getting bit guys I haven't had any
global swamp bite you guys yet which I
want to do but I'm working right okay is
there also when is that heal for the
frog go off I begin a pattern okay so
I'm gonna we're just gonna do the
whirlwind for this turn now so to come
over here it's gonna hit dead bones for
- oh and now it's dead homes turn along
swear it's not him that we're ones it's
him it's the pink one yeah sometimes
like the thing is with this game is
there's a lot of things going on so
something's the the rules are more they
don't have to be perfect you know I hate
because I was good just me right really
what we're playing for
is you know the moments where Justin has
the potential to lose his balls that's
what we're playing all right so I'm kind
of pissed off the code just you know
fucking explode in my ass so I'm gonna
fucking use my my pass back to grab his
book of curse spells okay yeah look at
this shit uh-huh I'm gonna cast it
you're gonna kill like a robot thank you
Amy
so wait do i cat do i roll then cast or
well how does it help uh well you can
guess sure go ahead and do a roll for me
I'll roll free he'll roll do we know
what he loves to spell it
Oh ball seventeen it's just that
seventeen is gonna get applied to this
spell okay okay okay so can be so you're
you're gonna be using is holy light so
who would like to heal for seventeen
least a wave myself well if you use them
myself if use on yourself you'll only be
healing yourself for eight so still
better than nothing
yep you got now you got to remember
people watching that these guys are in
character so it would be kind of out of
character I don't even think you have
line of sight on Justin but it would be
cut out of character for demos to heal
anyone else but himself
oh my butt's on fire it's like a 1 2 3 4
5 6 7 8 9 oh yeah yeah all he'll Bend
there was a dead body I guess I throw
the book back to Co innocence is not
broken
okay um now that is actually hopefully
your move though that's only my move
because I'm gonna stab the pink thing
with my war plate okay go ahead and roll
and no mr. fuckin overpowered well I
mean everybody's kind of like that's
just like just a little tax people isn't
it was a 50 all right so you hit purply
at War three three and then I get to
blink five spaces right yep one two
three four five never definitely don't
come by this total money you know I'm
hiding man I just got blue
he's almost full health again though
Roman like he was endanger the baby
shield himself raid with the power of
friendship right come oh yeah absolutely
under bus fire NASM alright the mobile
comes in your world wins co for two it
is now
justin's turn hodge how do you I don't
know what to do I don't have a weapon
suggesting you get healed for one cuz we
stay next to the total oh great alright
what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna stand in
front of the totem and I'm gonna
blockade up again
I I'm going full-on
protection mode I got a healing totem
behind me okay it's got a loan behind
the Frog give me a give me a roll let's
see how well your stances on this
blockade that frogs pretty sick just get
it all right good perfect you are ready
to take some hits for your allies all
right okay
so um let's go to one more whirlwind
this guy's gonna move forward a world
would cove - all right it's that look
opals turn trying to get a hang of this
game um let's see what do I want to do
what can I do
um guys help no aren't you just like um
you're right like why don't you shoot
him all right blue cobalt is going to be
using I forgot even had this one so
exciting blue cobalt is going to be
using tosser on red cobalt actually no
that's even better
haha blue cobalt is gonna try and fall
in Austin so let's go so he's gonna toss
Justin and he's gonna try to toss Justin
uh into the cave remember the kobolds
hate the dwarf the most which is why
I've had them kind of just constantly
going for him oh you lucky bugger he
goes through a hole he goes to grab
Justin but just completely whiffs Justin
Jukes out of the way dodging to the side
red bull red kobold is going to 1 2 3
welcome your totem 4 5 come right here
and he's going to what can we have red
Koval do Oh
chat chat is thinking that blockade
should stop tossing are they right or
wrong um no because he's because he's
gonna think of in the context of it it's
immune to damage but that's like when
you're somebody's attacking still this
is somebody trying to grab you right
it's like in Street Fighter their bodies
told ya you're blocking psychic throat
yeah yeah like these
his car that's a very good analogy Roman
so it didn't matter anyway though we
didn't even have to get to that point
because you know yeah we missed anyway
so red kobolds gonna go over here and
he's going to start whirlwind ding so
let's see if he's doing a good whirlwind
oh lucky you it's a 100 right red cobalt
starts the whirlwind and he just starts
going off in a random direction just woo
all the way into the fire
he's that one hola he just has maybe a
devil just went bump alone bounced off
trees in the fire red Koval takes 1
damage and is now burning oh man last we
got purple kobold who is now confused so
he's going to try and be unconfused
actually yellow cobble still there -
he's uncontrolled wind again he's just
going for a normal attack that day and
it's too Soko you do not get hit yellow
kobolds gonna move up here and he's
gonna again cast holy light was holy 1
or 3 it's probably three of guess yeah
it's 3 1 2 3 new kobold aren't doing
well and he's gonna try and heal purple
I'm sorry guys I know they have rabies
but oh my god he only heals in 4 5 ok I
can't get anything happening for the
bites 1 3 4 also just to clarify red
cobalt has my sword right get cold not
the purple no fun flais beats or yeah
thank you everybody for that afraid you
had that um so I guys I just want to say
I am like super intimidated by this guy
right here who okay oh that one the one
handling this is hanging out yeah
alright um it is now Roman Stern Roman
you can drive for one halo 4
on okay so we have Justin with no weapon
mm-hmm Thank You blue kobold what does
blue coal but look like is he shaky is
he look strong um blue Coble right now
he's like the leader the Cobell he's
still out of all the kobolds you can see
like you can see him yellow and the guy
who just went into the fire
he looks like he's still ready for a
fight okay
that's Romans subtle way of asking about
his hit points I didn't actually think
it was subtle it's subtle to some people
in Chad who have never seen these type
of games we played so okay so yellow
call balls just healing people left and
right yeah you like how what's roman do
you like how I made it really obvious
that this is just a bunch of tanks and
melees with a healer in the back and
he's the only Koval who's yet to take
any real damage well no the fogs gone we
can finally start doing hey the fog did
a lot of damage it did like over dead
tomato bolts know you like to click to
you baby you whatever you got to heal
your slots to me yeah you got to heal
he's at the years cuz you're
spitefulness made you take the book and
cast a random spell a takos book yeah
and you healed yourself to be fair I
like that I mean that was a I was what I
was gonna
Jesse heed you we needed a wild card at
that point things are not going well no
you know what right Lily he's intense
spaces you should do that again uh not
line of sight doesn't Roman have his own
books this yet he does why would he use
his own book I might need that book Rob
come on alright I'm like rare frost on
the yellow cobalt okay so you're doing
ray of Frost yellow kobold okay yep go
hello cobble go ahead and roll alright
yoke okay
come on hey Ted bones yeah what killed
the dinosaurs uh I don't know I killed
the dinosaurs
the ISEE all right you shoot your beam
you miss again you hit like right next
to them on the ground would you like to
take a break on Monday fact-checking
my joke wiki just yes I'm gonna shoot
you look bald with my bow oh my god it's
not a 113 okay so you hit yellow yellow
kobold 4-3 the Colville's themselves are
not looking good right now uh KO it is
your turn okay I don't think anyone's
world Oh red cobalt is technically
whirlwind ding so he's going to
whirlwind towards dead bones he takes
one damage because he's done fire should
he take more damage but he's actually
spinning spreading the fire he's not
stopped dropping it rolling yeah he's
just well he only know he's rolling on
the ground these whirlwind is now on a
90 degree angle he's just kind of picks
kicking up dirt Tasmanian Devil so he's
making like a trench towards he's
actually about to hit your tent I'm
sorry you guys are gonna lose your test
so you should have packed that up before
you left your camp we had it and who's
Ted right here look it's G tailing it's
an area they have those you know how
dirty does it be huh
alright co-occurs camera juicers cool
right a lot of money I have a sweet plan
I'm gonna I'm gonna run over here next
to the yellow kobold okay and I'm gonna
hug him oh okay go ahead and roll I told
you it was sweet you better use a toilet
roll the 20 boom baby
alright you walk up you roll you hug the
kobold
the kobold kind of looks at you and it's
kind of really confused like he's really
confused you know
even sure what has happened from this
yet I'm giving him a kobold you vote you
Coble to the hole did you say a full
body up did you like whisper something
in this year when you hugged him hey I
said I said oh gosh okay yeah uh so then
red cobalt is whirlwind ding he's now
destroyed your tent and he is still on
fire yeah oh yeah your tents on fire now
it's it's you have a problem dude
bullets if you want keep for cheating
we're not gonna get the money back on
its head we'll do it again
sandwiched it's okay we'll take it at
Justin's it's fine
I got I got this I got this I got a plan
okay it is your turn to bones all right
Co is within ten spaces me right yep
give me that book okay
there goes give me come on come on oh
it's a ten so your spell your casting is
force filler so fine color someone's
either a one by one or two by two block
of dirt and everyone that is in range of
it will either try to roll out of the
way or they'll take damage within 10
range as 10 range so you can go all the
way to the entrance of the cave just
this night sorry okay these two
okay can I block these like this slow
it's a tube I bet bones so I'm in the
middle of hugging one of those okay so
so it's a two by two if you go big so
it'd be like this egg if you okay yeah
yeah so that yeah
so we're CO and the kobolds are so you
to be fair he did shoot a flaming thing
into the fog when he was in there like a
gun you do a gun is like that's
dangerous man sure I don't with the I
don't remember what the dirt was called
that we used last game for this so we'll
just use this something yeah I can't
roleplay so you know there's that so who
you gonna just try just try to block it
all off just block it all up
yep that's like we can get out the back
way it's fine I don't know how the book
is going to go back through but science
and magic uh you know I'm gonna do I
want to just make a wall this will be
the easiest way so I'll be like this
yeah yeah yeah yeah so he has to bowl to
see be a poison is it yeah so we're
gonna roll to see if mr. Coble goes
do-do-do-do-do please my block out nine
so uh yeah he's gonna roll and it's
gonna roll towards cold towards uh watch
Mike oh yeah
he gets nicked though in nicked him okay
it takes just a little minute at least
now I've kind of see I'm not gonna get
pincer attack
I've just got to face the red cobalt
raycoleman traded up wanna cut on one
situation you're gonna go do that we're
gonna do this alright don't on fire red
Koval cuz anyone is ever on fire and
they want to fight you you have to get
away from them if they're on fire yes if
I light myself on fire to combat it well
red colitis work back red cobalt is
taking the damage from the fire it's
done to damage to you and we're gonna
see a flame spread to good old dead oh
no no no I'm not gonna let on that
little rule no all right things not
enough for you I would've chose
different come on one damage every turn
on this I'm not gonna light you on fire
on a 15 no yeah but if it gave me a plus
one to my damage I've been alright yeah
it's a frenzy it's like that's they go
come on fire 100% it doesn't actually
give you a plus one damage is just you
wait like yeah that's a Hitler good yeah
it doesn't though just let you know
should okay um wait that was just my
that was just my my move right because I
use the play uh the pass back you you
can use those move yes you can't attack
if you want still attack disco ball yeah
fun with my blinked at sure a tactical
wolf yeah yeah gnomes okay it's just a
broke up and you will which is yeah I
would yeah which we can i teleport
through things
uh no not no can i teleport no no Yuri
established through the fog that you
don't just visualize a place you must
move really quickly this former blade
sideways I know cuz you can't we just
like cut your pinky or something yeah
damage
I think teleport with your on with your
thing you should assume line-of-sight
when in doubt just as soon as in sight
okay I'm gonna so what that's like one
two three four five somebody's gonna
blink
find him okay Justin is your turn you
get healed for one all right oh my god
interrupt
what are you interrupt me Co I'm going
to blink over here okay oh right here so
you get to take a full full turn for
this right okay so I'm gonna hug this
cobalt you're just blinking over uh-huh
yeah and looking does not cost any
stamina so you're good a sweet hug okay
uh you try to hug the Cobell pushes you
back though he does not accept this
little ah damn look at that face you
can't be surprised I know he's growly
now because I counts as his don't turn
whirlwind kobold moves towards dead
bones he takes one fire damage and he
can't heavy thing he's just beating up
to ten still my strategy is to run away
he dies to the fire