[Music]
all right Justin it is your turn
I can't believe this you guys have had
the most possible luck in this but you
guys aren't even close to dying
what are these so what it did was just
summoner these allies no he just voted
something gem lines and he controls them
on his turn but I mean you could just
kill him yeah look uh there's no way to
written to be perfectly honest I don't
think Deadlands is going to control
these gem Ling's cuz there's a gem
fuckin Lord in the room
oh oh so boy oh no oh you hate them
they're not so many attacks I mean we
need ciutat it doesn't have an AE that's
yeah yeah it don't mean I do well the
thing is just it could hit one and then
hit the next and hit the next and then
well I know but in the end result one
attack others want to check on the gym
Lord yeah yeah yeah I mean do you not
have whirlwind to put the face I've got
toss still yeah could you toss yeah
managed as me it's not toss the gym
behind you at the gym gym at a gym would
gain you what two at two or more swings
yeah like Gemma the gym would they chain
react like if I tossed the gem Lord at
the those take dumplings or you toss the
gym load at me if you want to try
tossing the gym Lord again yeah yeah
just all right back to me awesome the
gym Lord said we have a cluster of gems
with the haha but there's a bigger
cluster headphone yeah I mean them if
you get accessories easier to hit seven
turns or four turns Roman for form on
Roman as my god Justin the Barbarian
here just kicks the shit out of a gym
Lord braces out that bonus I'm ready I'm
just gonna move Oh dad chats like man it
would have been easier if they just
didn't have gym link skin for all right
you go to pick up the gym Lord but he
you can't pick him up this time he
basically your arms lock you get into
one of those like arm wrestling things
and he kind of pushes you over here and
you kind of push him over here pushing a
co out of the way nobody takes damage
but everyone just gets shuffled around
all right from the pushing very
convenient w6 damaged saris like what
roman takes one damage also Justin takes
rays damage yeah you go every and puts a
bit of frenzy can I do anything else
right now
um well really grappling so you're kind
of grappling right now you can no you
can't do it like that's okay it's like
either is there anymore when you guys
failed like oh did the blunderbuss I'm
like it hits Justin I'm like fuck I
shouldn't have done that
you got a nice big encounter boss battle
planned and I think we fucked it up no
no no you uh are you in need of any more
gem Ling spawns sure or is that well
it's a it's going to be a that's just
insurance oh it's going to be a gem
board and the gym links turns I'm just
thinking well chats just saying that I
guess more need to be spawn huh what I
didn't really bond its what damage of
the disk I take he took two Dan or throw
damage my maybe earthquake Jesus Christ
chat look weird it got like 20 Geoff's
up here to a nothing all right it's time
for swarming here we go that entity
[Music]
that's it I delete the earthquake stuff
to you at this point
yeah just ways there's some confusion
yeah yeah yeah this isn't the last very
long whoops oh yeah that works too whew
no reason okay um why is the board like
freak out for you guys when I do that
yeah yeah very scary okay uh shouldn't
want to get me just yet no cuz they're
in jail or do you summon gems in front
of a gem Lord he's obviously controlling
these things they were passed up until
you spawned the leash want then they all
start attacking my god third Papa all
right so we're gonna do the gem Ling's
attacking dead bones first just to get
another way
3:7 gem Ling's all right you take seven
damage dead bones oh that's not that's
you just gave Viraj by them
uh it's only okay with this there's only
one attacking ko9 the funny thing is
like I know you guys are going like easy
at this point he misses Co because like
you guys already know oh just a E
anything and just think it's 17 attacks
in this box all right uh one two three
four five six
I'm gonna bring him here seven attack
Felipe no don't Felipe oh no what the
healer die god damn it
one of them available so what these guys
assault start to attack in the process
two of them die Justin you can pay
Felipe counters back so you can have two
attacks right indices in the fog okay so
here you go dude I'm just rolling once
and you guys are rolling 20s all right
there's a good hit that's five damage
two three four five one two three four
five Justin does ten damage that's two
more swings two more of these things
alright these were all done there was
one two three four five attacking Justin
oh man this is going way better than a
cold fire just that takes five damage
we've all 3:20 and I've rolled ten wave
roll oh yeah - once okay so the gem Lord
is going to shoot his beam um and he's
gonna shoot it this way yep coming back
okay it's gonna hit Roman and dead bones
and moved uh I don't think it's gonna
really hit Justin cuz it's gonna come I
know but what's else is in the way all
the Gimli
well they're gonna explode no threats
but they're not allies to you it's not
that you'd like the gym like Justin
doesn't get free attacks from NPCs cloud
it's not like whenever something dies oh
19 all right this is going to kill this
one
it's got to kill this one's gonna kill
this one it's going to come back this
way in this way and we'll clear that off
too so Roman takes five dead bones takes
photos Roman takes four dead bones takes
four one two three four and then then
he's going to do his big beefy arms
because he gets two free attacks and
he's gonna slam both of them onto
co-star who Greg's I'm not looking too
good I'm not up 15 well actually I can't
do that because the way this attack
works because it does three damage to
Coe and then Coe gets knocked back from
that and I can't hit ko with a second
punch so I'm just gonna just then with
the other one but Justin's gonna be
resistant to the knock back because is
it against a hole yeah but he wasn't he
grappling with Justin yeah he broke free
to do the laser beam thing yeah and then
now he's turning around to punch people
he punched you out of the way and then
he goes to punch trusted and then Justin
grabs his fist and just is like no oh no
he owes them yeah one other thing have
all the events been yes oh yes they have
all been done okay yeah
it is now Romans turn students rogem
Lord has a lot of cracks in him at this
point just look he's about to die guys
or split into like a million of these
things
oh god no that might be don't even say
it
who's up it will me wrong okay hey so
it's gotta I don't have an A 'if one
thing
don't use your frost beam I might die I
might die even if Roman uses like if the
frost me won't hit anything other than
KO Tim and the gem Lord because we
already have established the path of the
beam so until the gem leagues move in oh
I can move these crystals and Krysten
these crystals are shackle I can't move
this one it's really nope I don't want
to pick the crystals yeah okay is it a
good spot huh let's do this I don't
really have much in the way they can
move I'll move back
and I'm going to attack the gem lien
with reference Raya Frost
I give me two separate rules because
you're gonna do a bow aren't you yes
yeah you're going to try to kill two for
Justin okay
can we hear your joke and then give me
two rolls okay
hey kremlings would you like to build a
snowman oh I was pretty lame you're
lucky that's a fourteen alrighty kill
one look it's the context of that that
make it so much more powerful don't open
up if you had sang it then it would have
been a bit yeah if you had said do you
wanna build a snowman five um you missed
this one your arrow just whizzes
passionate Justin you get a free attack
okay can I just can I roll once I want
to attack all these guys that are around
me no this is this is an attack like
this is this is not your turn this is
just a bonus attack you won't get
anything I'll attack if I bust a little
gem then I get another bonus attack and
I miss the next little Jim yeah so just
just start rolling as long as you don't
know just low then I'll go through you
just want to clear all the ones around
you yeah yeah yeah keep going better
than one popped two popped and pops whoo
right
four pauses just insist on a rampage
he's just think if you don't have if you
had whirlwind you could have had five
attacks mother doing that one in the
boxes
you know I I hinted at it cuz I knew
this yeah this encounter is supposed to
be like he'll dwarf Arama if only we'd
say fire bro he was a whirlwind fire guy
fuck you Justin whatever Jamie might
deserve to die oh ya think you just
didn't take rabies to forgot about that
alright now has an attack was for the
ball and then you hit him four five one
two three four five alright so now it is
coaster string alright um ko shoot the
gem Ling's but not the crystal
I don't know a little like from I don't
like it's pretty obvious but now but
like there's like no point in attacking
anything when you can kill Jim Ling and
then Justin just hits it for five yeah
yeah yeah be totally paid do whatever
you think is best again um and I am
going to I want to move can I move into
an action still or no yeah I think I can
race you can yeah some of them fight I
wanna move right here I soaked a lot but
I want to throw my crystal catalyst in
dead bones his face
hope doesn't it or no yeah sure you
could I mean you're it's like any other
critical analyst so far cuz we've
established just once your dead bones
squeezed it and then they all popped out
I guess if you squeezed it and then
threw it quickly like a grenade sure you
can crystal catalyst grenade it okay
okay so uh where's your crystal catalyst
it was like you're stealing your book
there's a price dead bones there's
always a price the price is my health
hey this isn't gonna hurt I really need
to make it by the way I need to make it
so if we start on this side of the board
all the stuff on the right side is on
the left side and vice-versa for future
weeks so i want to go right on time
alright so you through acoustic
catalysts all right one two three four
five six seven eight nine ten all right
bleeping oh it has to be repaid seven to
expand flip is gonna turn so Philippe
isn't gonna be retarded
Felipe's going to wow I can't really go
through that I think I can only get two
so he's gonna back ll actually Oh
Philippe is gonna back up here and he's
gonna shoot these four he's not gonna
heal my god you're the worst healer ever
what no it's not enough Felipe's like co
is established yeah they should be zalto
come on face on her here
yeah unless code told him to heal him
he's not really gonna do it
he's just try to hold him to take the
best shots oh and now he's oh oh just I
like you get the good roles when you're
not attacking I know Justin you may have
four he was 18 Justin you may have four
swings alright number one number one yep
Humbert oh that's gonna be a Knick
number three
nah he never misses us another Nick you
never get hit so that's 12 damage and
one another one team Christopher five
six seven eight nine ten eleven twelve
yeah I'm probably missing two from the
previous turn all right eight crystals
one two three four five six seven oh my
god all right it is now that was Felipe
so now it is now dead phones turn dead
bones you're actually not looking too
healthy by the way you're in bad shape
here I I can make a team play and be a
good team ally or I can be a selfish
dick and run away
these things aren't likely to kill you
unless I roll 20 in which case Oh baby
uh-oh I can okay they're mostly is gonna
beat you then move on uh so I'm gonna
pass back Felipe's blunderbuss okay uh
you gotta do it no it says on the pass
back it has to be a consumable or an
ability that's a love that's if that's
case I'm just going to war played that
jamling behind me this is this one yep
just gonna attack him okay and yep yeah
but what the fuck is that uh it is
better it's eight or ten and blink five
spaces oh I see one oh that's yeah don't
ever do yet the way over here just put
me back over here I'm going backwards
and then you're moving as well and then
I'm gonna move and hide behind this rod
Wow
you don't realize how long yeah I do
realize how what you don't care you get
a free attack Justin I'm your second and
then that's two more oh thank god oh I
was waiting for you to have like four
tax lined up and then miss one cuz I
wasn't ever gonna give you the extra tax
and it never happened all right
quick question yep how long is Justin's
bigness gonna last yeah it's you know
whenever I would you ask that whatever I
want to get rid of it and it's a it's a
20 transformation I'm pretty much asked
because chat once the never mash it it's
fine that's that's a 20 and more Ellis
cat wants us dead yeah that's the point
you give them the explanation we're all
good now all right it's um Justin's turn
it's your turn Justin whoo boy all right
I am gonna go ahead and oh boy I think
she just hit the big guy ah well III
guess I could but I can also tossed a
big guy of the year yes
yeah torture for you that it's really
hard like horse the frame would be hard
for a person yeah but if you smash it
looks pretty beat up you smash it well
thank you just that I need to give you
stamina damage from your rabies yeah you
should get that checked out sure hmm by
the way we have been going for like two
hours so yeah after this break after the
combat ran bad okay after this break
yeah for sure all right so did you
consent to this Co I don't want to throw
a big crystal on you without you being
okay at this do it do it
all right
you go to grapple him and you shake him
a lot and you deal the damage but you
really can't throw him around anywhere
so he just takes five damage but when
you do this not bad when you do this
he starts cracking everywhere on his
body like he starts to shatter uh his
left arm falls off to the ground
whoa whoa he's just got one arm that's
awesome
it's now the gem Lords turn all right uh
all right so we're gonna have to get a
little creative here um be moving your
your amplified take on rubbers and now I
move them after I do the big beam ah all
right let's see much damage we get in
before this dad dies oh yeah and two
board shambling spawn check the chats
always all about my gem links I want to
make sure that I'll miss out because
there's not enough Jim blinks of the
board all right um so the gem Lord is
going to do his the gemenese are gonna
tack we're gonna have the five attack co
and co takes five damage then we're
gonna have three attack Roman good
positioning Roman that only one hits you
Roman Wolfe um then we have for
attacking Justin all right Justin takes
four then the gem Lord casts his beam
Denson oh oh my god 17 a blast one two
three four five I didn't even have them
hit Phillippe I do that in the wrong
order dad dad dad so it's going to hit
Phillipe and co-star so ko takes 4 1 2 3
4 and Phillippe is unconscious
Philippe hmm oh shit the healers down
yeah care your Lee of this dungeon
you're hanging out with a blown away you
don't even know Philippe's down
oh yeah yeah but whatever two more arm
swings so one swinging at code oh whoa
whoa whoa whoa
one arm swing I'm sorry what arm swing
when I'm swinging at Ko cuz he's a
little small one nine hits Coco gets
knocked back pushing a gem and ko takes
a three damage I'm about to die or
passed out I'm not sure this could have
been ended so much like earlier ago like
if like if Justin was just getting fed
the attacks he could possibly be gay oh
yeah we have selfie gay we have no be
gay yeah you know I organize my gosh
or just instead of Philippe had the
boner but just when the blunder plus
this encounter would be over and then I
would nerf it alright go ahead
Roman okay so he's cracked all over the
place worried we are lining up we're
going for the kill okay you're just
gonna text him wings attacking him with
Raya Frost who the genuine gem Lord he
okay but you're not to try to shoot
through guys so they might they might
take the hits for him I can live with
that
okay go ahead and roll let's hear his
fun I do I tell have any other options I
really hope this is a good one
really yeah the rest have been so
disappointing so far I'm just the first
two were great and then just downhill
from there all right
it's Jim Lord where's your jacket winter
is coming
oh man oh come on
fine you're gonna have network if we
don't laugh at it uh Roman shoots it he
manages to hit the gym Lord - Jim Ling
spawn the gym Ling explodes just teaches
falls apart shatters the other arm falls
the ground says just meet the two meaty
arms laying on the ground
and the gem Ling's all start to retreat
you guys are in a combat okay hey all
right so you guys have just defeated the
gym Jenn Lord some of the gem Ling's are
alive but the kind of like gun and
hiding in the corners their passive
again right yeah the amplifying crystals
that were like humming are just kind of
there these two still have the Paladin
chains and probably will for ever
they're not they're not really alive so
who cares all right so uh Roman you're
the leader
what's neck like a rock up on a
community college a is - so right in
this room there's a bunch of little
sparkles and there's just two big meaty
beefy arms just kind of laying there
okay guys settle up again dude see me
kick that Jim's ass
I need where's Philippe I need help hey
Philippe hey it's going sorry I got
pretty messed up in that fight well you
did good man
oh yeah we did it can I keep this gun uh
yeah sure I could I could really use
some help I hurt all over okay well you
know what Philippe Philippe has got your
back Philippe I will take some time and
he'll uh just top you guys off using his
yes Salome
Power Co bully pal any ability vest nice
I mean I don't know if you realize this
but I had already healed you guys during
the break oh I wasn't paying attention
sorry wow you're really good you're like
a heel of ninja yeah oh yeah I thought
you're gonna be a jackass as they know
that's your health was the game's oh no
no I definitely had a comment as long as
you get a breather I'll bring your
stamina back up something to know uh
Felipe's or do you anything about Kirin
cobalt rabies curing Coble rabies that's
well I don't hypothetically but why
would you want that are you that well
they're not I mean there is a way you
can get rid of it but it's like
temporary so you have to do it all the
time
oh man so it's Justin like a like a
we're Co bulb now yeah well hmm no he's
not like a we're kobold it's like he has
herpes and so it just flares up every
now and then would be a oh wow just
sorry that's that's pretty Terry's
factious yeah but uh you know I mean
it's it's pretty simple if you want to
you know just get rid of it if it's
bothering you for a bit uh Justin takes
so one means we can't rabies damage by
the way during this all you got to do is
just uh you know well this this is this
is secret you can't tell anyone you guys
know promise you won't tell anyone that
I told you to okay
of course yeah sure yeah you just got to
throw water on the person with rabies
and I will just get rid of it for a
while really yeah that's that's perfect
or job like experts like ordinary
or just kill consumers there's a problem
what all our buckets burned down there's
a lake right over there I'll be right
back no you don't know what that you
know what's right don't you come on no
what oh you don't know what I mean any
wonder I've had it for a little bit I
gotta have a little bit long yeah fine
so you don't so you don't want Justin to
go to the nearby lake and look American
waters anything in that lake and he's
not supposed to go anywhere unsupervised
can't just wander around Felipe you're
his handler and we'll hit Felipe you're
the what you need to escort him they do
the water follow me I'll take you to the
water all right sweet Kyle push him in
the water so how the heck okay burned
down buckets of water
well the buckets are made out of wood
and wood but the waters made out of
water
yeah but the woods matter would you like
a scientist or something me or him
clinical eco he knows that waters made
out of water that's true no idea
dead bones let's go good stuff I
what's this thing arms is to me the arms
we get an arm each hey you a left arm
like all right arm these are these arms
are massive they are far too heavy to
carry uh they're not as bloody as you
would think they are um it's like
somehow they like they cauterize itself
would have fell off so there's a little
bit of blood but they're big but they're
too heavy for you to carry could we cut
a fist off probably really hard to cut
mean you got a cut through the bone wait
do you have a very like sighs oh I
thought the arms were made a diamond or
Jen no no no like that those look like
diamond arms I don't know maybe maybe
it's he's made of a gym no no I don't
come across two of you gym Lords have
arms at first out of the night I
I wrestled that guy they were meeting
listen me I don't really want them I
thought they were made a gym la meanie I
mean you could like I'm surprised it
wasn't like a bodybuilder wearing a gym
costume and you could go get cooked
had a meal I guess I'm gonna leave the
Armsby you mentioned that there was
something sparkly though
no no just like there's little like spot
like diamond sparkles around road
because you know where these guys have
exploded there's no loot off this you
can roll for loot though Roman I've seen
this one easy kid and philippe is coming
in uh right what is it what's up oh hey
um so have you ever been past this room
I know you talked about how you never
saw this or never touched this before
but you know have you have you been
anywhere else
um I mean up ahead you know there was a
pack of like those Ella folks but I
think they moved on but I mean if we
want to go this way instead of going
like the other way through the K out of
the cave like look where you actually
good where you guys going I don't even
know uh
that's your business well how am I
supposed to hell's going how much part
of the party now man he's got a no look
if he's part of the party he's not going
to cut right outside this cave though is
a bridge it is there's a bridge troll on
it
so a bridge troll yeah you got it you
got to pay the you got to pay him he he
like a troll toll yeah he's pretty
reasonable you know he just accepts you
know treasure of like any kind but you
have to pay a giant arms
I probably carry much we could drag them
but I don't know if you'd want them T
does to trolls like uh like like dwarf
is dwarf oh nice meal for trolls I hate
a rolled dice cuz I don't want to decide
this all right let's not take your
question okay
nevermind okay though that was a secret
dice okay super die something happens so
do trolls like D Dwarfs
I don't know I mean it's not really a
troll but now but he's on a bridge
that's what roles do those but wait
so if he's know what it what is he
what's he like um see dude look like us
well like a couple uh he looks just like
you guys
yeah he looks just like just so you guys
yeah we all look pretty different but
it's like blemishes I mean y'all kind of
look the same really helps what wait a
minute yeah we're know yeah
Weasley to say to me okay just a minute
we're Keynes he's a no kinoma it's all
the same man this there's no difference
with you I mean you both were goggles
again with you I think we're talking
rich trouble is guys what I think I know
who the bridge troll is is he really
resented for is that the secret
oh no it's miss 'van miss him is the
bridge troll but he's a gnome
he said he looks like us that's he's
that I can't argue with this logic yeah
I actually that makes perfect sense it
really does this happens kinda you know
I don't know he's a dick yeah total dick
he's like a dick he's got that big hat
to make him flake feel oh I'm so much
bigger than everybody else I got a big
fucking stupid wizard hat hospice look
at me just figure it out man he charges
people keys to get across the bridge I
met it Oh oh my god we don't having a
key so all right hold on that's what you
do take a look I mean let's let's see
what we're actually deal with if it's a
discipline we got a plan but wait just
where's colt oh wait a minute
who left Justin on a tendon you told me
you gonna come over here you know you're
supposed to bring him what happened to
did you let him drink water he eat
even after I get some water Justin did
you drink some water baby all right I'm
gonna walk you out of all this dad I'm
sorry there's nothing I can do like I'm
just waiting symbols all day
oh yeah so yeah he dunked his head in
the water and he cured himself of it so
like um like completely so hey I should
have had a session of role I just need
to not I need to have you guys do all
the rules my rules are just ones today
least Oh should we should we fill in
kobold about the troll bridge situation
troll bridge yeah that's special bigger
than a cobalt just follow us we got the
plan in case it isn't a sin all right
everybody's okay with anything goes down
you jump it for
all right sounds good she probably
therapy The Wizard The Wonderful Wizard
of bridge we're not singing that song
anymore
we're singing it you double back Roman
oh god this isn't a mess and we all try
to leave so bringing all the guys up so
you're gonna peek around this corner
booth and you're gonna see on the bridge
what looks to be a little tiny gnome and
you don't even know what that other
thing is what the hell is God so wrote
Romans peaked around the corner he see
he sees what's going on you can see the
gnome that Felipe was talking about but
something else on that bridge that
doesn't look like a girl so guys good
news bad news
I mean the good news good news is it
looks like it's a gnome it's on the
bridge okay bad news is it's totally not
nestling and he's got some kind of bear
monkey with wait go well we know we know
that miss 'van can disguise himself mmm
April where to get a better monkey frog
really amazing recipe I thought this has
been said there was a fish monkey
we went yeah I remembered oh I clearly
not a visual pun see without a % bear
monkey wait was that yeah are you sure
no it's a monk fish fish monk thing yeah
I think hey Philippe yeah baby is key
okay get bleep in here yeah believe I'm
een I'm pretty sure I know what that is
that's that looks like an eagle bear
yeah they got a wings they could fly oh
no bear no leash yeah you sure it's not
a bear monkey uh honestly not really
sure it could be a bear monkey that
looking at it it's like a type do
monkeys have beaks why is this kind of
low quality when i zoom in that's weird
okay is it more bear or more monkey or
more eagle it's definitely bear but I'm
pretty sure the other half is eagle well
I mean I go
ways on this like can it fly yeah with
his wings okay I know you like me I mean
I sleep is gonna move a little bit
forward here I'm gonna move a little woo
loop is gonna move a little bit forward
he's gonna speak around he's like yeah I
could definitely see its wings lay right
on his back that's how he flies on hand
that's bad wait does lay eggs I don't
know I'm not a give Eagle bear master I
don't know these things you're the
scientist every time is a global valid
man you're the boss yeah you work you're
the boss okay kind of okay it's it's
just a gnome maybe we can kind of
bargain with it I heard that you know
you know they're shifty yes good i hey
hey i I got it I'm not a good fighter I
know I've you know but I know one thing
I'm good at
you got that over tongue I got a silver
tie what it disguise I I don't really I
don't know I don't really feel good
about using that though but oh come on I
don't really want to Bugs Bunny this guy
cuz that one time it's good well
actually you remember Mike uh yeah yeah
Mike Mike he disguise himself as a
female dwarf to get some some drinks in
a bar and the dwarfs took a liking to
him and he never came into real estate
two guys they just think they saw Jesus
he was this girl named Michelle I don't
think we need to read it to that at all
that's a hey put on your dress
no okay do it so is the plan dead bones
is gonna do the talking here I'm gonna
do the talking I'm gonna be all I want
no I don't want go with me oh yeah are
you just gonna buy yourself who's coming
Roman are you go with him I think Roman
should come alright and the guys you
kind of stay back yesterday hang your AK
in a non-threatening yeah sure maybe
hide the cobble Oh ashamed of him I
can't receive it Justin
oh my god Scott wait okay it's too late
no I'm just as in hello son Justin's in
this hey hey hey ha ha Isherwood would
like to pass to pay the fine is the only
way to pass the toll wait I may answer
that wrong to pay the toll is the only
way to find the pass what you gotta get
it y'all gettin a piece of treasure for
my treasure chest
you want a treasure yeah it's whether
it's on the bridge troll and if you
don't pay me I'll send my mighty eagle
bear after you but young and him he
could fly you know you're not a troll at
all
wait no no he's got to learn he's not a
troll he's a known oh now he's good look
at those ears
look Eddie short it's too short for no
I'm not at photos come who the hell's
calling me a troll ah that guy at the
back the dwarf he's a bit of a jackass
who's not with us yeah he's uh he's just
calling excuse me I'm gonna have a look
everything yeah yeah no you get through
I didn't say calling me a troll no no no
not a feed you to my eaglebear you
little dwarf
no I just what he got on you what do you
got on you uh on you what do I have on
me I Nessie is gonna reach to try and
take uh your emulative bones
would you like to resist ah would you
like to risk this Messi's little snatch
well it goes the grill if you snatches
out of my do I get to pass or is this
just like a random chase out this is the
shake town so he goes to reach reach for
your he goes to recall he goes to reach
for your Emmy little bones around your
neck and you grab your helmet because
you don't to lose that that's more
important to you
and he just swipes your Emmy little
bones I'll be taking that you may pass
the bridge dwarf oh okay going so it's
not a great is my group tool no no no
only dwarves cross this bridge not you
disgusting little
this out but I think gnomes I dare you
I'm not a gnome I'm the great Nessie
Bridge troll see I related to a
dissident yeah do you know miss Evan no
I don't believe I do huh no I'm an only
child
I've never ever loved another woman or
known another man just no flow family no
mother or father sister her husband can
you excuse us for a second
me and my bear and now you just did
we'll be right back Cory oh hey Justin
you were on the other side of the bridge
but you're just waiting I'm at this
point now you're you're a lady so you
could just you know you know I could
yeah but guess what yeah I'm all Skeeter
yeah but I mean it's not that bad
looking you could probably take 110 it
shouldn't be a problem for you I mean I
you know what
all right under this guy nice I'm not
whispering either give me your treasure
or get off my bridge uh I'll be I'll be
right back just you know that's right
better off my bridge you just about it
yes CDN dome I'm going to use disguise
and get my other shoes
uh where's disguise it's you're gonna
walk out the bridge together and you're
gonna try yes disguise I'm gonna use
gonna use this guy's yet all right so
wait wait is it R is it roll then voice
are voiced and roll um roll and then you
can do that what are you trying to turn
into that's what we need I'm going to
turn into a dwarf you're gonna turn into
a dwarf okay
just a dude dwarf is the normal dude
dwarf okay wait you're doing that right
beside Felipe you trying to tease me is
that what's going on here right this is
successful oh yeah you're successful you
are you're males Worf
Adi good I think come on are you doing
that hello there dwarf one treasure
please the crossbar let's know it's no
problem would you like Oh what do you
got uh you can have this spell wool
armor it's very nice very good you may
pass oh you're such a big strong troll I
hope you find love someday no I'm past
the beach and then hang out with Justin
okay yeah sock we get that moment to
talk with just uh yeah yeah you can talk
together all right guys we have a little
chat all right what's the game plan
Roman okay
so Justin got across I have no idea how
he's dumb as rocks then dead bones went
across he seemed to look like a dwarf
though so I'm starting to think this guy
is a thing for dwarfs I hate dwarfs wait
I I'm not this does he hate Keynes can I
cross you're not a keen Irene sorry
cobalt circles I've never been gay yeah
you guys were so large yeah well I am
you're just low on chance buddy I want
to grab some before we leave if I could
just get five red gems roaming then I'm
sure I could pass that huh why don't we
just get some gems from the cave and
give it to him he'll think the treasures
we could lie to him who that's actually
really Heidi that's a really good idea I
know I didn't even think of that
let's do obey we'll give one of the arms
mm okay let's just do the gems doesn't
work got arms okay so our guys went back
they collected a bunch of dude little
gems out of the cave
and then they're gonna reproach Nessie
hello there sir what is it you know
I understand you are looking for payment
for passage across this lovely priority
told you gnomes on it loud across this
bridge get lost
whoa whoa whoa let's not be so hasty
perhaps these little lovely bubbles will
change your mind I'm going to see what
you have here Hannah
ah look with your eyes not with your
hands
those look like some pretty good gems
but I still want your treasure cause
you're gonna give me a pre-stretch if
you want to cross at the very least you
know I think for you then what is your
name again my name is Nessie the bridge
troll but don't call me that I don't
land unlike people calling me troll I
totally understand I wouldn't want to
call you that either
what it's okay my name you know you see
me oh why you me that's a very pretty
name maybe for a little kiss I could let
you cross the bridge huh oh I wouldn't
want to be so forward but perhaps maybe
a little uh a little little lost rope
new you sir yeah hey let me just kind of
all right yeah however you may
definitely pass and come back anytime
you like maybe I will all right well
right now oh hey those other guys that
are behind me they're with me too though
where they go it's gonna be a little bit
more than a kiss and I don't have a moat
for that perhaps if you look the time I
could find a way to get something else
up that's Nessie being completely
absorbed in the the gracefulness of you
me allows all of Romans friends the past
bridge hey guys come on you you come
here - you come anytime you want you me
you spicy little devil you I might see
you on the way back
[Music]
you