hey Vsauce Michael here what is the
biggest number you can think of a Google
a googolplex a milli million all Plex
well in reality the biggest number is 40
covering more than 12,000 square meters
of Earth this 40 made out of
strategically planted trees in Russia is
larger than the battalion markers on
Signal Hill in Calgary the six found on
the above and badges in England even the
mile of pie Brady unrolled on
numberphile 40 is the biggest number on
earth in terms of surface area but in
terms of amount of things which is
normally what we mean by a number of big
40 probably isn't the biggest for
example there's 41 L and then there's 42
and 43 a billion a trillion you know no
matter how big of a number you can think
of you could always go higher so there
is no biggest last number except
infinity no infinity is not a number
instead it's a kind of number you need
infinite numbers to talk about and
compare amounts that are unending but
some unending amounts some infinities
are literally bigger than others
let's visit some of them and count Pasco
first things first
when a number refers to how many things
there are it is called a cardinal number
for example for bananas twelve flags
twenty dots twenty is the cardinality of
this set of dots now to
have the same cardinality when they
contain the same number of things we can
demonstrate this equality by pairing
each member of one set one-to-one with
each member of the other same
cardinality pretty simple we use the
natural numbers that is 0 1 2 3 4 5 and
so on as Cardinals whenever we talk
about how many things there are but how
many natural numbers are there
it can't be some number in the Naturals
because there'd always be one plus that
number after it instead there's a unique
name for this amount aleph-null Aleph is
the first letter of the Hebrew alphabet
and Aleph null is the first smallest
infinity it's how many natural numbers
there are it's also how many even
numbers there are how many odd numbers
there are it's also how many rational
numbers that is fractions there are that
it may sound surprising since fractions
appear more numerous on the number line
but as Cantor showed there's a way to
arrange every single possible rational
such that the naturals can be put into a
one-to-one correspondence with they have
the same cardinality point is Aleph null
is a big amount bigger than any finite
amount a googol a googolplex a
googolplex factorial to the power of a
googolplex to a googolplex squared times
Graham's number Aleph Nolan is bigger
but we can count past it how well let's
use our old friend the super task if we
draw a bunch of lines and make each next
line a fraction of the size and a
fraction of the distance from each last
line well we can fit an unending number
of lines into a finite space the number
of lines here is equal to the number of
natural numbers that there are the tube
can be matched one-to-one there's always
a next natural but there's also always a
next line both sets have the cardinality
L of null but what happens when I do
this
now how many lines are there Aleph null
plus 1 no unending amounts aren't like
finite amounts there are still only
Aleph null lines here because I can
match the Naturals 1 to 1 just like
before I just start here and then
continue from the beginning clearly the
amount of lines hasn't changed I can
even add two more lines three more four
more I always end up with only Aleph
null things I can even add another
infinite aleph-null of lines and still
not change the quantity every even
number can pair with these in every odd
number with these there is still a line
for every natural another cool way to
see that these lines don't add to the
total is to show that you can make this
same sequence without drawing new lines
at all just take every other line and
move them all together to the end it's
the same thing
what hold on a second this and this may
have the same number of things in them
but clearly there's something different
about them right I mean if it's not how
many things they're made of what is it
well let's go back to having just one
line after an aleph-null sized
collection what if instead of matching
the Naturals one to one we insist on
numbering each line according to the
order it was drawn in so we have to
start here and number left to right now
what number does this line get in the
realm of the infinite labeling things in
order is pretty different than counting
them you see this line doesn't
contribute to the total but in order to
label it according to the order it
appeared in well we need a set of labels
of numbers that extends past the
naturals
we need ordinal numbers the first
transfinite
ordinal is omega the lowercase Greek
letter Omega this isn't a joke or a
trick it's literally just the next label
you'll need after using up the infinite
collection of every single counting
number first if you got omega 'the place
in a race that would mean that an
infinite number of people finished the
race and then you did after Omega comes
Omega plus 1 which doesn't really look
like a number but it is just like 2 or
12 or 800 then comes Omega plus 2 Omega
plus 3 ordinal numbers label things in
order ordinals aren't about how many
things there are instead they tell us
how those things are arranged their
order type the order type of a set is
just the first ordinal number not needed
to label everything in the set in order
so for finite numbers cardinality and
order type
the same the order type of all the
naturals is Omega the order type of this
sequence is Omega plus 1 and now it's
Omega plus 2 no matter how long an
arrangement becomes as long as its well
ordered as long as every part of it
contains a beginning element the whole
thing describes a new ordinal number
always this will be very important later
on it should be noted at this point that
if you are ever playing a game of who
can name the biggest number and you're
considering Sain Omega plus 1 you should
be careful your opponents might require
the number of you name to be a cardinal
that refers to an amount these numbers
refer to the same amount of stuff just
arranged differently Omega plus 1 isn't
bigger than Omega it just comes after
Omega but aleph-null
isn't the end why well because it can be
shown that there are infinities bigger
than aleph-null
that literally contain more things one
of the best ways to do this is with
Cantor's diagonal argument in my episode
on the bonod tarski paradox I used it to
show that the number of real numbers is
larger than the number of natural
numbers but for the purposes of this
video let's focus on another thing
bigger than Aleph null the power set of
Aleph null the power set of a set is the
set of all the different subsets you can
make from for example from the set of 1
&amp; 2 I can make a set of nothing or 1 or
2 or 1 &amp; 2 the power set of 1 2 3 is the
empty set 1 &amp; 2 &amp; 3 &amp; 1 &amp; 2 &amp; 1 &amp; 3 &amp; 2
&amp; 3 &amp; 1
two three as you can see a power set
contains many more members than the
original set to ^ however many members
the original set had to be exact so
what's the power set of all the naturals
well let's see imagine a list of every
natural number cool
now the subset of all say even numbers
would look like this yes no yes no yes
no and so on the subset of all odd
numbers would look like this here's the
subset of just three seven and twelve
and how about every number except five
or no number except five obviously this
list of subsets is going to be well
infinite but imagine matching them all
one to one with a natural if even then
there's a way to keep producing new
subsets that are clearly not listed
anywhere here we will know that we've
got a set with more members than there
are natural numbers a bigger infinity
than aleph-null the way to do this is to
start up here in the first subset and
just do the opposite of what we see zero
is a member of this one
so our new set will not contain zero
next move diagonally down to one's
membership in the second subset one is a
member of it so it will not be in our
new one two is not in the third subset
so it will be in ours and so on
as you can see we are describing a
subset that will be by definition
different in at least one way from every
single other subset on this aleph-null
sized list even if we put this new
subset back in diagonalization can still
be done the power set of the Naturals
will always resist a one-to-one
correspondence with the naturals it's an
infinity bigger than aleph-null
repeated applications of power set will
produce sets that can't be put into
one-to-one correspondence with the last
so it's a great way to quickly produce
bigger and bigger infinities the point
is there are more Cardinals after
aleph-null
let's try to reach them now remember
that after Omega ordinals split and
these numbers are no longer Cardinals
they don't refer to a greater amount
than the last Cardinal we reached but
maybe they can take us to one wait what
are we doing Aleph null Omega come on
we've been using these numbers like
there's no problem but if at any point
down here you can always add one always
can we really talk about it this endless
process as a totality and then follow it
with something of course we can
this is math not science the things we
assumed to be true in math are called
axioms and an axiom we come up with
isn't more likely to be true if it
better explains or predicts what we
observe instead it's true because we say
it is its consequences just become what
we observe we are not fitting our
theories to some physical universe whose
behavior and underlying laws would be
the same whether we were here or not we
are creating this universe ourselves if
the axioms we declare to be true lead us
to contradictions or paradoxes we can go
back and tweak them or just abandon them
all together or we can just refuse to
allow ourselves to do the things that
cause the paradoxes that's it what's
fascinating though is that in making
sure the axioms we accept don't lead to
problems we've made math into something
that is as the saying goes unreasonably
effective in the Natural Sciences so to
what extent were inventing all of this
or discovering it it's hard to say all
we have to do to get Omega is say let
there be Omega and it will be good
that's what Ernest Zermelo did in 1908
when he included the axiom of infinity
in his list of axioms for doing stuff in
math the axiom of infinity is simply the
declaration that one infinite set exists
the set of all natural numbers if you
refuse to accept it that's fine
that makes you a finite list one who
believes only finite things exist
but if you accept it as most
mathematicians do you can go pretty far
past these and through these eventually
we get to Omega plus Omega except we
reached another ceiling going all the
way out to Omega plus Omega would be to
create another infinite set and the
axiom of infinity only guarantees that
this one exists are we going to have to
add a new axiom every time we describe a
LOF no more numbers no the axiom of
replacement can help us here this
assumption states that if you take a set
like say the set of all natural numbers
and replace each element with something
else like say bananas what you're left
with is also a set that sounds simple
but it's incredibly useful try this take
every ordinal up to Omega and then
instead of bananas put Omega plus in
front of each now we've reached Omega
plus Omega or Omega times to using
replacement we can make jumps of any
size we want so long as we only use
numbers we already achieved we can
replace every ordinal up to Omega with
Omega times it to reach omega x omega
omega squared we're cooking now the
axiom of replacement allows us to
construct new ordinals without end
eventually we get to Omega to the Omega
to the Omega to the Omega 2 Omega and we
run out of standard mathematical
notation
no problem this is just called epsilon
not and we continue from here but now
think about all of these ordinals all
the different ways to arrange aleph-null
things well these are well ordered so
they have an order type some ordinal
that comes after all of them in this
case that ordinal is called Omega one
now because by definition Omega one
comes after every single order type of
aleph-null things it must describe an
arrangement of literally more stuff than
the last Aleph I mean if it didn't it
would be somewhere in here but it's not
the Cardinal number describing the
amount of things used to make an
arrangement with order type Omega 1 is
Aleph one it's not known where the power
set of the naturals falls on this line
it can't be between these Cardinals
because well there aren't Cardinals
between them it could be equal to a
loved one that belief is called the
continuum hypothesis but it could also
be larger we just don't know the
continuum hypothesis by the way is
probably the greatest unanswered
question in this entire subject and
today in this video
I will not be solving it but I will be
going higher and higher to bigger and
bigger infinities now using the
replacement axiom we can take any
ordinal we've already reached like say
Omega and jump from Aleph to Aleph all
the way out to a love Omega or peck why
not use a bigger ordinal like Omega
square to construct Aleph Omega squared
Aleph Omega Omega Omega Omega Omega
Omega Omega our notation only allows me
to add countably many omegas here but
replacement doesn't care about whether
or not I have a way to write the numbers
it reaches wherever I land will be a
place of even bigger numbers allowing me
to make even bigger and more numerous
jumps than before the whole thing is a
wildly accelerating feedback loop of
imbibing we can keep going like this
reaching bigger and bigger infinities
from below replacement and repeated
power sets which may or may not line up
with the ellipse can keep our climb
going forever so clearly there's nothing
beyond them
right not so fast that's what we said
about getting past the finite to Omega
why not accept as an axiom that there
exists some next number so big no amount
of replacement or power setting on
anything smaller could ever get you now
such a number is called an inaccessible
cardinal because you can't reach it from
below now interestingly within the
numbers we've already reached a shadow
of such a number can be found Aleph null
you can't reach this number from below
either all numbers less than it are
finite and a finite number of finite
numbers can't be added multiplied
exponentiate 'add replaced with finite
jumps a finite number of times or even
power set a finite number of times to
give you anything but another finite
amount sure the power set of a milli
million to a googolplex to a googolplex
to a googolplex is really big but it's
still just finite not even close to
Aleph null the first smallest infinity
for this reason Aleph null is often
considered an inaccessible number some
authors don't do this though saying an
inaccessible must also be uncountable
which okay makes sense I mean we've
already accessed Aleph null but remember
the only way we could is by straight-up
declaring its existence axiomatically we
will have to do the same for
inaccessible Cardinals it's really hard
to get across
just how unfathomable the size of an
inaccessible Cardinal is I'll just leave
it at this
the conceptual jump from nothing to the
first infinity is like the jump from the
first infinity to an inaccessible
set theorists have described numbers
bigger than inaccessible x' each one
requiring a new large cardinal axiom
asserting its existence expanding the
height of our universe of numbers will
there ever come a point where we devise
an axiom implying the existence of so
many things that it implies
contradictory things will we someday
answer the Continuum Hypothesis maybe
not but there are promising directions
and until then the amazing fact remains
that many of these infinities perhaps
all of them are so big it's not exactly
clear whether they even truly exist or
could be shown to in the physical
universe if they do if one day physics
finds a use for them that's great but if
not that's great too that would mean
that we have with this brain a tiny
thing a cept Elian times smaller than
the tiny planet it lives on discovered
something true outside of the physical
realm something that applies to the real
world but is also strong enough to go
further past what even the universe
itself can contain or show us or be and
as always thanks for watching
another interesting fact about
transfinite ordinals is that arithmetic
with them is a little bit different
normally two plus one is the same as one
plus two but Omega plus one is not the
same as one plus Omega 1 plus Omega is
actually just omega think about them as
order types one thing placed before
Omega just uses up all the naturals and
leaves us with order type Omega one
thing placed after Omega requires every
natural number and then Omega leaving us
with Omega plus 1 as the order type