hey Vsauce Michael here if you rearrange
the letters in William Shakespeare you
can spell here was I like a song in the
King James Bible in psalm 46 the 46th
word is shake and the 46th word from the
bottom is sphere William Shakespeare was
46 years old when the King James Bible
was completed is this just a coincidence
yes it is
given enough searching enough words
enough data you can eventually find and
should indeed expect all kinds of neat
coincidences it's just probability
here's another good example think of a
card any card value and suit okay got it
mentally focus on that card deliver it
to my brain using ESP whoa I got it here
it is amazing right now think of another
card are you ready okay it's some well
it's this one right one more time
think of a card really think about it
and there it is impressed
probably not but approximately seven of
you might be you see there are only 52
cards if each card is equally likely to
be thought of I had a one in 52 chance
of guessing your card and about a 1 in
every 140,000 chance of doing so three
times in a row if say a million people
watch this video and play along after
three tries you could expect about seven
people to be left who had their imagined
card pulled by mean each time
except not more than seven actually
you see there's even more magic
happening here and by magic I mean math
when asked to arbitrarily think of a
card studies have shown that people tend
to think of certain cards more often
than others these are the results from a
study of a few hundred people hearts are
named a bit more often than the other
suits the three cards I drew are the top
three most often thought of but would it
be more amazing if it actually was magic
yes and no obviously magic as a
performance is important it reminds us
that being stupefied and curious and
humbled is fun without a visceral
reaction to the unknown would we care to
learn or study or investigate but yet
explanations don't dull mystery they
empower the mystified explanations
aren't ends their end trances the start
of an ability to use reassemble and
reimagine new things out of what you now
know here's a cool fact if you divide a
deck of cards exactly in half there will
always be the same number of red cards
in one half as there are black cards in
the other no matter how mixed up the
cards were before you began it's not
magic though it's just that think of it
this way half of the cards in a deck are
red so all the red cards could fit in
one deck half this means that the number
of cards in a half that aren't red that
is our black cards are necessarily equal
in number to the Reds that must be in
the other half knowing this you can
devise an even neater trick like the
really cool trick Matt Parker just
showed off on his channel which you
should subscribe to or like this one
take an easier to count number of cards
like say 10 and then place another 10
cards on top but face up have a friend
shuffle the whole mess however they wish
cuts
messy cuts riffle smooshing they just
can't cause any card to flip over then
ask them to hand you the pack and behind
your back even while blindfolded show
them that you can separate the deck into
two halves with the same number of
face-up cards every time over and over
again all you have to do is count out
ten cards the number of face-up cards in
one hand will equal the number of
facedown cards in the other flip one of
the packs over and all of its facedown
cards will turn into face-up ones tada
the face-up counts are now equal here's
another trick that shows off some neat
mathematical properties to help me with
this trick I've brought in Vanessa from
the YouTube channel braincraft it's an
awesome Channel please go check it out
but first check out this trick are you
ready I'm ready
we've got ten cards on the table five
diamonds and five clubs ace to five of
each go ahead and put the clubs on top
of the diamonds face up face up yep
alright now I am going to mix these
cards up alright and you are going to
use your ESP abilities to get the cards
paired up at the end are you ready okay
so I want to mix these up take some off
the top moving to the bottom taking
cards from the bottom and just like I
don't
okay I'm gonna I'm gonna cut these as
well let me know where you want to cut
them okay yeah there okay we'll cut the
cards there and I'm gonna take half of
what's here five cards and deal him down
one two three four five
imma set the other five right there now
we have two piles and it is your turn to
start swapping we got four swaps you can
make and a swap involves taking the top
card and moving it to the bottom okay
alright now you can divvy up these four
swaps however you want you can do four
here you can do 2 &amp; 2 1 &amp; 3 whatever you
want okay I'll do three here and one
yeah interesting yeah right you do it
I'll do it one two three and then one
swap here good yes now we're left with
these two cards on top I'm going to take
them off and set them right here now
three swaps ah all three on this pile
ooh
in our esteem okay it's your choice one
two three and the top two cards I will
peel off and we'll set aside all right
now two swaps to heal two here mm-hmm
all right one two
once again the cards that are on top get
peeled off and set aside one swap and
one here one here okay
so I'll take these away and we're left
with two cards will they be the same
will they be a match let's find out
yes okay whoa don't say okay yet because
things aren't okay something magic just
happened we've got all of these cards we
set aside and yet they're all matches
both aces right there what are these
both fives you also matched up the
threes and of course the fours you're
welcome
thank you very much but not you Vanessa
you mathematics every time no matter how
your friend decided to swap matching
pairs will be together how well it's all
about cycles if you have some cards in a
particular order and you cut them
somewhere doesn't matter whether you
will only change the positions of the
individual cards but not the sequence
the next card down will always be the
next card in order with the whole thing
wrapping back around it helps to think
of the order not as a tower but as a
clock now when the trick we just did
each cards match is always just five
cards away in the sequin
because 5:00 happens to also be the
number of cards in half the pack
dividing the pack in half leaves pairs
lined up no matter how we've cut the
deck in the trick however we added a bit
of extra confusion by dealing the top
half down onto the table one two three
four five this has the effect of
reversing its order now instead of
having the same position in each pack
pairs have mirrored positions the number
of cards below any given card in the
bottom pack is the number above it in
the top pack this balance means that
swapping all the cards above a target in
the bottom pack leaves it on top and
swapping the number of cards below it
from the other pack leaves its match on
the other top of course the number of
cards above and below a target card in
the bottom pack is just the number of
all the other cards in that half which
is the total amount in each pack minus
one that's why with five cards in each
pack we started with four swaps then
after each packet shrunk to four we did
three swaps as long as the total number
of swaps adds up to the pack total minus
1 we'll have matching pairs on top you
can extend these facts about cyclical
sequences to other tricks of your own
imagining this is one of my favorite
tricks it comes from Peter Magowan on
the stem maths magic channel trick time
once again I'm joined by Vanessa from
brain craft and ace through five of
diamonds and ace through five of clubs
Vanessa could you please take the ACE
through five of diamonds and put them on
top of the clubs but flip them over so
they're facedown okay so we now have a
kind of messy little deck here where all
the black cards are face up and the reds
are face down but we're gonna mix these
up a lot we can even riffle shuffle this
riffle shuffle riffle shuffle right kind
of divide it in half like this and then
well it's hard to do with few cards but
I know you do this little yeah and they
do a little you know room very good yeah
thank you
where would you like me to cut these
right there okay cool now there's
another way you can kind of mix up and
deal cards it's called the down over
deal goes like this one card goes down
the next goes over one goes down one
goes over down over down over down over
till you're done okay but now it's your
turn all right I'm gonna go two at a
time and you're gonna tell me whether
these first two cards should be dealt
down or should be turned over okay down
down what about these down down over
over this to me down or your bottom over
all right now let's go four at a time
okay
one two three four should these go down
or over over over what about these
former
damn and the final two over now we can
do this as long as often as you want I
can keep doing this we can do - we can't
afford a time how do you feel uh let's
do it once more and do two at a time two
times okay down down down down
you're getting fat huh down okay all
right now I'm going to make two little
piles like a little book all right one
okay
now Vanessa should I close this book
like this or like this like this all
right there we go
now you had completely free choice here
mm-hmm you made a lot of different
decisions somewhat arbitrarily but yet
like oil and water the black and the red
cards have separated and only the Reds
are face-up
I knew this would happen but it's not
because of magic it's because of math
here's how it works the red cards all
start out facedown the black cards
face-up no amount of cutting or rippling
will change the fact that Reds are
facedown and blacks are face-up
but when you down over Deal you cause
every other card to have its original
facing Direction reversed down over down
over down over down over down over this
alternating sequence is maintained
through any number of cuts because it's
cyclical this is the key to the trick
because when we alternatively deal cards
into book halves one pile will contain
cards reversed by the down over deal the
other cards not reverse depending on how
you close the book either all reversed
carts are unrehearsed or all unrehearsed
cards are reversed
either way the original division by
color comes back the swaps missed things
up by introducing an illusion of control
but in reality the swaps are what are
known as a hummer deal a swap
flips the facing direction
the cards you flip but simultaneously
moves them to the correct category
preserving the sequence as long as you
swap an even number of cards the facing
direction of all of them is reversed but
the positions they wind up in are still
correct according to the sequence
finally let's end with something popular
that also sounds cool on the surface
until you go deeper understand it better
and it winds up being well even cooler
the number of different ways 52 cards
can be arranged there's obviously a lot
the top card could be any card
so there's 52 different possibilities
any remaining cards can follow so there
are 51 possibilities for the next card
54 the third spot 49 for the fourth and
so on multiplying all of these numbers
together gives us how many unique ways
52 cards can be arranged 52 factorial is
a gigantic amount so large in fact every
time you shuffle a deck of cards
well smoosh it for a few minutes or
riffle at 7 or more times
chances are you have put those playing
cards into an order that they have never
been in in the entire history of cards
or humans or the universe seriously this
is because 52 factorial is eight point
zero six five eight times 10 to the 67th
in comparison the observable universe is
only about 10 to the 18th seconds old
even if you had been properly shuffling
a deck every single second since the
universe began 13.7 billion years ago
you still to this day wouldn't have even
come close to assembling every
arrangement possible but even that
doesn't paint the whole picture of just
how big 52 factorial is scotch appeal
wrote what in my opinion are some of the
most mind-boggling visualizations
of the size of 52 factorial imagine
setting a timer to count down 52
factorial seconds while the timer runs
stand on the equator and wait 1 billion
years after a billion years have passed
take a single step forward and then wait
another billion years before taking a
second step and so on
once you have walked all the way around
the earth take a single drop of water
out of the Pacific Ocean that's 5
hundredths of a milliliter and set it
aside now continue walking at a rate of
one step every billion years removing
one drop after every journey around the
entire Earth and by the time the Pacific
Ocean is completely empty put a single
sheet of paper on the ground refill the
ocean and keep going until the stack of
paper reaches the Sun at that point how
many seconds will be left on the timer
will it be zero a few hundred a few
billion no there will still be 8 times
10 to the 67 seconds left
you have barely made a dent if you start
all over again and do that whole thing a
thousand more times you will only be 1/3
of the way done luckily Scott has a
great idea for how to pass the rest of
the time if you're bored of paper and
water and walking instead he says deal
yourself 5 cards every billion years
when you finally deal yourself a royal
flush buy a lottery ticket if the ticket
wins the lottery throw a single grain of
sand into the Grand Canyon as soon as
the Grand Canyon is completely full of
sand
remove one ounce of rock that's about 28
grams from Mount Everest
by the time Mount Everest is leveled
take a look at the clock
this is what will be left do the whole
Royal Flush lottery ticket Grand Canyon
on Everest thing 256 more times and then
and only then will your timer have
reached zero that is how big 52
factorial is it's pretty big but now
think about this the number of possible
people the number of different humans
there could be is well even larger what
that means is that even though you will
probably die most people including
possibly the smartest or funniest or
most annoying possible person won't even
get to die like you do they won't even
get to be born so I'm glad you were and
as always thanks for watching
dogs are