hey Vsauce Michael here this is the song
of the kawaii
OOW bird in 1987 this species of bird
became extinct there are no more but
before the last living one died its song
was recorded this is that song it is the
song of an ending the final member of a
species asking to know one hey where are
we all it's a male calling for a mate
that will never come for what it's worth
the song is still here we are listening
to it now because it was recorded the
species is lost but the song isn't and
that's the heart of something really big
remember that the world record comes
from core meaning heart to record is to
wreak or to bring something back into
your heart echoes fossils bones
footprints nature's memory is only so
immediate I mean even light itself
scatters is absorbed and dims according
to the inverse-square law the universe
forgets slowly
but we humans have created special ways
to preserve moments to take them and
turn them into stories things that can
be shared recorded retold disappear
perhaps much later than they would
otherwise I recently had the opportunity
to speak with Sir David Attenborough the
mind and voice behind so many important
stories and Natural History programs
like the very new planet Earth - from
BBC earth I even got to see an episode
and of course it's phenomenal it's also
a time capsule of sorts a gift that
perhaps humans alone on this planet can
give earth a record of itself I'd like
to share our conversation with you we
covered many things technology
science communication humans life
language but let's start with one of the
most immediate effects the program has
on viewers it's a mirror in nature in
animals we see ourselves despair love
hope heroes and villains now whether the
animals themselves are aware of these
emotions or themes is difficult to know
or even investigate but I asked Sir
David Attenborough about storytelling
and the responsibilities that come with
that power this whole program is like a
night at the movies but the characters
are animals and there haven't been
scripted it makes me wonder if you know
all the things that pull at our hearts
that we write for the screen for actors
are just us replaying the same dramas
that have been around since earth began
well that's that's true life has the
same
[Music]
hard-fought moments the first life the
emergence of a new individual creature
onto this planet the end is an
in-between while those mating and
there's aggression and the so on and so
these are the eternal stories and you
you neglect them or or ignore their
power at your peril I mean these are the
important stories and you you do try to
do them justice them it both in a
fundamental truth the founders and in
the trimmings give advice for younger
science communicators when it comes to
reaching a large audience enacting the
change that they want to see I don't
think I have any advice honestly I'm
still learning and still struggling with
things and it's a very presumption
shampoo person who starts giving handing
out advice people know that know what
they're after
Barnard's if they're only good in the
business they know what they're after
and then I want to do and in any case
the advice I give it's bound to be about
yesterday's technology or yesterday's
way of doing things and tomorrow is what
we're all about and and it's it's young
people today who are using the new
technology in ways that I can't dream of
so I wouldn't give advice to people I
mean people talk about going to learn to
make documentary films and and I say
don't come to me I'm use yesterday's
equipment you've got to be using
tomorrow's equipment and you'll do it in
your and that equipment well if you're
true to it will dictate the way in which
you deal with it which you handle these
things and that's the way you get
advanced is in whatever technology
indeed whatever art we're talking about
technology is a big part of planet Earth
- we can document record track and film
animals now like never before
in the ten years since the first planet
Earth drones have become smaller and
quieter we have learned how to better
find and study and predict animal
behavior
planet Earth two captured things that we
science had not yet seen happen and in
some cases didn't even know did happen I
just was really struck today by the
landmark nature of the program that's
why I think it's so important I think
that we're documenting things that 50
years ago no one even had seen and I
think we have a responsibility for
better or worse to document these things
for ourselves for others and for the
future I think we have a very fortunate
time living and very fortunate
technologies enable us to do things and
we ought to use it with some sense of
responsibility for the next generation
and it is absolutely the case that a
demonstrable species are disappearing
and it's quite possible that things that
I filmed 20 years ago in 30 years time
will not be exist so we have a that as a
responsibility I mean what would we not
give to be able to see a but I canis or
dinosaur hunting people had been around
that money the time scales different
city better to say mammoth it would be
great to see a mammoth would it not or
even a dodo bird I'd like yeah I
wouldn't mind seeing a dado cut we have
photographs of them are just inky no no
no no yeah we don't even have a complete
genuine individual body really no the
last complete one was a specimen in
Oxford's Museum and in the middle of the
early nineteenth century developed
maggots and so on so they burnt it but
they then some pulled out one or two of
the bones but now you have you have you
can put together and enough bones from
different individuals to have a complete
dodo skeleton so you know who the shape
of every bone but then you don't have
the individual and even the ones you'll
see in museums no one nearly all was
made of sort of chicken feathers and
suitably dyed and painted with a plaster
head
the camera can now capture things that
nature and ourselves previously
struggled to keep with such detail like
the dodo bird which went extinct in the
1600s it's easy to feel sad that such
creatures are lost that we can't pet
them today or that there wasn't a planet
Earth program back then to at least film
them but speaking of that emotion
feeling hope and pity at the
helplessness of an animal in the wild
being hunted as prey struggling to get
back on land to feed its children like
these chinstrap penguins should we do
more than record them I mean in cases
like this ought we intervene and give
them a helping hand when it comes to
interfering where would you draw the
line what if I wanted to like help the
chinstrap penguins get on to the land
yeah is that a good way to interfere or
even then should I let them grow at
their own wise I mean if you if you see
if you're filming a little Impala formal
antelope form hiding in the grass
freezing still refusing to move and you
see a cheetah
stalking towards it and you've been
filming this little pond form because
you've been relationship with its mother
so you weren't seeing it suckling and so
on and the temptation here you can see
this cheetah getting closer to lean out
of the land robe and say shoot you know
and then now if you did that certainly
the form would run and would be actually
terrified out of its wits and run
probably so far I wouldn't be able to
find this way back
the cheetah would have lost its prey
wouldn't been able to catch up with it
and so the cheetah would go back and and
have to find another Impala for the
first Impala fawn will probably not get
back and we knocked off by something
else because it's away from its home
territory so what you've done is
actually make things worse I also asked
about humans where is the planet Earth
episode about people he said this your
own species is it
kettle of fish it's why you can't make a
natural history series about Homo
sapiens that's any good because I mean I
once wrote one I once started to write a
series well why don't we look at human
beings just as though they are animals
we'll fill them in the same way if you
had film monkeys or elephants or
whatever but then at the penny dropped
you can't make a series about any animal
how human or anything else unless you
deal with sexuality and courtship so
suddenly you find that you are at your
peeping toms that you're going to you're
going to film people in courtship
without ten IAM impossible you can do
that with animals yeah yes you do but
that's the point you can't do that van
der waals because we are not animal in
not animals in that sense we are animals
in other senses but we can't do it to
our own species in my du
right how are we different the closer we
look for differences distinctions
hard-and-fast discrete separations the
more blur we see we aren't the only
things that use tools that play that
communicate that have social structure
the differences we hope to find often
turn out to be issues not of
unprecedented features but of matters of
degree even language now appears not to
be a sudden invention or gift but rather
a property that emerged from a happy
accident of more primitive features we
happen to be in the right place to
inherit Sir David Attenborough and I
spoke about distinctions and words when
I asked about life what would you say
defines life and defines defines you
mice yeah life what is the difference
between two particles are living and
dead yeah don't know because you can't
simply say it's it's it's reproduction
because the little bubbles reproduce you
know it's funny that that line is so
hard to define when we spend our whole
lives alive yeah and that's why when
you're dealing with
the questions about well how did life
start you say well I can't tell you how
excited exactly but I can tell you where
it started all the sort of things that
that began and they were things like
complex molecules which we've got a
membrane around them and eventually
before you knew where they were they
were viruses but when that magic moment
comes an extraordinary still don't
understand I like that I hadn't really
thought of this before but yeah dead and
alive or concepts we came up with I once
tried to ask someone who was an expert
is a hyena a cat or a dog and he just
refused to answer he said we make up
these categories absolutely right I mean
we have this passion to classify and
that's the basic classical it's the only
way you can hunt handle very very
complex subjects you have to solve
classify in order to be able to get in
to handle of all bits but that's a human
concept that's what we've done we have
to decide that that that's a captain
that's a dog because those are the two
things that we started off with but then
as you explore the world you would
discover that there are things that are
neither harder and you can then
eventually if you're clever enough and
lucky enough to find the specimens you
can form a phylogenetic tree and you can
see the spread then the time when at the
base of route there's a thing that which
is that what you might call a cog or a
dog or a cat or whatever I mean which is
neither one or the other that's the way
it is and then they've out diversified
and then slowly became things but but
it's a it's a human construct what do
you want people to take away from planet
Earth - as opposed to planet Earth one
or other programs you've worked on the
reality and the importance of the world
the recognition that we aren't the only
species that inhabited the recognition
that in moral terms we can't assume that
everything is ours for to do with
exactly how we
and that other creatures on the earth
also have places in the in grand scheme
of things and then actually we are part
of that and that if we damage them in
the end read Amager selves why is it
important for us to record and document
to give ourselves the perspective of
ourselves on our own futures and iron
past our planet is amazing nature
preserves itself as best it can
but the hill it rolls down natural
selection isn't about preserving the
past it's about survival we however can
tell stories about things describe them
record them measure them with more
detail and voice than any other living
or nonliving thing even if a story is
just made up it's still an attempt to
articulate encapsulate and preserve
something a thought and idea that
otherwise would be forgotten I don't
know if this ability makes humans
different from other animals but it does
in a way mean that we are our planet's
autobiographer 'he's the part of it that
documents and records and tells about it
so let's tell as many stories as
possible and as always thanks for
watching
[Music]
you